<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To assess the effects of <z:chebi fb="5" ids="15940">nicotinic acid</z:chebi> (NA), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5296">gemfibrozil</z:chebi> and combination therapy on the <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile of patients with clinical atherosclerotic disease and isolated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0473527" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoalphalipoproteinemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Isolated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0473527" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoalphalipoproteinemia</z:e> (low <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47775">high density lipoprotein cholesterol</z:chebi> [<z:chebi fb="0" ids="47775">HDL-C</z:chebi>] alone) accounts for a significant percentage of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004416'>premature atherosclerosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, it remains unclear whether currently available pharmacotherapy has the ability to favorably affect the <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile and therefore potentially reduce clinical events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Twenty-three patients with clinically well-defined <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> and isolated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0473527" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoalphalipoproteinemia</z:e> were prospectively randomized to receive <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5296">gemfibrozil</z:chebi>, NA or combination therapy in an open-label, crossover design trial to assess the effects on serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">Lipid</z:chebi> profiles and other relevant laboratory variables were monitored while the patients were on and off pharmacologic <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi>-modulating therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In those 14 patients able to tolerate <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> forms of pharmacotherapy, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="47775">HDL-C</z:chebi> of 0.89 +/- 0.17 mmol/liter (34.5 +/- 6.5 mg/dl) increased by 15%, to 1.02 +/- 0.18 mmol/liter (39.7 +/- 7.1 mg/dl), while taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5296">gemfibrozil</z:chebi> (1,200 mg/day); by 35%, to 1.20 +/- 0.21 mmol/liter (46.5 +/- 8.1 mg/dl), while taking NA (mean dose 2,250 mg/day); and by 45%, to 1.29 +/- 0.19 mmol/liter (50.0 +/- 7.5 mg/dl), while taking combination therapy of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5296">gemfibrozil</z:chebi> plus NA (p &lt; 0.001 for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> interventions as compared with baseline/washout; p &lt; 0.005 NA vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5296">gemfibrozil</z:chebi>; p &lt; 0.001 combination therapy vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5296">gemfibrozil</z:chebi> alone; p = 0.088 combination therapy vs. NA alone) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Statistically significant favorable alterations were also observed with <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47774">low density lipoprotein cholesterol</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="47774">LDL-C</z:chebi>), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="47774">LDL-C</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="47775">HDL-C</z:chebi>, non-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="47775">HDL-C</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="47775">HDL-C</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> (Apo) B and Apo B/Apo A1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In the majority of patients with clinical atherosclerotic disease and isolated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0473527" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoalphalipoproteinemia</z:e>, pharmacologic therapy to raise <z:chebi fb="0" ids="47775">HDL-C</z:chebi> is not only feasible but is also effective with currently available agents, particularly when used in combination </plain></SENT>
</text></document>