<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>Insulin resistance</z:hpo> (IR) and related metabolic disturbances are characterized by low levels of adiponectin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>High molecular weight adiponectin (HMWA) is considered the active form of adiponectin and a better marker of IR than total adiponectin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study is to compare the utility of total adiponectin, HMWA and the HMWA/total adiponectin index (SA index) for the identification of IR and related metabolic conditions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A cross-sectional analysis was performed in a group of ambulatory subjects, aged 20 to 70 years, in Mexico City </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Areas under the receiver operator characteristic (ROC) curve for total, HMWA and the SA index were plotted for the identification of metabolic disturbances </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Sensitivity and specificity, positive and negative predictive values, and accuracy for the identification of IR were calculated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The study included 101 men and 168 women </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The areas under the ROC curve for total and HMWA for the identification of IR (0.664 vs. 0.669, P = 0.74), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> (0.592 vs. 0.610, P = 0.32), <z:hpo ids='HP_0002155'>hypertriglyceridemia</z:hpo> (0.661 vs. 0.671, P = 0.50) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0473527" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoalphalipoproteinemia</z:e> (0.624 vs. 0.633, P = 0.58) were similar </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A total adiponectin level of 8.03 mug/ml was associated with a sensitivity of 57.6%, a specificity of 65.9%, a positive predictive value of 50.0%, a negative predictive value of 72.4%, and an accuracy of 62.7% for the diagnosis of IR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The corresponding figures for a HMWA value of 4.25 mug/dl were 59.6%, 67.1%, 51.8%, 73.7% and 64.2%.The area under the ROC curve of the SA index for the identification of IR was 0.622 [95% CI 0.554-0.691], <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> 0.613 [95% CI 0.536-0.689], <z:hpo ids='HP_0002155'>hypertriglyceridemia</z:hpo> 0.616 [95% CI 0.549-0.683], and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0473527" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoalphalipoproteinemia</z:e> 0.606 [95% CI 0.535-0.677] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Total adiponectin, HMWA and the SA index had similar utility for the identification of IR and metabolic disturbances </plain></SENT>
</text></document>