<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>This study investigates the effect of enoxaparin (Lovenox, Klexane), a low-molecular-weight <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi>, on <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo> following a photothrombotic lesion using <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52261">rose bengal</z:chebi> dye in the rat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>An area of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> was provoked in the right hemisphere of rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>Edema</z:hpo> developed over 24 h after the lesion, as seen comparing water content of a core sample from the right hemisphere to that of a similar sample from the left hemisphere of each rat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Enoxaparin at 0 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>5 mg/kg i.v. plus 2 mg/kg s.c. reduced <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo> 24 h after lesion induction by 32% (p &lt; 0.01) when the treatment was started 2 h after photothrombotic insult, with maintenance doses of 2 mg/kg s.c. enoxaparin at 6 and 18 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>When the same initial treatment with enoxaparin was started 18 h after insult, there was still a significant reduction of 20% (p &lt; 0.01) in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002181'>cerebral edema</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Administration of enoxaparin 18 h after insult reduced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002181'>cerebral edema</z:hpo> in a dose-dependent manner </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was no evidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002170'>intracranial hemorrhages</z:hpo> in any of the animal groups and when the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> content of the brain samples was assayed by the method of Drabkin, no increase in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> content was seen compared to sham-operated animals </plain></SENT>
</text></document>