<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: We sought to evaluate whether transthoracic contrast echocardiography using second harmonic imaging (SHI) is a diagnostic alternative to transesophageal contrast echocardiography (TEE) for the detection of atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001694'>right to left shunt</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Paradoxic embolism is considered to be the major cause of cerebral ischemic events in young patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Contrast echocardiography using TEE has proven to be superior to transthoracic echocardiography (TTE) for the detection of atrial shunting, SHI is a new imaging modality that enhances the visualization of echocardiographic contrast agents </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We evaluated 111 patients with an ischemic cerebral embolic event for the presence of atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001694'>right to left shunt</z:hpo> using an intravenous (IV) contrast agent in combination with three different echocardiographic imaging modalities: 1) TTE using fundamental imaging (FI); 2) TTE using SHI; and 3) TEE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The severity of atrial shunting and the duration of contrast visibility within the left heart chambers were evaluated for each imaging modality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Image quality was assessed separately for each modality by semiquantitative scoring (0 = poor to 3 = excellent) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Presence of atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001694'>right to left shunt</z:hpo> was defined as detection of contrast bubbles in the left atrium within the first three cardiac cycles after contrast appearance in the right atrium either spontaneously or after the Valsalva maneuver </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 57 patients showed evidence of atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001694'>right to left shunt</z:hpo> with either imaging modality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Fifty-one studies were positive with TEE, 52 studies were positive with SHI, and 32 were positive with FI (p&lt;0.001 for FI vs. SHI and TEE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The severity of contrast passage was significantly larger using SHI (61.6+/-80.2 bubbles) compared to FI (53.7+/-69.6 bubbles; p&lt;0.005 vs. SHI) but was not different compared to TEE (43.9+/-54.3 bubbles; p = NS vs. SHI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The duration of contrast visibility was significantly longer for SHI (17.4+/-12.4 s) compared to FI (13.1+/-9.7 s; p&lt;0.001) and TEE (11.9+/-9.6 s; p&lt;0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Mean image quality improved significantly from FI (1.5+/-0.8) to SHI (2.0+/-0.8; p&lt;0.001 vs. FI) and TEE (2.5+/-0.7; p&lt;0.001 vs. SHI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In combination with IV contrast injections, TEE and SHI have a comparable yield for the detection of atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001694'>right to left shunt</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Both modalities may miss patients with atrial shunting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>In young patients with an unexplained cerebrovascular event and no clinical evidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018799" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiac disease</z:e>, a positive SHI study may obviate the need to perform a TEE study to search for cardiac sources of emboli </plain></SENT>
</text></document>