<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The goal of this study was to investigate transesophageal echocardiographic (TEE) findings after the termination of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> to clarify the direct evidence for occurrence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> cardiogenic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0262935" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain embolism</z:e> (CBE) in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004757'>paroxysmal atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (PAF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: Among 98 consecutive patients with CBE, we investigated TEE in 16 patients with PAF (Group CBE, 72 +/- 10 years) within 7 days of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> and 2 weeks after the first study, in comparison with 15 age-matched PAF patients without CBE (Group N) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The duration from reversal to <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> sinus rhythm to first TEE was 6 +/- 1 days in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were no significant differences in left atrial dimension and emptying flow velocity of the left atrial appendage (LAA-eV) between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Group CBE had significantly larger LAA area (4.3 +/- 1.3 cm2 vs. 3.1 +/- 1.0 cm2, p &lt; 0.05), smaller LAA fractional area change (LAA-FAC) (43 +/- 25% vs. 80 +/- 22%, p &lt; 0.001), and a higher incidence of left atrial spontaneous echo contrast (LAA-SEC) (25% vs. 7%, p &lt; 0.05) than group N, and those abnormalities in group CBE were significantly improved at the second TEE (LAA area: to 3.2 +/- 0.9 cm2, p &lt; 0.05; LAA-FAC: to 84 +/- 26%, p &lt; 0.001; LAA-SEC: to 0%, p &lt; 0.05), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: LAA-FAC is a more sensitive marker for LAA dysfunction than the widely used index, LAA-eV, and a sustained deterioration of LAA-FAC may be direct evidence for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> formation and occurrence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> CBE in patients with PAF </plain></SENT>
</text></document>