<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Intracarotid (i.c.) administration of thrombin induced a marked accumulation of 111indium-labelled platelets and 125I-labelled fibrinogen within the cranial vasculature of anaesthetized rabbits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Thrombin (100 iu kg-1, i.c.) - induced platelet accumulation was completely abolished by pretreatment with desulphatohirudin (CGP 39393; 1 mg kg-1 i.c., 1 min prior to thrombin) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Administration of CGP 39393 1 or 20 min after thrombin produced a significant reduction in platelet accumulation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>3 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Intravenous (i.v.) administration of the platelet activating factor (PAF) receptor <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi> BN 52021 (10 mg kg-1) 5 min prior to thrombin (100 iu kg-1, i.c.) had no effect on platelet accumulation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>4 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>An inhibitor of NO biosynthesis, L-NG-<z:chebi fb="13" ids="29785">nitro</z:chebi> arginine <z:chebi fb="36" ids="29309">methyl</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="21" ids="35701">ester</z:chebi> (L-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NAME</z:e>; 100 mg kg-1, i.c.), had no significant effect on the cranial platelet accumulation response to thrombin (10 iu kg-1, i.c.) when administered 5 min prior to thrombin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>5 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Defibrotide (32 or 64 mg kg-1 bolus i.c. followed by 32 or 64 mg kg-1 h-1, i.c., infusion for 45 min) treatment begun 20 min after thrombin (100 iu kg-1, i.c.) did not significantly modify the cranial platelet accumulation response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>6 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Cranial platelet accumulation induced by thrombin (100 iu kg-1, i.c.) was significantly reversed by the fibrinolytic drugs urokinase (20 iu kg-1, i.c., infusion for 45 min), anisoylated plasminogen streptokinase activator complex (APSAC) (200 micrograms kg-1, i.v </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>bolus) or recombinant tissue plasminogen activator (rt-PA; 100 micrograms kg-1, i.c. bolus followed by 20 micrograms kg-1 min-1, i.c., infusion for 45 min) administered 20 min after thrombin.8 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>These results suggest that neither endogenous PAF nor NO modulate thrombin-induced intracranial platelet accumulation in the rabbit </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>However, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_179'>fibrin deposition</z:mpath> appears to play an important role as shown by the ability of fibrinolytic agents to reverse platelet and fibrinogen accumulation induced by i.c. thrombin </plain></SENT>
</text></document>