<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>Endocarditis</z:hpo> is uncommon in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The characteristics of culture-positive (CPE) and culture-negative <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> (CNE) in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1512441" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">high-risk cancer</z:e> patients are not known; therefore we sought to evaluate the disease characteristics in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> at a comprehensive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> center </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We retrospectively reviewed the transthoracic (TTE) and transesophageal (TEE) echocardiograms obtained from 654 consecutive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> patients in whom <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> was suspected between 1994 and 2004 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>Endocarditis</z:hpo> was confirmed in 45 (7%) of 654 patients using modified Duke University criteria based on information obtained from hospital records and computerized data systems </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In 21 (95%) of 22 cases, TEE examinations were diagnostic, and 16 (42%) of 38 patients with initially nondiagnostic TTE studies had the diagnosis confirmed by TEE study; this difference between diagnostic TEE and initial nondiagnostic TTE was significant (p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Among the 26 (58%) patients with CPE, Staphylococcus aureus (35%) was the most common organism isolated, followed by coagulase-negative Staphylococcus species (23%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Eighteen (78%) of 23 patients with a central venous catheter had CPE, whereas only 8 (36%) of 22 patients without a central venous catheter had CPE (odds ratio [OR], 6.3; 95% confidence interval [CI], 1.69-23.53; p &lt; 0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Vegetations were larger in patients with CPE than in patients with CNE (median +/- standard deviation, 10 +/- 8.8 vs. 8.7 +/- 3.9 mm) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Fifteen patients (58%) with CPE and 10 (53%) with CNE had embolic complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We note that cutaneous and septic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0034065" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pulmonary emboli</z:e> were more common in patients with CPE than in patients with CNE (31% vs. 11% and 15% vs. 0%, respectively), whereas embolic cerebrovascular and fatal embolic coronary events were more common in patients with CNE than in those with CPE (37% vs. 12% and 21% vs. 0%, respectively; p = 0.026) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The 4-week <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo>-attributable <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> rate did not differ significantly between the groups (CPE, 15% vs. CNE, 32%; p = 0.28) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>On stepwise multivariate regression analysis, patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> (OR, 22.52; 95% CI, 2.25-225.48; p &lt; 0.008) and those with embolic cerebrovascular events (OR, 17.07; 95% CI, 1.63-178.45; p &lt; 0.01) had an increased probability of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> due to <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The clinical spectrums of CPE and CNE differed in these patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In patients with CNE, embolic cerebrovascular and fatal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> were relatively common </plain></SENT>
</text></document>