<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Cerebral microbleeds (MBs) are known to be indicative of <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp>-prone <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0155765" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">microangiopathy</z:e> and may predict incident intracerebral haemorrhage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, there is controversy concerning the causal relationship between the presence of MBs and haemorrhagic transformation (HTf) after ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Of the 1034 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> who were consecutively admitted to our hospital, 377 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> due to large-artery atherothrombosis or cardioembolism were selected for participation in this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We examined the MBs using T2*-weighted gradient-echo MRI performed within 24 hours after admission, and the incidence of HTf was assessed using follow-up brain MRI during the hospitalisation period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of the 377 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, 234 were male (62.1%) and the mean age was 66.2 +/-11.7 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>MBs were initially found in 109 patients (28.9%), and newly incident HTf was noted during the hospitalisation period in 74 patients (19.6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The presence of MBs was not increased in the patients with HTf (24.3% vs. 30.0% in the patients without HTf; p = 0.331) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In addition, the number of MBs was not higher in the patients with HTf (0.7+/-1.5 vs. 1.8+/-8.1; p = 0.234) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This lack of significance between MBs and HTf persisted after stratification by <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> mechanism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This study suggests that underlying MBs do not predict incident HTf after <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The clinical significance of MBs should be differentially evaluated according to the type of disease (intracerebral haemorrhage vs. HTf) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>