<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0002725'>Systemic lupus erythematosus</z:hpo> may present with a wide variety of neurological manifestations, which could be related to the presence of vasculopathy and microembolic signals (<z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: We aimed to determine the prevalence of <z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi> and altered blood flow velocities (BFVs) by transcranial Doppler (TCD) in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0752335" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropsychiatric lupus</z:e> erythematosus (NPLE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Fifteen consecutive patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> NPLE (cases) and 30 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002725'>systemic lupus erythematosus</z:hpo> but without <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> NPLE (controls) underwent TCD testing for comparison purposes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: We found higher mean BFVs in cases compared with controls in the left (100 vs. 73.5 cm/s, p = 0.018) and in the right (96 vs. 70 cm/s, p = 0.013) middle cerebral arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The proportion of <z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi> in both groups was the same (13%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Abnormal TCDs were more frequent in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> NPLE, 67 versus 17% (p = 0.001), and occurred more often in patients who presented <z:hpo ids='HP_0001250'>seizures</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The frequency of <z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi> was the same in both groups; however, patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001250'>seizures</z:hpo> due to <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> NPLE usually present with higher BFVs than controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>This could be a marker of diffuse <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> cerebral vasculopathy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>