<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Background. @nbsp; Cerebrovascular complications (CVCs) have remained a major therapeutic and prognostic challenge associated with infective <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo>, and definite risk factors have not been fully elucidated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This prospective study was designed to the evaluate the total incidence of CVC associated with infective <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> and major risk factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Methods. @nbsp; During 2 study periods, from June 1998 through April 2001 and from September 2002 through January 2005, patients were prospectively enrolled in the study regardless of neurological symptoms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Study patients underwent neurological examinations and magnetic resonance imaging of the brain, and cerebrospinal fluid analyses of inflammatory and neurochemical markers of brain damage (neurofilament protein and glial fibrillary acidic protein) were performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Results. @nbsp; Sixty patients who experienced episodes of left-sided infective <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> were evaluated; 35% of these patients experienced a symptomatic CVC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Silent cerebral complications were detected in another 30% of the patients, and the total CVC rate was 65% (95% confidence interval, 58%-72%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Five percent of patients experienced their first neurological symptom after the initiation of antibiotic treatment without prior surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No new symptomatic CVCs were detected after 10 days of antibiotic treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>No neurological deterioration was observed after surgery in patients who were established to have a symptomatic CVC preoperatively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A larger heart valvular vegetation size was a risk factor for both symptomatic and silent CVCs; Staphylococcus aureus etiology conferred a higher risk for symptomatic cerebral complication only </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Conclusions. @nbsp; The use of sensitive methods of detection indicates that the incidence of CVC associated with infective <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> is high, but the risk for neurological deterioration during cardiac surgery after a CVC is lower than previously assumed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The major mechanism behind cerebral complications associated with infective <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> is cerebral embolization, although the dominant neurological symptoms vary considerably </plain></SENT>
</text></document>