<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: This study investigated the fate of the stent inner surface in carotid artery stenting (CAS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In addition, the occurrence of late cerebral micro-embolism after CAS has been studied in order to identify predictors and correlate it with a possible neo-intimal layer </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A series of patients were evaluated before CAS through aortic arch trans-oesophageal echocardiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Six months after CAS, the stent coverage by neo-intima and the possible presence of uncovered plaques were determined by high-resolution duplex scanning (5-17-Hz probe and 3D reconstruction) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Possible micro-embolic signals (MESs) were evaluated through transcranial duplex scanning (30-min analysis of ipsilateral middle cerebral artery with a 1-4-Hz probe) and correlated with patients' characteristics, intimal media thickness (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e>) (&gt;0.9mm vs. &lt;0.9mm) and uncovered proximal plaques, type of stent (closed vs. open cells) and aortic arch complicated plaques (&gt;4mm) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Fisher's and Wilcoxon tests were used to evaluate differences across groups for categorical and continuous variables, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In the 68 CASs examined (40 closed cells and 28 open cells), the stent was completely covered by neo-intima in 52 cases (76.4%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Complete coverage was significantly correlated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e>&lt;0.9mm and the absence of a proximal plaque uncovered by the stent (100% vs. 0%, p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>Hypertension</z:hpo> was an independent predictor of complete intimal coverage (p=0.002), while the stent type did not influence this process </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The MESs were significantly more frequent in patients with complicated aortic arch plaques (62.5% vs. 23.8%, p&lt;0.012), independently from <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> other factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The extent of the stent neo-intimal formation is independent of stent type, but it is correlated with proximal plaque coverage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Six months after CAS, MESs are still possible and are not prevented by complete neo-intimal stent coverage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Complicated aortic arch <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> is an independent predictor of late <z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi>, thus underlying its importance in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0917798" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral ischaemia</z:e> <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>