<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Numerous pathogens can cause infective <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo>, including Haemophilus parainfluenzae </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>H. parainfluenzae is part of the H. aphrophilus, Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans, Cardiobacterium hominis, Eikenella corrodens, and Kingella kingae group that may cause about 3% of the total <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> cases, and is characterized by a <z:hpo ids='HP_0011011'>subacute</z:hpo> course and large vegetations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>CASE PRESENTATION: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> H. parainfluenzae <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> developed in a 54-year-old woman, with no underlying predisposing factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The patient presented with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo> of 3 days duration and a severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Magnetic resonance imaging of the brain revealed multiple <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007780" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral emboli</z:e> with hemorrhagic foci </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Upon suspicion of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo>, cardiac transesophageal ultrasonography was performed and revealed massive vegetations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The patient underwent emergency mitral valve replacement, and was further treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29007">ceftriaxone</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Blood cultures grew H. parainfluenzae only after valve replacement, and a 6-week course of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29007">ceftriaxone</z:chebi> was prescribed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: We underline the typical presentation of large vegetations in H. parainfluenzae <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo>, which are associated with embolic phenomena and resulting severity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Although the majority of the few cases reported in the literature are <z:hpo ids='HP_0011011'>subacute</z:hpo> in progress, our case further underlines the possibility that H. parainfluenzae <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> may develop rapidly </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Thus, awareness of the imaging characteristics of the pathogen may enhance early appropriate diagnosis and therapeutic response </plain></SENT>
</text></document>