<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Left atrial catheter ablation of the pulmonary veins (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PV</z:e>) has evolved as an important therapeutic option for the treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We aimed to investigate the incidence and predictors of silent <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007780" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral embolism</z:e> associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PV</z:e> catheter ablation, detected by diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging (DW-MRI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: We performed a prospective analysis of 53 consecutive patients with persistent or paroxysmal AF that underwent <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PV</z:e> ablation and post-procedural cerebral MRI 1 day after lasso catheter-guided ostial <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PV</z:e> ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients were analysed for possible demographical, medical, echocardiographical, and procedural predictors of embolic events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A mean of 3.5 +/- 0.5 PVs were ablated per patient </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In six patients, DW-MRI depicted new clinically silent microembolism after <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PV</z:e> ablation (11%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The number of ineffective medical antiarrhythmic agents prior to ablation procedure was significantly higher in the embolism group (3.3 +/- 0.5 vs. 2.2 +/- 1.4, P = 0.014) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010068" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Coronary heart disease</z:e> (CAD) was more frequent in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007780" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral embolisms</z:e> (33 vs. 2%, P = 0.031); left ventricular volume (130 +/- 12 vs. 103 +/- 26 mL, P = 0.002), and septal wall thickness (13.0 +/- 1.4 vs. 7.9 +/- 4.8 mm, P = 0.025) were significantly increased </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: This study shows a high incidence of silent micro-embolic events after <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PV</z:e> ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CAD, left <z:hpo ids='HP_0002119'>ventricular dilatation</z:hpo>, and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_159'>hypertrophy</z:mpath> were potential predictors of this complication </plain></SENT>
</text></document>