<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>Cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> in patients with carotid artery <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> is most often caused by <z:hpo ids='HP_0001907'>thromboembolism</z:hpo>, while hemodynamic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> mechanism is rare </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Differences in plaque <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> according to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> mechanism are an understudied issue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this pilot study was to compare carotid plaque <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> in patients with thromboembolic and hemodynamic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We included 6 patients with hemodynamic and 27 with embolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> who had carotid endarterectomy (CEA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We compared plaque <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> markers (macrophages, T cells, MMP-9, plaque rupture, surface <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e>, intraplaque <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp>, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> core) between patients with hemodynamic and embolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> and assessed vascular events and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> during the first year post CEA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Compared to patients with hemodynamic mechanism, those with embolic mechanism showed a higher median (interquartile range) content of T cells/mm(2) [49.66 (21.26-71.39) vs. 10.28 (7.05-13.87); P=0.0005] and higher median total percentages of macrophage area [2.81% (1.69-4.09) vs. 0.99% (0.57-1.50); P=0.003] and MMP-9 area [0.63% (0.42-1.01) vs. 0.25% (0.05-0.45); P=0.007] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Signs of plaque instability such as plaque rupture, surface <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> and intraplaque <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp> showed a tendency to be more pronounced in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001907'>thromboembolism</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The incidences of vascular events and the survival rates in the first year after CEA were similar in the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Major differences in plaques related to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> mechanism were found in patients with symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0100546'>carotid stenosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, further investigations are necessary to validate our results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Identification of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> mechanism may improve risk stratification and could help to identify the most suitable secondary <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> prevention strategy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>