<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Summary: This study evaluated: 1) the effect of recanalization on changing clinical outcome, 2) the relationship between dose of Urokinase (UK) and incidence of recanalization and intracranial haemorrhage, and 3) the efficacy and feasibility of balloon disruption (BD) in the treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007780" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral embolism</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Sixty-one patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> embolism of the major cerebral arteries treated by endovascular approaches over the past nine years were retrospectively evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Among them, 30 cases were treated by BD alone or in conjunction with intra- arterial fibrinolysis in the last five years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The other 31 cases, mostly treated in the first four years, were treated with intra-arterial fibrinolysis alone and were used as controls to evaluate the efficacy of BD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Control angiography was performed just after the reperfusion procedure to evaluate the degree of recanalization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Angiographic responses were graded using modified Thrombolysis in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>Myocardial Infarction</z:hpo> (TIMI) criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Clinical outcome was evaluated using modified Rankin Scale (mRS) score at the time of discharge </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Thirty-six of the 61 patients (59.0%) achieved high-grade recanalization (TIMI grade 3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Significantly more patients attained favorable outcome (mRS score 0-1) in the high-grade recanalization group than the low-grade recanalization group (41.7% vs. 16.0%, p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Concerning patients treated with BD, significantly more patients attained good recanalization and significantly more patients were ambulatory (mRS score 0-3) than those treated with intra-arterial fibrinolysis alone (76.7% vs. 41.9%, p &lt; 0.01; 70.0% vs. 41.9%, p &lt; 0.05, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>A significantly lower dose of UK was used, and relatively less intracranial haemorrhage was seen in patients treated with BD than those treated with intra- arterial fibrinolysis (194,000 +/- 191,000 units vs. 388,000 +/- 231,000 units, p=0.001; 16.7% vs. 38.7%, p=0.055, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Concerning morbidity and mortality of BD, there was one <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> caused by dissection of the M2 portion of the middle cerebral artery (<z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>) that happened during BD on a distally migrated <z:mpath ids='MPATH_110'>embolus</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Although no conclusions can be drawn from our study, a favorable outcome for <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> embolism of the major cerebral arteries is expected by attaining good recanalization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In addition, BD is an effective technique that can achieve high-grade recanalization alone, or reducing the dose of fibrinolytic agent </plain></SENT>
</text></document>