<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Twenty one patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085642" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">livedo racemosa</z:e> (LRa) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0031036" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">periarteritis nodosa</z:e> cutanea were screened for the presence of anti-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="28494">cardiolipin</z:chebi> antibody (aCL) by ELISA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>11 out of 21 revealed positive aCL whose clinical features could be divided into 3 groups: 4 patients with livedo with ulceration, 2 with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000999'>pyoderma</z:hpo> gangrenosum-like lesions, and 5 with extensive LRa. #1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The summer ulceration of leg of 4 patients were surrounded by several tiny <z:hpo ids='HP_0000967'>petechiae</z:hpo> where hyaline microthrombi of blood capillaries in the upper dermis were demonstrated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> had multiple cerebral microinfarctions on magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). #2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000999'>Pyoderma</z:hpo> gangrenosum-like lesions of 2 patients consisted of painful punched-out <z:mpath ids='MPATH_579'>ulcers</z:mpath> on livedoid lesions where intravascular endothelial <z:mpath ids='MPATH_134'>hyperplasia</z:mpath> in a small artery was demonstrated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Both had multiple cerebral microinfarctions. #3 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Another clinical manifestation of the patients with positive aCL was extensive form of LRa of 5 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> had positive ANA, however none of them exhibited cerebral microinfarctions on MRI. #4 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The remaining 10 patients with negative aCL showed no relationship with such clinical and laboratory manifestations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These results indicate that there is a significant correlations between summer ulceration with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000967'>petechiae</z:hpo>, capillary microthrombi of the skin, positive aCL and cerebral microinfarctions on MRI </plain></SENT>
</text></document>