<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Carotid angioplasty and stenting (CAS) has proven to be a potential alternative to carotid endarterectomy in the treatment of severe <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0741975" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Patient selection has emerged as a means of optimizing the outcomes of CAS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine whether the presence of preprocedural neurologic symptoms and having a history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001677'>coronary artery disease</z:hpo> (CAD) are associated with greater embolic risk during CAS through analysis of the embolic debris captured within protective filters </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 233 consecutive CAS procedures were performed between 2003 and 2009 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Particles of embolic debris within the filters were quantified by photomicroscopy and video imaging software </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Particulate size was determined by measuring the length along the longest axis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Preprocedural neurologic symptoms included <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>transient ischemic attack</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>cerebrovascular accident</z:hpo>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100576'>amaurosis fugax</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>History of CAD included prior <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo>, coronary artery bypass grafting, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>congestive heart failure</z:hpo>, or abnormal stress test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of the 137 (58.8%) filters that were analyzed (mean age, 71.3 ± 9.1 years, 56.9% male), 52 (38.0%) and 80 (58.4%) filters were from symptomatic and CAD patients, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Filters of symptomatic (S) patients contained both a greater number and larger mean particle size compared with those of asymptomatic (AS) patients (S: 15.8 ± 13.5 particles vs. AS: 9.8 ± 8.7 particles, P = 0.002; S: 507 ± 389 μm vs. AS: 398 ± 181 μm, P = 0.03; respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Filters from CAD patients also had a greater number of particles, but trended toward smaller minimum size than those in non-CAD patients (CAD: 14.4 ± 12.8 particles vs. non-CAD: 8.8 ± 7.4 particles, P = 0.002; CAD: 167 ± 172 μm vs. 228 ± 203 μm, P = 0.06) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These findings suggest that the presence of preprocedural neurologic symptoms and a history of CAD are associated with increased embolization during CAS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Therefore, the benefit of carotid stenting should be tempered by the potential for increased perioperative events in both symptomatic and CAD patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>