<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Indication to carotid revascularisation is commonly determined by percent of stenosis as well as neurological symptoms and clinical conditions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>High plaque embolic potential is defined as 'vulnerability'; however, its characterisation is not universally used for carotid revascularisation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We investigated the role of contrast-enhanced ultrasonography (CEUS) to identify carotid vulnerable plaque </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Patients undergoing carotid endarterectomy were preoperatively evaluated by cerebral computed tomography (CT) scan and CEUS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Contrast microbubbles detected within the plaque indicated neovascularisation and were quantified by decibel enhancement (dB-E) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Plaques were histologically evaluated for five features: (microvessel density, fibrous cap thickness, extension of calcification, inflammatory infiltrate and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> core) and blindly scored 1-5 to assess plaque vulnerability </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Analysis of variance (ANOVA), Fisher's and Student's t-test were used to correlate patients' characteristics, histological features and dB-E </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In 22 patients, dB-E (range 2-7.8, mean 4.85 ± 1.9 SD) was significantly greater in symptomatic (7.40 ± 0.5) vs. asymptomatic (3.5 ± 1.4) patients (p = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A higher dB-E was significantly associated with thinner fibrous cap (&lt;200 μm, 5.96 ± 1.5 vs. 3 ± 1, p = 0.01) and greater inflammatory infiltrate (3.2 ± 0.9 vs. 6.4 ± 1.2, p = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Plaques with vulnerability score of 5 had significantly higher dB-E compared with those with vulnerability score of 1 (7.6 ± 0.2 vs. 2.5 ± 0.6, respectively, p = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Preoperative ipsilateral embolic lesions at CT were correlated with higher dB-E (5.96 ± 1.5 vs. 3.0 ± 1.0, p = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: CEUS with dB-E is indicative of the extent of plaque neovascularisation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>It can be used therefore as a marker for vulnerable plaque </plain></SENT>
</text></document>