<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: and purpose N-terminal probrain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi>, which is mainly produced by the heart, is increased in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We aimed to determine if N-terminal probrain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> could be a biomarker for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> with a cardioembolic cause </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Consecutive sample of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> patients admitted to a <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo> Unit </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>Ischemic stroke</z:hpo> subtype was classified using the TOAST classification </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Blood samples were drawn within 72 h after <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Serum N-terminal probrain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> concentration was measured using an electrochemiluminescence immunoassay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Mean values of N-terminal probrain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> were compared between patients with hemorrhagic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> vs. <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo>, cardioembolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> vs. noncardioembolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, cardioembolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> with <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> vs. noncardioembolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> using t-test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Receiver operating characteristic curves were used to test the ability of N-terminal probrain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> values to identify cardioembolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> and cardioembolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> with <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Ninety-two patients were included (66 with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo>) with a mean age of 58·6 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Twenty-eight (42·4%) <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic strokes</z:hpo> had a cardioembolic cause </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Mean N-terminal probrain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> values for cardioembolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> were significantly higher (P&lt;0·001) (491·6; 95% confidence interval 283·7-852·0 pg/ml) than for noncardioembolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> (124·7; 86·3-180·2 pg/ml) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The area under the receiver operating characteristic curve for N-terminal probrain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> in cardioembolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> was 0·77 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The cut-off point with the highest sensitivity and specificity was set at 265·5 pg/ml (71·4% and 73·7% respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The area under the curve of N-terminal probrain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> for cardioembolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> related to <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> was 0·92, cut-off was set at 265·5 pg/ml (sensitivity 94·4%, specificity 72·9%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: N-terminal probrain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> is a biomarker with a good accuracy to predict <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> of cardioembolic cause, namely associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>