<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: 'Silent' <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> are complications of transcatheter aortic valve implantation (TAVI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To assess the occurrence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e>, identify predictive risk factors and examine the impact on patient health-related quality of life (HRQoL) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Cerebral diffusion weighted MRI of 31 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001650'>aortic stenosis</z:hpo> undergoing CoreValve TAVI was carried out </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>HRQoL was assessed at baseline and at 30 days by SF-12v2 and EQ5D questionnaires </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: New cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> occurred in 24/31 patients (77%) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> in 2 (6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo> was associated with a greater number and volume of cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Age (r=0.37, p=0.042), severity of atheroma (arch and descending aorta; r=0.91, p&lt;0.001, r=0.69, p=0.001, respectively) and catheterisation time (r=0.45, p=0.02) were predictors of the number of new cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>HRQoL improved overall: SF-12v2 physical component summary increased significantly (32.4±6.2 vs 36.5±7.2; p=0.03) with no significant change in mental component summary (43.5±11.7 vs. 43.1±14.3; p=0.85) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The EQ5D score and Visual Analogue Scale showed no significant change (0.56±0.26 vs. 0.59±0.31; p=0.70, and 54.2±19 vs. 58.2±24; p=0.43) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Multiple small cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> occurred in 77% of patients with TAVI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The majority of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> were 'silent' with clinical <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> being associated with a both higher <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> number and volume </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Increased age and the severity of aortic arch atheroma were independent risk factors for the development of new cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Overall HRQoL improved and there was no association between the number of new cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> and altered health status </plain></SENT>
</text></document>