<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: The goal of this study was to compare the rate of cerebral microembolization during carotid artery stenting (CAS) with proximal versus distal cerebral protection in patients with high-risk, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi>-rich plaque </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Cerebral protection with filters partially reduces the cerebral embolization rate during CAS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Proximal protection has been introduced to further decrease embolization risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Fifty-three consecutive patients with carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006135'>artery stenosis</z:mp> and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi>-rich plaque were randomized to undergo CAS with proximal protection (MO.MA system, n = 26) or distal protection with a filter (FilterWire EZ, n = 27) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Microembolic signals (<z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi>) were assessed by using transcranial Doppler during: 1) lesion wiring; 2) pre-dilation; 3) stent crossing; 4) stent deployment; 5) stent dilation; and 6) device retrieval/deflation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging was conducted before CAS, after 48 h, and after 30 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients in the MO.MA group had higher percentage diameter stenosis (89 ± 6% vs. 86 ± 5%, p = 0.027) and rate of ulcerated plaque (35% vs. 7.4%; p = 0.019) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Compared with use of the FilterWire EZ, MO.MA significantly reduced mean <z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi> counts (p &lt; 0.0001) during lesion crossing (mean 18 [interquartile range (IQR): 11 to 30] vs. 2 [IQR: 0 to 4]), stent crossing (23 [IQR: 11 to 34] vs. 0 [IQR: 0 to 1]), stent deployment (30 [IQR: 9 to 35] vs. 0 [IQR: 0 to 1]), stent dilation (16 [IQR: 8 to 30] vs. 0 [IQR: 0 to 1]), and total <z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi> (93 [IQR: 59 to 136] vs. 16 [IQR: 7 to 36]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The number of patients with <z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi> was higher with the FilterWire EZ versus MO.MA in phases 3 to 5 (100% vs. 27%; p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>By multivariate analysis, the type of brain protection was the only independent predictor of total <z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi> number </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>No significant difference was found in the number of patients with new post-CAS embolic lesion in the MO.MA group (2 of 14, 14%) as compared with the FilterWire EZ group (9 of 21, 42.8%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In patients with high-risk, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi>-rich plaque undergoing CAS, MO.MA led to significantly lower microembolization as assessed by using <z:chebi fb="28" ids="39005,39010">MES</z:chebi> counts </plain></SENT>
</text></document>