<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Significant atherosclerotic stenosis of internal carotid artery (ICA) origin is common (5-10% at ≥ 60 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Intravascular ultrasound (IVUS) enables high-resolution (120 µm) plaque imaging, and IVUS-elucidated features of the coronary plaque were recently shown to be associated with its symptomatic rupture/<z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Safety of the significant carotid plaque IVUS imaging in a large unselected population is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL/METHODS: We prospectively evaluated the safety of embolic protection device (EPD)-assisted vs. unprotected ICA-IVUS in a series of consecutive subjects with ≥ 50% ICA stenosis referred for carotid artery stenting (CAS), including 104 asymptomatic (aS) and 187 symptomatic (S) subjects (age 47-83 y, 187 men) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>EPD use was optional for IVUS, but mandatory for CAS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Evaluation was performed of 107 ICAs (36.8%) without EPD and 184 with EPD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Lesions imaged under EPD were overall more severe (peak-systolic velocity 2.97 ± 0.08 vs. 2.20 ± 0.08 m/s, end-diastolic velocity 1.0 ± 0.04 vs. 0.7 ± 0.03 m/s, stenosis severity of 85.7 ± 0.5% vs. 77.7 ± 0.6% by catheter angiography; mean ± <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SEM</z:e>; p&lt;0.01 for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> comparisons) and more frequently S (50.0% vs. 34.6%, p=0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No ICA <z:mpath ids='MPATH_81'>perforation</z:mpath> or dissection, and no major <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> occurred </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was no IVUS-triggered cerebral embolization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In the procedures of (i) unprotected IVUS and no CAS, (ii) unprotected IVUS followed by CAS (filters - 39, flow reversal/blockade - 3), (iii) EPD-protected (filters - 135, flow reversal/blockade - 48) IVUS + CAS, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>TIA</z:hpo> occurred in 1.5% vs. 4.8% vs. 2.7%, respectively, and minor <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> in 0% vs. 2.4% vs. 2.1%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>EPD intolerance (on-filter ICA spasm or flow reversal/blockade intolerance) occurred in 9/225 (4.0%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>IVUS increased the procedure duration by 7.27 ± 0.19 min </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Carotid IVUS is safe and, for the less severe lesions in particular, it may not require mandatory EPD use </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>High-risk lesions can be safely evaluated with IVUS under flow reversal/blockade </plain></SENT>
</text></document>