<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Thirteen adult patients with established <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0221057" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">thalamic syndrome</z:e>, resistant to prior <z:chebi fb="29" ids="35480">analgesic</z:chebi> and other therapy, were treated with intravenous infusions of the opiate <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="1" ids="7459">naloxone</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A total of twenty treatments were administered with doses of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="7459">naloxone</z:chebi> varying from 4.0-8.0 mgs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Seven patients exhibited beneficial effects with the duration of the resultant pain relief ranging from four days to two and a half years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In these patients, pain and hyperpathia were completely obtunded in six out of seven and partially in one </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Side effects of therapy were minimal and of short duration being mainly confined to the cardiovascular system </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>During therapy <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients had continuous E.C.G. monitoring </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In certain ischaemic conditions of the central <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system, endogenous opioids possibly reduce cerebral blood flow via. inhibition of the locus coeruleus and subsequent release of <z:chebi fb="15" ids="33569">noradrenaline</z:chebi>: hence <z:chebi fb="1" ids="7459">naloxone</z:chebi> by inhibiting the opioids could increase cerebral perfusion pressure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>This study has shown the benefit of treating patients with cerebral ischaemic lesions with an opioid <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The rapidity of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of pain relief in these patients would appear to indicate a mode of action by increasing cerebral perfusion </plain></SENT>
</text></document>