<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The value of the EEG has not been diminished by the advent of new diagnostic procedures and the improvement of older techniques </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>For electro-encephalography is in essence a 'clinical' method, reflecting in its own particular way, the variable status of the brain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Moreover, in conjunction with these methods the EEG can provide for better information concerning the brain's condition </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Furthermore in particular serio-angiography and C.B.F. measurements can furnish us more detailed insight in the EEG phenomena which may occur in differed types of cerebro-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Generally the changes of the local EEG phenomena, which may occur in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0917798" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral ischaemia</z:e> correlate well with the angiographic and r.C.B.F. data </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In cerebral haemorrhage and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1263885" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cerebral tumour</z:e> however the r.C.B.F. values are commonly more diffusely reduced as could be expected from the extent of the EEG disturbances </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Increased r.C.B.F. values may be encountered over <z:hpo ids='HP_0002858'>meningioma</z:hpo> due to increased perfusion of the Xenon133 in this electrically inactive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e>; they can also occur in malign <z:hpo ids='HP_0100843'>glioblastoma</z:hpo>, where direct arterio-venous connections are responsable for the so called shunt peaks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These peaks may also be found in patients with arterio-venous malformations or with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischaemia</z:e>, in the latter case due to marked reduction of the local pH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Remarkable was the discrepancy between the local increase of the C.B.F. and the local deterioration in the EEG following intracarotid injection of HC1 papaverine; the same applied to the reaction of EEG and C.B.F. in case of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> with loss of autoregulation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>