<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Computerized Axial Tomography (C.A.T.) easily distinguishes between the two types of cerebral accident responsible for the two major categories of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002301'>hemiplegia</z:hpo> in childhood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>1) In <z:hpo ids='HP_0002301'>hemiplegias</z:hpo> which develop in association with hemiclonic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002133'>status epilepticus</z:hpo> (H </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>H. and H </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>H </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>E. syndromes), in the majority of cases there is an appearance of cortico-sub-<z:hpo ids='HP_0002120'>cortical atrophy</z:hpo> involving the whole hemisphere contralateral to the <z:hpo ids='HP_0002301'>hemiplegia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> develops following <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>oedema</z:hpo> of the hemisphere which accompanies the initial <z:hpo ids='HP_0002133'>status epilepticus</z:hpo> and which is clearly shown by a very early T.A.C </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>2) In congenital or acquired <z:hpo ids='HP_0002301'>hemiplegias</z:hpo> not associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002133'>status epilepticus</z:hpo> there is, in most cases, an appearance of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> or, very rarely, haemorrhage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>It is thus possible, from a physiopathogenic standpoint, to draw a clear distinction between these two major forms of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> infantile <z:hpo ids='HP_0002301'>hemiplegia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The first (H </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>H. and H </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>H </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>E. syndromes) usually result from hemispheric <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> which develops in association with a unilateral or predominantly lateral episode of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002133'>status epilepticus</z:hpo>, whilst the second group are usually the result of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>