<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Pathogenetic role of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) on myocardial and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarctions</z:e> was studied in 2340 consecutive autopsies of the aged </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>AF was found in 405 cases or 17.3%, and the incidence of AF increased with age </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>Myocardial infarction</z:hpo> and scar were found in 56.8% in AF, but in 36.4% in non-AF (p less than 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Small <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> was 2.9 times (12.6% vs. 4.3%), and the scar was 1.5 times (27.2% vs. 18.7%) as prevalent in AF as in non-AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Intracardiac <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0333205,C1260883" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">mural thrombus</z:e> was found in 14.8% in AF and in 4.8% in non-AF, 8 to 10 times as prevalent in small <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (29.4% vs. 3.7%) and scar (17.4% vs. 1.7%) in AF as in non-AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Coronary stenotic index revealed no difference between AF and non-AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Large <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> was observed in 21.9% in AF and 7.3% in non-AF, and this difference was prominent in cases with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> or myocardial scar indicating the common pathogenetic role of AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In cases with large <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> severe cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> was less frequent in AF than in non-AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Medium sized cortical infarction was also prevalent in AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The prevalences of myocardial and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarctions</z:e> were not different in AF complicated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001654'>valvular heart disease</z:hpo> from those without it, but increased in the permanent AF in comparison to the transient AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>AF induced small <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> and large or medium sized <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarctions</z:e> by embolism from <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0333205,C1260883" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">mural thrombus</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The mechanism for the difference in size is discussed </plain></SENT>
</text></document>