<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: This study attempted to determine whether a subset of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001634'>mitral valve prolapse</z:hpo> and no <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> at rest will develop <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> during exercise and have a higher than anticipated risk of morbid cardiovascular events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>Mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001634'>mitral valve prolapse</z:hpo> identifies a subset of patients at higher risk for morbid events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001634'>mitral valve prolapse</z:hpo> may be intermittent and could go unrecognized </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A provocative test to unmask <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> in these patients would be useful </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Ninety-four adult patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001634'>mitral valve prolapse</z:hpo> and no <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> at rest were studied during supine bicycle ergometry using color flow Doppler echocardiography in the apical four-chamber and long-axis views </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Patients were prospectively followed up for morbid events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Thirty (32%) of 94 patients had exercise-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Prospective follow-up (mean 38 months) showed more morbid events in the group with than without <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> and included, respectively, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> (43% vs. 5%, p &lt; 0.0001), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>congestive heart failure</z:hpo> (17% vs. 0%, p &lt; 0.005) and progressive <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> requiring mitral valve replacement surgery (10% vs. 0%, p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Cerebral embolic events, <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0001699'>sudden death</z:hpo> were rare and not different between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001634'>mitral valve prolapse</z:hpo> without <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> at rest, exercise provokes <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> in 32% of patients and predicts a higher risk for morbid events </plain></SENT>
</text></document>