<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Ninety-five patients aged 60 years or over with a permanent pacemaker implanted for <z:hpo ids='HP_0011704'>sick sinus syndrome</z:hpo> were divided into two groups: 32 patients with physiological pacing (group P) and 63 patients with ventricular pacing (group V) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The mean follow-up period was 45.0 +/- 36.6 months in group P and 50.3 +/- 37.8 months in group V </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0004757'>Paroxysmal atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (Af) occurred in 28% of group P and 71% of group V (p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The incidence of stable Af was also lower in group P than in group V (9% vs. 30%, p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>None of group P with only <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0079035" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bradyarrhythmia</z:e> had stable Af </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, 6 of 21 patients (29%) in group V with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0079035" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bradyarrhythmia</z:e> showed stable Af </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference in stable Af between group P with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001662'>bradycardia</z:hpo>-<z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> syndrome (<z:chebi fb="6" ids="32816">BTS</z:chebi>) and group V with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="32816">BTS</z:chebi> (19% vs. 31%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A lower incidence of embolic events was also observed in group P (3% vs. 25%, p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Nine of 16 patients with embolic events in group V died of complications following embolism (8 patients; <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007780" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral embolism</z:e>, one patients: renal and superior mesenteric arterial embolism) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The survival rates at 5 and 10 years were 80% and 69%, respectively, for group P and 56% and 33% for group V (p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Thus, with regard to permanent pacing for patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011704'>sick sinus syndrome</z:hpo>, physiological pacing should be selected for control of morbidity and total mortality </plain></SENT>
</text></document>