<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Administration of bovine thrombin (100 u kg-1) into the carotid artery of rabbits induces a sustained accumulation of 111 Indium-labelled platelets within the cranial vasculature over the subsequent 3 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Intracarotid (i.c.) administration of defibrotide (64 mg kg-1 bolus plus 64 mg kg-1 h-1 for 1 h) prior to i.c. thrombin (100 u kg-1) significantly reduces the ability of thrombin to induce cranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001907'>thromboembolism</z:hpo> in rabbits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>3 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Intravenous (i.v.) administration of thrombin (20 u kg-1) in rabbits induces a reversible accumulation of radiolabelled platelets into the thoracic circulation which is significantly reduced by i.v. administration of defibrotide (64 mg kg-1 bolus plus 64 mg kg-1 h-1 for 1 h) prior to i.v. thrombin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In contrast, platelet accumulation in response to <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="2" ids="18361">diphosphate</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="13" ids="16761">ADP</z:chebi>; 20 micrograms kg-1, i.v.) or platelet activating factor (PAF; 50 ng kg-1, i.v.) is not significantly affected by this treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>4 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Intravenous administration of the nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> (NO)-synthase inhibitor NG-<z:chebi fb="13" ids="29785">nitro</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16467,29952">L-arginine</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="36" ids="29309">methyl</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="21" ids="35701">ester</z:chebi> (L-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NAME</z:e>; 10 mg kg-1) potentiates platelet accumulation induced by low dose thrombin (10 u kg-1, i.v.) within the pulmonary vasculature of rabbits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The potentiated response is significantly abrogated following pretreatment with defibrotide (64 mg kg-1 bolus plus 64 mg kg-1 h-1 for 1 h, i.v.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>5 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Intravenous injection of human thrombin (1250 u kg-1) to mice induces <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> within the majority of animals which is significantly reduced by pretreatment with defibrotide (150-175 mg kg-1, i.v.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In contrast, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> induced by i.v. collagen (1.25 mg kg-1) plus <z:chebi fb="47" ids="28918,33568">adrenaline</z:chebi> (75 microg kg-1) is not significantly affected by defibrotide pretreatment.6 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The inhibitory effect of defibrotide in mice is abolished following concomitant treatment with the inhibitor of fribrinolysis, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="48669">tranexamic acid</z:chebi> (100 mg kg-1, i.v.), but is unaffected following treatment with the cyclo-oxygenase inhibitor, aspirin (300 mg kg-1, i.p.).7 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>The protective effect of defibrotide against thrombin-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001907'>thromboembolism</z:hpo> in the mouse is potentiated by recombinant tissue-plasminogen activator (rt-PA; 1 mg kg-1, i.v.) or unfractionated <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> (10 u kg-1, i.v.) administration.8 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>The results suggest that defibrotide may possess antithrombotic activity on thrombin-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001907'>thromboembolism</z:hpo> which, at least in the mouse, may be partially mediated via induction of the fibrinolytic pathway </plain></SENT>
</text></document>