<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE: Our aim was to analyze the role that C </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Miller Fisher (C.M.F.) had in promoting an understanding of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007273" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid artery disease</z:e> (CAD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Although Chiari in 1905 and later Hunt, Moniz, and Hultquist, among others, described the association of CAD and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, this received little attention until C.M.F. published his clinicoanatomic correlations in "Occlusion of the Carotid Arteries." Until then, some 55% of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>strokes</z:hpo> were attributed to "vasospasm." METHODS: We analyzed articles ("Occlusion of the Internal Carotid Artery," 1951; "Occlusion of the Carotid Arteries," 1954; "Transient Monocular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000618'>Blindness</z:hpo> Associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002301'>Hemiplegia</z:hpo>," 1952; "The Microembolic Theory of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>Transient Ischemic Attacks</z:hpo>," 1976; "A Clinico-pathologic Study of Carotid Endarterectomy Plaques," 1986) and conducted personal interviews with C.M.F </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: During the 1950s, C.M.F. described the clinical implications of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>transient ischemic attacks</z:hpo> and their relationship to CAD and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The last sentence in the 1951 article read: "Unexplained <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007780" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral embolism</z:e> may arise from thrombotic material lying in the carotid sinus." In the same article he also wrote that "it is even conceivable that some day vascular surgery will find a way to by-pass the occluded portion of the artery during the period of ominous fleeting symptoms," heralding the future surgical treatment of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007273" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid artery disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>C.M.F. called attention to the commonness of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0741975" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid disease</z:e>, described transient monocular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000618'>blindness</z:hpo>, and studied the relationship between plaque pathology and clinical findings </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: C.M.F.'s clinicopathologic observations were a major factor in promoting recognition of the clinical features, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> risk, and treatment of CAD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>