<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Embolization of gaseous and particulate matter is incriminated in the neuropsychological morbidity of CPB and can be reduced by membrane oxygenators and arterial line filtration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It is not known if the use of arterial line filtration in conjunction with membrane oxygenators might have an additive effect in reducing cerebral injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Forty patients undergoing elective coronary artery surgery were prospectively randomized to a 43 microns <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> coated arterial line filter (Cobe Sentry) or to no filtration (control group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> operations were performed by one surgeon (<z:chebi fb="6" ids="39161">DPT</z:chebi>) using intermittent <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischaemia</z:e> with nonpulsatile CPB, a COBE <z:mp ids='MP_0005481'>CML</z:mp> membrane oxygenator and alpha-stat paCO2 management </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Flow rates were maintained between 2.0 and 2.4 l-1 m2 per min with a perfusion pressure of 50-80 mmHg and a systemic temperature of 34 degrees C </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Cerebral injury was defined by careful neurological examination and serial measurement of the serum concentration of S-100 protein (a highly specific astroglial cell derivative, elevated serum levels of which correlate with proven cerebral injury) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There was no difference [mean (S.D.)] in the control and filter groups with respect to age [61(9) vs. 62(9) years], ejection fraction, number of grafts [2.8(0.6) vs. 2.6(0.7)] or CPB times [55(19) vs. 57(18) min] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Preoperatively, no patient had detectable S-100 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the postoperative period 23 of 40 patients (58%) showed elevated S-100 levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>At 1, 5 and 24 h the respective number of patients in the control and filter groups with elevated S-100 was (14 vs. 9), (4 vs. 0), (4 vs. 0)) (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>No patient had overt cerebral injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This study suggests that (i) subclinical cerebral injury is common (58% of patients in this study) even after apparently uncomplicated surgery with short CPB times; (ii) serum S-100 protein is a valuable marker for investigating potentially cerebral protective innovations during CPB; and (iii) arterial line filtration significantly reduces but does not eliminate cerebral injury </plain></SENT>
</text></document>