<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To explore the hypothesis that intermittent ischaemic arrest (IIA) provides better myocardial preservation but generates a larger number of cerebral microemboli (ME) and consequently a higher incidence of post-operative <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0262405" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral dysfunction</z:e> compared with the single clamp technique (SCT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Ninety-one patients with stable <z:mp ids='MP_0006112'>angina</z:mp> undergoing elective CABG with no clinical evidence of aortic or cerebro-vascular or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027765" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neurological disease</z:e> were prospectively randomized to: IIA (n = 43) or SCT with intermittent anterograde cold blood cardioplegia (n = 48) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Myocardial preservation was assessed by measuring serum CK-MB, Troponin-T (TnT) and Troponin-I (TnI) and from pre- and post-operative ECGs and left ventricular (LV) function by echocardiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Intra-operative cerebral ME were counted by transcranial Doppler of the right middle cerebral artery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients completed the Luria Nebraska Neuropsychological Battery (LNNB) tests for motor, visual, reading, memory and intellectual processes the day before surgery and at 1 week and 6 months post-operatively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Serum levels of the neuro-specific protein S-100 were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The two groups were comparable for age, sex, extent of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001677'>coronary disease</z:hpo>, previous <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo>, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> and number of arterial and venous grafts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The median number of ME detected per patient was 34 (range 4-208) and was similar in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Protein S-100 levels remained <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> and similar in both groups at <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> times except in one patient with SCT who had an operative <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>LNNB scores were similarly depressed at 1 week and recovered in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cases at 6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>There was no correlation between the number of ME and LNNB scores </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Median peak TnI levels were 0.64 microg/l with IIA vs. 0.87 microg/l with SCT (P = NS) and TnT 0.8 microg/l vs. 1.08 microg/l (P &lt; 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>SCT was however associated with longer mean ischaemic (67.6 +/- 16.1 vs. 34.5 +/- 16.5 min, P &lt; 0.001) and mean bypass time (88.5 +/- 18.2 vs. 74.6 +/- 26.3 min, P &lt; 0.004) than IIA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Four patients with SCT and none with IIA had ECG changes suggestive of MI (P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: During elective CABG in patients with no clinical evidence of aortic or cerebro-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> the incidence of peri-operative ME and post-operative neuropsychological disturbances are comparable with both techniques of myocardial preservation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Biochemical analysis suggests that IIA provides more effective myocardial preservation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>