<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: We started with Sarajevo Vascular Study (SVS) in 1994 with basic aim to evaluate <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0003838" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">arterial occlusive disease</z:e> (AOD) of lower extremities and investigate possible effect of amelioration of risk factors to <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> regression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In 1996 we expanded SVS to polyvascular atherosclerotic disease, asymptomatic or symptomatic atherosclerotic disease on various vascular beds i.e. lower extremity <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0003838" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">arterial occlusive disease</z:e> (AOD), cerebrovascular disease (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e>), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001677'>coronary artery disease</z:hpo> (CAD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We enrolled a total of 1680 pts. in the study but this number has changed depending on war migrations, comorbidity, or paramedical reasons </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Follow-up of 10 yrs. had 645 pts, and follow-up of 8 yrs. had 1035 pts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHOD: We enrolled a total of 1680 pts, 954 pts with symptomatic disease, and 246 pts without atherosclerotic disease but with at least 3/8 multiple risk factors (MRF), and as controls 400 pts without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> and less than 3 MRF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>STUDY DESIGN: one center, prospective, consecutive, with evaluation of epidemiological data--gender, age, comorbidity, antropometrical data, hemodynamic data--systolic and dystolic velocities, pulsatility and resistive indices, and morphologic data </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Clinical variables--gender, age, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>, smoking, <z:hpo ids='HP_0010980'>hyperlipoproteinemia</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> and fibrinogen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Score of MRF was calculated as x/8 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Out of total of 645 pts (10 yrs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>follow-up) 399 pts (62%) had AOD, out of them single AOD had 295 pts (74%), and polyvascular disease 104 pts (26%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>63 (61%) pts of symptomatic group had combination of AOD + CAD, and 41 pts (39%) had AOD + <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> + CAD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In the pts with 8 yrs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>follow-up (n-1035) AOD had 548 pts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>(53%), single AOD had 334 pts (57%) and polyvascular had 122 pts (39%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Out of symptomatic pts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>71 (58.2%) had AOD + CAD, and 51 (41.8%) had AOD + CAD + <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Asymptomatic disease on the very entry period of the study was significant for both groups, p &lt; 0.01 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: (i) we found a significant number of asymptomatic atherosclerotic changes on other vascular beds, (ii) score of MRF has correlated with polyvascular disease and with overall outcome (iii) antropomethric, haemodynamic, and morphological parameters of human blood vessels have been measured and systematically documented in Bosnia and Herzegovina </plain></SENT>
</text></document>