<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Extracranial carotid artery <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysm</z:hpo> (CCA), although uncommon, represents a challenge to treatment strategy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to analyze the treatment evolution and clinical outcome of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients with CCA over a two decade period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Clinical data of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients diagnosed with CCA who underwent interventions from 1984 to 2004 were reviewed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients were divided into two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Group I (1985-1994) and group II (1995-2004) were compared with regards to clinical presentation, treatment modality, and clinical outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 42 cases of CCA were found during the study period (group I, n=22; group II, n=20) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Pulsatile neck mass was the most common presenting symptom (n=39, 93%), followed by neurological symptoms (n=6, 14%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Twenty two (52%) were atherosclerotic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysms</z:hpo>, fifteen (36%) false <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysms</z:hpo>, and five (12%) posttraumatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysms</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Both groups shared similar comorbidities and demographic profiles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients in group I underwent operative interventions, which included 12 resection with interposition bypass grafting (55%), six resection with patch angioplasty (27%), and four carotid ligation (18%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In group II, five patients underwent resection with interposition placement (25%) and one carotid ligation (5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The remaining 14 patients underwent endovascular interventions (70%) which included seven stent-graft exclusions, six carotid stenting with coil exclusions, and one endovascular occlusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Hospital length of stay was significantly shorter in group II than group I (3.5 vs. 9.4 days, p&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The incidence of cranial nerve injury in group I and II were 14% vs. 5% (p&lt;0.04), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>The 30-day mortality/major <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> rates in group I and II were 14% vs. 5% (p&lt; 0.04), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>During the follow-up period (0.8 months-20 years; mean, 4.6 years), 16 patients died, largely due to cardiac etiologies (n=11, 69%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Treatment modality of CCA has largely evolved from operative to endovascular intervention at our institution </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>Treatment benefits of endovascular modality include shorter convalescent and less procedural-related complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>This evolution reflects the improvement of endovascular devices and increased utility of endovascular applications </plain></SENT>
</text></document>