<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Although <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> is a silent <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0849867" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">widespread disease</z:e>, the focal character of the lesions triggering the clinical manifestations is unquestionable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that symptomatic patients with advanced, unstable carotid plaques have increased local intraplaque and circulating levels of fibrin-fibrinogen related products </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Plaque tissue and plasma samples were studied in 106 patients undergoing endarterectomy for symptomatic and asymptomatic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0741975" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Fibrin-fibrinogen related products were evaluated by ELISA, Western-blotting, and histology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> tested parameters were compared with patient carotid symptomatology, multiple vascular risk factors (VRF), bilateral carotid pathology, ultrasound examination, and previous therapies with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statins</z:chebi> and/or antiplatelet drugs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In symptomatic patients, plasma D-dimer was elevated in patients with unstable carotid plaques (UNS) compared with stable (STA) ones (857+/-121 vs. 692+/-156 ng/ml, p=0 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>026) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, plasma D-dimer was significantly increased in patients with a coexistence of carotid and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001677'>coronary artery disease</z:hpo>, compared to others (976+/-325 vs. 714+/-197 ng/ml; p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Intra-plaque D-dimer content was increased in ulcerated-complicated (UC) plaques compared with fibrous non-complicated (F) plaques in symptomatic patients (5.9+/-1 vs. 1.8+/-1, p&lt;0.001), and in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020443" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypercholesterolaemia</z:e>, compared with those with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> cholesterol levels (6.1+/-1 vs. 2.9+/-0.7; p=0.027) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, there was no correlation between D-dimer content in the carotid plaque and plasma D-dimer levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0003124'>Hypercholesterolemia</z:hpo> and UC plaques appear to be associated with high fibrin intraplaque turnover as demonstrated by higher intraplaque D-dimer </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Plasma markers of fibrin turnover were increased in UNS plaques, and in patients with coexisting carotid and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001677'>coronary artery disease</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Although, both plasma and plaque D-dimers were associated with unstable <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0741975" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid disease</z:e>, the usefulness of the measurement of plasma D-dimer in these patients should be confirmed by prospective studies </plain></SENT>
</text></document>