<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>CONTEXT: By definition, levels of metabolic risk factors predict atherosclerotic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e>, but the effects of long-term adverse change and instability remain underresearched </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Our objective was to quantify long-term rates of change and instability in risk factors and relate these measures to clinical atherosclerotic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> outcomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>DESIGN AND SETTING: We conducted a prospective cohort study with unmatched and age- and follow-up-matched control analyses at a teaching hospital day ward </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>PARTICIPANTS: Participants included 465 predominantly healthy white males in an occupational cohort who had undergone repeated metabolic risk factor measurements (mean observation period 11.6 yr, range 2-28 yr), 62 of whom developed clinical atherosclerotic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES: Rate of change and instability in metabolic risk factor levels were quantified in each individual by linear regression with time and evaluated as predictors of atherosclerotic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> and coronary and cerebrovascular disease separately </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: As expected, baseline and/or mean follow-up measures of established risk factors relating to blood pressure, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> metabolism, and subclinical <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> were significant predictors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Predictors independent of baseline and mean follow-up levels, confirmed in matched and unmatched analyses, were 1) for atherosclerotic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e>, instability in weight (cases vs. controls: 2.9 vs. +2.5%); 2) for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010068" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary heart disease</z:e>, instability in body mass index (3.0 vs. +2.3%), a decline (-0.041 vs. -0.011 per decade) and instability (19.1 vs. 14.6%) in the <z:chebi fb="6" ids="39025">high-density lipoprotein</z:chebi>/non-<z:chebi fb="1" ids="47775">high-density lipoprotein cholesterol</z:chebi> ratio, declining erythrocyte sedimentation rate, and increasing <z:chebi fb="3" ids="27226">uric acid</z:chebi>; and 3) for cerebrovascular disease, a decline in insulin sensitivity (-0.394 vs. 0.324 per decade) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Within an individual, long-term change in metabolic risk factors, as well as their absolute levels, can be important in atherosclerotic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>