<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The presence of Chlamydia pneumoniae in murine brain tissue was studied in atherosclerotic and non-atherosclerotic mice, after peritoneal injection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, we investigated whether increased permeability of the blood-brain barrier was implicated in cerebral C. pneumoniae <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and whether intra-cerebral C. pneumoniae <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> leads to microglial activation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Using a polymerase chain reaction, C. pneumoniae DNA was found in the brain tissue of 33% of the mice, 3, 7 and 21 days after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>Atherosclerosis</z:hpo> and age does not influence the extend of the cerebral <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Semiquantitative analyses showed that intra-cerebral C. pneumoniae <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was not accompanied by an altered function of the blood-brain barrier </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Microglial activation was assessed with immunohistochemistry, quantified in the hippocampus of each infected mouse and compared with mock infected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Enhanced microglial activation was found in the atherosclerotic mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Since microglial activation is a key factor in a number of neuroinflammatory diseases, C. pneumoniae <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> might play a role in these diseases </plain></SENT>
</text></document>