<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Vascular localization of symptomatic large artery atherosclerotic (LAA) <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> differs for unknown reasons by race-ethnicity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> (MetSD) is associated with higher atherosclerotic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> risk and comprises abnormal risk factors that can vary by race </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Thus, we investigated whether MetSD may contribute to race-ethnic differences in LAA <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> by examining the association of MetSD with symptomatic intra- and extracranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> among a diverse race-ethnic group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHOD: We analyzed data prospectively collected over a 4-year period on subjects with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo>/<z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>TIA</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Independent vascular risk factor associations with intracranial and extracranial LAA vs. non-LAA mechanism were evaluated in two groups stratified by race-ethnicity; whites and non-whites (Hispanics, African-American, and Asian-American) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 1167 patients met study criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Intracranial LAA was more prevalent in non-whites vs. whites (20.4% vs. 9.6%, P&lt;0.001), while extracranial LAA had a more frequent point value in whites compared to non-whites (10.7% vs. 7.5%, P=0.267) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The presence of MetSD was more prevalent in both intracranial and extracranial LAA group than in non-LAA group: no significant differences were observed in the prevalence of MetSD between intra vs. extracranial LAA or whites vs. non-whites </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, with increasing numbers of abnormal metabolic components, whites were more likely to have experienced extracranial LAA, whereas non-whites were more likely to have experienced intracranial LAA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>After adjusting for covariates, MetSD was associated with extracranial LAA in whites (OR, 1.98; 95% CI, 1.13-3.45), while there was a tendency that intracranial LAA was associated with MetSD in non-whites (OR, 1.80; 95% CI, 0.97-3.32) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>No association was found between MetSD and extracranial LAA in non-whites and between this syndrome with intracranial LAA in whites </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our results showed that the impact of MetSD on the distribution of cervicocephalic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> differed by race-ethnicity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>This finding may in part explain the well-known differences in race-ethnic predilection to intracranial or extracranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>