<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Lead is involved in the pathogenesis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020538" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="HTN">hypertensive disease</z:e> and may be related to cerebrovascular disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We studied the association of body lead level with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> subtypes and severity of cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> in order to identify the significance of lead exposure to cerebrovascular disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: From April, 2002 to March, 2005, we studied the lead level in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients receiving digital subtraction angiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Diameter stenosis at extracranial carotid, intracranial carotid and vertebrobasilar system was calculated according to the NASCET criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A blood sample and a mobilization test of 72-h urine sample were collected for lead measurement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In a total of 213 subjects, 19 were free of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> (blood lead level=4.62+/-2.41 microg/dL, body lead store=39.04+/-20.91 microg) and 194 were <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> patients (4.89+/-2.75 microg/dL, 45.13+/-29.8 microg; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> vs. non-<z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, P&gt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In the 153 subjects with atherosclerotic origin, body lead store but not blood lead level in the intracranial carotid system was significantly higher in &gt; or =50% group than &lt;50% group (blood lead: 5.61+/-3.02 microg/dL vs. 4.80+/-2.50 microg/dL, Student's t-test, P=0.129; body lead store: 51.7+/-27.0 microg vs. 41.9+/-23.5 microg, Student's t-test, P=0.038, multivariate logistic regression, odds ratio=1.02, 95% CI: 1.00-1.03, P=0.043) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, there was no significant association between lead level and stenotic severity in extracranial and vertebrobasilar systems (P&gt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our study demonstrated that long-term lead exposure as measured by body lead store might carry a potential risk of intracranial carotid <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>