<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND AIMS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000956'>Acanthosis nigricans</z:hpo> (AN) has been reported in association with severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0002652'>skeletal dysplasias</z:hpo> due to activating mutations in FGFR3, including thanatophoric <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>, severe <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0001080" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">achondroplasia</z:e> (ACH) with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001263'>developmental delay</z:hpo> and AN (SADDAN syndrome), and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010273" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Crouzon syndrome</z:e> with AN </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>There are isolated reports of patients with ACH and AN </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In this series, we report clinical and biochemical data on five male patients, four with ACH and one with hypochondroplasia (<z:chebi fb="1" ids="24536">HCH</z:chebi>), who developed AN without SADDAN </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: We compared the results of a 1.75 g/kg oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test performed in patients with ACH/<z:chebi fb="1" ids="24536">HCH</z:chebi> and AN with age-, sex-, and puberty-matched short children </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Three of the patients were treated with recombinant human GH (dose range, 45-50 microg/kg/d), one patient had discontinued treatment 6 months before presentation, and one had never been treated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients had a fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> of less than 6 mmol/liter, and no patient had a plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> greater than 7.8 mmol/liter at 2 h after ingestion of a <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> load </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Although body mass index was higher in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002652'>skeletal dysplasia</z:hpo> (28.9 +/- 7.3 vs. 20 +/- 0.6 kg/m(2); P = 0.01), mean fasting plasma insulin concentration was greater in controls (14.4 +/- 4.8 vs. 6.0 +/- 4.5 mU/liter; P = 0.03), as was homeostasis assessment index for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> (2.5 +/- 0.9 vs. 1.17 +/- 0.8; P = 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our findings suggest that the development of AN in patients with ACH/<z:chebi fb="1" ids="24536">HCH</z:chebi> is not due to <z:hpo ids='HP_0008189'>insulin insensitivity</z:hpo> either on its own or secondary to treatment with recombinant human GH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Whether the AN is due to altered melanocyte function in these individuals remains to be established </plain></SENT>
</text></document>