<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to analyse human leukocyte antigen (HLA) and disease association in common <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">blood diseases</z:e> [<z:hpo ids='HP_0005506'>chronic myelogenous leukemia</z:hpo> (<z:mp ids='MP_0005481'>CML</z:mp>), <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> nonlymphocytic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> (ANLL), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0039730" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">thalassemia</z:e> and severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo>] in Thais </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The subjects were patients from the Hematological Clinic, Departments of Medicine and Pediatrics, Ramathibodi Hospital who were referred for HLA typing for bone marrow transplantation (BMT) at the Histocompatibility Laboratory from March 1988 to September 1997 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A total of 129 patients had complete HLA-ABC typing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The patients included 45 <z:mp ids='MP_0005481'>CML</z:mp>, 40 ANLL, 26 thalassemia (Thal) and 18 severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> (SAA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Of these, 88 patients were typed for HLA class II </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The HLA class I (ABC) and II (DR, DQ) typings were performed by microlymphocytotoxicity test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>It was found that HLA class I was associated with <z:mp ids='MP_0005481'>CML</z:mp>, ANLL and Thal, whereas, HLA class II was associated with SAA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>HLA-B8 and HLA-B18 were increased in <z:mp ids='MP_0005481'>CML</z:mp> with R.R. values of 12.2 and 3.9, respectively, whereas, HLA-B18 was increased in ANLL with R.R. value of 4.5 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In addition, HLA-DR2 and DR3 were increased in SAA with R.R. values of 3.8 and 4.8, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>For Thal, HLA-A2 and B46 were increased in Thal in Central Thais with R.R. values of 3.3 and 6.1, respectively, whereas, HLA-B13 was increased in Thal in Northern Thais with R.R. value of 8.5 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>On the other hand, HLA-B7 was absent in <z:mp ids='MP_0005481'>CML</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>HLA-Cw7 was decreased in <z:mp ids='MP_0005481'>CML</z:mp> and SAA, whereas, HLA-DR6 was decreased in ANLL and SAA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, HLA-Cw6 was also decreased in <z:mp ids='MP_0005481'>CML</z:mp>, whereas, HLA-A33 and Bw4 were decreased in SAA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Although the sample size of each disease was small, the increase of HLA-DR2 was observed in SAA in Thais which was similar to other studies in different ethnic groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>These preliminary data may be useful for further study in HLA and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1533163" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">blood disease</z:e> association </plain></SENT>
</text></document>