<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: To report long-term pulmonary, thyroid, and ocular complications in patients who had conditioning regimens including total body irradiation (TBI) before bone marrow transplantation (BMT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND MATERIALS: Between June 1986 and December 1995, 478 patients received TBI in our institution </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The present study includes 186 adult patients who had complete remission lasting one year or more after BMT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>There were 108 males and 78 females </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Median age was 36.5 years (range 15-60) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Initial diagnoses were <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> (50%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0006721'>acute lymphoid leukemias</z:hpo> (16%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0004808'>acute myeloid leukemias</z:hpo> (16%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> myeloid <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> (13%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> (3%), and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplasia</z:hpo> (2%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At the time of BMT, 43.5% of patients were in complete response and 56.5% in partial response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Treatment consisted of a single dose TBI at 10 Gy in 9% and fractionated TBI delivering 12 to 13.5 Gy in 6 fractions in 91% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>From 1986 to October 1991, TBI was performed in lateral position with 9 MV energy (57% of patients) and thereafter in alternate prone and supine positions with 15 MV energy (43%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Chemical conditioning regimen was <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4027">cyclophosphamide</z:chebi> (60 mg/kg at D-4 and D-3) in 69% and CBV (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="4027">cyclophosphamide</z:chebi> 1500 mg/m(2) from D-6 to D-3, BCNU 300 mg/m(2) at D-6, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4911">VP-16</z:chebi> 200 mg/m(2) from D-6 to D-4) in 25% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Fifty eight percent of patients received autologous and 42% allogeneic BMT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients had clinical, biologic, and functional examinations at one-year intervals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Median follow-up from BMT was 49 months (range 12-136) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Late pulmonary effects were observed only in functional explorations, without clinical effect, including restrictive syndrome in 8% and alteration in the diffusing capacity of <z:chebi fb="168" ids="17245">carbon monoxide</z:chebi> in 12% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>No patient showed clinical thyroid symptoms, and 10% developed biologic dysfunction: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000821'>hypothyroidism</z:hpo> (6.5%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0100646'>thyroiditis</z:hpo> (3%), and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018213" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Basedow disease</z:e> (0.5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Ocular complications occurred in 29.5%, including <z:hpo ids='HP_0000518'>cataract</z:hpo> (15%), dry syndrome (13%), and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000491'>keratitis</z:hpo> (1.5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>In univariate and multivariate analysis, pulmonary complications were statistically increased by chronicle <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018133" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GVH">graft vs. host disease</z:e> (GVHD) vs. no (p = 0.02), prone and supine vs. lateral TBI position (p = 0.02), and with 15 MV vs. 9 MV beam energy (p = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000518'>Cataract</z:hpo> occurred less frequently with fractionated than with single-dose TBI (p = 0.000002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>No differences were observed regarding age, sex, initial diagnosis, status at the time of BMT, conditioning chemotherapy regimen, and total dose of TBI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="19" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: From this retrospective study it was shown that long-term complications of TBI were not symptomatic in most patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="20" pm="."><plain>The role of parameters of irradiation and especially position of treatment and beam energy should be emphasized and assessed with a longer follow-up </plain></SENT>
</text></document>