<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We report two patients who developed atypical <z:mp ids='MP_0001212'>skin lesions</z:mp> caused by Curvularia sp. and Pseudallescheria boydii after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The first patient (female, 18-year-old) had multiple hemorrhagic vesicles on day +30 after her second BMT for graft failure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Pseudallescheria boydii was isolated from a skin biopsy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The patient died of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002093'>respiratory failure</z:hpo> probably as a consequence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0553576" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">systemic fungal infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The second patient (male, 9-year-old) developed an <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0276085" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ecthyma gangrenosum</z:e>-like lesion on his right palm on day +8 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Curvularia sp. was isolated from a skin biopsy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Liposomal amphotericin was given to achieve a total dose of 30 mg/kg and followed by oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6076">itraconazole</z:chebi> until steroids were discontinued </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> resolved completely and the patient has remained disease-free </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We conclude that emerging fungal organisms such as those described in this report are increasingly recognized in this setting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Early recognition and biopsy of these cutaneous lesions will allow prompt initiation of therapy to prevent <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0243026" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">systemic infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>