<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To report a case series of high-dose continuous infusion <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35627">beta-lactam</z:chebi> antibiotics for the treatment of resistant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0854135" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Pseudomonas aeruginosa infections</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>CASE SUMMARY: Continuous infusion <z:chebi fb="0" ids="3508">ceftazidime</z:chebi> or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2960">aztreonam</z:chebi> was administered to achieve target drug concentrations at or above the minimum inhibitory concentration, when possible, in 3 patients with P. aeruginosa <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The maximal calculated target drug concentration was 100 mg/L </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the first patient, with primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002721'>immunodeficiency</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo>, and aggressive cutaneous <z:hpo ids='HP_0005517'>T-cell lymphoma/leukemia</z:hpo>, continuous infusion <z:chebi fb="0" ids="3508">ceftazidime</z:chebi> (6.5-9.6 g/day) was used to successfully treat multidrug-resistant P. aeruginosa <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004610" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bacteremia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In the second patient, with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0272187" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">leukocyte adhesion deficiency</z:e> type 1, continuous infusion <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2960">aztreonam</z:chebi> (8.4 g/day) was used to successfully treat multidrug-resistant P. aeruginosa wound <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In the third patient, with severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo>, continuous infusion <z:chebi fb="0" ids="3508">ceftazidime</z:chebi> (7-16.8 g/day) was used to treat P. aeruginosa <z:hpo ids='HP_0002090'>pneumonia</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004610" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bacteremia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In each patient, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004610" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bacteremia</z:e> cleared, infected wounds healed, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002090'>pneumonia</z:hpo> improved in response to continuous infusion <z:chebi fb="0" ids="3508">ceftazidime</z:chebi> or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2960">aztreonam</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>DISCUSSION: Treatment strategies for multidrug-resistant P. aeruginosa <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> are limited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A novel treatment strategy, when no other options are available, is the continuous infusion of existing <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35627">beta-lactam</z:chebi> antibiotics to maximize their pharmacodynamic activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>High-dose continuous infusion <z:chebi fb="0" ids="3508">ceftazidime</z:chebi> or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2960">aztreonam</z:chebi> was used for the successful treatment of resistant systemic P. aeruginosa <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> in 3 chronically immunocompromised patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Continuous infusion <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35627">beta-lactam</z:chebi> antibiotics are a potentially useful treatment strategy for resistant P. aeruginosa <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> in immunocompromised patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>