<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To discuss pharmacotherapy challenges encountered during treatment of a pediatric <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>oncology</z:hpo> patient with Burkholderia cepacia <z:mpath ids='MPATH_681'>septicemia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>CASE SUMMARY: An 11-year-old male with a history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> presented to the emergency department with a 1-day history of cough and purulent nasal discharge 6 months after undergoing bone marrow transplant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Blood cultures obtained from the patient's Broviac catheter revealed <z:mp ids='MP_0001795'>gram-negative</z:mp> rods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="8232">Piperacillin</z:chebi>/tazobactam and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28864">tobramycin</z:chebi> were administered, but the patient worsened clinically, with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo> and chills </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>B. cepacia was identified as the offending pathogen, and the therapy was changed to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="43968">meropenem</z:chebi> and ciprofloxacin, as <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8232">piperacillin</z:chebi>/ tazobactam and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28864">tobramycin</z:chebi> are ineffective against Burkholderia spp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Intravenous <z:chebi fb="0" ids="45924">trimethoprim</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="9332">sulfamethoxazole</z:chebi>, the drug of choice for Burkholderia spp. <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e>, was unavailable as it had been placed on national manufacturer backorder </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The patient improved initially, but he later experienced recurrence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo>, and blood culture results were positive for Burkholderia spp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Infection</z:e> was eradicated after removal of the central line and administration of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="3508">ceftazidime</z:chebi> and oral <z:chebi fb="1" ids="50694">minocycline</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>DISCUSSION: Literature reveals few cases of B. cepacia in pediatric <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>oncology</z:hpo> patients, and to our knowledge, no cases have been reported in bone marrow transplant patients in the US </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Burkholderia spp. is highly resistant to many antibiotics, and commonly used agents for the empiric treatment of febrile <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> are not active against this organism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This indicates that most <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>oncology</z:hpo> patients who present with this <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> would not receive appropriate initial treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In addition, antibiotic therapy may need to be modified, based on drug availability </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: B. cepacia is an emerging multidrug-resistant pathogen that can produce severe <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in immunocompromised patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>It is pertinent to consider this organism in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>oncology</z:hpo> patients who do not improve with standard therapy, as prompt use of correct pharmacotherapy is necessary to avoid serious morbidity as well as mortality in this population </plain></SENT>
</text></document>