<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948224" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Stenotrophomonas maltophilia infection</z:e> is of concern in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Antibiotics active against S. maltophilia are rarely used in the treatment of febrile <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo>, making it important to identify the factors influencing mortality in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> patients with S. maltophilia <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to analyze the clinical characteristics and outcomes of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> and hemopathic patients with S. maltophilia <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and assess the factors influencing the mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The microbiology laboratory records of Erciyes University, Faculty of Medicine Hospital were reviewed to retrospectively identify patients with S. maltophilia <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> between January 2007 and June 2011 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A total of 38 patients (25 male, 13 female) were eligible for the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The median age of the patients was 53 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The underlying disease was <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0848852,C0376545" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">hematological malignancy</z:e> and disorders in 76.3 % (29 cases), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0280100" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">solid tumors</z:e> in 15.8 % (six cases), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> in 7.9 % (three cases), while 18.4 % (seven cases) were hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) recipients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>An indwelling central venous catheter was used in 32 cases (84.2 %) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Twenty-seven patients (71.1 %) were neutropenic at the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Nine patients (23.7 %) were receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50858">corticosteroid</z:chebi> therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The overall 14-day mortality rate was 50 % </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Three of the patients received empirical antibacterial treatment, and three HSCT recipients received <z:chebi fb="0" ids="45924">trimethoprim</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="9332">sulfamethoxazole</z:chebi> prophylaxis, which is active against S. maltophilia </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0100806'>sepsis</z:hpo> (OR 13.24, 95 % confidence interval (CI) 1.62-108.57) and the duration of the treatment (OR 0.73, 95 % CI 0.60-0.90) were related to <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> based on logistic regression analysis findings </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In immunocompromised hematology-<z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>oncology</z:hpo> patients with severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0100806'>sepsis</z:hpo>, S. maltophilia should be considered as a possible cause of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>, and should be given effective empirical antibiotic treatment immediately; the antimicrobial spectrum may be narrowed according to results of antibiotic susceptibility test </plain></SENT>
</text></document>