<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We evaluated the results of a novel conditioning regimen of reduced dose <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4027">cyclophosphamide</z:chebi> (Cy, 25 mg/kg for four days), fludarabine (Flu, 30 mg/m(2) for four days), and rabbit ATG (2.5 mg/kg for three days) for allogeneic transplant of children with SAA, implemented since January 2009 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Overall, 23 patients were treated with this regimen (16 male, seven female), including 10 diagnosed with VSAA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Donors included eight-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MSD</z:e> and 15 UD (five-matched UD, and 10 mismatched UD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients showed neutrophil and platelet engraftment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Cumulative incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> (grade 2 or above) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> GVHD was 26.1% and 8.7%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Estimated two-yr <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">FFS</z:e> and OS for the entire cohort was 90.3 ± 6.5% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Rates of TRM and graft failure were 5.3% and 4.3%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No difference in OS was found according to disease severity (SAA vs. VSAA, p = 0.184), or according to donor type (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MSD</z:e> vs. UD, p = 0.699) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Excellent outcomes of patients with VSAA underscore the efficacy of allogeneic transplant as a means of expediting hematopoietic recovery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Improved survival of UD transplant reaffirms its role as a valid therapeutic alternative in the absence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MSD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>