<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The records of 96 pediatric patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> or a <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancy</z:e> who underwent bone marrow transplantation between 1979 and 1986 at The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia were reviewed for laboratory evidence of <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The most common <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> diseases identified were <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019348" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">herpes simplex</z:e> virus (HSV), cytomegalovirus and adenoviruses, which were found in 19 (20%), 17 (18) and 17 (18) patients, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>HSV was more common in patients with than without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018133" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GVH">graft vs. host disease</z:e> (GVHD) (9 of 30; 30% vs. 10 of 66; 15%), but the difference did not reach statistical significance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Late or prolonged isolation of HSV occurred in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> GVHD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Cytomegalovirus was significantly more common in patients with than without GVHD (10 of 30; 33% vs. 7 of 66; 11%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The presence of pretransplant antibody to cytomegalovirus or HSV was a good predictor of subsequent <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Adenoviruses were isolated from <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> 3 patients with Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Adenovirus type 12, a serotype uncommon in man and known to be highly tumorigenic in young hamsters, was recovered from 4 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Adenoviruses were not notably more common in patients with GVHD (6 of 30; 20% vs. 11 of 66; 17%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Other <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> demonstrated included 5 parainfluenza, 4 enteroviruses, 3 human <z:hpo ids='HP_0002721'>immunodeficiency</z:hpo> virus, 1 respiratory syncytial virus, 1 influenza B and 1 rhinovirus </plain></SENT>
</text></document>