<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A case-control interview study of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> was conducted to evaluate suspected risk factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Cases (N = 59) newly diagnosed during 1975-82 at 25 Baltimore area hospitals were compared with 59 individually matched (on age, sex and race) controls selected by random digit dialing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The average educational level was less for cases than controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The major job-related findings were a significant excess for occupational exposure to paint (OR = 6.1; 95% C.I. = 1.2-29.7), further substantiated by a positive dose-response relationship, although painters were not at excess risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>An increased risk of occupational exposure to viruses (OR = 9.0; 95% C.I. = 0.8-105.6) was noted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Additional evidence implicating <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> factors included a significant association with prior history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0012115'>hepatitis</z:hpo> (OR = 9.0; 95% C.I. = 1.0, 84.2) and an elevated risk for pre-diagnostic receipt of blood transfusions (OR = 7.1; 95% C.I. = 0.7-68.4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Risks were not increased for other occupational, residential, personal, or medical treatment exposures or for other <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e>, medical conditions, smoking or alcohol consumption prior to diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Because of the small number of subjects studied and the multiple comparisons examined, these findings should be interpreted cautiously and confirmation should be undertaken in larger, population-based studies </plain></SENT>
</text></document>