<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The patient was a 59-year-old man who had been in hospital suffering from <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> with transfusion <z:mp ids='MP_0005639'>hemosiderosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Sudden <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of <z:mp ids='MP_0000746'>weakness</z:mp>, <z:mp ids='MP_0000745'>shaking</z:mp> chills and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> was observed after his staying out overnight on July 25, 1981 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>His temperature was 39.3 degrees C and he complained of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002027'>abdominal pain</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003270'>abdominal distension</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>His blood pressure dropped to a dangerous level and tonic <z:mp ids='MP_0000947'>convulsions</z:mp> that had begun in the upper body gradually extended to the whole body and he died 23 hours after his return </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>V. vulnificus was isolated by the blood culture performed before <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>During his stay away from the hospital, he had eaten raw cuttlefish, which was considered to be the source of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>V. vulnificus is one of the halophilic marine vibrios and is isolated frequently in summertime from the sea foods and sea water near Japan </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>It has been disclosed that the presence of underlying diseases such as liver <z:hpo ids='HP_0001394'>cirrhosis</z:hpo>, <z:mp ids='MP_0005638'>hemochromatosis</z:mp> can predispose a person to fatal <z:hpo ids='HP_0100806'>sepsis</z:hpo> by V. vulnificus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In this case, besides <z:mp ids='MP_0000221'>leukocytopenia</z:mp>, the presence of <z:mp ids='MP_0005639'>hemosiderosis</z:mp> induced by many transfusions was considered to be a major cause leading to the fulminating course of the disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>