<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="209807">Cefoxitin</z:chebi> (CFX) at a daily dose of 3 to 12 grams was administered to patients who had hematopoietic disorders as underlying diseases and having severe <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Efficacy and safety of the drug were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The underlying diseases in the 64 patients included in the evaluation of efficacy were <z:hpo ids='HP_0004808'>acute myelocytic leukemia</z:hpo> (30 cases), <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> lymphocytic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> (9), <z:hpo ids='HP_0004836'>acute promyelocytic leukemia</z:hpo> (3), <z:hpo ids='HP_0004845'>acute monocytic leukemia</z:hpo> (2), <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> myelocytic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo>-blastic crisis (10), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0023440" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">erythroleukemia</z:e> (2), malignant <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (2), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> (2), and others (4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> were <z:mpath ids='MPATH_681'>septicemia</z:mpath> in 3 patients, suspected <z:mpath ids='MPATH_681'>septicemia</z:mpath> in 47, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011947'>respiratory tract infections</z:hpo> in 7, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0555971" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">oral infections</z:e> in 3, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000010'>urinary tract infections</z:hpo> in 2, and others in 2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The clinical efficacy of CFX was 'excellent' in 13 patients, 'good' in 26, 'fair' in 6, 'poor' in 19 for an efficacy rate of 60.9% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The efficacy rate classified according to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> was 66.7% in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_681'>septicemia</z:mpath>, 66.0% in suspected <z:mpath ids='MPATH_681'>septicemia</z:mpath>, 42.9% in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011947'>respiratory tract infections</z:hpo> and 66.7% in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0555971" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">oral infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The organisms isolated from the patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_681'>septicemia</z:mpath> were E. coli in 2 patients and B. cereus in 1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>B. cereus was not susceptible to CFX </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The efficacy rate was 60.0% in the 10 patients whose causative organisms were identified and 61.1% in the 54 patients whose causative organisms were not identified </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference in the efficacy rate between the patients who had failed to respond to prior antibiotic therapy and those treated with CFX from the beginning </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The efficacy rates for the former group (23 patients) and for the latter group (41 patients) were 56.5% and 63.4%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The efficacy rate in patients with an initial neutrophil count less than 500/mm3 (35 cases) and from 501 to 1,000/mm3 (13 cases) were 57.1% and 76.9%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Side effects which might have been caused by CFX were <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0015230" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">skin eruptions</z:e> in 2 patients (2.6%) and transient elevation of GOT and GPT in 1 patient (1.3%) among 76 patients who were evaluated for safety </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CFX was considered to be a markedly useful and safe drug in the treatment of patients with hematopoietic disorders who developed severe <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>