<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="17698">Chloramphenicol</z:chebi> was introduced into medical practice in 1949 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>At therapeutic concentrations of 10 to 20 micrograms drug per ml, the drug inhibits <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> ribosomal and, to a lesser extent, mammalian <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> protein synthesis but concentrations above 60 micrograms drug per ml induce progressive reduction of oxygen-dependent cellular metabolism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Some adverse reactions (e.g. bone marrow suppression and the "<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0270276" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">gray baby syndrome</z:e>") reflect these effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The pathogenesis of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17698">chloramphenicol</z:chebi>-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> remains unclear </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="17698">Chloramphenicol</z:chebi> is most bioavailable after oral administration and has a remarkable ability to diffuse into body fluids and tissues </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, there are wide interindividual variations in its metabolism and elimination, particularly in newborns </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="17698">Chloramphenicol</z:chebi> is indicated for invasive <z:chebi fb="1" ids="28971">ampicillin</z:chebi>-resistant H. influenzae <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e>; for patients allergic to <z:chebi fb="93" ids="17334">penicillin</z:chebi> with pneumococcal, meningococcal or H. influenzae <z:hpo ids='HP_0001287'>meningitis</z:hpo>; in patients under 8 years of age with Rocky Mountain spotted <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo>; and for the treatment of brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_612'>abscess</z:mpath> and other severe anaerobic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> (excluding <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo>) due to B. fragilis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Other indications include selected patients with Salmonella <z:hpo ids='HP_0001287'>meningitis</z:hpo> or <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0035585" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">rickettsioses</z:e> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1708554" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">intraocular infections</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Unravelling the pathogenesis of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17698">chloramphenicol</z:chebi>-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> is critical to more widespread application of this remarkable antimicrobial </plain></SENT>
</text></document>