<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>Aplastic anemia</z:hpo> (AA) is a rare, life threatening disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Allogeneic bone marrow transplantation (BMT) offers the only possibility of cure, i. e </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>life-long remission </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The probability of survival after BMT from an HLA-identical sibling has clearly improved over the last years and at present is about 80% in patients &lt; 16 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Transplantation from alternative donors, however, faces unsolved immunological problems </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>For demographic reasons most patients lack a matched sibling donor </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For these patients immunosuppressive therapy (IST) is the only alternative therapeutic approach </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However this treatment has frequently resulted in clonal, i. e. potentially malignant disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Overall probability of survival here is only 50%, in severely granulocytopenic patients (&lt; 0.2 G/l) even lower </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These individuals represent an important subgroup in pediatric AA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Some patients show only partial reconstitution of their hematopoiesis but satisfactory quality of life </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Based on the results of prospective studies a protocol for IST in AA using anti-lymphocyte globulin (ALG), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4031">cyclosporin A</z:chebi> (CSA) and G-CSF is presented </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>For BMT-patients likewise a protocol for conditioning (ALG, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4027">cyclophosphamide</z:chebi>) and GvHD-prophylaxis is suggested </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Standardisation and improvement of supportive therapy is the third important objective of this pilot protocol </plain></SENT>
</text></document>