<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Between 1984 and 1991 24 patients with severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> (SAA) were transplanted with HLA identical sibling donor BM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The overall long-term survival was 79 +/- 8% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The average age was 21 years (range 4-53 years) and the median pre-transplant disease duration was 35 days (range 12-2998 days) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Over one-half (15 of 24) of the patients had received &gt; 10 units of blood product transfusions prior to BMT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The pre-transplant conditioning regimen consisted of 200 mg/kg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4027">cyclophosphamide</z:chebi> (CY) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="4031">Cyclosporine</z:chebi> (CYA) was administered from 2 days prior to BMT and continued for 6-12 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Two of the 24 patients failed to achieve primary engraftment (FTE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>One of these patients had autologous recovery of BM function and is alive and well </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Five of the 22 patients who engrafted failed to sustain engraftment (FTSE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Of these, three are alive and well following a second BMT or marrow boost </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Only 1 of the 22 patients who engrafted had clinically significant (i.e. Stage II-IV) <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> GVHD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>No patient developed <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> GVHD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Our results indicate that BMT following a regimen consisting of CY with the continuous use of CYA in the post-transplant period is well tolerated and associated with excellent long-term survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The high incidence of secondary graft instability (i.e. FTSE), however, suggests that future studies should focus on post-transplantation immunomodulation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>