<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0012115'>Hepatitis</z:hpo> G virus (HGV) has been reported in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004787'>fulminant hepatitis</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo>, but HGV <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi> has also been found in healthy individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The possible associations of HGV with liver function and hematologic abnormalities in asymptomatic blood donors were investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>STUDY DESIGN AND METHODS: Serum HGV <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi> was determined in 200 repeat donors (Group A), 44 subjects with elevated alanine aminotransferase (Group B), and 54 <z:hpo ids='HP_0012115'>hepatitis</z:hpo> C virus carriers (Group C) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Liver histology was evaluated in Group C by using the histologic activity index </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: HGV <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi> was detected in three subjects of Group A (1.5%; 95% CI: 0.3-4.3), two of Group B (4.5%; 95% CI: 0.6-15.5%), and six of Group C (11.1%; 95% CI: 4.2-22.6) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001882'>leukopenia</z:hpo> and elevated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="24190">gamma-glutamyl</z:chebi> transpeptidase was higher in the 11 viremic donors than in 88 nonviremic subjects (36% vs. 2.3%, and 55% vs. 22%, respectively; p &lt; 0.05), matched for clinical and demographic characteristics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean histologic activity index score +/- standard error was 4 +/- 0.7 in the HGV <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi>-positive donors and 3.4 +/- 0.3 in the HGV <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi>-negative donors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: HGV is endemic in Italian blood donors, although it has a limited role in causing liver damage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Further studies are needed to clarify its role in inducing transfusion-associated disease in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0854467" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">myelosuppression</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>