<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The urinary excretion and pharmacokinetics of <z:chebi fb="2" ids="15368">acrolein</z:chebi> (ACRO) and its parent drug <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4027">cyclophosphamide</z:chebi> (CP) were investigated in 16 randomly selected bone marrow transplant (BMT) recipients when CP was used for conditioning </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Patients suffering from <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> (n = 3) received a 4-day course of CP at a dose of 50 mg/kg daily infused intravenously (i.v.) over 1 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> (n = 13) were given either a combination of busulphan followed by CP at a dose of 50 mg/kg infused i.v. over 1 h for 4 days, or CP at a dose of 60 mg/kg by i.v. infusion over 1 h daily for 2 days followed by total body irradiation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Serial plasma samples and urine were collected after the start of the first CP dose </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>CP was analyzed by capillary gas chromatography, whereas ACRO was measured in urine by liquid chromatography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The plasma concentration-time data for CP conformed to the two-compartment model and the mean and s.e.m. values of alpha, beta, Vss, total clearance, and renal clearance observed were 1.29 (0.31) h(-1), 0.17 (0.03) h(-1), 0.67 (0.13) l/kg, 0.14 (0.02) l/h x kg, and 0.0188 (0.0052) l/h x kg, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean and s.e.m. values of fraction of CP excreted in the form of ACRO during this interval (fmu) and ratio of the 24-h urinary concentration of ACRO/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> (Cmu(n)) were 1.96 (0.35%) and 9.11 (2.19) microg of ACRO/mg of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi>, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Two patients developed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085692" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hemorrhagic cystitis</z:e> (HC) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Each of these two patients excreted significantly (P &lt; 0.01) more ACRO in the first and second 4-h urine collection periods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, there was no significant difference in fmu or Cmu(n) of ACRO between either of these two patients and the rest </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This suggests that the rate of appearance of ACRO in urine is more crucial for developing HC than the cumulative amount excreted </plain></SENT>
</text></document>