<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVEExamine the efficacy and safety of lixisenatide (20 μg once daily, administered before the morning or evening meal) as add-on therapy in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> patients insufficiently controlled with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> alone.RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODSA 24-week, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study in 680 patients with inadequately controlled type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (HbA1c 7-10% [53-86 mmol/mol]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Patients were randomized to lixisenatide morning (n = 255), lixisenatide evening (n = 255), placebo morning (n = 85), or placebo evening (n = 85) injections.RESULTSLixisenatide morning injection significantly reduced mean HbA1c versus combined placebo (mean change -0.9% [9.8 mmol/mol] vs. -0.4% [4.4 mmol/mol]; least squares [LS] mean difference vs. placebo -0.5% [5.5 mmol/mol], P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>HbA1c was significantly reduced by lixisenatide evening injection (mean change -0.8% [8.7 mmol/mol] vs. -0.4% [4.4 mmol/mol]; LS mean difference -0.4% [4.4 mmol/mol], P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Lixisenatide morning injection significantly reduced 2-h postprandial <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> versus morning placebo (mean change -5.9 vs. -1.4 mmol/L; LS mean difference -4.5 mmol/L, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>LS mean difference in fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> was significant in both morning (-0.9 mmol/L, P &lt; 0.0001) and evening (-0.6 mmol/L, P = 0.0046) groups versus placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mean body weight decreased to a similar extent in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Rates of adverse events were 69.4% in both lixisenatide groups and 60.0% in the placebo group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Rates for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002017'>nausea and vomiting</z:hpo> were 22.7 and 9.4% for lixisenatide morning and 21.2 and 13.3% for lixisenatide evening versus 7.6 and 2.9% for placebo, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> occurred in 6, 13, and 1 patient for lixisenatide morning, evening, and placebo, respectively, with no severe episodes.CONCLUSIONSIn patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> inadequately controlled on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, lixisenatide 20 μg once daily administered in the morning or evening significantly improved glycemic control, with a pronounced postprandial effect, and was well tolerated </plain></SENT>
</text></document>