<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Angiotensin receptor blockers are renoprotective in hypertensive azotemic patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, but their efficacy in early <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0011881" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">diabetic kidney disease</z:e> is uncertain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We performed a 6-year randomized clinical trial in 169 American Indians with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and normoalbuminuria (albumin/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> ratio [ACR] &lt;30 mg/g; n = 91) or <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> (ACR 30-299 mg/g; n = 78) at baseline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The primary outcome was decline in glomerular filtration rate (GFR) to ≤60 mL/min or to half the baseline value in subjects who entered with GFR &lt;120 mL/min </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Another outcome was differences in glomerular structure at end of treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Subjects received 100 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6541">losartan</z:chebi> or placebo daily </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>GFR was measured annually; 111 subjects underwent kidney biopsies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Only nine subjects reached the GFR outcome, and the unadjusted hazard ratio (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6541">losartan</z:chebi> vs. placebo) was 0.50 (95% CI 0.12-1.99) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Differences in mesangial fractional volume were not estimated in the combined <z:mp ids='MP_0002871'>albuminuria</z:mp> groups because of an interaction with treatment assignment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In separate analyses, mesangial fractional volume was lower in subjects treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6541">losartan</z:chebi> in the <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> group (18.8 vs. 25.6%; P = 0.02), but not in the normoalbuminuria group (19.6 vs. 17.8%; P = 0.86) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Treatment with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6541">losartan</z:chebi> may preserve some features of kidney structure in American Indians with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>