<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Basilar occlusions treated with conventional therapy (<z:chebi fb="2" ids="50249">anticoagulants</z:chebi> or antiplatelets) have a poor outcome (80p. cent mortality) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This unfavorable outcome may require a treatment within 6 hours by intra-arterial thrombolysis, sometimes followed by percutaneous transluminal angioplasty (<z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp>) in case of atherothrombotic occlusion due to a tight atherosclerotic stenosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A 48 year-old patient, presented with left <z:hpo ids='HP_0001269'>hemiparesis</z:hpo>, left multimodal <z:hpo ids='HP_0003474'>hypoesthesia</z:hpo>, paralytic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001260'>dysarthria</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>CT-scan showed a spontaneous hyperdensity of the basilar artery and arterial occclusion was confirmed by angiography, which showed an atherothrombotic occlusion involving the proximal part of the vessel </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Intra-arterial thrombolysis began five hours after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> with 0,25mg/kg of Rt-Pa (Actilyse((R))), given by bolus followed by 4 others bolus of 10mg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After a total dose of 60mg, arterial recanalization was obtained showing a tight atherosclerotic stenosis involving the proximal part of the basilar artery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp> was performed 18 hours later with a ballon inflation at 6 atmospheres during 20 seconds </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>It allowed to decrease the stenosis from 80p. cent to 60p. cent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The patient recovered and MRI at D20 showed a small right lateral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> involving the pons </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Our study confirms the usefulness of intra-arterial thrombolysis in basilar <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Consecutive <z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp> may be proposed in case of associated atherosclerotic stenosis, and the interest of <z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp> is further discussed </plain></SENT>
</text></document>