<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Multiple case series, mostly highly selected, have demonstrated a very high mortality following <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> basilar <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The more widespread availability and use of non-invasive vascular imaging over recent years has increased the rate of ABAO diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To estimate the proportion of diagnosed ABAO among <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> in an era of increasing use of non-invasive vascular imaging and to compare the characteristics and outcomes between these two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We compared 27 consecutive cases of ABAO identified in a university hospital between 2003 and 2007 with 311 unselected cases of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> from two 4 month surveys </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: ABAO diagnosis increased from 0.3% of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> (2003-2004) to 1.1% (2007), reflecting the increased use of non-invasive vascular imaging </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In comparison to <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo>, ABAO patients were younger (mean age 60 vs. 71 years), were more likely to be male (89% vs. 60%), had less <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (7% vs. 26%), more severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>strokes</z:hpo> (baseline NIHSS over 20: 52% vs. 12%), higher admission white cell count (12,000 vs. 9000 cells/ mm3), lower admission systolic blood pressure (140 +/- 24 vs. 153 +/- 27 mmHg), higher in-hospital mortality rates (30% vs. 8%) and worse functional outcome (modified Rankin scale &lt; or = 3, 22% vs. 56%) (P&lt; 0.05 for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Rates of reperfusion therapy for ABAO increased from 0 in 2003-2004 to 60% in 2007 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In this study, ABAO patients represented approximately 1% of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> and were about a decade younger than patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We report a lower ABAO mortality compared to previous more selected case series; however, most survivors had a poor functional outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Given the marked clinical <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo> of ABAO, a low threshold for non-invasive vascular imaging with a view to definitive reperfusion treatment is needed </plain></SENT>
</text></document>