<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Because extracranial atheromatous disease of the carotid arterial system is a common cause of '<z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>', ophthalmologists may be the first to see patients at risk who present with early signs of this condition </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>I </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The history of previous observations of these signs and the <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>anatomy</z:mp> and <z:mp ids='MP_0001532'>physiology</z:mp> of the structures involved are described </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The physical and subjective signs and the significance of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007787" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="tia|TIA|T.I.A.">transient ischaemic attacks</z:e> are discussed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Methods of diagnosis are reviewed with special reference to ophthalmodynamometry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>II </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A series of patients personally investigated and treated is analysed: (1)Endarterectomy was performed in seventy cases of internal carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006135'>artery stenosis</z:mp> during a 15-year period (1959-73) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>(2) 36 cases from the years 1970-73 were studied in detail </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>(3) 50 per cent. of these presented with ocular symptoms, which were the only complaint in 22 per cent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>(4) 95 per cent. of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients with ocular symptoms experienced recurrent transient <z:hpo ids='HP_0000572'>visual loss</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>(5) 61 per cent. of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients with ocular symptoms showed significant fundus changes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>(6) ODM enabled the haemodynamics of the carotid arterial systems to be evaluated in 79 per cent. of the patients studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>(7) The results of surgery suggest that patients who present with ocular symptoms have a better prognosis than those who present with neurological symptoms only </plain></SENT>
</text></document>