<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AT-1362 was found to be a potent, selective, and competitive inhibitor of thrombin, with a Ki value of 6.7 nM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In a rat model of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo> induced by partial stasis and endothelial disruption, the ID(50) values (a dose required to obtain 50% inhibition of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> formation over each vehicle group) of AT-1362 and argatroban were 0.03 mg/kg i.v. plus 0.5 microg/kg/minute and 0 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>13 mg/kg i.v. plus 8.7 microg/kg/minute, respectively, and the antithrombotic effect of AT-1362 without prolongation of <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp> time lasted for 2 hours and disappeared 4 hours after oral administration of 30 mg/kg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the rat tail transection model, the BT(2) values (a dose causing two-fold prolongation of the <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp> time over each vehicle group) of AT-1362 and argatroban were 0.56 mg/kg i.v. plus 9.3 microg/kg/minute and 1.1 mg/kg i.v. plus 73.3 microg/kg/minute, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The reduction of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> formation and the prolongation of <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp> time were correlated with an ex vivo activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT) for both drugs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>AT-1362 at 0.3 mg/kg i.v. plus 5 microg/kg/minute and argatroban at 0.6 mg/kg i.v. plus 40 microg/kg/minute significantly (p&lt;0.05 and p&lt;0.01, respectively) improved the vessel patency in a FeCl(2)-induced carotid artery <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> model in rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These results suggest that AT-1362 may be a potent antithrombotic agent for the treatment of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">thrombotic diseases</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>