<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Increasing use of transgenic and gene targeting techniques for the investigation of hemostasis and vascular biology has generated interest in experimental models of carotid artery <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> in mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: We tested the hypothesis that <z:hpo ids='HP_0002791'>hypoventilation</z:hpo> in anesthetized mice may cause <z:mp ids='MP_0002318'>hypercapnia</z:mp>, increased carotid artery blood flow, and altered thrombotic responses to photochemical injury of the carotid artery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Arterial blood gases and carotid artery blood flow were measured in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="7983">pentobarbital</z:chebi>-anesthetized BALB/c or C57BL/6 J mice with and without mechanical ventilation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Photochemical injury of the carotid artery was induced using the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52261">rose bengal</z:chebi> method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Compared with ventilated mice, unventilated mice had a 45% increase in carotid artery blood flow (0.74 +/- 0.04 vs. 0.41 +/- 0.03 mL min-1; P &lt; 0.001) that was associated with an elevation of arterial PCO2 (58 +/- 4 vs. 33 +/- 4 mmHg; P &lt; 0.05) and a decrease in arterial pH (7.18 +/- 0.05 vs. 7.32 +/- 0.03; P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Time to first occlusion of the carotid artery after photochemical injury was shorter in ventilated than in unventilated mice (29 +/- 6 vs. 73 +/- 9 min; P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Time to stable occlusion was also shorter in ventilated mice (49 +/- 8 vs. 81 +/- 6 min; P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Elevated carotid artery blood flow, hypercarbic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001941'>acidosis</z:hpo>, and prolonged occlusion times also were observed in mice ventilated with supplemental carbon dioxide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: General anesthesia without mechanical ventilation has the potential to confound studies of experimental <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> in vivo by producing <z:hpo ids='HP_0002791'>hypoventilation</z:hpo>, <z:mp ids='MP_0002318'>hypercapnia</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001941'>acidosis</z:hpo>, and altered carotid artery blood flow </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Mechanical ventilation with maintenance of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> blood gases may enhance the physiological insight gained from experimental models of carotid artery <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> in mice </plain></SENT>
</text></document>