<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Apixaban is an oral, direct and highly selective factor Xa (FXa) inhibitor in late-stage clinical development for the prevention and treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001907'>thromboembolic diseases</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: We evaluated the in vitro properties of apixaban and its in vivo activities in rabbit models of <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> and hemostasis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Studies were conducted in arteriovenous-shunt <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> (AVST), <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo> (VT), electrically mediated carotid <z:hpo ids='HP_0004420'>arterial thrombosis</z:hpo> (ECAT) and cuticle <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp> time (BT) models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In vitro, apixaban is potent and selective, with a K(i) of 0.08 nm for human FXa </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>It exhibited species difference in FXa inhibition [FXa K(i) (nm): 0.16, rabbit; 1.3, rat; 1.7, dog] and anticoagulation [EC(2x) (microm, concentration required to double the prothrombin time): 3.6, human; 2.3, rabbit; 7.9, rat; 6.7, dog] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Apixaban at 10 microm did not alter human and rabbit platelet aggregation to <z:chebi fb="13" ids="16761">ADP</z:chebi>, gamma-thrombin, and collagen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In vivo, the values for antithrombotic ED(50) (dose that reduced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> weight or increased blood flow by 50% of the control) in AVST, VT and ECAT and the values for BT ED(3x) (dose that increased BT by 3-fold) were 0.27 +/- 0.03, 0.11 +/- 0.03, 0.07 +/- 0.02 and &gt; 3 mg kg(-1) h(-1) i.v. for apixaban, 0.05 +/- 0.01, 0.05 +/- 0.01, 0.27 +/- 0.08 and &gt; 3 mg kg(-1) h(-1) i.v. for the indirect FXa inhibitor fondaparinux, and 0.53 +/- 0.04, 0.27 +/- 0.01, 0.08 +/- 0.01 and 0.70 +/- 0.07 mg kg(-1) day(-1) p.o. for the oral <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50249">anticoagulant</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="8" ids="10033">warfarin</z:chebi>, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In summary, apixaban was effective in the prevention of experimental <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> at doses that preserve hemostasis in rabbits </plain></SENT>
</text></document>