<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Although the vascular pathology of carotid arteries is widespread, the function of salivary glands in reduced arterial flow conditions is not much investigated clinically and in experiments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>At the same time blood supply is a keystone to <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> functioning of every organ and especially of salivary secretion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to estimate functional activity of salivary glands in reduced and restored blood supply conditions in experiment by sialoscintigraphy which is an approved method for functional assessment of salivary glands </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The ligature of a. carotis communis dextra was performed on 20 Californian rabbits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After 28 days sialoscintigraphy with Tc99 pertechnetate and revascularization through resection of the occluded part of a. carotis communis and reconstruction with venous autograft was performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>One month later sialoscintigraphy was done </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The functional activity of rabbit salivary glands after the ligature of a. carotis communis is strongly depressed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The revascularized glands accumulated isotope slowly, but the level of accumulation was higher than on the control side </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The ligature and reconstruction of a common carotid artery on rabbits confirm the important role of the arterial blood supply in functional activity of salivary glands and may be an appropriate experimental model for investigation of ischemic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0036093" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">disease of salivary glands</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>