<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>To determine the incidence and extent of distal embolization during percutaneous transluminal balloon angioplasty (<z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp>) and rotational thrombectomy (PRT), we collected, filtered, and weighed the distal effluent of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> thrombotically occluded canine arteries following mechanical thrombolysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>PRT (n = 11) and <z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp> (n = 10) were equally effective in recanalizing occluded vessels (91% vs. 90%) and reduced percent diameter stenosis to a similar degree (97 +/- 6% to 8 +/- 11% and 100 +/- 0% to 17 +/- 23%, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Distal embolization following mechanical intervention was observed in 10 of 10 and 8 of 9 arteries recanalized with PRT and <z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp>, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The mean weights of collected emboli were similar between the two groups (18 +/- 24 mg vs. 37 +/- 79 mg, PRT vs. <z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp>, P = NS), although the range of size and weight of thromboemboli was larger in the <z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp> group (0-206 mg vs. 2-51 mg, PRT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Angiographically defined residual <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> was significantly less frequent in arteries recanalized with PRT as compared with <z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp> (10% vs. 55%, P = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In summary, PRT and <z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp> are equally effective in recanalizing acutely occluded canine arteries and result in similar reductions in percent diameter stenosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Each intervention results in distal embolization of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">thrombi</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>PRT is associated with a reduced incidence of angiographically evident residual <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> at the site of arterial injury and may avoid embolization of large fragments occasionally produced by <z:mp ids='MP_0002633'>PTA</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Thus PRT may serve as a useful alternative to coronary angioplasty during <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>