<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>From March 1980 to July 1988 a consecutive series of 256 patients (p.) underwent 301 carotid endarterectomy + patch with routine use of continuous intraoperative EEG monitoring and selective use of an intraluminal shunt (IS) for the presence of an atherosclerotic plaque concerning the internal carotid artery (ICA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Patients were divided in two groups: the first (42 p.) marked by contralateral ICA occlusion, the second (214 p.) without contralateral ICA occlusion (259 CEA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Immediate peroperative, long term and global (immediate and long term) outcomes were prospectively and comparatively studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A temporary IS was inserted in 27 p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>(64%) of the group I and in 38 p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>(14%) of the group II </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Immediate permanent postoperative neurological deficit occurred in 1 p. of group I (2.38%) and in 2 p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>(0.9%) in group II </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Immediate postoperative mortality was 0% and 0.9% in group I and II respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> p. had neurological valuation and Echo-Doppler of operated ICA and of the contralateral ICA every 6 months (middle follow-up 44 months) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>New neurological symptoms compared in 5.8% of p. of group I and in 5.23% of p. of group II with a <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> rate of 0% and 2.32% respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>There were 2 restenosis of operated ICA, both of them in p. of group I, that underwent reoperation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In the two groups the principal causes of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> were myocardial <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>; in the group I no <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> was due to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> versus 1.86% in the group II </plain></SENT>
</text></document>