<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Among 2923 severely injured patients in the period 1980-1988, 17 had injuries or large supraaortic arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The incidence was 0.58%, with an overall mortality of 53% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In 75% of survivors there was a persistent neurological deficit </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We treated 5 penetrating (A. carotis 4, A. vertebralis 1) and 12 nonpenetrating (A. carotis 11, A. vertebralis 1) injuries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> penetrating carotid injuries (4) repair was performed on admission and mortality was 50%; 1 of 2 survivors has postoperative <z:hpo ids='HP_0001269'>hemiparesis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Localization of nonpenetrating carotid injuries (11) was intrathoracic (2), in the neck (7) and intracranial (2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Main complication of nonpenetrating extracranial carotid injuries is neurological deficit (7/9) due to <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> (3) or stenosis (4) with embolism (2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Surgery was performed in 3 cases comprising pseudoaneurysm in 2 and concomitant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0003496" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">aortic rupture</z:e> in 1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Mortality was 44%, and 80% of survivors had persistent neurological deficits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Extracranial carotid injuries (n = 13) carried a mortality rate of 83% in occluded and 29% in nonoccluded vessels (p less than 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Location of carotid injury in the neck (n = 11) carried a mortality of 55%, and intracranial (n = 2) of 100% respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Duplex-Doppler scanning of carotid arteries is a safe, noninvasive method which is essential in blunt carotid artery trauma </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Prognosis is dependent upon the size of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Once neurologic deficit has been established for more than 24 hours, reconstruction of the artery should be postponed and performed only for complications (pseudoaneurysm or embolization) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Clamping of arteries without hypothermic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0444720" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">circulatory arrest</z:e> or shunt should be avoided </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>The danger of rupture in dissection and pseudoaneurysm is slight.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>