<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The effects of a thrombin active-site inhibitor on arterial and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo>, and thrombin-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>thrombocytopenia</z:hpo> were determined in anesthetized rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Desamino<z:chebi fb="0" ids="29996"> D-Phe</z:chebi>-Pro-Arg-<z:chebi fb="1" ids="17478">aldehyde</z:chebi> (BMY 44621) was administered before experimental intervention as a loading i.v. dose plus continuous i.v. infusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Carotid artery <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> was produced by transmural vessel injury and vena cava <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> was produced by partial stasis of blood flow combined with endothelial injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>Thrombocytopenia</z:hpo> was induced by an i.v. injection of human alpha-thrombin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>BMY 44621 inhibited arterial and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo> in a dose-dependent manner </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Its threshold antithrombotic dose for <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo> was half of that for <z:hpo ids='HP_0004420'>arterial thrombosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Maximum reductions in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> weight were greater for venous (&gt; 90%) compared to arterial (57%) <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> and correlated with 2-and 9-fold prolongation of ex vivo thrombin clotting time, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A 40% reduction in platelet counts induced by thrombin injection was abolished by the threshold dose of BMY 44621 for inhibiting <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>These experiments demonstrate that thrombin's active-site is an effective target for inhibiting venous and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004420'>arterial thrombosis</z:hpo>, although <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo> is more sensitive to this therapeutic strategy than <z:hpo ids='HP_0004420'>arterial thrombosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>