<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The antithrombotic and <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp> time (BT)-prolonging effects of TAK-029, a novel <z:chebi fb="2" ids="17089">glycoprotein</z:chebi> IIb/IIIa <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, were characterized and compared with those of conventional antithrombotic agents in guinea pigs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>TAK-029 potently inhibited the binding of fibrinogen and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042974" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">von Willebrand</z:e> factor to purified human GPIIb/IIIa with IC50 values of 0.67 +/- 0.03 and 0.33 +/- 0.04 nM; it also inhibited human platelet aggregation induced by various aggregating agents with IC50 values of 29 to 38 nM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The in vitro antiplatelet effect of TAK-029 was potent in humans, guinea pigs and monkeys </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>When TAK-029 was given p.o. to guinea pigs, severe prolonging of BT (&gt;1800 sec) was not observed with plasma concentrations of TAK-029 that inhibited ex vivo platelet aggregation by &lt; 100% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The p.o. administration of TAK-029, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9588">ticlopidine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37941">clopidogrel</z:chebi> prolonged BT to the same extent, in parallel with their inhibition of ex vivo platelet aggregation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>TAK-029 inhibited ex vivo platelet <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0001511" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">adhesion</z:e> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> formation in an arteriovenous shunt model more strongly than <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9588">ticlopidine</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37941">clopidogrel</z:chebi> and aspirin at doses causing similar prolongations of BT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In a balloon catheter-induced carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> model, i.v. administration of TAK-029 significantly inhibited <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> formation without prolonging BT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At doses that caused an incomplete antithrombotic effect, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15544">PGE1</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="40585">alpha-cyclodextrin</z:chebi> and argatroban produced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002615'>hypotension</z:hpo> and prolongation of BT, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>TAK-029 may be effective in patients suffering from arterial <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">thrombotic diseases</z:e>, which are refractory to these conventional antithrombotic agents </plain></SENT>
</text></document>