<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The efficacy of a postoperative treatment with Low molecular weight <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> (LMWH) vs <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9588">Ticlopidine</z:chebi> in controlling early <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp>, intimal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_134'>hyperplasia</z:mpath> and growth of true endothelial cells in small prosthetic expanded <z:chebi fb="3" ids="53251">polytetrafluoroethylene</z:chebi> (ePTFE) grafts (4 mm) interposed in the carotid artery of sheep has been evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>EXPERIMENTAL DESIGN: Thirty animals were randomized into three different groups: control group (CTRL); <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9589">ticlopidine hydrochloride</z:chebi> (TICL) 250 mg/b.d. by month for 4 weeks from day 1; LMWH 3,085 IU AXa s.c. preoperatively and once a day for the same period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Complete <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> of the graft occurred in 7 sheep in the CTRL group and 5 in the TICL group while 2 partial <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> were observed in the LMWH group (n.s.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> the evaluable cases, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_134'>hyperplasia</z:mpath> was observed in both anastomotic areas and did not involve the middle portion of the graft </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The mean +/- SD intimal thickness was 603 +/- 20 micron in the CTRL group, 356 +/- 10 in the TICL group and 152 +/- 17 in the LMWH group (p &lt; 0.001) compared to the 60 +/- 12 of the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> intima </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>True endothlial cells were found mainly in the LMWH group close to the arterial anastomosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The postoperative use of LMWH seems to inhibit intimal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_134'>hyperplasia</z:mpath>, with interesting results also on patency and cellular coverage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Further studies are necessary to support this promising trend </plain></SENT>
</text></document>