<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>Subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> is often accompanied by systemic complications and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Elevated levels of circulating <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33567">catecholamines</z:chebi> may be involved in the pathophysiology behind these events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The alpha-2-<z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="4" ids="46631">clonidine</z:chebi> inhibits sympathetic outflow by a central mechanism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Unrestricted sympathoexcitation may be detrimental and administration of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="46631">clonidine</z:chebi> may be beneficial in these patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Using isotope dilution methodology, <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> kinetic determinations, comprising determination of arterial <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> concentration and rates of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> spillover to and removal, or clearance, from plasma, were performed on three occasions during the first week after <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> in 25 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Eleven of these patients received <z:chebi fb="4" ids="46631">clonidine</z:chebi> (continuous i.v. infusion 5.8 +/- 0.7 microg x kg(-1) x 24 h(-1)) and the remainder, standard therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Initial results were compared with 17 healthy age-matched subjects and eight patients suffering from severe traumatic brain injury without traumatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>Subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> patients exhibited markedly elevated arterial plasma <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> concentrations [3.74 +/- 0.48, P &lt; 0.001 vs. healthy subjects (1.59 +/- 0.11 nmol/L) and P &lt; 0.05 vs. head trauma patients (1.94 +/- 0.29 nmol/L)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The rate of clearance of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> from plasma in the subarachnoid patients was also significantly greater than that observed in the healthy subjects (2.66 +/- 0.15 vs. 2.14 +/- 0.15 L/min, P &lt; 0.05) and the head trauma patients (2.00 +/- 0.12 L/min, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Compared with both control groups, on admission the rate of spillover of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> to plasma following <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> was markedly elevated (9.11 +/- 1.12, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="4" ids="46631">Clonidine</z:chebi> treatment (continuous i.v. infusion 5.8 +/- 0.7 microg x kg(-1) x 24 h(-1)) did not reduce the increased rate of spillover of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> to plasma following <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Sympathetic <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> activity is markedly elevated following subarachnoid <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="4" ids="46631">Clonidine</z:chebi> had no effect on the rate of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> spillover to, or clearance from, plasma in these patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Clearly, further studies are required to elucidate the mechanisms responsible for generating sympathetic <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> activation following <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>