<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Cilostazol, an inhibitor of phosphodiesterase (PDE) type 3, is used clinically in peripheral artery disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>PDE3 inhibitors may be clinically useful in the treatment of delayed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> after <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The authors present the first results on the effect of cilostazol on cerebral hemodynamics in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> participants </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In this double-blind, randomized, crossover study, 200 mg cilostazol or placebo was administered orally to 12 healthy participants </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Cerebral blood flow was measured using 133Xe inhalation and single <z:chebi fb="23" ids="30212">photon</z:chebi> emission computerized tomography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mean flow velocity in the middle cerebral arteries (VMCA) was measured with transcranial Doppler, and the superficial temporal and radial arteries diameters were measured with ultrasonography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>During the 4-hour observation period, there was no effect on systolic blood pressure (P = 0.28), but diastolic blood pressure decreased slightly compared with placebo (P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>VMCA decreased 21.5 +/- 5.7% after cilostazol and 5.5 +/- 12.2% after placebo (P = 0.02, vs. placebo), without any change in global or regional cerebral blood flow </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The superficial temporal artery diameter increased 17.6 +/- 12.3% (P &lt; 0.001 vs. baseline) and radial artery diameter increased 12.6 +/- 8.6% (P &lt; 0.001 vs. baseline) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Adverse events, especially <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo>, were common </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The findings suggest that cilostazol is an interesting candidate for future clinical trials of delayed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>