<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To review the management and some of the recent advances in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> haemorrhagic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>DATA SOURCES: Articles and published reviews on <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> haemorrhagic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>SUMMARY OF REVIEW: Hypertensive intracerebral haemorrhage or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid haemorrhage</z:hpo> (SAH) from a ruptured intracranial saccular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysm</z:hpo> are the commonest causes for an <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> haemorrhagic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Both lesions are often clinically characterised by a sudden severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002013'>vomiting</z:hpo> with the remaining neurological features dependent on the site of the lesion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The diagnosis requires an urgent non-contrast cerebral computed tomography (CT) scan and a lumbar puncture if the CT scan fails to demonstrate intracranial blood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Treatment of both intracerebral haemorrhage and SAH includes resuscitation (e.g. cardiovascular and respiratory support) and preventative therapy (e.g. maintaining hydration and nutrition, and preventing <z:hpo ids='HP_0002835'>aspiration</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0011127" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pressure sores</z:e>, etc) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Further management of an intracerebral haemorrhage by removing the clot is only beneficial if it is near the surface (although stereotactic catheter insertion and infusion of thrombolytics have been used with variable success with deeper haematomata) and if there are signs of intracerebral shift or compression of vital structures (e.g. cerebellar haematoma) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Management of SAH still requires nimodipine and early angiography with surgery to reduce the incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> and rebleeding, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>While intravascular techniques using the Guglielmi detachable coil have improved the outcome in surgically inaccessible (and accessible) <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysms</z:hpo>, management of resistant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> using 'triple H' therapy (i.e. <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0546817" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypervolaemia</z:e> and haemodilution), intraarterial papaverine, angioplasty, and intrathecal tPA, have not been uniformly successful </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> haemorrhagic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> requires an urgent non-contrast cerebral CT scan for diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Treatment of an intracerebral haematoma requires evacuation of the clot if accessible and if it is causing an intracerebral shift or compression of vital structures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Nimodipine and urgent surgery to reduce the incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> and rebleeding, respectively, are standard for the management of a patient with a SAH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>While recent advances in intravascular techniques using the Guglielmi detachable coil hold promise, successful management of resistant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> remains elusive </plain></SENT>
</text></document>