<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The sphingosylphosphorylcholine-Rho-kinase pathway plays an important role in Ca(2+) sensitization of vascular smooth muscle contraction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Eicosapentaenoic acid (<z:chebi fb="113" ids="28364">EPA</z:chebi>) inhibits sphingosylphosphorylcholine -Rho-kinase-activated Ca(2+)-sensitization in vitro and in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> (SAH) models in vivo and has also been shown to inhibit the occurrence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of SAH in a prospective, nonrandomized study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The current prospective, multicenter, randomized study was performed to confirm the preventive effects of <z:chebi fb="113" ids="28364">EPA</z:chebi> on <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> in patients with SAH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The trial population comprised 162 patients who underwent surgical clipping within 72 hours of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of SAH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Of these patients, 81 received 2700 mg/day <z:chebi fb="113" ids="28364">EPA</z:chebi> from the day after surgery until day 30 (<z:chebi fb="113" ids="28364">EPA</z:chebi> group), and 81 did not receive <z:chebi fb="113" ids="28364">EPA</z:chebi> (control group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The primary end point was the occurrence of symptomatic vasospasm (SV) or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> caused by <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> (CIV) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The occurrences of SV (15% vs. 30%, P = 0.022) and CIV (7% vs. 21%; P = 0.012) were lower in the <z:chebi fb="113" ids="28364">EPA</z:chebi> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis revealed an adjusted odds ratio of 0.39 (95% confidence interval, 0.17-0.89; P = 0.028) for SV inhibition by <z:chebi fb="113" ids="28364">EPA</z:chebi> and 0.27 (95% confidence interval, 0.09-0.72; P = 0.012) for CIV inhibition </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: These results indicate that oral <z:chebi fb="113" ids="28364">EPA</z:chebi> reduces the frequency of SV and CIV after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of aneurysmal SAH </plain></SENT>
</text></document>