<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to evaluate the effect of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0032914" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="PEE|PREG1|PEE1">preeclampsia</z:e> and its severity on maternal mean middle cerebral artery blood flow velocity (mean <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>-CBFV) using transcranial doppler sonography (TCD), as well as the effect of <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> on mean <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>-CBFV in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0032914" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="PEE|PREG1|PEE1">preeclampsia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study used a prospective, comparative design </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>TCD was used to examine maternal mean <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>-CBFV in both healthy subjects (controls) and preeclamptic subjects (cases) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The two groups were similar in age, gestational age, and parity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Healthy subjects were categorized into three groups: Group I, 6-14 weeks, n = 10; Group II, 24-40 weeks, n = 27; Group III, postpartum n = 15, 12-36 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Serial TCD examinations of the middle cerebral artery were completed in 21 preeclamptic subjects at four different points in time: Time I is an initial measurement before delivery; Time 2 is also before delivery but after <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> had been administered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Time 3 is postpartum while on <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> (12-24 h), Time 4 is postpartum off <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi>, (24-48 h) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Preeclamptic subjects had significantly increased mean <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>-CBFV when compared to healthy subjects: antepartum (mean 78.2 vs. 55.1 cm/sec, P &lt; 0.0005); postpartum (mean 101.3 vs. 69.8 cm/sec, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Severe preeclamptics had significantly higher mean <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>-CBFV than mild preeclamptics at each point in time: Time 1: P &lt; 0.016; Time 2: P &lt; 0.040; Time 3: P &lt; 0.002; and Time 4: P &lt; 0.028 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These data support the theory that <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> of the smaller diameter vessels is a major component of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0032914" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="PEE|PREG1|PEE1">preeclampsia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>