<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi> synthesis inhibitor, dactinomycin, intended to suppress induction of vasoconstrictor <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> endothelin, prevented <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> almost completely in the dog <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> (<z:chebi fb="75" ids="15414">SAM</z:chebi>) model [8] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Since <z:chebi fb="0" ids="51451">endothelin receptor antagonists</z:chebi> have not shown so potent effect as dactinomycin in animal SAH models, we aimed clinical use of dactinomycin for improvement of final outcomes of severe SAH patients now suffering vasospasm </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Before clinical application, we examined therapeutic dose and timing of administration of dactinomycin in animal models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the dog two-<z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp> model, dactinomycin treatment (0.01 mg/kg i.v. for 5 days) started at 6 hours after the second blood injection on Day 2 prevented vasospasm, but that started on Day 3 did not </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Low dose of dactinomycin (0.003 mg/kg i.v. for 5 days) rather aggravated vasospasm even though the treatment started on Day 0 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In the rat vasospasm model, high dose of dactinomycin (0.03 mg/kg i.p. for 3 days) or relatively low dose of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28748">doxorubicin</z:chebi> (0.6 mg/kg i.p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>once) prevented vasospasm even though the treatment started on Day 4 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The present study suggests that <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi> synthesis inhibitors, such as dactinomycin and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28748">doxorubicin</z:chebi>, may aufficiently prevent or ameliorate <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265110" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral vasospasm</z:e> in severe SAH patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>