<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: To investigate whether nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> (NO) contributes to formation of abnormal collateral circulation in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) samples were obtained from the subarachnoid space of the Sylvian fissure during combined bypass surgery for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya disease</z:e> and kept frozen until NO metabolites, nitrate and <z:chebi fb="95" ids="16301">nitrite</z:chebi>, were measured using a Griess method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Compared with control CSF obtained from 18 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0010828'>hemifacial spasm</z:hpo>, unruptured <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysm</z:hpo>, etc., concentrations of NO metabolites in 26 CSF samples of 18 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya disease</z:e> were significantly higher (mean +/- SE; 17.6 +/- 1.2 vs. 10.5 +/- 1.0 microM, p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In eight patients, the CSF samples from both the first and second operation could be obtained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>NO metabolite concentrations (20.5 +/- 2.3 microM) in CSF obtained from the first surgery decreased to 15.7 +/- 1.8 microM (p &lt; 0.01) in CSF obtained from the second, contralateral procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The cases of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya disease</z:e> with greater development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya</z:e> vessels at angiographic stage 3 and 4 tended to show higher concentrations of NO metabolites than cases at earlier or later stages with a few <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya</z:e> vessels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>INTERPRETATION: Nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> concentrations in CSF are chronically elevated in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya disease</z:e>, probably reflecting development of abnormal collateral circulation. i.e. <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya</z:e> vessels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Vascular bypass surgery can reduce abnormal collateral circulation with reduced production of nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>