<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">Moyamoya disease</z:e> (MMD) is an uncommon cerebrovascular disorder, characterized by progressive occlusion at the terminal portion of the internal carotid artery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Incidence of the disease is high in East Asia and familial MMD accounts for about 15% of the disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Although the pathogenesis is unknown, association of HLA class I or II alleles with MMD has been reported with conflicting results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We investigated whether there is a difference in HLA class II association between familial and non-familial forms of the disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 70 Korean children with MMD, including 16 familial cases (10 probands), and 207 healthy controls were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Among familial cases, only 10 probands were used for the HLA frequency analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>High resolution HLA-DRB1 and DQB1 genotyping was performed using polymerase chain reaction (PCR)-sequence specific oligonucleotide hybridization and PCR-single strand conformation polymorphism methods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The phenotype frequencies of HLA-DRB1(*)1302 (70.0%) and DQB1(*)0609 (40.0%) were significantly increased in familial MMD compared to both controls [vs. 15.5%, corrected p (p(c)) = 0.008, odds ratio (OR) = 12.76; vs. 4.3%, p(c) = 0.02, OR = 14.67] and non-familial MMD patients (vs. 14.8%, p(c) = 0.02, OR = 13.42; vs. 1.9%, p(c) = 0.02, OR = 35.33) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The frequencies of DRB1 and DQB1 alleles in non-familial MMD patients were not significantly different from those in controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our findings suggest that the genetic polymorphism of HLA class II genes or other closely linked disease relevant gene(s) could be a genetic predisposing factor for familial MMD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>