<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: To obtain information on affected vessels in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya disease</z:e> (MMD), we analyzed the vascular morphological characteristics of MMD using three-dimensional (3D) constructive interference in steady-state (CISS) magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The population of this 3D-CISS MRI study consisted of 51 patients with MMD: 16 patients with atherosclerotic middle cerebral artery (<z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>) stenosis or occlusion, 42 MRI control patients, and 28 control digital subtraction angiography (DSA) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We measured the outer diameters of the terminal portion of the internal carotid artery (ICA) and the proximal portion of the <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> (M1 portion) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We evaluated the inner diameter as the relative value (%) obtained from magnified DSA images and analyzed these data </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The outer diameters of the ICA and M1 portions were significantly smaller in the MMD group than in the other two groups, while the M1 outer diameter of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> group was not significantly different compared to the control (ICA: MMD, 2.61 ± 0.46 mm vs. control, 4.04 ± 0.50 mm and M1: MMD, 1.92 ± 0.43 mm vs. control, 3.34 ± 0.54 mm vs. <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo>, 3.45 ± 0.56 mm) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, in MMD patients, the outer diameter was unrelated to the progression of the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="8069">luminal</z:chebi> stenosis grade estimated by DSA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This is the first report that the outer diameters of both the ICA and M1 decrease in MMD patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Our findings suggest that the vascular constrictive changes of the affected arteries are an important phenomenon reflecting MMD pathology </plain></SENT>
</text></document>