<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Ten patients, seven children and three adults, with "<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya</z:e>" disease were examined by <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e>-CT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MRI findings in these patients were compared with X-ray CT findings to study the features of the ischemic lesions in "<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya</z:e>" disease and the following results were obtained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Old cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002120'>cortical atrophy</z:hpo> and intracerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0008817'>hematoma</z:mp> in "<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya</z:e>" disease were better delineated by image of the spin echo method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>It is possible to differentiate the ischemic lesions such as ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo>, or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> by calculating the T1 and T2 value from the T1 and T2 image </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Ischemic lesions in "<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya</z:e>" disease most often occurred in the watershed area of the anterior cerebral artery-middle cerebral artery or the middle cerebral artery-posterior cerebral artery, and these ischemic lesions were classified into three types according to the location of the lesion, i.e. cortical ischemic, subcortical ischemic and combined type. "<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">Moyamoya</z:e>" disease in the advanced stage, which was often seen in children, showed the combined type with poor outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>From the above results, it might be concluded that MRI is superior to X-ray CT as a <z:chebi fb="6" ids="33295">diagnostic aid</z:chebi> to detect ischemic lesions in "<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya</z:e>" disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>