<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Adult identical twins with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">Moyamoya disease</z:e> are reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Laboratory examinations such as blood types, AB, Rh(+), HLA (human leucocytic antigen) analysis [AW26(9), A26(10), BW62(15), BW61(40), CW3], and finger prints, and hairs confirmed that two patients were identical twins </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Both had <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> serum immunoglobulin levels and no anti-DNA antibodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patient No. 1, a 39-year-old female, was admitted to our service with chief complaints of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002018'>nausea</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002013'>vomiting</z:hpo> and left <z:hpo ids='HP_0001269'>hemiparesis</z:hpo> with sudden <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> on Oct 31, 1981 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The patient had an episode of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002445'>tetraplegia</z:hpo> that occurred suddenly at 4 years of her age and lasted about a week </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Motor <z:mp ids='MP_0000746'>weakness</z:mp> had completely disappeared but <z:hpo ids='HP_0002342'>moderate mental retardation</z:hpo> remained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>She had been employed just prior to this attack </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CT and angiographic examinations revealed ventricular <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp> with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">Moyamoya disease</z:e>, which had miliary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysm</z:hpo> in the branch of the right posterior choroidal artery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The operation of encephalomyosynangiosis was performed on her left hemisphere </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The postoperative course was uneventful </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Patient No. 2, the twin sister of patient No. 1, was in good health and mental state until 19 years of her age, when she suddenly lost consciousness and developed <z:hpo ids='HP_0001269'>hemiparesis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>After this attack, her motor function had recovered well </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>However, mental ability gradually deteriorated and she was admitted to a psychiatric ward </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CT examination and angiographic studies were performed on Oct 12, 1982, and she was diagnosed as having <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">Moyamoya disease</z:e>.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>