<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We reported a rare case of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">Moyamoya disease</z:e> in the aged associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007780" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral embolism</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A 76-year-old female was brought into our hospital by ambulance 30 min after an attack of fainting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>She had no past history of cerebrovascular disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>On admission her consciousness level was JCS 3-IA and she showed Rt. <z:hpo ids='HP_0001269'>hemiparesis</z:hpo> ECG exhibited Af <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>No abnormal region was recognized on brain CT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Emergency cerebral angiograms (AG) disclosed that unexpectedly she had <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">Moyamoya disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Stenotic or occluded lesions were seen from bilateral IC terminal portions to <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> and ACA, and basal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026654" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MYMY|MYMY1">moyamoya</z:e> vessels were visualized </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Transdural anastomosis was poor and posterior circulation was the main source of collateral flow </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Mode of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> and neurological signs suggested that the cause of the attack was Lt </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion at its sphenoidal portion by cardiogenic embolism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Superselective endovascular fibrinolysis was carried out by the use of urokinase and low molecular weight <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52071">Dextran</z:chebi> and Lt </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> was able to be recanalized </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>She was recovered without neurological deficit </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Lt </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>STA-<z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> anastomosis and encephalo-myosynangiosis was performed in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> stage because stenosis had remained in Lt </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> and hypo-perfusion in bilateral frontal lobes was presented on SPECT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Post-operative AG demonstrated that Lt </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> was occluded but Lt. frontal lobe was supplied with plenty of blood flow from Lt </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>STA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="19" pm="."><plain>During the next day morning, she had another attack of fainting and showed moderate consciousness disturbance and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002427'>motor aphasia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="20" pm="."><plain>No abnormal change was noticed on brain CT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="21" pm="."><plain>Emergency AG revealed that Lt </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="22" pm="."><plain>STA had become stuffed up with embolic and bypass flow had disappeared </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="23" pm="."><plain>Superselective endovascular fibrinolysis was able to recanalize the blood flow imperfectly, but mild motor apasia remained due to Lt. frontal infarction </plain></SENT>
</text></document>