<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: The peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone represents the morphologic substrate for reentry <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> after <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo>, and its extent is a strong predictor of major cardiac events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Although delayed <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33375">gadolinium</z:chebi> enhancement magnetic resonance imaging (DGE-MRI) was shown to allow for detailed characterization of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> by quantifying <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> core zone and peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone volume, potentials of DGE-MRI for measuring changes in peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone volume are unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Therefore, we aimed to assess changes in volume of the peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone among patients with ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> treated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35620">vasodilator</z:chebi> therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: Core and peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone volumes as assessed with DGE-MRI were measured in 5 patients at baseline and after 6 months treatment with sustained-release <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4653">dipyridamole</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Core zone volume remained stable during follow-up [median (range), 19 mL (9 to 42) vs. 16 mL (11 to 46); P=0.785] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The ratio between the peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone and the core zone volume decreased significantly at 6 months compared with baseline [median (range), 0.22 (0.19 to 0.42) vs. 0.18 (0.09 to 0.32); P=0.043], and a trend toward reduction in peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone volume was found [median (range), 5 mL (2 to 8) vs. 3 mL (2 to 6); P=0.059] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone volume decreased in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> but 1 patient over the follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This initial experience suggests that reverse remodeling of the peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone with reduction in peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone volume may take place in patients with ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Quantification of this process may be feasible with DGE-MRI, but further studies are needed to confirm this hypothesis and to further clarify the role of DGE-MRI for the assessment of changes in peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> zone volume in patients with ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>