<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Previous studies have shown poor outcomes in pediatric heart transplant recipients with a high PRA or a positive direct donor-recipient cross-match </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study describes outcomes in patients with a positive cross-match at a large pediatric program </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Pediatric heart transplant patients at a large single center between January 1993 and July 2009 were reviewed; those with cross-match data were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Cross-match data were available in 242/262 (92.4%) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Indications for transplant were <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (58%), CHD (32%), and retransplant (7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>PRA was ≥10% in 31/213 (14.6%) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A retrospective cross-match was positive in 17/31 (55%) patients with PRA ≥10% and 0/182 with PRA &lt;10% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In positive cross-match patients, rejection frequency in the first year post-transplant was higher than negative cross-match patients (1.69 vs. 0.96 episodes/pt year, p = 0.014) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was no difference in rejection frequency after the first year post-transplant (0.18 vs. 0.12 episodes/pt year, p = 0.14) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Overall survival was not significantly different between the groups with a median follow-up time of 4.5 yr </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Heart transplantation in patients with a positive cross-match may result in good medium-term survival but a higher frequency of early rejection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Further investigation is warranted to define which patients with a positive cross-match will do poorly </plain></SENT>
</text></document>