<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>Heart failure</z:hpo> (HF) is a complex clinical syndrome and is thought to have a genetic basis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Numerous case-control studies have investigated the association between <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> and polymorphisms in candidate genes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Most studies focused on the angiotensin-converting enzyme insertion/deletion (ACE I/D) polymorphism, however, the results were inconsistent because of small studies and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneous</z:hpo> samples </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The objective was to assess the association between the ACE I/D polymorphism and HF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We performed a meta-analysis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> case-control studies that evaluated the association between ACE I/D polymorphism and HF in humans </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Studies were identified in the PUBMED and EMBASE databases, reviews, and reference lists of relevant articles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Two reviewers independently assessed the studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Seventeen case-control studies with a total of 5576 participants were included in the meta-analysis, including 2453 cases with HF and 3123 controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo> between studies was significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>No association was found under <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> the four genetic models (D vs. I, DD vs. ID and II, DD and ID vs. II, DD vs. ID) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Subgroup analyses for ischemic HF (IHF) and HF because of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001644'>dilated cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (DHF) also showed no significant association between ACE I/D polymorphism and HF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>No significant association between the ACE I/D polymorphism and risk of HF was found in this meta-analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The future studies should focus on large-scale prospective and case-control studies which designed to investigate gene-gene and gene-environment interactions to shed light on the genetics of HF </plain></SENT>
</text></document>