<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: In both <z:hpo ids='HP_0011665'>takotsubo cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (TC) and reperfused anterior <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e>), negative T waves commonly appear on the ECG in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011011'>subacute</z:hpo> phase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to clarify the ECG differences between these diseases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: We compared the ECGs with the greatest amplitude of negative T wave from 34 patients with TC and 237 patients with a first reperfused anterior <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e> who were admitted within 6 h of symptom <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> and who had no <z:mp ids='MP_0010515'>abnormal Q-waves</z:mp> on discharge ECG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Time from symptom <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> to recording the ECG did not differ between TC and anterior <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e> (2.4 ± 1.5 vs. 2.1 ± 2.0 days, P = 0.48) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>TC was associated with a greater maximal amplitude of negative T wave (1.00 ± 0.44 vs. 0.79 ± 0.46 mV, P = 0.044), and a greater number of leads with negative T waves (9.5 ± 1.0 vs. 6.0 ± 2.1, P&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Negative T waves were consistently observed in leads -aV(R) and V(4-6), whereas negative T waves were rare in lead V(1) in TC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Negative T waves in lead -aV(R) (ie, positive T waves in lead aV(R)) and no negative T waves in lead V(1) identified TC with 94% sensitivity and 95% specificity, representing the highest diagnostic accuracy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: During the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011011'>subacute</z:hpo> phase, deeper negative T waves were more frequently and broadly distributed, particularly around leads facing the apical region, in TC than in reperfused anterior <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>