<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Pawlak A, Gil RJ, Kulawik T, Pronicki M, Karkucińska-Więckowska A, Szymańska-Dębińska T, Gil K, Lagwinski N, Czarnowska E (Central Clinical Hospital of Ministry of Internal Affairs and Administration, Warsaw; Mossakowski Medical Research Centre, Academy of Science, Warsaw; The Children's Memorial Health Institute, Warsaw, Poland; and Community Medical Centers, Fresno, CA, USA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Type of desmin expression in cardiomyocytes - a good marker of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> development in idiopathic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001644'>dilated cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>J Intern Med 2012; 272: 287-297 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Aim.  The aim of this study was to determine whether remodelling of the desmin (DES) cytoskeleton affects myocardial function and whether it could be a useful marker of disease progression in patients with idiopathic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001644'>dilated cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0264793" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IDC">IDCM</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Material and methods.  Endomyocardial biopsy was performed in 195 IDCM patients, and five to six specimens were collected from the left ventricle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>DES expression was evaluated using tissue immunostaining and Western blotting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The study population was assigned to four groups according to DES expression type: I, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> DES staining at Z-lines giving a regular pattern of cross-striation (n = 57); IIA, increased DES staining with a regular pattern of cross-striation (n = 40); IIB, increased DES staining with an irregular pattern of cross-striation and/or the presence of aggregates (n = 56); and III, decreased/lack of DES staining (n = 42) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>Fibrosis</z:mp>, cardiomyocyte <z:mpath ids='MPATH_159'>hypertrophy</z:mpath> and ultrastructure were assessed for the four types of DES expression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Results.  The pathological types of DES expression (IIB or III) were associated with pathological changes in mitochondria and the contractile apparatus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Cardiomyocyte diameter and level of <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> were both significantly affected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>DES expression type correlated with NYHA class, left ventricular end-diastolic diameter, left ventricular ejection fraction and the level of N-terminal pro-brain natriuretic protein </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Conclusion.  The type of immunohistochemical DES expression correlated with the level of myocardial injury at the cellular and organ levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>This correlation was similar to that observed between DES expression and the well-established biochemical, echocardiographic and clinical parameters of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> (HF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>DES expression type could be used as an important diagnostic feature of HF development </plain></SENT>
</text></document>