<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>Oxidative stress</z:mp> contributes to the pathogenesis of many diseases, including <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>, but the role and regulation of oxidative DNA damage in many cases have not been studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Here, we set out to examine how oxidative DNA damage is regulated in cardiomyocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Compared to <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> healthy controls, human hearts in end-stage <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (EsCM) showed a high degree of DNA damage by histological evidence of damage markers, including <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52617">8-oxoG</z:chebi> and γH2AX (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="52617">8-oxoG</z:chebi>: 4.7±0.88 vs. 99.9±0.11%; γH2AX: 2.1±0.33 vs. 85.0±13.8%; P&lt;0.01) This raised the possibility that defective DNA repair may be partly responsible </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Indeed, nutrient deprivation led to impaired base-excision repair (BER) in cardiomyocytes in vitro, accompanied by loss of the BER enzyme OGG1, while BER activity was rescued by recombinant OGG1 (control vs. nutrient deprived vs. nutrient deprived+OGG1; 100±2.96 vs. 68.2±7.53 vs. 94.0±0.72%; ANOVA, P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Hearts from humans with EsCM and two murine models of myocardial stress also showed a loss of OGG1 protein </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>OGG1 loss was inhibited by the autophagy inhibitor bafilomycin and in autophagy-deficient Atg5(-/-) mouse embryonic fibroblasts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, pharmacological activation of autophagy, itself, did not induce OGG1 loss, suggesting that autophagy is necessary but not sufficient for OGG1 turnover, and OGG1 loss requires concurrent nutrient deprivation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Finally, we found that the role of autophagy in nutrient starvation is complex, since it balanced the positive effects of ROS inhibition against the negative effect of OGG1 loss </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Therefore, we have identified a central role for OGG1 in regulating DNA repair in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The manipulation of OGG1 may be used in future studies to examine the direct contribution of oxidative DNA damage to the progression of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>