<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Genetic diversity of Trypanosoma cruzi may play a role in pathogenesis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> forms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Natural populations are classified into 6 Discrete Typing Units (DTUs) Tc I-VI with taxonomical status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to identify T. cruzi DTUs in bloodstream and tissue samples of Argentinean patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>PCR-based strategies allowed DTU identification in 256 clinical samples from 239 Argentinean patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Tc V prevailed in blood from both asymptomatic and symptomatic cases and Tc I was more frequent in bloodstream, cardiac tissues and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0343801" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">chagoma</z:e> samples from immunosuppressed patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Tc II and VI were identified in a minority of cases, while Tc III and Tc IV were not detected in the studied population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, Tc I and Tc II/VI sequences were amplified from the same skin biopsy slice from a kidney transplant patient suffering <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> reactivation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Further data also revealed the occurrence of mixed DTU populations in the human <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, our findings provide evidence of the complexity of the dynamics of T. cruzi diversity in the natural history of human <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> and allege the pathogenic role of DTUs I, II, V and VI in the studied population </plain></SENT>
</text></document>