<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We sought to develop and validate a quantitative risk-prediction model for predicting the risk of posttransplant in-hospital mortality in pediatric heart transplantation (HT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Children &lt;18 years of age who underwent primary HT in the United States during 1999-2008 (n = 2707) were identified using Organ Procurement and Transplant Network data </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A risk-prediction model was developed using two-thirds of the cohort (random sample), internally validated in the remaining one-third, and independently validated in a cohort of 338 children transplanted during 2009-2010 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The best predictive model had four categorical variables: hemodynamic support (ECMO, ventilator support, VAD support vs. medical therapy), cardiac diagnosis (repaired <z:hpo ids='HP_0002564'>congenital heart disease</z:hpo> [CHD], unrepaired CHD vs. <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo>), <z:hpo ids='HP_0000082'>renal dysfunction</z:hpo> (severe, mild-moderate vs. <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath>) and total <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16990">bilirubin</z:chebi> (≥ 2.0, 0.6 to &lt;2.0 vs. &lt;0.6 mg/dL) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The C-statistic (0.78) and the Hosmer-Lemeshow goodness-of-fit (p = 0.89) in the model-development cohort were replicated in the internal validation and independent validation cohorts (C-statistic 0.75, 0.81 and the Hosmer-Lemeshow goodness-of-fit p = 0.49, 0.53, respectively) suggesting acceptable prediction for posttransplant in-hospital mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We conclude that this risk-prediction model using four factors at the time of transplant has good prediction characteristics for posttransplant in-hospital mortality in children and may be useful to guide decision-making around patient <z:mp ids='MP_0008913'>listing</z:mp> for transplant and timing of mechanical support </plain></SENT>
</text></document>