<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Copeptin, in addition to troponin, has recently been suggested for non-invasive differentiation between Tako-Tsubo <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (TTC) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In order to test this hypothesis, we investigated release patterns of pituitary copeptin and cardiac troponin in 49 patients with TTC and 49 age-, gender-, and ECG-matched control patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Elevated copeptin levels (i.e. &gt;12 pmol/l) at cardiac catheterization were found in 23/49 (47%) TTC patients and 25/49 (51%) <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Of these, median copeptin levels were almost identical in both cohorts (34.1 vs. 35.4 pmol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Subgroup analysis according to ECG changes revealed that <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e> patients with ST-segment elevation had 3.6-fold higher copeptin levels than <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e> patients without ST-segment elevation (p&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, in patients with TTC and atypical (midventricular) ballooning on left ventricular angiography, copeptin levels were 5.7-fold higher than in TTC patients with a typical (apical) type of ballooning (p&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Elevated troponin T levels (i.e. &gt;0.01 μg/l) at catheterization were detectable in 47/49 (96%) TTC patients and 45/49 (92%) <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e> patients; however, peak levels did not differ significantly between both cohorts (median 0.35 vs. 0.27 μg/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Subgroup analysis according to ECG changes revealed 2-fold higher peak troponin T levels in TTC patients presenting with ST-segment elevation than non-ST-segment elevation (p&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, copeptin does not seem to significantly increase non-invasive differentiation between TTC and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AMI</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>At present, coronary angiography, specifically in patients with ST-segment elevation at presentation remains absolutely mandatory </plain></SENT>
</text></document>