<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: The goal of this study was to define electrocardiographic (ECG) and echocardiographic characteristics of adolescent African athletes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Recent observations in African athletes reported large prevalence of left ventricular (LV) <z:mpath ids='MPATH_159'>hypertrophy</z:mpath> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>ECG abnormalities</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>No data, so far, exist for adolescent Africans, which comprise a growing proportion of competitive/professional athletes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The study included 154 soccer players participating at the 8th African Under-17 Championship of 2009, representing Algeria, Burkina Faso, Cameroon, Gambia, Guinea, Malawi, Nigeria, and Zimbabwe </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>For comparison, 62 Italian players with similar ages, sport achievements, and training schedules were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: African athletes showed higher R5/S1-wave voltages than Caucasian athletes (48.6 ± 12.1 mm vs. 34.1 ± 8.9 mm; p &lt; 0.01), larger prevalence of ECG LV <z:mpath ids='MPATH_159'>hypertrophy</z:mpath> (89% vs. 42%; p &lt; 0.001), ST-segment elevation (91% vs. 56%; p &lt; 0.001), and deeply inverted, or diffusely flat/biphasic, T waves (14% vs. 3% [p &lt; 0.05] and 25% vs. 8% [p &lt; 0.008], respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>LV wall thicknesses were increased in Africans by 5% compared with Caucasians, and exceeded <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> limits (≥13 mm) in 4 Africans but in no Caucasians </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No athlete showed evidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathies</z:hpo> (i.e., <z:hpo ids='HP_0001639'>hypertrophic cardiomyopathy</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011663'>arrhythmogenic right ventricular cardiomyopathy</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>On individual analysis, Algerians showed lower R/S-wave voltages compared with other African athletes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Increased wall thickness (≥13 mm) was observed only in sub-Saharian athletes (from Burkina Faso, Cameroon, and Niger) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: African athletes displayed large proportion of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>ECG abnormalities</z:hpo>, including a striking increase in R/S-wave voltage, ST-segment elevation, and deeply inverted or diffusely flat T waves by adolescence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>LV remodeling in African athletes was characterized by a disproportionate wall thickening than in Caucasians but similar cavity size </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Finally, distinctive peculiarities existed in African athletes according to the country (and ethnic) origin </plain></SENT>
</text></document>