<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: Late ventricular potentials (LPs) are considered to be useful for identifying patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> at risk of developing <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>(123)I-metaiodobenzylguanidine (MIBG) scintigraphy, which is used to evaluate cardiac sympathetic activity, has demonstrated cardiac sympathetic denervation in patients with malignant ventricular tachyarrhythmias </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study was undertaken to clarify the relationship between LPs and (123)I-MIBG scintigraphy findings in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001644'>dilated cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (<z:chebi fb="20" ids="15767">DCM</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 56 patients with <z:chebi fb="20" ids="15767">DCM</z:chebi> were divided into an LP-positive group (n = 24) and an LP-negative group (n = 32) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>During the compensated period, the delayed heart/mediastinum count (H/M) ratio, delayed total defect score (TDS), and washout rate (WR) were determined from (123)I-MIBG images and plasma brain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> (BNP) concentrations were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Left ventricular end-diastolic volume (LVEDV), left ventricular end-systolic volume (LVESV), and left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) were simultaneously determined by echocardiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: LVEDV, LVESV, LVEF and plasma BNP concentrations were similar in the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, TDS was significantly higher (35 ± 8 vs. 28 ± 6, p &lt; 0.005), the H/M ratio was significantly lower (1.57 ± 0.23 vs. 1.78 ± 0.20, p &lt; 0.005), and the WR was significantly higher (60 ± 14% vs. 46 ± 12%, p &lt; 0.001) in the LP-positive than in the LP-negative group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The average follow-up time was 4.5 years, and there were nine <z:hpo ids='HP_0001699'>sudden deaths</z:hpo> among the 56 patients (16.1%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In logistic regression analysis, the incidences of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001699'>sudden death</z:hpo> events were similar in those LP-negative with WR &lt;50%, LP-negative with WR ≥ 50% and LP-positive with WR &lt;50% (0%, 10.0% and 14.3%, respectively), but was significantly higher (41.2%) in those LP-positive with WR ≥ 50% (p &lt; 0.01, p &lt; 0.05, and p &lt; 0.05, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The present study demonstrated that the values of cardiac (123)I-MIBG scintigraphic parameters were worse in LP-positive <z:chebi fb="20" ids="15767">DCM</z:chebi> patients than in LP-negative <z:chebi fb="20" ids="15767">DCM</z:chebi> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, in LP-positive <z:chebi fb="20" ids="15767">DCM</z:chebi> patients with a high WR, the incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001699'>sudden death</z:hpo> events was higher than that in other subgroups of <z:chebi fb="20" ids="15767">DCM</z:chebi> patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>