<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES: Implantable cardioverter defibrillator (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>) therapy is recommended as the primary tool for prevention of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001645'>sudden cardiac death</z:hpo> (SCD) in symptomatic patients with severe left ventricular dysfunction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>There is a paucity of information on whether this recommendation is appropriate for the Korean population with severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>SUBJECTS AND METHODS: The study group consisted of 275 consecutive patients (mean age 65 years, 71% male) who met the <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> implantation criteria for primary prevention (left ventricular ejection fraction ≤30% and New York Heart Association functional class II or III) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We analyzed the clinical characteristics and outcomes of an ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (ICMP) group (n=131) and a non-ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (NICMP) group (n=144) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The outcomes of these 2 groups were compared with the Multicenter Automatic Defibrillator Implantation Trial II (MADIT-II) conventional and Defibrillators in the Non-ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>Cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> Treatment Evaluation (DEFINITE) standard therapy groups, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Eighty patients (29%) died during a follow-up period of 40±17 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The NICMP group had better <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause mortality rates than the ICMP group (19% vs. 40%, p&lt;0.001), however both groups had a similar incidence of SCD (7% vs. 10%, p=0.272) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The 2-year <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause mortality and SCD for the ICMP group were similar to those of the MADIT-II conventional therapy group (20% vs. 20%, 7% vs. 10%, respectively, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> p&gt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo>-cause mortality and the incidence of SCD in the NICMP group were comparable to those of the DEFINITE standard therapy group (13% vs. 17%, 6% vs. 6%, respectively, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> p&gt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Korean patients with severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> in both the ICMP and NICMP groups had <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-caused mortality and risk of SCD comparable to patients in the MADIT-II and DEFINITE standard therapy groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Therefore, the primary prevention criteria for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> implantation would be appropriate in both Korean ICMP and NICMP patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>