<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Impairment of diastolic function and late remodeling are concerns after left ventricular restoration (LVR) for ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study aims to evaluate the effects of combined surgery of myoblast sheets (MS) implantation and LVR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Rat <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> model was established 2 weeks after left anterior descending artery ligation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>They were divided into three groups: sham operation (n=15; group sham), LVR by plicating the infracted area (n=15; group LVR), and MS implantation with LVR (n=15; group LVR+MS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Serial echocardiographic study revealed significant LV redilatation and decrease of ejection fraction 4 weeks after LVR in group LVR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>MS implantation combined with LVR prevented those later deteriorations of LV function in group LVR+MS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Four weeks after the operation, a hemodynamic assessment using a pressure-volume loop showed significantly preserved diastolic function in group LVR+MS; end-diastolic pressure (LVR vs. LVR+MS: 9.0±6.6 mm Hg vs. 2.0±1.0 mm Hg, P&lt;0.05), end-diastolic pressure-volume relationship (LVR vs. LVR+MS 42±23 vs. 13±6, P&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Histological examination revealed <z:mp ids='MP_0005482'>cellular hypertrophy</z:mp> and LV <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> were significantly less and vascular density was significantly higher in group LVR+MS than in the other two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction demonstrated significantly suppressed expression of transforming growth factor-beta, Smad2, and reversion-inducing cysteine-rich protein with Kazal motifs in group LVR+MS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: MS implantation decreased <z:mp ids='MP_0003141'>cardiac fibrosis</z:mp> by suppressing the profibrotic gene expression and attenuated the impairment of diastolic function and the late remodeling after LVR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>It is suggesting that MS implantation may improve long-term outcome of LVR for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0151744" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IHD">ischemic heart disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>