<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Current guidelines for the primary prevention of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001645'>sudden cardiac death</z:hpo> have used a left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≤35% as a critical point to justify implantable cardioverter defibrillator (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>) implantation in post <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> patients and in those with nonischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001644'>dilated cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We compared mortality and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> activation rates among different <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> group recipients using a cut-off value for LVEF ≤35% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We followed up for a mean period of 41.1months 495 ICD recipients (442 males, 65.6years old, 68.9% post <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> patients, 422 with LVEF≤35%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Prevention was considered primary in patients who fulfilled guidelines criteria or had inducible <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> during programmed ventricular stimulation for patients with LVEF &gt;35% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Over the course of the trial, 84 of 495 patients died; 69 experienced cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> (6 sudden) and 15 non cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> recipients with LVEF ≤35% compared to those with preserved LVEF (mean LVEF=43%) had a greater incidence of total mortality (18% vs. 11%, log rank p=0.028) and cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> (15.4% vs. 5.5%, log rank p=0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There was no difference in the incidence for appropriate device therapy between patients with LVEF ≤35% and those with LVEF &gt;35% (56.9% vs. 65.8%, log rank p=0.93) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In the multivariate analysis the presence of advanced New York Heart Association stage predicted both total mortality (HR=2.69, 95% CI 1.771-4.086) and cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> (HR=3.437, 95% CI 2.163-5.463) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> therapy may protect <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> patients at early stages from arrhythmic morbidity and mortality, based on an electrophysiology-guided risk stratification approach </plain></SENT>
</text></document>