<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>HIV <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> remains highly prevalent among the estimated 33 million HIV-infected individuals worldwide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This is particularly true in developing countries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Potential mechanisms responsible for myocardial dysfunction following <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019693" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">HIV infection</z:e> include direct effects of HIV proteins </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We have previously reported that cardiac myocyte-specific expression of HIV-Tat (Tat) results in a murine <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We now report that Tat exhibits decreased myocardial ATP [<z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild type</z:mp> (WT) vs. Tat transgenic (TG), P &lt; 0.01] and myocyte GSH levels (WT vs. TG, P &lt; 0.01), decreased GSH/GSSG ratio (WT vs. TG, P &lt; 0.01), increased <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16240">H(2)O(2)</z:chebi> levels (WT vs. TG, P &lt; 0.05), and increased catalase (TG vs. WT, P &lt; 0.05) and GPX1 (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> peroxidase 1) activities (WT vs. TG, P &lt; 0.05), blunted cardiac myocyte positive inotropy (% peak shortening, WT vs. TG, P &lt; 0.01; +dl/dt, WT vs. TG, P &lt; 0.01) and negative inotropy (-dl/dt, WT vs. TG, P &lt; 0.01), and blunted inotropic responses to Ca(2+) (P &lt; 0.01, for each) and shortened anatomical and functional survival in vitro (P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The sulfhydryl donor, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28939">N-acetylcysteine</z:chebi> (NAC; 10(-4) M), completely reversed both the positive and negative inotropic defects in Tat; increased GSH (P &lt; 0.01) and GSH/GSSG (P &lt; 0.01); reversed <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16240">H(2)O(2)</z:chebi> level (P &lt; 0.05) and GPX1 activity (P &lt; 0.05); and normalized the blunted inotropic response to Ca(2+) (P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>NAC (10(-7)) M normalized duration of contractile function from &lt;40 min to &gt;120 min (P &lt; 0.01), with no effect on GSH and GSH/GSSG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>NAC (10(-4) M) reverses cardiac myocyte dysfunction and markers of <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>NAC (10(-7) M) enhances myocyte function independent of changes in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Elucidating the molecular mechanisms involved in the GSH-dependent and GSH-independent salutary effects of NAC should identify novel therapeutic targets for myocardial proteinopathies recently appreciated in human <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathies</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>