<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:chebi fb="19" ids="27568">Selenium</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="23354">coenzyme</z:chebi> Q10 are essential for the cell </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Low cardiac contents of <z:chebi fb="19" ids="27568">selenium</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="23354">coenzyme</z:chebi> Q10 have been shown in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo>, but inconsistent results are published on the effect of supplementation of the two components separately </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A vital relationship exists between the two substances to obtain optimal function of the cell </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>However, reports on combined supplements are lacking </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A 5-year prospective randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial among Swedish citizens aged 70 to 88 was performed in 443 participants given combined supplementation of <z:chebi fb="19" ids="27568">selenium</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="23354">coenzyme</z:chebi> Q10 or a placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Clinical examinations, echocardiography and biomarker measurements were performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Participants were monitored every 6th month throughout the intervention </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The cardiac biomarker N-terminal proBNP (NT-proBNP) and echocardiographic changes were monitored and mortalities were registered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>End-points of mortality were evaluated by Kaplan-Meier plots and Cox proportional hazard ratios were adjusted for potential confounding factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Intention-to-treat and per-protocol analyses were applied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: During a follow up time of 5.2years a significant reduction of cardiovascular mortality was found in the active treatment group vs. the placebo group (5.9% vs. 12.6%; P=0.015) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>NT-proBNP levels were significantly lower in the active group compared with the placebo group (mean values: 214ng/L vs. 302ng/L at 48months; P=0.014) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In echocardiography a significant better cardiac function score was found in the active supplementation compared to the placebo group (P=0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Long-term supplementation of <z:chebi fb="19" ids="27568">selenium</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="1" ids="23354">coenzyme</z:chebi> Q10 reduces cardiovascular mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>The positive effects could also be seen in NT-proBNP levels and on echocardiography </plain></SENT>
</text></document>