<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Trypanosoma cruzi infection</z:e> induces progressive <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>cardiac inflammation</z:mp> that leads to <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> and modifications in the heart architecture and functionality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">Statins</z:chebi>, such as 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl <z:chebi fb="3" ids="15346">coenzyme A</z:chebi> (HMG CoA) reductase inhibitors, have been studied due to their pleiotropic roles in modulating the <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammatory response</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Our goal was to evaluate the effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9150">simvastatin</z:chebi> on the cardiac inflammatory process using a cardiotropic strain of T. cruzi in a murine model of Chagas <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>C57BL/6 mice were infected with 500 trypomastigotes of the Colombian strain of T. cruzi and treated with an oral dose of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9150">simvastatin</z:chebi> (20 mg/Kg/day) for one month and inflammatory and morphometric parameters were subsequently evaluated in the serum and in the heart, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9150">Simvastatin</z:chebi> reduced the total cholesterol and <z:mp ids='MP_0002501'>inflammatory mediators</z:mp> (interferon-gamma, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e> <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> factor-alpha, CCL2 and CCL5) in the serum and in the heart tissue at 30 days post-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Additionally, a proportional reduction in heart weight and inflammatory infiltration was observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9150">Simvastatin</z:chebi> also reduced epimastigote proliferation in a dose-dependent manner in vitro and was able to reduce blood trypomastigotes and heart amastigote nests during the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> phase of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> in vivo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Based on these data, we conclude that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9150">simvastatin</z:chebi> exerts a modulatory effect on the <z:mp ids='MP_0002501'>inflammatory mediators</z:mp> that are elicited by the Colombian strain of T. cruzi and ameliorates the heart damage that is observed in a murine model of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>