<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Many patients with idiopathic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001644'>dilated cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (<z:chebi fb="20" ids="15767">DCM</z:chebi>) have been diagnosed on the basis of the exclusion of significant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242231" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary stenosis</z:e> and the presence of left ventricular (LV) dysfunction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In the present study, we investigated the possibility that coronary multispasm is one of the mechanisms leading to diffuse idiopathic <z:chebi fb="20" ids="15767">DCM</z:chebi>-like LV dysfunction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Forty-two patients with severely depressed LV function but without significant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242231" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary stenosis</z:e> were enrolled (baseline LV ejection fraction, 33 ±11%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>An <z:chebi fb="9" ids="15355">acetylcholine</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi>) provocation test was performed at the time of coronary angiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In patients with a positive <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> provocation test (n = 20), coronary angiography revealed multivessel diffuse <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010073" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary spasm</z:e> with marked electrocardiogram changes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In patients with a negative <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> provocation test (n = 22), significant findings compatible with idiopathic <z:chebi fb="20" ids="15767">DCM</z:chebi> were more frequently observed on magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) or in LV biopsies compared with the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi>-positive group (MRI, 73% vs. 12%; and LV biopsy, 71% vs. 0%, respectively; P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi>-positive group, LV function significantly improved after the administration of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38215">calcium channel blockers</z:chebi> (LV ejection fraction, 34 ±12% vs. 54 ±10%; and brain natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi>, 803 ± 482 pg/mL vs. 69 ± 84 pg/mL, at baseline and 1 year, respectively; P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our results raise the possibility that patients with LV dysfunction due to repeated coronary multispasm are being diagnosed as idiopathic <z:chebi fb="20" ids="15767">DCM</z:chebi>, and that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38215">calcium channel blockers</z:chebi> may prove to be a promising therapeutic strategy in those patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>