<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> induced by Trypanosoma cruzi (T. cruzi) <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> is a major cause of mortality and morbidity affecting the cardiovascular system for which presently available therapies are largely inadequate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Transforming Growth Factor beta (TGFß) has been involved in several regulatory steps of T. cruzi invasion and in host tissue <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>GW788388 is a new TGFß type I and type II receptor kinase inhibitor that can be orally administered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the present work, we studied its effects in vivo during the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> phase of experimental <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODOLOGY/PRINCIPAL FINDINGS: Male Swiss mice were infected intraperitoneally with 10(4) trypomastigotes of T. cruzi (Y strain) and evaluated clinically </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We found that this compound given once 3 days post <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> (dpi) significantly decreased <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242723" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">parasitemia</z:e>, increased survival, improved cardiac electrical conduction as measured by PR interval in electrocardiography, and restored connexin43 expression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We could further show that <z:mp ids='MP_0003141'>cardiac fibrosis</z:mp> development, evaluated by collagen type I and fibronectin expression, could be inhibited by this compound </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, we further demonstrated that administration of GW788388 at the end of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> phase (20 dpi) still significantly increased survival and decreased <z:mp ids='MP_0003141'>cardiac fibrosis</z:mp> (evaluated by Masson's trichrome staining and collagen type I expression), in a stage when parasite growth is no more central to this event </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION/SIGNIFICANCE: This work confirms that inhibition of TGFß signaling pathway can be considered as a potential alternative strategy for the treatment of the symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> found in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> phases of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>