<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: This study sought to investigate regional left ventricular (LV) rotation in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001639'>hypertrophic cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (HCM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: The study comprised 44 patients with HCM with a typical reverse septal curvature (age 40 ± 14 years, 33 men) and 44 healthy volunteers (age 39 ± 14 years, 32 men) in whom LV rotation could be assessed at the basal and apical LV level with speckle-tracking echocardiography, using the QLAB Advanced Quantification Software version 6.0 (Philips, Best, The Netherlands) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In HCM patients, lower values of initial counter-clockwise rotation at the basal LV level (1.5 ± 1.2 vs. 0.6 ± 0.9°, P &lt; 0.001) were seen, in particular in the septal segment (1.7 ± 1.6 vs. 0.4 ± 0.7°, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>After this period, the direction of rotation changed to clockwise with a peak basal rotation of -4.8 ± 2.0° in controls vs. -6.1 ± 2.5° in HCM patients (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Peak basal rotation in HCM patients was in particular higher in the anterior (-6.6 ± 3.0 vs. -4.4 ± 2.4°, P &lt; 0.01) and septal (-5.4 ± 2.6 vs. -3.9 ± 1.9°, P &lt; 0.05) segments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The normalized (corrected for peak basal rotation) global back-rotation rate was lower in HCM patients (4.1 ± 3.1 vs. 6.3 ± 4.9 s(-1), P &lt; 0.05), in particular driven by a lower rate in the septal segment (3.8 ± 2.6 vs. 6.4 ± 4.8 s(-1), P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At the apical level, changes in rotation and back-rotation were more homogeneous </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Changes in rotation and back-rotation at the LV basal level in HCM patients are mainly caused by regional changes in the basal septal and anterior segments, the segments mostly involved in the hypertrophic process </plain></SENT>
</text></document>