<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: The maintenance of sinus rhythm is crucial for the functional capacity of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001639'>hypertrophic cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (HCM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Using a multimodality approach, we attempted to identify potential predictors of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004757'>paroxysmal atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (PAF) in HCM patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Thirty HCM patients (17 males, mean age 57.9 ± 13.6) with at least one documented PAF episode and 32 age- and sex-matched HCM control patients as well as 25 healthy volunteers were studied in sinus rhythm </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Study subjects underwent 2D echocardiography including a colour Doppler myocardial imaging evaluation of the left atrium (LA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Additionally, an orthogonal electrocardiogram was acquired; P-wave duration, maximum, and mean energies were calculated for each subject at each orthogonal lead and the composite vector axis using the Morlet wavelet analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Compared with HCM controls, in HCM-PAF patients, LA antero-posterior diameter was significantly enlarged (LAD(AP): 46.1 ± 5.9 vs. 40.0 ± 4.7 mm, P &lt; 0.001), peak strain rate of the LA lateral wall in the reservoir phase was significantly decreased (LAT peak SR-S: 1.93 ± 0.51 vs. 2.55 ± 0.83 s(-1), P &lt; 0.01), and P-wave duration in the Z-lead was significantly prolonged (P-durZ: 106.9 ± 24.6 vs. 86.2 ± 14.3 ms, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Cut-off values and areas under the curve (AUCs) for individual parameters were 42.0 mm, 2.32 s(-1), and 98.8 ms and 0.81, 0.74, and 0.78, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A multivariable model combining LAD(AP), LAT peak SR-S and P-durZ had an AUC of 0.90, a sensitivity of 0.87, and a specificity of 0.91 for identifying PAF patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: P-wave duration combined with LA antero-posterior diameter and myocardial deformation indices resulted in a higher power for discriminating HCM-PAF patients, when compared with individual parameters derived from either wavelet analysis or 2D echocardiography </plain></SENT>
</text></document>