<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>UNLABELLED: Purpose: Decline in physical function is commonly observed in patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0003606'>kidney failure</z:mp> on dialysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Whether lung <z:mpath ids='MPATH_107'>congestion</z:mpath>, a predictable consequence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0546817" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">fluid overload</z:e>, may contribute to the low physical functioning of these patients has not been investigated. ♢ METHODS: In 51 peritoneal dialysis (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PD</z:e>) patients, we investigated the cross-sectional association between the physical functioning scale of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022658" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Kidney Disease</z:e> Quality of Life Short Form (KDQOL-SF: Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, CA, USA) and an ultrasonographic measure of lung water recently validated in dialysis patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The relationship between physical functioning and lung water was also analyzed taking into account the severity of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002094'>dyspnea</z:hpo> measured using the New York Heart Association (NYHA) classification currently used to grade the severity of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>. ♢ RESULTS: Evidence of moderate-to-severe lung <z:mpath ids='MPATH_107'>congestion</z:mpath> was evident in 20 patients, and this alteration was asymptomatic (that is, NHYHA class I) in 11 patients (55%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>On univariate analysis, physical functioning was inversely associated with lung water (r = -0.48, p &lt; 0.001), age (r = -0.44, p = 0.001), previous cardiovascular events (r = -0.46, p = 0.001), and fibrinogen (r = -0.34, p = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Physical functioning was directly associated with blood pressure, the strongest association being with diastolic blood pressure (r = 0.38, p = 0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The NYHA class correlated inversely with physical functioning (r = -0.51, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In multiple regression analysis, only lung water and fibrinogen remained independent correlates of physical functioning </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The NYHA class failed to maintain its independent association. ♢ CONCLUSIONS: This cross-sectional study supports the hypothesis that symptomatic and asymptomatic lung <z:mpath ids='MPATH_107'>congestion</z:mpath> is a relevant factor in the poor physical functioning of patients on <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>