<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Background: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001639'>Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (HCM) is a common cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001699'>sudden death</z:hpo> in athletes and differentiating this condition from the nonpathological "<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0340520" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">athlete's heart</z:e>" remains a challenge </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The development of pathological <z:hpo ids='HP_0001712'>left ventricular hypertrophy</z:hpo> (LVH) is associated with left atrial (LA) <z:mpath ids='MPATH_66'>dilatation</z:mpath> and dysfunction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>LA strain and strain rate by two-dimensional (2D) speckle tracking are novel indices of LA function and might contribute to differentiate physiological from pathological LVH among athletes with underdiagnosed HCM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Methods: We evaluated 20 patients with nonobstructive HCM, 20 highly trained athletes and 20 healthy controls matched for age, gender, and body surface area </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients underwent a transthoracic echocardiogram with evaluation of LA strain: s-wave (LASs); and strain rate: s-wave (LASRs) and a-wave (LASRa) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Results: LV mass index, LA volume index, and ejection fraction were comparable between patients with HCM and athletes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients with HCM had a significantly lower LASs (19 + 8% vs. 43 + 8%, P &lt; 0.01), LASRs (0.7 + 0.2 s-1 vs. 1.6 + 0.2 s-1, P &lt; 0.01), and LASRa (-0.8 + 0.1 s-1 vs. -1.4 + 0.3 s-1, P &lt; 0.01) compared to athletes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Among hypertrophic subjects, independent predictors of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_159'>hypertrophy</z:mpath> related to HCM were LASs and E/é ratio </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: LA myocardial deformation is significantly impaired in patients with HCM compared to athletes and healthy controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>LA strain and strain rate assessed by 2D speckle tracking should be incorporated in the evaluation of trained athletes with LVH and LA <z:mpath ids='MPATH_66'>dilatation</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>