<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: A novel concept for the treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> is the neutralization of antibodies against the β(1)-adrenergic receptor (anti-β(1)AR-ab) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In a rat model of autoimmune <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo>, the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="23449">cyclic peptide</z:chebi> COR-1 (given i.v. once monthly) neutralized anti-β(1)AR-abs and prevented anti-β(1)AR-ab-induced myocardial damage, and completely reverted cardiac dysfunction over 3-6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: A clinical phase I trial was designed as a single-blinded, placebo-controlled study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Fifty human volunteers received COR-1 or matching placebo as a single i.v. administration with ascending doses (10-240 mg) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Primary endpoints were safety and tolerability, while the pharmacokinetic profile of COR-1 was assessed as a secondary endpoint </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> five investigated dose groups were well tolerated; no drug-related side effects occurred </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Pharmacokinetics revealed a favourable profile with an almost complete plasma clearance within 60 min after administration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Pharmacodynamic investigation showed dose-dependent efficacy with almost complete scavenging of pathological anti-β(1)AR-abs ex vivo at the two highest doses </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>No anti-COR-1 autoantibodies occurred </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>No other effects on the immune system (such as an increase of crucial cytokines) were observed up to 43 days after drug administration, nor upon incubation of anti-β(1)AR-ab-positive patient blood samples with COR-1 ex vivo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: COR-1 was shown to be safe after i.v. administration in vivo; no relevant side effects occurred </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Efficacy was estimated from ex vivo investigation of the potency to neutralize specific anti-β(1)-AR-abs.Trial registration: NCT 01043146, Eudra CT 2008-007745-31 </plain></SENT>
</text></document>