<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Progressive <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> is a major cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> in Duchenne <z:hpo ids='HP_0003560'>muscular dystrophy</z:hpo> (DMD) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Coupling between Ca(2+) handling and contractile properties in dystrophic hearts is poorly understood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>It is also not clear whether developing <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>cardiac failure</z:hpo> is dominated by alterations in Ca(2+) pathways or more related to the contractile apparatus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We simultaneously recorded force and Ca(2+) transients in field-stimulated papillary muscles from young (10 - 14 wks) <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> (wt) and dystrophic mdx mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Force amplitudes were five-fold reduced in mdx muscles despite only 30 % reduction in fura-2 ratio amplitudes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This indicated mechanisms other than systolic Ca(2+) to additionally account for force decrements in mdx muscles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>pCa-force relations revealed decreased mdx myofibrillar Ca(2+) sensitivity. 'In vitro' motility assays, studied in mdx hearts here for the first time, showed significantly slower sliding velocities. mdx MLC/MHC isoforms were not grossly altered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Dystrophic hearts showed echocardiography signs of early ventricular wall <z:mpath ids='MPATH_159'>hypertrophy</z:mpath> with a significantly enlarged end-diastolic diameter 'in vivo' </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, fractional shortening was still comparable to wt mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Changes in the contractile apparatus satisfactorily explained force drop in mdx hearts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: We give first evidence of early <z:mpath ids='MPATH_159'>hypertrophy</z:mpath> in mdx mice and possible mechanisms for already functional impairment of cardiac muscle in DMD. © 2012 The Authors Journal of Cellular and Molecular Medicine © 2012 Foundation forCellular and Molecular Medicine/Blackwell Publishing Ltd </plain></SENT>
</text></document>