<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> right ventricular pacing (RVP) upgraded to cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) have been excluded from the majority of clinical trials of CRT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Little is known with regard to predictors of response in this population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that reversal of RVP-induced electrical dyssynchrony (indexed by QRS duration) by CRT would predict a favorable response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The purpose of this study was to identify baseline characteristics associated with response in patients upgraded to CRT from <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> RVP </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Consecutive patients presenting for CRT at the Cleveland Clinic between 9/30/2003 and 7/8/2008 with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> RVP and serial echocardiograms were included in this analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RVP was defined as &gt;85% pacing on a pre-CRT device check, previous AV node ablation, or complete pacer dependency per chart notes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Response was defined as a reduction in left ventricular end-systolic volume (LVESV) of≥15% from baseline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Clinical, electrocardiographic, and echocardiographic data were extracted to determine covariates associated with response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 112 patients met inclusion criteria of whom 72 (64.3%) met criteria for response over a median follow up of 9.9 months (interquartile range (6.5-14.7)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>No significant differences were noted in terms of male gender (68.1% vs. 75.0%, p=0.52), ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (55.6% vs. 55.0%, p=1.0), pre-CRT QRS duration (ms) (189.1±vs 185.5±26.8, p=0.47), duration of RVP prior to CRT upgrade (years) (5.8±3.9 vs. 6.2±4.0, p=0.57), or baseline LVESV(ml)(160.0±60.7 vs. 172.8±67.2, p=0.32) between responders and non-responders, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Percent reduction in QRS duration between the right ventricular-paced and first biventricular-paced waveform was significantly greater in responders compared to non-responders (%)(14.4±13.2 vs. 7.2±14.0, p=0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In multivariate analysis, percent reduction in QRS narrowing was the lone factor associated with response (odds ratio 0.02 (0.001-0.42), p=0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Reversal of electrical dyssynchrony predicts response to CRT in chronically RV paced patients upgraded to CRT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Traditional factors associated with a favorable response to CRT in de novo implants (female gender, non-ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo>, and a wider baseline QRS duration) are not significantly associated with response in upgraded patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Duration of RVP prior to CRT upgrade is not an important determinant of response </plain></SENT>
</text></document>