<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Hereditary <z:hpo ids='HP_0100724'>thrombophilias</z:hpo> are a heterogenous group of genetic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0005779" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coagulation disorders</z:e> which, particularly in combination with acquired prothrombotic factors, induce a predisposition to <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>After characterization of frequent thrombophilic syndromes like factor V-Leiden or the prothrombin 20210GA mutation, a number of case-control studies screened for the prevalence of these mutations in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0005305'>cerebral venous thrombosis</z:hpo> (CVT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Our meta-analysis shows that factor V-Leiden and prothrombin are frequent and significantly associated with CVT (16.4% vs. 4.9% or 4.3, P &lt; 0.001, and 12.1% vs. 1.9% or 5.8, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo>, only factor V-Leiden and not prothrombin is a weak but significant risk factor (5.9% vs. 2.6% or 1.6, P &lt; 0.001, and 4.1% vs. 3.3% or 1.4, P = 0.1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The C677T homozygous point mutation in the MTHFR, a <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">homocysteine</z:chebi>-degrading enzyme, was also associated with arterial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> (16% vs. 15% or 1.5, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>For CVT, sufficient data are lacking </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We therefore recommend screening for <z:hpo ids='HP_0100724'>thrombophilia</z:hpo> in CVT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0033036" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">atrial premature complex</z:e> (APC) resistance should be considered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>As long as controlled studies are lacking, individual <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50249">anticoagulant</z:chebi> therapy must take hereditary and precipitating factors into account to assess potential thrombotic risk </plain></SENT>
</text></document>