<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Dural sinus <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> (<z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi>) is an uncommon cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The safest and most effective therapy for <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi> has not been conclusively identified </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A retrospective chart review of data for 31 patients who were treated for <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi> at our institution between 1992 and 2001 was performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Four treatment strategies were identified, i.e., 1). medical observation only, 2). systemic anticoagulation (AC) therapy with <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi>, 3). endovascular chemical thrombolysis with urokinase or tissue plasminogen activator and concurrent systemic AC therapy, and 4). mechanical endovascular clot thrombolysis with concurrent systemic AC therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Complications and clinical outcomes were assessed for each group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients treated solely with medical observation fared the worst; four of five patients experienced intracranial hemorrhagic complications, and only two of five exhibited clinical improvement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients who received systemic AC therapy experienced no hemorrhagic complications, even when pretreatment <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp> was present; 75% (six of eight patients) exhibited improvement with AC therapy alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Chemical thrombolysis was very effective in restoring sinus patency (90% of patients); however, 30% of patients (3 of 10 patients) experienced hemorrhagic complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Sixty percent of patients (6 of 10 patients) who underwent chemical thrombolysis exhibited clinical improvement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Patients who underwent mechanical thrombectomies demonstrated a low hemorrhagic complication rate, and most (88%) made good recoveries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Therapy directed at the underlying clot in <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi> must begin without delay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Our results suggest that supportive medical management of <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi>, without therapy directed at the clot or clotting process, is not effective </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Systemic AC therapy, even in the presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001342'>intracerebral hemorrhage</z:hpo>, seems to be safe </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">Heparin</z:chebi> can be safely titrated to yield partial thromboplastin times of 60 to 70 seconds </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Chemical clot thrombolysis is efficacious in opening occluded sinuses but may cause <z:hpo ids='HP_0002170'>intracranial hemorrhage</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>We currently recommend either systemic AC therapy or systemic AC therapy in conjunction with mechanical clot thrombectomy as a safe effective treatment for <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>