<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We investigated whether there is an association between factor V Leiden (FVL) and/or prothrombin gene G20210A mutation (PT20210A) and cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0001907'>thromboembolism</z:hpo> in a pediatric Argentinean population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>From May 1992 to January 2002, 44 consecutive children with arterial <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> (AIS) and 23 children with cerebral sinovenous <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVT</z:e>) were prospectively studied at a single center </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of both mutations was compared with a 102 age-matched controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In children with AIS, the frequencies (patients vs. controls), odds ratio (OR), and 95% confidence interval (95% CI) for the presence of FVL were as follows: 2.3% vs. 2%, OR/95% CI, 1.16/0.2 to 13.2; P value = 0.99 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>No cases of PT20210A were found in this group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In children with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVT</z:e>, the frequencies (patients vs. controls), OR, and 95% CI were as follows: FVL (4.3% vs. 2%, OR/95% CI, 2.27/0.22 to 6.2; P value = 0.99) and PT20210A (4.3% vs. 1%; OR/95% CI, 4.6/0.3 to 76.3; P value = 0.3354) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>One child with PT20210A also had an inherited <z:hpo ids='HP_0005543'>protein C deficiency</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In 12 (18%) out of the 67 children with cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0001907'>thromboembolism</z:hpo>, without the aforementioned mutations, other prothrombotic disorders were detected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Although a multi-center prospective study with a large number of Argentinean pediatric patients is needed to obtain considerable evidence, no association between factor V Leiden and/or prothrombin gene G20210A mutation and cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0001907'>thromboembolism</z:hpo> was found in this pediatric series </plain></SENT>
</text></document>