<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Central neuropathic pain (CNP) after <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> has not been studied in sufficient detail and published studies have only included patients with cerebral artery <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> or <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study evaluates the prevalence and factors associated with CNP after cerebral venous (and sinus) <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> (CVT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This observational study included <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients admitted to our <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> unit for CVT between January 2002 and December 2007 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Clinical data for each patient were collected prospectively and were combined with retrospective review of neuroradiological imaging </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>CVT patients were systematically examined at the outpatient clinic at 6 months, 12 months, and annually thereafter, and information on long-term functional outcome, including the presence of CNP, were obtained by open-ended questions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A standardized CNP assessment was performed during the last outpatient visit and was based on the patient's interview and clinical examination </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Pain characteristics were assessed by the DN4-questionnaire </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CNP was considered when the patient met the following criteria: painful area within the area of sensory abnormalities and follow-up MRI showing brain parenchymal lesion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Among the 43 patients admitted for CVT, seven (16%) developed CNP during the first year of follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Standardized CNP assessment was performed 24.9 ± 11.6 months after CVT: eight patients (19%) suffered from CNP </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Initial motor deficit (87 vs. 17%, p &lt; 0.001), initial <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0748618" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">sensory deficit</z:e> (62 vs. 20%, p = 0.03), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> (75 vs. 23%, p = 0.009), right-sided lesion on initial MRI (62 vs. 17%, p = 0.017), thalamic (37 vs. 0%, p = 0.005) and basal ganglia involvement (25 vs. 0%, p = 0.03) and vein of Galen occlusion (25 vs. 0%) were significantly associated with CNP </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Despite several methodological limitations, CNP after CVT seems to be frequent, accounting for one-fifth of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cases of CVT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Some clinical and radiological factors might contribute to the development of CNP </plain></SENT>
</text></document>