<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To analyse the outcome of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005305'>cerebral venous thrombosis</z:hpo> (CVT) patients presenting with isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo>, specifically to compare isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> patients with early vs. late CVT diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHOD: In the International Study on Cerebral Vein and Dural Sinus <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>Thrombosis</z:mp> (ISCVT) database we compared the outcome of patients with isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> and a CVT diagnosed early (≤7 days from <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo>) vs. late (&gt;7 days) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We retrieved 100 patients with isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo>, 52 patients with early CVT diagnosis (early isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo>) and 48 with late CVT diagnosis (late isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Neurological worsening was more frequent within early isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> patients (23% vs. 8%) (p = 0.045) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At the last follow-up (median 411 days), 93% patients had a complete recovery, and 4% were dead or dependent, with no significant difference between early isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> and late isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The outcome of CVT patients with isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> diagnosed early or late was similarly favourable, but there was a higher proportion of neurological worsening in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> phase among early isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> patients, who need close neurological monitoring </plain></SENT>
</text></document>