<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>L-Asparaginase treatment during induction therapy in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> lymphoblastic <z:mpath ids='MPATH_336'>leukaemia</z:mpath> (ALL) is known to be frequently complicated by <z:hpo ids='HP_0001907'>thromboembolic events</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It was recently suggested that L-asparaginase derived from Erwinia chrysanthemi alters the coagulation system less severely than does Escherichia coli asparaginase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In a series of 11 adult patients with ALL, we investigated some parameters of the coagulation system during treatment with Erwinia asparaginase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The doses employed were rather high; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients below the age of 60 years received 15,000 U/m2 daily over 14 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In accordance with what is known from treatment with E. coli asparaginase, we observed significant lowering of antithrombin as well as of fibrinogen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, as to fibrinogen indeed a significant decrease had occurred prior to the institution of Erwinia asparaginase treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The most striking observation in the present study was that the levels of prothrombin complex, reflecting the function of K-vitamin dependent coagulation factors II, VII and X, remained within <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> ranges during treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>This indicates that these coagulation factors were not affected by Erwinia asparaginase, an observation at variance with several reports where E. coli asparaginase was investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This latter observation was the only finding which could lend support to the view that Erwinia asparaginase affects the coagulation system less than E. coli asparaginase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Finally, one of our patients developed a sinus <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp>, a severe thrombotic complication </plain></SENT>
</text></document>