<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> may affect gastric acid output and intragastric pH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In patients with an insufficient lower esophageal sphincter, this effect may theoretically influence the severity of reflux disease, as well as the efficacy of acid suppressive therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To evaluate whether the H. pylori status of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) affects the severity of disease and the efficacy of <z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">omeprazole</z:chebi> therapy to maintain disease remission, we conducted this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> were prospectively studied by upper gastrointestinal endoscopy with biopsy sampling for histology and H. pylori culture before start of treatment and at annual follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At endoscopy, <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> was graded according to the criteria of Savary-Miller, and the presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, hiatal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019270" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">herniation</z:e>, or other abnormalities was recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">Omeprazole</z:chebi> was started at an initial dose of 20 mg daily; the dose was adjusted based on symptoms and the endoscopical findings </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: One hundred thirty-seven <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> patients were included and followed up for a mean 56.6 months; 49 (36%) of them were infected with H. pylori </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>H. pylori-infected and -uninfected patients did not differ with respect to age (60 +/- 13 vs 61 +/- 14 yr, p = 0.65) or duration of follow-up (54 +/- 30 vs 58 +/- 31 months, p = 0.12) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>H. pylori-negative patients tended to present with more severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> at baseline (median Savary-Miller score 3 vs 2, p = 0.06) and had a higher prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (39/88 vs 10/49, p = 0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, no difference was found with respect to the dose of <z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">omeprazole</z:chebi> needed for maintained relief of symptoms and endoscopical signs of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (median 40 mg in both groups, p = 0.35) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: H. pylori-negative <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> patients have a higher prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, but do not need a higher dose of <z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">omeprazole</z:chebi> to maintain symptomatic and endoscopical disease remission </plain></SENT>
</text></document>