<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Helicobacter pylori has apparently colonized the human stomach since time immemorial and is superbly adapted for persistence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Several genotypes, including cag+, are associated with increased risk of gastric and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0013289" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">duodenal diseases</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>With modern life, for probably the first time in human history, there are large numbers of noncolonized persons </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Duodenal ulceration has been present essentially for only 200 years; that its incidence rose just as H. pylori was waning is best explained by changes in gastric microecology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>As H. pylori is disappearing, duodenal ulceration and <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> rates are falling </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, more proximal diseases, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>), <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, and <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinomas</z:mp> of the gastric cardia and lower esophagus, are increasing; colonization with cag+ H. pylori strains appears protective against these diseases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Thus, in the 21st century, the continuing decline in H. pylori may lead to the disappearance of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002588'>duodenal ulcers</z:hpo> and distal <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancers</z:hpo> and toward a marked increase in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, and esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>