<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Helicobacter pylori exaggerates the effect of acid suppressive drugs on intragastric pH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It is unknown whether this is relevant for the treatment of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>AIM: To compare oesophageal acid exposure and symptoms in H. pylori-negative and H. pylori-positive <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> patients during low and profound acid suppression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> patients with gastro- oesophageal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017168" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GERD">acid reflux</z:e> were studied by 24-h oesophageal pH-metry at baseline and during randomized treatment with <z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">omeprazole</z:chebi> 40 mg b.d. or <z:chebi fb="10" ids="8776">ranitidine</z:chebi> 150 mg b.d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>H. pylori status was determined by a serum IgG ELISA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Symptoms were scored on a four-graded scale </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of 58 patients, 26 (14 H. pylori-negative, 12 H. pylori-positive) were randomized to <z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">omeprazole</z:chebi>, 32 (16 H. pylori-negative, 16 H. pylori-positive) to <z:chebi fb="10" ids="8776">ranitidine</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At baseline, oesophageal acid exposure and symptoms did not differ between H. pylori-negative and H. pylori-positive: mean time proportion pH &lt; 4 per 24 h was 16.1% (95% CI 11.5-23.2) in H. pylori-negative, and 15.8% (11.3-21.4) in H. pylori-positive patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">Omeprazole</z:chebi> treatment resulted in a decrease of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017168" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GERD">acid reflux</z:e> per 24 h from 23.4% (7.9-39.3) to 0.0% (0.0-2.9) in H. pylori-negative, and from 17.3% (8.9-38.8) to 0.1% (0.0-1.7) in H. pylori-positive patients; <z:chebi fb="10" ids="8776">ranitidine</z:chebi> resulted in a decrease from 14.4% (10.5-18.5) to 9.3% (5.6-12.8) in H. pylori-negative, and from 15.1% (9.8-21.0) to 9.0% (3.1-20.1) in H. pylori-positive patients, the difference between H. pylori-negative and H. pylori-positive patients being N.S </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference between H. pylori-negative and H. pylori-positive patients with respect to erect and supine <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017168" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GERD">acid reflux</z:e>, or symptom scores in both treatment groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> does not influence oesophageal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017168" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GERD">acid reflux</z:e> and symptoms in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e>, either at baseline or during low as well as profound acid suppressive therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>We conclude that the dose of acid suppression does not have to be titrated upon H. pylori status in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>