<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The incidence rates of gastric cardia and esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinomas</z:mp> are increasing, but data suggest that carriage of cagA(+) Helicobacter pylori strains may protect against development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Our aims were to examine the relationship between pre-malignant and malignant lesions in the gastric cardia and serum antibodies to H. pylori antigens in patients with and without complications of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> was 40% in controls compared with 13% in patients with complicated or uncomplicated <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and cardia <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Cardia <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> (IM) and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> were present and concordant in 28% of controls but less frequent in patients with Barrett's alone or with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>/<z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (0% for each, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Carriage of cagA(+) strains was present in 34% of patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> and significantly associated with increased frequency and severity of cardia <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, IM, and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> but not with <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>IgA and HspA seropositivity were significantly increased in H. pylori-colonized patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> compared to persons with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> cardia histology (p &lt;/= 0.005) but not in persons with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0014852" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">esophageal disease</z:e> or cardia <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We conclude that carriage of cagA(+) H. pylori strains and induction of particular serological responses are significantly associated with marked histological findings in the gastric cardia but not with <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of either the gastric cardia or esophagus </plain></SENT>
</text></document>