<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> is associated with <z:mp ids='MP_0008010'>gastric adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, the mechanisms of this interaction are still unclear </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study was conducted to explore the effects of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> on early and late stage gastric <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0596263" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">carcinogenesis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>This study included 134 patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of the stomach (ACS), 67 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002582'>chronic atrophic gastritis</z:hpo> (CAG), and 65 <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> controls recruited at Memorial Sloan-Kettering <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Center (MSKCC) from November 1, 1992 to November 1, 1994 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Epidemiologic data were collected by a modified National <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Institute Health Habits History Questionnaire </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was diagnosed by pathological evaluation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Risk factors were analyzed using logistic regression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The odds ratio (OR) associated with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was 10.4 [95% confidence interval (CI): 2.6-41.6] for CAG and 11.2 (95% CI: 2.5-50.3) for <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> in comparison with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> controls, with adjustment for pack-years of smoking, alcohol drinking, body mass index, total caloric intake, dietary fat and fiber intake, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>But H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was not associated with risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>stomach cancer</z:hpo> when patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>stomach cancer</z:hpo> were compared with patients with CAG (OR = 0.6, 95% CI: 0.3-1.3) after controlling for potential confounding variables </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This association was persistent when only patients with both <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0005231'>chronic gastritis</z:hpo> were considered as cases and patients with CAG were considered as controls (OR = 0.7, 95% CI: 0.3-2.0) in the multivariate analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Our results suggest that H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> may be involved in the early stage of development of CAG, but not in the development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>stomach cancer</z:hpo> from CAG, and indicate that strategies for prevention of <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>stomach cancer</z:hpo> should target the early stage to eliminate H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in high-risk populations </plain></SENT>
</text></document>