<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: This study was undertaken to prospectively determine the prevalence of gastric H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and Barrett's complicated by <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> or <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The prevalence of H. pylori was determined in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> patients compared to a control population of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) only </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients had a minimum of 10 gastric surveillance biopsies obtained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>H. pylori colonization was determined upon the basis of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="51686">hematoxylin</z:chebi> and eosin and use of a modified Giemsa and or Steiner's silver stain of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> gastric biopsy specimens </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Two hundred and eighty-nine Barrett's patients and 217 GERD control patients were included in the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>H. pylori was found in 95/289 (32.9%) of the Barrett's patients, compared with 96/217 (44.2%) of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> controls (NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Forty-seven of the Barrett's patients had low-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>/indefinite <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>, 14 high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>, and 20 Barrett's <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>When Barrett's was subgrouped according to absence of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>, and presence of low-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>, high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>, or <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp>, H. pylori prevalence was found to be significantly less for patients with Barrett's high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> (14.3%) and <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (15.0%) versus patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> alone (44.2%), Barrett's alone (35.1%), or Barrett's with low-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> (36.2%) (p = 0.016) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This difference could not be explained by differences between <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> patients infected with H. pylori and those who were not with respect to gender, smoking history, alcohol consumption, use of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="49200">proton pump inhibitor</z:chebi>, or length of Barrett's mucosa </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Barrett's high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> and <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> are significantly more prevalent in patients who are not infected with H. pylori </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>H. pylori appears to have a protective effect against the development of Barrett's <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>