<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) colonization is associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0005231'>chronic gastritis</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0004398'>peptic ulcer</z:hpo> disease, and <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of the distal stomach </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, the role of H. pylori strain variation in complicated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo>, especially <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Therefore, the aim of this study was to evaluate the prevalence of colonization by cagA+ and cagA- H. pylori strains in the spectrum of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo>, including <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 251 patients undergoing endoscopy were categorized into four groups: controls, patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> alone, and patients with short- and long-segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients underwent upper endoscopies with biopsies and serum collections </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>H. pylori and degree of mucosal <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> in gastric biopsies were assessed and serological assessment made for H. pylori and cagA status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The overall prevalence of H. pylori colonization in the study population was 35% (95% confidence interval = 29.5-41.4%) which did not differ significantly among the groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, colonization by cagA+ H. pylori strains was significantly more prevalent among controls (11/25; 44%) and patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (13/36; 36%) than in patients with short-segment (2/10; 20%) or long-segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (0/18; 0%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> were less likely to be colonized by cagA+ H. pylori strains than reflux patients without <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (odds ratio = 0.27, 95% confidence interval = 0.11-0.67, p = 0.004) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Colonization by cagA+ H. pylori strains may be protective against the formation of short- and long-segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and its malignant complications </plain></SENT>
</text></document>