<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: The hypothesis that colonization with cagA(+) Helicobacter pylori strains protects against the development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) and its complications is tested </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Antral biopsy specimens were obtained for detection of H. pylori </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A serum sample was obtained for determination of IgG antibodies to H. pylori and to the CagA protein </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 736 patients were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>118 patients had reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo>, 36 had <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, 108 had <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatal hernia</z:hpo> without signs of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> (the reflux group), and 20 patients had esophageal or <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>stomach cancer</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The remaining 454 patients had no signs of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The 262 patients with reflux disease had a significantly lower prevalence of H. pylori (34.9%) than the 454 controls (54.6%; p&lt;0 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Among 310 H. pylori-positive patients from whom serum was available, colonization with cagA(+) strains was detected in 59% in the control group versus 35% in the reflux group (p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Conclusion: Patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> have a significantly lower prevalence of H. pylori colonization than controls, in particular of the cagA(+) type </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>These data suggest that colonization with cagA(+) H. pylori strains may be protective against the development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>