<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>To clarify the clinicopathological characteristics of <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of the gastric cardia (AGC), including its association with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath>, 49 surgically resected early AGCs (EAGCs) were examined clinicopathologically, histopathologically, histochemically, and immunohistochemically </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The clinicopathological characteristics of the patients with EAGC were compared with those of 293 patients with early <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of the distal stomach (EADS) and 7 patients with early <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of the esophagus (EAE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Histochemical staining with paradoxical concanavalin A (ConA) and immunohistochemical staining with monoclonal antibodies 45M1, Ccp58, and 56C6 were performed to investigate the differentiation phenotype of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>ConA and 45M1 were used for markers of the gastric phenotype, and Ccp58 and 56C6 were used for markers of the intestinal phenotype </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>EAGC was associated with a higher mean age (p &lt; 0.0001), a higher male-to-female ratio (p &lt; 0.05), a higher incidence of elevated-type <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> (p &lt; 0.0001), a higher incidence of differentiated-type <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> (p &lt; 0.0001), and greater depth of invasion (p &lt; 0.05) compared with EADS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>EAE was associated with a higher incidence of elevated-type <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> (p &lt; 0.001), a higher incidence of differentiated-type <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> (p &lt; 0.05), and larger <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> size (p &lt; 0.05) compared with EADS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> in patients with EAGC was significantly lower than in patients with EAE (10.2%, 5/49 patients vs. 100%, 7/7; p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of intestinal (Barrett's) <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> in surrounding non-neoplastic mucosa in patients with EAGC was significantly lower than in patients with EADS or EAE (36.7%, 18/49 patients vs. 72.0%, 211/293 and 85.7%, 6/7; p &lt; 0.0001 and p &lt; 0.05, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>EAGC was associated with a higher incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> that reacted positively for gastric phenotype markers alone than EADS (32.7%, 16/49 cases vs. 17.1%, 50/293; p &lt; 0.05) and a lower incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> that reacted positively for both gastric and intestinal markers than EADS or EAE (40.8%, 20/49 cases vs. 59.7%, 175/293 and 85.7%, 6/7; p &lt; 0.05, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Our findings indicate that AGC forms a specific category different from both <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of the distal stomach and esophagus in terms of association with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> or <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath>, and the differentiation phenotype of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>