<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND/AIM: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> can be expected to be more resistant to the effects of acidic refluxate, and, hence, it can be postulated that patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> experience less reflux complaints </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A cross-sectional study in consecutive patients presenting with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e> was done in order to test this hypothesis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Patients received a standardized questionnaire, and overall and specific symptom scores were assessed on a five-point Likert scale </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Reflux oesophagitis</z:e> was diagnosed in 128 patients and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> in 42 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e> had statistically significantly higher symptom scores than patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> (mean +/- SD): 9.1 +/- 6.3 vs. 6.2 +/- 5.4 (p = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The scores for heartburn and acid regurgitation were significantly higher in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e>, while there was a trend for epigastric pain, retrosternal pain, and vomitus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The symptom scores of patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> older than 60 years were not different from patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e> older than 60 years: 5.2 +/- 4.8 vs. 7.4 +/- 6.4 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, the symptom scores of patients younger than 60 years were significantly higher in those with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e>: 10.2 +/- 5.7 vs. 7.2 +/- 5.7 (p = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Odynophagia, heartburn, and acid regurgitation scored significantly higher in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e> younger than 60 years as compared with Barrett patients younger than 60 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> indeed suffer less from reflux complaints </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>However, this is only true for those younger than 60 years </plain></SENT>
</text></document>