<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>There is growing controversy over the cost-effectiveness of surveillance endoscopy for patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A retrospective review was performed of 80 patients who underwent resection for Barrett's <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> to assess the influence of endoscopic surveillance on long-term survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Twelve patients initially were diagnosed with benign <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and were followed with endoscopic surveillance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The remaining 68 patients had the diagnosis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> made at the time of their <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> diagnosis or resection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients in surveillance programs were younger (53 vs. 64 years; P = 0.008), had better performance status (8.9 vs. 8.2; P = 0.04), had less <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> (0.3 vs. 5.5 kg; P &lt; 0.001), had a similar incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> symptoms (75% vs. 60%), and were less likely to undergo preoperative chemotherapy and/or radiation therapy (8% vs. 28%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Pathologic stage was 0 or I in 9 (75%) of 12 patients in the surveillance group compared to 12 (18%) of 68 of those in the no surveillance group (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Median survival for patients in the surveillance group was 107 months compared to 12 months for those in the no surveillance group (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Stratifying for stage, surveillance (hazard ratio = 3.05; confidence interval = 1.09 to 8.57; P = 0.034) was the only predictor of survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Surveillance endoscopy permits early diagnosis of <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and contributes substantially to long-term survival </plain></SENT>
</text></document>