<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To know the relationship between endoscopic <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> and H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004398'>peptic ulcer</z:hpo> disease has declined in recent years, while <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett esophagus</z:hpo>, and distal esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> have increased </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Some authors think these epidemiologic changes are related to the simultaneous decrease in H. pylori colonization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHOD: From 1997 to 1999, 192 patients underwent gastrointestinal endoscopy and detection of H. pylori (rapid urease test and/or seric antibodies and/or histologic examination and/or C13 marked <z:chebi fb="20" ids="16199">urea</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients were retrospectively divided according to endoscopic diagnosis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (Savary-Miller) and positivity of any H. pylori test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Both groups were compared using Fisher exact test and odds ratio (OR) with 95% confidence intervals (CI 95%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 80 (40.6%) were H. pylori-positive without <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo>, and 18 (9.4%) had <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> and H. pylori positivity (p = 0.01) [OR = 0.39 (CI 95% = 0.15-0.62)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Of the remaining 133 patients, after separating those who received treatment that could modify <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> (n = 59), and 50 (37.6%), were H. pylori without positive without <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo>) 18 (13.5%) had <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> and H. pylori positivity maintaining significance p = 0.003) [OR 0.32 (CI 95% (-0.1)-0.8)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The severity of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (Savary-Miller) was compared with the presence of Helicobacter pylori, but no relationship was found (p = 0.3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: 1) <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> seems to be a protective factor for the presence of endoscopic <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>2) When <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> is present, the degree of damage appears to be independent of the H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>