<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND/AIMS: We aimed to investigate the prevalence of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> in the cardia of a patient group with high incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> presenting for elective upper endoscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We also re-evaluated the relation between <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> in the cardia and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo>, smoking, alcohol history, H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> elsewhere in the stomach </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODOLOGY: Sixty patients presenting for elective upper endoscopy were included in this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Prior to undergoing endoscopy each patient was questioned with regard to the clinical indication and symptoms including heartburn, regurgitation, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002015'>dysphagia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In addition, a smoking and alcohol history were recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Endoscopic biopsies: 1) one from the midantrum on the lesser curvature, 2) one from the incisura angularis, 3) one from the mid-corpus on the lesser curvature, 4) one from the columnar side of the squamocolumnar junction, 5) one from the squamous side of the squamocolumnar junction, 6) one from 2 cm distal to the esophagogastric junction, 7) one from across the squamocolumnar junction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Slides were stained using a combination of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="51686">hematoxylin</z:chebi>-eosin with Alcian blue at pH 2.5 for <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Each specimen was examined for the presence of H. pylori </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was 63% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Prevalence of the H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was significantly lower in the patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> of the cardia than in the patients without <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> of the cardia (P = 0.025) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>There was a positive correlation between the age of the patients and having <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> of the cardia (r = 0.286, P = 0.008) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>There was no relationship between <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> of the cardia and pyrozis, regurgitation, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002015'>dysphagia</z:hpo>, history of alcohol and smoking <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> determined by endoscopy or histopathology, sex, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> elsewhere in the stomach (P &gt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The incidence of the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> of the gastric cardia in Turkey is less than that of western countries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>Intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> of the gastric cardia negatively correlates with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>And there was no relationship between gastric cardia <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> and reflux disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Further investigations are needed for determining the premalign lesion and etiologic factors for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1333763" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer of the gastric cardia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>