<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND/AIMS: Specialized <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> around the esophagogastric junction is considered to be premalignant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to examine prospectively the prevalence of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> and to correlate its presence with clinical, endoscopic and histological findings </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODOLOGY: In 101 symptomatic patients (40 women, 61 men; mean age: 55 yr, range: 20-79 yr), biopsies were taken from gastric type mucosa just distal to the esophagogastric junction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>They were stained with <z:chebi fb="1" ids="51686">hematoxylin</z:chebi> and eosin and alcian blue-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="29149">periodic acid</z:chebi> Schiff for the detection of specialized <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> and <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> of the cardiac mucosa (<z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp>) and with Warthin-Starry for H. pylori presence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>Metaplasia</z:mpath> was detected in 27 patients (26.7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Multiple logistic regression analysis revealed that <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> was associated significantly with age (odds ratio, 2.8; 95% confidence interval, 1.2-6.6), endoscopic suspicion of short segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (odds ratio, 3.6; 95% confidence interval 2.2-6.9), detection of H. pylori (odds ratio, 2.8; 95% confidence interval, 1.1-7) and presence of <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> (odds ratio, 6.4; 95% confidence interval, 2.8-16.8) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The prevalence of specialized <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> around the esophagogastric junction is high in symptomatic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Age, endoscopic evidence of short segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and histological presence of H. pylori and <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> are independent risk factors associated with its presence </plain></SENT>
</text></document>