<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>Inflammation</z:mp> of the gastric cardia, which is the most proximal portion of the stomach, in most instances is the result of either <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> or H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Histologic distinction between these two entities is important because the treatment, natural history, and risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancy</z:e> are different </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Moreover, multilayered epithelium, a possible precursor to <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, has only recently been described in the gastric cardia, and its relationship to <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to compare the histologic features of the gastric cardia and the prevalence of multilayered epithelium in patients with reflux versus H. pylori-associated <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Routinely processed <z:chebi fb="1" ids="51686">hematoxylin</z:chebi> and eosin-stained mucosal biopsies of the gastric cardia from 30 patients with reflux-associated <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp>, 25 with H. pylori-associated <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp>, and 30 control patients (no reflux, no H. pylori) were evaluated for a wide variety of histologic features such as <z:mpath ids='MPATH_166'>goblet cell metaplasia</z:mpath>, presence of multilayered epithelium, type of glandular epithelium (mucous, oxyntic, mixed mucous/oxyntic), pancreatic <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath>, overall degree of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, and the quantity of individual types of inflammatory cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The clinical and histologic features were compared between the two study groups and controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Clinically, the reflux <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> group (male/female ratio: 21/9, mean age 56 years) had a significantly higher male/female ratio (p &lt;0.01) and a slightly higher mean age in comparison with the H. pylori group (male/female ratio: 9/16, mean age 50 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Histologically, the reflux group had significantly less overall <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> (p &lt;0.05), with fewer plasma cells (p &lt;0.04) and neutrophils (p &lt;0.006), but a higher prevalence of multilayered epithelium [9 of 30 (30%) vs 1 of 25 (4%) in the H. pylori group, p = 0.01] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the reflux <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> group, multilayered epithelium was significantly associated with neutrophilic <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> (p &lt;0.05), but not any other features of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> or with any of the specific epithelial cell types </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The control group showed less inflammatory activity in comparison with the H. pylori group and a lower prevalence of multilayered epithelium and eosinophilic <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> in comparison with the reflux group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The clinical and pathologic features of reflux <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> are distinct from H. pylori <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>carditis</z:mp> and are characterized by less overall <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> and fewer neutrophils and plasma cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Multilayered epithelium not uncommonly occurs in the cardia of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> but without <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, further supporting our hypothesis that multilayered epithelium may represent an early precursor in the development of columnar <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>