<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Recent studies indicate that colonization with cagA-positive Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) strains may protect against <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) and its complications, but the role of cagA in the etiology of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> has so far been poorly investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The pathogenesis of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> (IM) at an endoscopically <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> esophagogastric junction (EGJ) is still unclear, and the role of the H. pylori virulence factor cagA in it has not been investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of our study was to assess the relationship between H. pylori and cagA-positive H. pylori in particular and IM at an endoscopically <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> EGJ and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Serum samples were obtained from 62 patients without IM, 43 patients with IM at an endoscopically <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> junction, and 51 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>IM was defined as presence of goblet cells with positive staining with Alcian blue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of H. pylori and cagA was investigated by assessment of IgG antibody levels as determined by ELISA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The overall H. pylori prevalence was 59% (92/156), and the cagA prevalence was 29% (46/156) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Although 63% (39/62) of IM negative subjects and 74% (32/43) of those with IM at the junction were H. pylori positive, only 41% (21/51) of Barrett's patients tested positive </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The differences between the IM negative and the Barrett's group (p = 0.02) and between IM at the junction and Barrett's were significant (p = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The relative cagA prevalence (percentage with cagA positivity and H. pylori positivity) was 56% (22/39) in patients who were IM negative, 59% (19/32) in those with IM at the junction, and 24% (5/21) in those with Barrett's </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of anti-CagA was significantly lower in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> compared with patients who were IM negative (p = 0.002) and those who had IM at the junction (p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>No difference in cagA prevalence was seen between the latter groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These findings are in line with the concept that H. pylori and cagA-positive strains in particular protect against the development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In contrast, our findings do not support the theory that IM at an endoscopically <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> esophagogastric junction is associated with H. pylori or cagA-positive strains </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>IM at the junction and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> seem to have different etiologies </plain></SENT>
</text></document>