<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Since the rediscovery of Helicobacter pylori two decades ago, it has become increasingly clear that the true relationships between this organism and diseases of the upper gastrointestinal tract are highly complex </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>H. pylori colonization is a strong risk factor for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0030920" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="PUD|pud|GDU">peptic ulceration</z:e> and distal <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo>; however, <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> has no adverse consequences for most hosts, and the prevalence of H. pylori is inversely related to <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) and its sequelae, which include <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>One clinical implication stemming from these data is that H. pylori eradication may not be appropriate in certain human populations due to potential beneficial effects conferred by persistent gastric <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>However, the majority of published intervention trials indicate that H. pylori treatment neither leads to the development of clinically significant de novo <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> nor exacerbates existing reflux disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Superimposed upon these observations are reports that long-term acid suppression induced by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="49200">proton-pump inhibitors</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="4" ids="53266">PPIs</z:chebi>) in conjunction with H. pylori colonization may enhance the development of atrophic <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo>, a well-recognized histologic step in the progression to intestinal-type <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Therefore, current evidence-based recommendations regarding management of H. pylori-positive individuals with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> include the following </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>H. pylori should not be treated with the intent to either improve reflux symptoms or prevent the development of reflux complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, if patients are to receive long-term acid suppressive therapy, they should be tested for H. pylori and treated if positive, due to the potential for <z:chebi fb="4" ids="53266">PPIs</z:chebi> to accelerate <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> within H. pylori-infected mucosa </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Optimal first-line regimens in this country consist of a <z:chebi fb="4" ids="53266">PPI</z:chebi> in combination with clarithromycin and either <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2676">amoxicillin</z:chebi> or <z:chebi fb="1" ids="6909">metronidazole</z:chebi> (triple therapy) for at least 7, but preferably 10, days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Because the most effective second-line regimens contain <z:chebi fb="1" ids="6909">metronidazole</z:chebi>, it is advisable to use <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2676">amoxicillin</z:chebi> instead of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="6909">metronidazole</z:chebi> as first-line therapy in order to optimize results should subsequent therapy be required </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>If first-line regimens fail to eliminate H. pylori, patients should receive quadruple therapy consisting of a <z:chebi fb="4" ids="53266">PPI</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="6" ids="33301">bismuth</z:chebi> subsalicylate, <z:chebi fb="1" ids="6909">metronidazole</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="9" ids="27902">tetracycline</z:chebi> for 14 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Due to the availability and accuracy of noninvasive diagnostic tests for H. pylori, it is recommended that successful cure be confirmed after intervention </plain></SENT>
</text></document>