<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Concerns have been raised that subsequent pregnancy after antireflux surgery (ARS) may predispose to wrap disruption or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019270" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">herniation</z:e> and adversely affect outcomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Some surgeons withhold ARS in women of childbearing age for fear of this, but outcomes in this population have not been reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> childbearing-age women who underwent ARS for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) between January 1991 and July 2000 were asked to complete a detailed questionnaire </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients with subsequent pregnancies (SP) after ARS were compared with patients without subsequent pregnancies (NP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Ninety-five of the 118 patients (81%) completed the questionnaire at a mean follow-up of 4.9 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Fifteen patients had 19 subsequent pregnancies after undergoing ARS, and retching and/or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002013'>vomiting</z:hpo> were reported during 13 of the pregnancies (69%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Preoperative incidence of complicated-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> including strictures (11% vs. 20%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (19% vs. 13%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (36% vs. 33%), and ulceration (4% vs. 0%)-were similar between the nonpregnant and pregnant groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Incidence of postoperative moderate to severe esophageal (7% vs. 8%) and extraesophageal symptoms (0% vs. 6%) were similar between the SP and NP groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Postoperative prevalence of antisecretory medications was similar in SP and NP groups (13% and 23%, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The incidence of fundoplications redone did not reach statistical difference between the NP (11%) and SP (0%) groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Long-term outcomes and failure rates were similar in both groups, except the SP group reported greater overall satisfaction with ARS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Women of childbearing age have a high incidence of complicated <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>, which may contribute to higher-than-expected rates of symptomatic and anatomic fundoplication failures than first-time ARS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Subsequent pregnancies do not adversely affect outcomes after ARS </plain></SENT>
</text></document>