<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: The acidity of the refluxate into the esophagus is a key factor for the pathogenesis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> can influence gastric acid secretion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We have reported that H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> prevents reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> by decreasing gastric acid secretion in Japanese patients, but the role of this organism in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> is unclear </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to investigate the prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and gastric acid secretion in Japanese patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> with or without <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We enrolled 112 reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> patients who were examined for the status of H. pylori and acid secretion in this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>They were divided into three groups, according to the presence or absence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> as follows: reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> group without <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> alone) (80 patients); short-segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> group (16 patients); and long-segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> group (LSBE) (16 patients) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Age- and sex-matched control subjects were also assigned to the 80 patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was determined by histology, rapid urease tests, and serum IgG antibodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Gastric acid secretion was evaluated by the endoscopic gastrin test (EGT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The overall prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in the reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> patient group (24.1%) was significantly lower than the control group (71.2%) (odds ratio 0.13, 95% confidence interval 0.07-0.24; p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in the patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> tended to be lower than that in the patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> alone (reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> alone; 30.0%, SSBE; 18.7%, LSBE; 0%), especially in the patients with LSBE compared with the reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> alone group (p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The EGT value of the respective reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> patient group was significantly higher than the control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The EGT value in the patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> tended to be higher than that in the patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> alone, but the difference was not statistically significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>When examined in H. pylori-negative subjects, no difference was found in the EGT value between the control subjects and the patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> alone, but it was significantly higher in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> than the control subjects (p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>On the other hand, when examined in the H. pylori-positive subjects, the EGT value was significantly higher in the patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> alone than in the control subjects (p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> may play a protective role in the development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, especially in the development of LSBE in Japan </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Gastric acid hypersecretion may be concerned with the development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> in addition to the absence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>