<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> is accompanied by a lower prevalence of reflux disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>There is still an ongoing debate as to whether H. pylori actually protects against the development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e> or is merely an epiphenomenon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A cross-sectional study was performed to study the relation of H. pylori with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatus hernia</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL AND METHODS: Consecutive patients undergoing upper gastrointestinal endoscopy in a period of ten years were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Included were patients with active <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e> and/or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatus hernia</z:hpo> and/or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>As a reference group, patients without macroscopic abnormalities were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>H. pylori was detected applying routine diagnostic modalities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In the ten years 11,691 consecutive patients were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Reflux oesophagitis</z:e> was seen in 1535 patients, 307 patients had <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> and a <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatus hernia</z:hpo> was present in 2116 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The reference group consisted of 5341 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>H. pylori was significantly less often detected in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> compared with the reference group, 20 vs 29% (p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Also presence of H. pylori was significantly lower in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatus hernia</z:hpo> 20 vs 29% (p&lt;0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The present study confirms, in a very large group of patients studied in one single centre, the findings of earlier papers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Patients without H. pylori <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> suffer more often from reflux disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>There is a relation between H. pylori and reflux disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>However, the consequence of this relation will not be the same in every patient </plain></SENT>
</text></document>