<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Endoscopic ablation of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> has been described in which various thermocoagulation modalities are used in combination with a high dose of a <z:chebi fb="0" ids="49200">proton pump inhibitor</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>No randomized comparison of ablation strategies has been published </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Referred patients were screened to identify those with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> 2 to 7 cm in length, without high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Included patients received <z:chebi fb="0" ids="7915">pantoprazole</z:chebi> (40 mg twice a day), followed by randomization to treatment with <z:chebi fb="17" ids="49474,49475">argon</z:chebi> plasma coagulation (APC) or multipolar electrocoagulation (MPEC) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The primary outcome measure was the number of treatment sessions required for endoscopic ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of 235 patients screened, 52 were randomized </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean length of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> was 3.1 cm in the MPEC group vs. 4.0 cm in the APC group (p = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Otherwise, the treatment groups were similar with regard to baseline characteristics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The mean number of treatment sessions required for endoscopic ablation was 2.9 for MPEC vs. 3.8 for APC (p = 0.04) in an intention-to-treat analysis (p = 0.249, after adjustment for the difference in length of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The proportion of patients in which ablation was endoscopically achieved proximal to the gastroesophageal junction was 88% for the MPEC group vs. 81% for the APC group (p = 0.68) and histologically achieved in 81% for MPEC vs. 65% for APC (p = 0.21) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The mean time required for the first treatment session was 6 minutes with MPEC vs. 10 minutes with APC (p = 0.01) in per protocol analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>There was no serious adverse event, but transient moderate to severe upper-GI symptoms occurred after MPEC in 8% vs. 13% after APC (p = 0.64) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Conclusions Although there were no statistically significant differences, ablation of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="7915">pantoprazole</z:chebi> and MPEC required numerically fewer treatment sessions, and endoscopic and histologic ablation was achieved in a greater proportion of patients compared with treatment with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="7915">pantoprazole</z:chebi> and APC </plain></SENT>
</text></document>