<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: We have previously reported that <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> prevents reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (RE) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (BE) by decreasing gastric acid secretion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Gastroesophageal (GE) junction <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp>, including Barrett's <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp>, has been thought to be a complication of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, the relationship between H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>, gastric acid secretion, and GE junction <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> has not yet been investigated in Japan </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to evaluate this relationship in the Japanese population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 168 Japanese patients (RE alone: 80, short-segment BE (SSBE): 16, long-segment BE (LSBE): 20, GE junction <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp>: 12, distal early <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EGC</z:e>): 40; male/female = 106/62; mean age 61.5 yr) and 80 Japanese control subjects who had no localized lesions in the upper gastrointestinal tract (male/female = 43/37, mean age 58.1 yr) were enrolled for this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was determined by biopsy, the rapid urease test, and measurement of the serum H. pylori IgG antibody </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Gastric acid secretion was assessed by the endoscopic gastrin test (EGT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RE was diagnosed according to the Los Angeles classification </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in the patients with RE alone (30%) was significantly lower than that in control subjects (71.2%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There was also a tendency for the prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> to be lower in patients with BE (SSBE, 18.7%; LSBE, 0%) when compared to that in patients with RE alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>On the other hand, while the prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in patients with GE junction <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (58.3%) was significantly lower than that in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EGC</z:e> (87.5%), it tended to be higher than that in patients with RE alone or BE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The mean EGT value in patients with RE alone (3.74 mEq/10 min) was significantly higher than that in control subjects (1.83) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The mean EGT value in patients with BE (SSBE, 4.74; LSBE, 4.76) tended to be even higher than that in patients with RE alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The mean EGT value in patients with GE junction <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (3.94) was significantly higher than that in control subjects and patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EGC</z:e> (0.67), but it was comparable to that independent of the H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> status in patients with RE alone or BE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Preservation of gastric acid secretion may be important for the development of GE junction <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> in Japanese people, irrespective of the H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> status </plain></SENT>
</text></document>