<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Reducing mucosal cyclo-oxygenase-2 and <z:chebi fb="11" ids="26333">prostaglandin</z:chebi> E(2) production and suppressing intraoesophageal acid may be effective chemopreventive strategies in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>AIM: To compare the effects of aspirin and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8887">rofecoxib</z:chebi> when administered with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50275">esomeprazole</z:chebi> on <z:chebi fb="11" ids="26333">prostaglandin</z:chebi> E(2) production, cyclo-oxygenase-2 expression and proliferating cell nuclear antigen expression in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This exploratory, multicentre, randomized, open-label, four-way crossover study in 45 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> evaluated <z:chebi fb="11" ids="26333">prostaglandin</z:chebi> E(2) content, proliferating cell nuclear antigen expression, and cyclo-oxygenase-2 expression after 10 days of sequential treatments with: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50275">esomeprazole</z:chebi> 40 mg twice daily plus aspirin 325 mg once daily (E40 b.d. + A325); E40 b.d. plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8887">rofecoxib</z:chebi> 25 mg once daily (E40 b.d. + R25); E40 b.d.; and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8887">rofecoxib</z:chebi> 25 mg once daily (R25) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="11" ids="26333">Prostaglandin</z:chebi> E(2) content reduction in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> tissue was significantly greater with E40 b.d. + A325 compared with E40 b.d. + R25, E40 b.d. or R25 (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> treatments containing E40 b.d. significantly decreased proliferating cell nuclear antigen expression from baseline (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>None of the treatments significantly reduced cyclo-oxygenase-2 expression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The combined treatment of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50275">esomeprazole</z:chebi> 40 mg b.d. and aspirin 325 mg significantly decreased mucosal <z:chebi fb="11" ids="26333">prostaglandin</z:chebi> E(2) content and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> treatments containing <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50275">esomeprazole</z:chebi> significantly reduced proliferating cell nuclear antigen expression in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>