<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Expression of TGF-beta1, a major member of the TGF-beta superfamily and important promoter of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0598934" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor growth</z:e>, was investigated in a series of primary resected esophageal (Barrett's) <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinomas</z:mp> to establish its potential clinical significance and prognostic relevance in this entity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A series of 123 primary resected <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinomas</z:mp> of the distal esophagus, arising in association with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, and corresponding <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> squamous epithelium (n = 12) and non-malignant Barrett's mucosa (n = 11), were investigated by means of quantitative RT-PCR for expression of TGF-beta1, using paraffin embedded tissue samples </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Gene expression levels were correlated with clinical parameters and overall survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>TGF-beta1 <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> was expressed in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e>, but relative gene expression levels varied largely among different <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The relative gene expression was significantly higher in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> tissue compared to squamous epithelium (P = 0.005) and Barrett's mucosa (P=0.002), expressing only low amounts of TGF-beta1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Relative overexpression of the TGF-beta1 gene was associated with advanced UICC stage (III/IV vs. I/II; P = 0.009), depth of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> infiltration (pT3 vs. pT1/2; P &lt; 0.001), nodal involvement (pN1 vs. pN0; P = 0.006), and lymphatic vessel invasion (L1 vs. L0; P = 0.011) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>On univariate survival analysis, TGF-beta1 overexpression had a significant negative impact on survival (log rank test; P = 0.0255) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, the prognostic impact was not independent from other strong predictors of survival (pT, pN) on multivariate survival analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Our data show that TGF-beta1 overexpression is associated with advanced stage of esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> and implies a negative impact on survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The TGF-beta pathway may be a potential target for molecular therapies of advanced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> of this entity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>