<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Short segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> is defined by the presence of &lt;3 cm of columnar-appearing mucosa in the distal esophagus with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> on histophatological examination </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> is a risk factor to develop <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of the esophagus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>While <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> develops as a result of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo>, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> in the gastric cardia is a consequence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> and is associated with distal gastric <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>It can be difficult to determine whether short-segment columnar epithelium with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> are lining the esophagus (a condition called short segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>) or the proximal stomach (a condition called <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> of the gastric cardia) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>AIMS: To study the association of short segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (length &lt;3 cm) with gastric <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> (antrum or body) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> by H. pylori </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: Eight-nine patients with short segment columnar-appearing mucosa in the esophagus, length &lt;3 cm, were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Symptoms of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> were recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Biopsies were obtained immediately below the squamous-columnar lining, from gastric antrum and gastric corpus for investigation of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> and H. pylori </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Forty-two from 89 (47.2%) patients were diagnosed with esophageal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> by histopathology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The mean-age was significantly higher in the group with esophageal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The two groups were similar in terms of gender (male: female), <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> symptoms and H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Gastric <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> (antrum or body) was diagnosed in 21 from 42 (50.0%) patients in the group with esophageal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> and 7 from 47 (14.9%) patients in the group with esophageal columnar appearing mucosa but without <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>Intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> is a frequent finding in patients with &lt;3 cm of columnar-appearing mucosa in the distal esophagus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In the present study, short segment <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> in the esophagus is associated with distal gastric <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>Gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> symptoms and H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> did not differ among the two groups studied </plain></SENT>
</text></document>