<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett esophagus</z:hpo> is highly prevalent in the Western world; however, only a minority of affected individuals progress to esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Whereas many studies have examined risk factors for development of Barrett <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath>, few data are available on risk factors for progression to <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Identifying simple, reliable, clinical, and endoscopic predictors of high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> and <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> would be helpful for risk stratification in screening and surveillance programs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Clinical, endoscopic, and histologic data were reviewed for patients with a new Barrett diagnosis between 2002 and 2005 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients were classified, by an expert gastrointestinal pathologist, as having <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath>, indefinite-for-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>, low-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>, high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>, and esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Gender, age, race, ethnicity, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatal hernia</z:hpo> presence and size, Barrett segment length, H. pylori status, alcohol, smoking, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="49200">proton pump inhibitor</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="4" ids="53266">PPI</z:chebi>) use and duration, and reflux symptom duration were evaluated by logistic regression analysis for their association with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> severity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>, 109 patients (26 women, 83 men, mean age: 58.8) were newly diagnosed with Barrett <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> (n = 39), indefinite/low-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> (n = 35), and high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>/esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (n = 35) over a 3-year period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>On logistic regression analysis, duration of reflux symptoms for &gt;or=20 years (odds ratio [OR]: 5.66, P = .012), longer Barrett segment length (OR for 3-6 cm vs. &lt;3 cm: 9.05, P &lt; .0001; OR for &gt;or=6 cm: 8.374, P &lt; .0001), <z:hpo ids='HP_0100790'>hernia</z:hpo> size &gt;or=4 cm (OR: 10.63, P = .014), and male gender (OR: 4.03, P = .0019) were associated with higher pathologic grade </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Duration of reflux symptoms and Barrett length were significant as both discrete and continuous variables </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Absence of H. pylori (OR: 2.731, P = .060) approached significance in predicting <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> severity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In bivariate models, gender and Barrett length (continuous form) were significantly associated with grade when considered together (OR: 2.52, P = .0490 and OR: 1.30, P &lt; .0001), as were gender and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100790'>hernia</z:hpo> size &gt;4 cm (OR: 4.64, P = .0049 and OR: 12.18, P = .0197) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Male gender, longstanding <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatal hernia</z:hpo> size, and segment length are strongly associated with higher grades of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> at index diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>These factors along with H. pylori status warrant further prospective evaluation as predictors of risk for development of high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> and esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>