<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Ethnic differences in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) and its complications as well as racial variations in the prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> are well documented </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Nevertheless, the association between reflux disease, H. pylori, and race has not been adequately explored </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>AIMS: We estimated the strength of the association between H. pylori, ethnicity, and the <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) spectrum, including <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, in Asian patients presenting for endoscopy in a tertiary referral center </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Prospectively, we studied 188 consecutive patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>, short- and long-segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, and controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients underwent gastroscopy with gastric biopsies to assess H. pylori, <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo>, and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CagA status and H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> were determined by immunoblot assay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The overall prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was 52.1% (of which 77.6% were cagA(+)) and was lowest in the long-segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> group (36.7%) (p = .048) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>When <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> was present, the length of abnormality was 44.8% shorter in the presence of H. pylori (p = .015) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Indians had the highest prevalence of H. pylori (75%) and Malays the lowest (19.6%) (p &lt; .001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In Indians, increased prevalence of H. pylori and cagA-positive strains was associated with reduced severity of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> (p &lt; .004 and p &lt; .001, respectively), a trend not apparent in the other races </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Corpus <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath>, which was almost exclusively associated with H. pylori, was highest in Indians as compared to the other races (p = .013) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Presence of H. pylori was associated with a reduced severity of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> spectrum disease in Asians, especially Indians </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> may protect against complicated reflux disease via induction of corpus <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>