<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: There are situations in which the specimens obtained after endoscopic mucosal resection of superficial <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> arising from <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> are not adequate for histopathological assessment of the margins </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In these cases, immunohistochemistry might be an useful tool for predicting <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0920420" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer recurrence</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>AIM: To evaluate the value of p53 and Ki-67 immunohistochemistry in predicting the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0920420" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer recurrence</z:e> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> referred to circumferential endoscopic mucosal resection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Mucosectomy specimens from 41 patients were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> endoscopic biopsies prior to endoscopic mucosal resection presented high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> was detected in 23 of them </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Positive reactions were considered the intense coloration in the nuclei of at least 90% of the cells in each high-power magnification field, and immunostaining could be classified as superficial or diffuse according to the mucosal distribution of the stained nuclei </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Endoscopic mucosal resection samples detected <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> in 21 cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In these cases, p53 immunohistochemistry revealed a diffuse positivity for the great majority of these <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancers</z:e> (90.5% vs. 20%), and Ki-67 showed a diffuse pattern for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cases (100% vs. 30%); conversely, patients without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> revealed a superficial or negative pattern for p53 (80% vs. 9.5%) and Ki-67 (70% vs. 0%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>During a mean follow-up of 31.6 months, 5 (12.2%) patients developed six episodes of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1458156" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">recurrent cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Endoscopic mucosal resection specimens did not show any significant difference in the p53 and Ki-67 expression for patients developing <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> after endoscopic treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: p53 and Ki-67 immunohistochemistry were useful to confirm the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>; however, they had not value for predicting the recurrent <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> after circumferential endoscopic mucosal resection of Barrett's <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>