<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>In 2007 Helicobacter pylori research continued to deal with some controversies raised in the last decade </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The main problems remain unsolved: <z:hpo ids='HP_0004398'>peptic ulcer</z:hpo> disease negative for H. pylori, synergism of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and aspirin and other <z:chebi fb="2" ids="35475">nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs</z:chebi> or cyclooxygenase 2 specific inhibitors, the role of H. pylori eradication in uninvestigated and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0267167" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">nonulcer dyspepsia</z:e>, and the possible protective effect of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> against <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> and its complications such as <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The incidence and prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004398'>peptic ulcer</z:hpo> disease as well as <z:mpath ids='MPATH_579'>ulcer</z:mpath>-related mortality are continuing to decline <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> over the world </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The increasing consumption of anti-inflammatory and antisecretory drugs was not found to change the trend over the last period and therefore H. pylori was considered the key factor in causing <z:mpath ids='MPATH_579'>ulcer</z:mpath>-related mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Some progress has been achieved in understanding H. pylori-induced immunological processes, and attack mechanisms, as well as specific pathogenesis in uremic and cirrhotic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There is still a lot to learn about the bacterium and host factors related to H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and its complications </plain></SENT>
</text></document>