<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Genetic or epigenetic alterations in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (BE) with/without Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> remain unclear </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We examined the effects of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> on genetic instability (GIN), the CpG island methylation status and a biomarker related to BE <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0596263" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">carcinogenesis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We analyzed 113 Japanese individuals with endoscopically suspected BE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The patients included, Group CLE (n = 25): no specialized <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> (SIM) in a columnar lined epithelium (control); Group BE (n = 88): <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> had SIM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Microsatellite instability and a loss of heterozygosity as GIN, the methylation status at hMLH1, E-cadherin, p16 and APC, and immunoreactivity using a monoclonal antibody (mAb) Das-1, which specifically reacts with BE, were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Nine additional patients with BE were prospectively followed up for 2 years after successful H. pylori eradication </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The frequency of GIN, methylation at E-cadherin and APC, and mAb Das-1 reactivity in Group BE was significantly higher than that in Group CLE (p &lt; 0.0001, p &lt; 0.0001 and p &lt; 0.005, and p &lt; 0.0001, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, GIN, E-cadherin methylation and mAb Das-1 reactivity showed a significantly higher incidence in patients with H.pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> than in those without H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> (p &lt; 0.01, p &lt; 0.005, and p &lt; 0.01, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, the patients from Group BE were observed to change to a stable state of molecular alterations in 60% for GIN, 42.9% for E-cadherin methylation and 55.6% for APC methylation, or a reduction of mAb Das-1 reactivity was noted in 25% following eradication </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> may therefore affect these molecular alterations associated with the pathogenesis of BE, to some degree, in the Japanese population </plain></SENT>
</text></document>