<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Precise classification of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancers</z:e> of the esophagogastric junction according to Siewert may be difficult for the presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatal hernia</z:hpo>, which subsequently leads to a difficult choice of the surgical procedure of esophagectomy or gastrectomy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Ninety-six patients with such <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancers</z:e> were operated on in our department in 7 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Twenty-nine patients (30.2%), classified as type I (group 1), underwent a transthoracic esophagectomy with gastric pull up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Sixty-seven patients (69.8%) classified as type II or III (group 2) underwent an extended gastrectomy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We compared the patients of both groups retrospectively for disease-free survival and postoperative complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The general performance status of most patients was comparable in both groups and was assigned to the American Society of Anesthesiologists class II or III </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Statistically significant differences between the groups were seen for the postoperative reintubation rate [group 1: 31.0% vs. group 2: 9.0% (P = 0.009)], median time for surgery [group 1: 6 (3.5-8.5) hours vs. group 2: 4.7 (2.2-11.5) hours (P = 0.001)], time in the intensive care unit [group 1: 6 (3-85) days vs. group 2: 3 (1-54) days (P = 0.001)], median hospitalization time [group 1: 23 (14-105) days vs. group 2: 18 (10-63) days (P = 0.018)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No statistical difference was observed for the recurrence-free survival of 40% after 3 years (P = 0.311), the mortality rate, the morbidity rate (P = 0.108), surgical and respiratory complications, and the incidence of anastomotic leakage (P = 0.645) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We conclude that in selected cases it may be possible to perform an extended gastrectomy for small type I <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancers</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>