<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Prediction of progression to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (BE) is difficult using current techniques </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We determined whether DNA promoter hypermethylation of genes frequently methylated in esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (p16 and APC) could be used as predictors of progression in BE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We first performed a cross-sectional study to evaluate the prevalence of gene hypermethylation in biopsies from patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> esophagus (n=17), BE (n=102), and <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (n=42) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We then performed a nested case-control study comparing gene hypermethylation in BE patients who progressed from baseline pathology to high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> (n=7) vs. patients who did not progress (n=50) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: None of the patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> esophagus had p16 or APC hypermethylation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Hypermethylation was prevalent in BE without <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> or low-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> (p16=31% and APC=50%; P&lt;0.01) and high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> or <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (p16=54% and APC=68%; P&lt;0.001) compared with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> esophagus (not detected) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients who progressed from baseline pathology to high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> had higher prevalence of hypermethylation in their initial esophagus biopsies compared with those who did not progress for both p16 (100 vs. 33%; P=0.008) and APC (86 vs. 40%; P=0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Hypermethylation of both p16 and APC was a strong predictor of subsequent progression to high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> during a mean follow-up time of 4.1 years (odds ratio (95% confidence interval)=14.97 (1.73,inf), P=0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Among patients who were negative for both p16 and APC hypermethylation, none progressed from baseline pathology to high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Hypermethylation of both p16 and APC strongly predicts progression to high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> in patients with BE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Absence of p16 and APC hypermethylation is associated with a benign course </plain></SENT>
</text></document>