<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: The aim of this study was to determine the contribution of preoperative gastric secretory and hormonal response, to the appearance of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> in the esophageal stump following subtotal esophagectomy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Thirty-eight end-stage chagasic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002571'>achalasia</z:hpo> patients submitted to esophagectomy and cervical gastric pull-up were followed prospectively for a mean of 13.6 +/- 9.2 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Gastric acid secretion, pepsinogen, and gastrin were measured preoperatively in 14 patients who have developed <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (Group I), and the results were compared to 24 patients who did not develop <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (Group II) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In the group (I), the mean basal and stimulated preoperative gastric acid secretion was significantly higher than in the group II (basal: 1.52 vs. 1.01, p = 0.04; stimulated: 20.83 vs. 12.60, p = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Basal and stimulated preoperative pepsinogen were also increased at the Group I compared to Group II (Basal = 139.3 vs. 101.7, p = 0.02; stimulated = 186.0 vs. 156.5, p = 0.07 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There was no difference in preoperative gastrin between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>Gastritis</z:hpo> was present during endoscopy in 57.1% of the Group I, while it was detected in 16.6% of the Group II, p = 0.014 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> in the esophageal stump was associated to high preoperative levels of gastric acid secretion, serum pepsinogen, and also <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> in the transposed stomach </plain></SENT>
</text></document>