<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We re-evaluated a cohort of patients referred for reflux symptoms and objectively diagnosed with pathological reflux, with the purpose of clarifying the course of conservatively treated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL AND METHODS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> consecutive patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> diagnosed between 1984 and 1988 showing pathologic 24-h pH-metry in the interval 3.8-10% and without any previous surgery in the gastroesophageal tract were assessed for further follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A total of 40 evaluable patients were followed in the years 2007-08 with endoscopy, manometry, 24-h pH-metry, Helicobacter pylori assessment and the self-administered questionnaires the <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> Impact Scale, the Reflux Disease Questionnaire, the Quality of Life in Reflux and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0013395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Dyspepsia</z:e> and the Medical Outcome Study Short Form-36 Health Survey </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Baseline data from the 1980s were retrieved and compared with the evaluations conducted at follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At follow-up 20.7 years (range 18.8-23.5 years) after referral, the study population showed more use of acid suppressants (p = 0.007) and increasing prevalences of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (p = 0.001) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (p = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>Esophagitis</z:hpo> was seen in 16/40 patients (40%) at baseline and in 29/40 (72.5%) at follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>No significant deterioration was seen at follow-up in manometry data and in most pH data </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (ERD) were less likely to have a positive H. pylori test (hazard ratio 0.054; p = 0.002) than non-erosive (NERD) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Symptom evaluations showed significantly lower quality of life in the ERD group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>After 20 years a considerable part of the cohort still experienced symptoms of reflux and showed endoscopic progression, although no significant deteriorations were seen in manometry data and in most pH-metry data </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was inversely associated with erosive <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> and this supports the hypothesis that H. pylori colonization is a protective factor against <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>