<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011459'>esophageal carcinoma</z:hpo> (EC) report deficits in quality of life (QOL), depending on the extent of malignant disease and the goals of treatment at the time of QOL measurement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>AIMS: To quantify the association of marital status and changes in QOL over time in patients with EC and patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (BE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Eligible patients in the Mayo Clinic Esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>Adenocarcinoma</z:mp> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's Esophagus</z:hpo> Registry completed QOL assessments at baseline and approximately 1 year later </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>QOL was determined with a ten-point linear analog self-assessment scale evaluating overall QOL and 12 subscales </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Overall, 489 BE patients and 212 EC patients were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Married EC patients reported higher baseline QOL in legal concerns (8.1 vs. 7.1; p = .04) and friend and family support (9.3 vs. 8.4; p = .02) than single EC patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Over time, married EC patients had a decrease in pain frequency QOL compared to single EC patients (-0.9 vs. +0.6; p = .02), with other QOL measures being stable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Married BE patients showed higher social activity QOL at baseline than single BE patients (7.5 vs. 6.9; p = .02); QOL was stable over time between the marital status groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Minor, but statistically significant, changes were reported regarding QOL in two categories at baseline and over time among married and single patients with EC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Minor differences may be present between married and single EC patients regarding spiritual QOL at baseline and in overall physical well-being QOL at baseline and over time, although these differences did not reach statistical significance </plain></SENT>
</text></document>