<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>Obesity</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux</z:hpo>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> have <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> been linked to esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In addition, the decline in Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in affluent societies has also been suggested to be a major factor in the recent rise in the incidence of esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>If H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> has a protective role, populations with a naturally low prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> such as the ethnic Malays of Northeastern Peninsular Malaysia should have high rates of esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>AIM: To test this hypothesis, we investigated the incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011459'>esophageal carcinoma</z:hpo> among the ethnic Malays of the state of Kelantan in Northeastern Peninsular Malaysia </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The pathology services in the state of Kelantan are provided by two main hospitals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The histopathological records of both hospitals were systematically examined to retrieve <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cases of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011459'>esophageal carcinoma</z:hpo> diagnosed between 2004 and 2008 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Incidence rates were determined based on the most recent population census </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The age-standardized incidence rates (per 100,000 population) of esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> among Malay men and women were 0.75 and 0.69, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The corresponding rates for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002860'>squamous cell carcinoma</z:hpo> of the esophagus were 0.66 and 1.34, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The low rates of <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002860'>squamous cell carcinoma</z:hpo> of the esophagus in the study area, despite the fact that H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> is virtually absent, does not support the hypothesis that the absence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> is a pivotal factor in the pathogenesis of these <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancers</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>