<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND AIM: An algorithm (GastroPanel) for the non-invasive diagnosis of atrophic <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> has been previously proposed, based on serum pepsinogen-I, gastrin-17, and Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) antibodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of the present study was to evaluate whether serum markers correlate with and predict gastric <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The baseline data of the prospective ProGERD study, a study on the long-term course of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> (n=6215 patients), served to select patients with atrophic <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> diagnosed in biopsies from gastric antrum and corpus, and control cases without <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A total of 208 pairs were matched for age, sex, <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> status (erosive vs non-erosive), presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, and histological H. pylori status were retrieved </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Serum pepsinogen-I, gastrin-17, and H. pylori antibodies were determined using specific enzyme immunoassays </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A significant negative correlation was found between the degree of corpus <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> and the level of serum pepsinogen-I </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A previously-reported negative correlation between the degree of antral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> and serum gastrin-17 could not be confirmed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The low sensitivity (0.32) and specificity (0.70) of the GastroPanel algorithm were mainly due to over diagnosis and under diagnosis of advanced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> in the antrum </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The diagnostic validity of the GastroPanel algorithm to diagnose gastric <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> non-invasively is not sufficient for general use in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>