<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: to investigate the endoscopy and histology of short-segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (SSBE) and cardia <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> (CIM), and their correlation with Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: biopsy specimens were taken from 32 SSBE patients and 41 CIM patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> appearance of the esophagogastric junction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Eight biopsy specimens from the lower esophagus, cardia, and gastric antrum were stained with <z:chebi fb="1" ids="51686">hematoxylin</z:chebi>/eosin, Alcian blue/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="29149">periodic acid</z:chebi>-Schiff, Alcian blue/high iron <z:chebi fb="3" ids="15571,23666">diamine</z:chebi> and Gimenez dye </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Results were graded independently by one pathologist </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: the SSBE patients were younger than the CIM patients (P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The incidence of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> and incomplete <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> subtype was higher in SSBE patients than in CIM patients (P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was correlated with antral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> (P &lt; 0.05), but not with reflux symptomatic, endoscopic, or histological markers of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> in CIM patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>SSBE was correlated with reflux symptomatic and endoscopic <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (P &lt; 0.01), but not with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and antral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> risk is significantly greater in SSBE patients than in CIM patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CIM is a manifestation of H. pylori-associated and multifocal atrophic <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo>, whereas SSBE may result from <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GERD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>