<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To investigate the relationship between <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (BE), a rat model of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux</z:hpo> with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was established and the degree of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, incidence of BE and esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (EA) were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Eight-week-old male specific-pathogen-free SD rats were divided into five groups randomly: pseudo-operation group; esophagojejunum anastomosis (EJA) group; EJA with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> group; EJA with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="41423">celecoxib</z:chebi>-treated group; EJA with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="41423">celecoxib</z:chebi>-treated group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Rats were kept for 30 weeks after surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Esophageal lesion was evaluated grossly and microscopically </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The expression of COX-2 and CDX2 was determined by RT-PCR and immunohistochemistry staining </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The level of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26338">PGE</z:chebi>₂ was assessed by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Esophageal mucosal injury in the group of EJA with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was decreased than that in EJA group (p &lt; .05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The incidence of BE and EA in rats undergoing EJA with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was increased than in rats undergoing EJA with no statistical difference </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="41423">Celecoxib</z:chebi> treatment decreased the incidence of EA in rats undergoing EJA with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> (p &lt; .05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The expression of CDX2 <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> was decreased in rats with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> or treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="41423">celecoxib</z:chebi> than in the rats of pseudo-operation group (p &lt; .05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>When compared with those in rats of pseudo-operation group, the expression of COX-2 mRNA and the level of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26338">PGE</z:chebi>₂ were upregulated in rats undergoing EJA irrespective of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> (p &lt; .05) and downregulated in rats treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="41423">celecoxib</z:chebi> (p &lt; .05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>When H. pylori colonized in esophagus, the severity of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> and the incidence of BE and EA were increased significantly </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Higher levels of COX-2 expression and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26338">PGE</z:chebi>₂ were detected in rats with esophageal H. pylori colonization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: When H. pylori infect in stomach, it may reduce the severity of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>However, when colonizes in esophagus, H. pylori increases the severity of <z:mp ids='MP_0003278'>esophageal inflammation</z:mp> and the incidence of BE and EA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="41423">Celecoxib</z:chebi> administration attenuates the incidence of EA by inhibiting COX-2 expression </plain></SENT>
</text></document>