<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Infection</z:e> with Helicobacter pylori is associated with significantly reduced risks of oesophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp>; however, few studies have examined the association between H. pylori and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> (BO), the precursor lesion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We explored the relationship between H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and BO and sought to identify potential modifiers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We compared the prevalence of positive H. pylori serology among 217 adults with simple BO (without <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>), 95 with dysplastic BO and 398 population controls sourced from the metropolitan Brisbane area </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We determined H. pylori serostatus using enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>To estimate relative risks, we calculated odds ratios (OR) and 95% confidence intervals (CI) using multivariable logistic regression in the entire sample and stratified by factors known to cause BO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of H. pylori seropositivity was 12%, 3%, and 18%, respectively, among patients with simple BO, dysplastic BO and population controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>BO patients were significantly less likely to have antibodies for H. pylori (Simple BO: OR = 0.51, 95% CI: 0.30-0.86; Dysplastic BO: OR = 0.10, 95% CI: 0.03-0.33) than population controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>For simple BO, the association was diminished after adjustment for frequency of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017168" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GERD">gastro-oesophageal reflux</z:e> (GOR) symptoms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Adjustment for frequency of GOR symptoms did not substantially alter the observed effect for dysplastic BO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Although there was some variation in the magnitude of risk estimates across strata of age, sex, GOR symptoms and use of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="49200">proton pump inhibitors</z:chebi> or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37961">H2-receptor antagonists</z:chebi>, the differences were uniformly nonsignificant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> is inversely associated with BO, and our findings suggest that decreased acid load is not the only mechanism underlying the H. pylori protective effect </plain></SENT>
</text></document>