<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Probe-based confocal laser endomicroscopy (pCLE) is an imaging technique that allows real-time in vivo histological assessment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (BE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The objectives of this study were to create and test novel pCLE criteria for dysplastic BE (phase I), and to evaluate accuracy, interobserver variability, and learning curve in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> prediction (phase II) using these criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In phase I, using 50 pCLE videos, a pCLE expert and gastrointestinal pathologist formulated new BE criteria by consensus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>These criteria were tested and refined in an independent set of 30 pCLE videos </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In phase II, a formal training session for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> assessors (three each experts/trainees) was conducted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Finally, using 75 testing videos, each video was interpreted as <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> (high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> (HGD)/<z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>) vs. no <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> and the assessors' confidence in interpretation was noted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Interobserver agreement and accuracy (95% confidence interval (CI)) were determined for BE histology prediction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of multiple pCLE criteria tested (phase I), only those with ≥70% sensitivity or specificity were included in the final set: epithelial surface: saw-toothed; cells: enlarged; cells: pleomorphic; glands: not equidistant; glands: unequal in size and shape; goblet cells: not easily identified </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Overall accuracy in diagnosing <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> was 81.5% (95% CI: 77.5-81), with no difference between experts vs. non-experts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Accuracy of prediction was significantly higher when endoscopists were "confident" about their diagnosis (98% (95-99) vs. 62% (54-70), P&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Accuracy of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> prediction for the first 30 videos was not different from the last 45 (93 vs. 81%, P=0.51) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Overall agreement of the criteria was substantial, κ=0.61 (0.53-0.69), with no difference between experts and non-experts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: We demonstrate the development and validation of new pCLE criteria for the prediction of HGD/<z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> in BE patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Using these criteria, this study demonstrated that overall accuracy in predicting <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> was high with substantial interobserver agreement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>After a structured teaching session, accuracy and agreement between experienced and non-experienced observers was not different, suggesting a short learning curve </plain></SENT>
</text></document>