<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To establish the prevalence and risk factors of erosive <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (EE) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (BE) among patients routinely referred for upper endoscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL AND METHODS: A total of 4032 consecutive patients referred to a regional hospital for upper endoscopy due to upper gastrointestinal and/or "alarm" symptoms were examined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Analysis was performed on the prospectively selected patients (40 in each group) with EE of different grades and BE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: EE was diagnosed in 474 patients (11.75%): grade A, in 194 (41%); grade B, in 167 (35%); grade C, in 65 (14%); and grade D, in 48 patients (10%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Increasing severity of erosive <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> and presence of its complication--<z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>--were associated with the decreasing prevalence of H. pylori and increasing <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatal hernia</z:hpo> size (P&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Male gender (OR, 3.57; 95% CI, 1.12 to 10.62), <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatal hernia</z:hpo> &gt;2 cm (OR, 3.73; 95% CI, 1.60 to 8.68), and absence of H. pylori (OR, 4.24; 95% CI, 1.07 to 16.84) were the factors found to be associated with severe EE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The factors associated with BE were as follows: <z:mpath ids='MPATH_579'>ulcer</z:mpath> and/or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0014866" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">stricture of esophagus</z:e> (OR, 11.94; 95% CI, 2.51 to 41.37), age &gt;60 years (OR, 1.06; 95% CI, 1.01 to 1.20), smoking &gt;10 cigarettes per day (OR, 4.62; 95% CI, 1.01 to 12.50), <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatal hernia</z:hpo> &gt;2 cm (OR, 5.22; 95% CI, 1.86 to 14.64), and absence of H. pylori (OR, 5.60; 95% CI, 1.38 to 22.72) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The prevalence of EE was found to be low, and the prevalence of BE was found to be very low among routinely endoscoped patients in primary and secondary care settings in a Lithuanian rural area with high H. pylori prevalence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Increasing severity of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> was associated with the decreasing prevalence of Helicobacter pylori </plain></SENT>
</text></document>