<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0267167" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Functional dyspepsia</z:e> is a group of disorders featuring symptoms believed to be derived from the stomach and duodenum such as upper abdominal discomfort, pain, postprandial fullness and early satiety </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A key diagnostic requisite is the absence of organic, metabolic, or systemic disorders to explain "dyspeptic symptoms." Therefore, when <z:hpo ids='HP_0004398'>peptic ulcer</z:hpo> diseases (including scars), erosive <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> and upper gastrointestinal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancies</z:e> are found at endoscopic examinations, the diagnosis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0267167" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">functional dyspepsia</z:e> is excluded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>One notable exception, however, is <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>According to the Rome III definition, H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> is included in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0267167" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">functional dyspepsia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>This is an obvious deviation from the diagnostic principle of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0267167" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">functional dyspepsia</z:e>, since H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> is a definite cause of mucosal <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, which affects a number of important gastric <z:mp ids='MP_0001532'>physiologies</z:mp> such as acid secretion, gastric <z:chebi fb="32" ids="24621">endocrine</z:chebi> function and motility </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> persistent nature of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> also results in more dramatic mucosal changes such as <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> or <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath>, the presence of which in the esophagus (<z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>) precludes the diagnosis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0267167" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">functional dyspepsia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Since careful endoscopic examination can diagnose reliably H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> not only in Japan but also in Western contries, it is now feasible and more logical to exclude patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0005231'>chronic gastritis</z:hpo> caused by H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> as having dyspeptic symptoms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>It is time to establish the Asian consensus to declare that H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> should be separated from <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0267167" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">functional dyspepsia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>