<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Previous studies comparing the prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> in Latinos and non-Latino whites are inconsistent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of the study is to compare the prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> in Latinos and non-Latino whites and to determine risk factors associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Between March 2005 and January 2009, consecutive Latino and non-Latino white patients who underwent endoscopy for primary indication for symptoms of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> were identified by examining the internal endoscopy database at Los Angeles County + USC Medical Center </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> was defined by columnar-lined distal esophagus on endoscopy confirmed by <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> on histology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Clinical features and endoscopic findings were retrospectively reviewed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The mean age of the 663 patients was 50 ± 12 years, 30% were male, and 92% were Latino </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Compared with non-Latino whites, Latinos had more females (72% vs. 46%; P = 0.0001) and more <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> (53% vs. 24%; P = 0.003) but less tobacco use (7% vs. 17%; P = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Overall, 10% (68/663) of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients had <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> whereas the prevalence was 10% (62/611) among the Latinos and 12% (6/52) among the non-Latino whites (OR 0.9, 95% CI 0.4-2.1; P = 0.75) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>One patient in the Latino group had high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>On multivariate analysis, male gender (AOR 2.3, 95% CI 1.4-4.1; P = 0.002), <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (AOR 2.2, 95% CI 1.1-4.5; P = 0.03), and age ≥55 years (AOR 2.2, 95% CI 1.3-3.8; P = 0.006) were independently associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>; Latino ethnicity remained nonsignificant (AOR 1.1, 95% CI 0.4-2.7; P = 0.88) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In Latinos undergoing endoscopy for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> symptoms, the prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> was 10%, comparable with non-Latino white controls as well as the prevalence previously reported among Caucasians </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In addition to established risk factors, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>