<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine the prevalence of gastrointestinal (GI) manifestations associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (DM) in a Taiwanese population undergoing bidirectional endoscopies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Subjects voluntarily undergoing upper endoscopy/colonoscopy as part of a medical examination at the National Taiwan University Hospital were recruited during 2009 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Diagnosis of DM included past history of DM, fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> ≥ 126 mg/dL, or glycated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> (HbA(1c)) ≥ 6.5% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Comparisons were made between diabetic and nondiabetic subjects, subjects with lower and higher HbA(1c) levels, and diabetic subjects with and without complications, respectively, for their GI symptoms, noninvasive GI testing results, and endoscopic findings </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Among 7,770 study subjects, 722 (9.3%) were diagnosed with DM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The overall prevalence of GI symptoms was lower in DM subjects (30.3 vs. 35.4%, P = 0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the prevalence of erosive <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (34.3 vs. 28.6%, P = 0.002), <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (0.6 vs. 0.1%, P = 0.001), <z:hpo ids='HP_0004398'>peptic ulcer</z:hpo> disease (14.8 vs. 8.5%, P &lt; 0.001), gastric <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasms</z:hpo> (1.8 vs. 0.7%, P = 0.003), and colonic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasms</z:hpo> (26.6 vs. 16.5%, P &lt; 0.001) was higher in diabetic subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Diagnostic accuracy of immunochemical fecal occult blood test for colonic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasms</z:hpo> was significantly decreased in DM (70.7 vs. 81.7%, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Higher HbA(1c) levels were associated with a decrease of GI symptoms and an increase of endoscopic abnormalities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Diabetic subjects with complications had a higher prevalence of colonic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasms</z:hpo> (39.2 vs. 24.5%, P = 0.002) than those without </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: DM and higher levels of HbA(1c) were associated with lower prevalence of GI symptoms but higher prevalence of endoscopic abnormalities </plain></SENT>
</text></document>