<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND/AIMS: The relationship between gastroesophageal junction <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (GEJA) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> is not well defined; thus, we retrospectively investigated this relationship </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We examined 852 cases (646 men) of <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>GEJA was defined as type II according to the classification system of Siewert and Stein </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We compared the prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and corporal <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> in GEJA patients with distal <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: GEJA was observed in 80 (including 6 cases of Barrett's <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0546837,C0014859" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">esophageal cancer</z:e>) of the 852 cases of <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> examined (9.4%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The rate of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was significantly lower in patients with GEJA than in patients with distal <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> (73.8 vs. 94.1%, p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of corporal <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> was also significantly lower in patients with GEJA than in patients with distal <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> (80.7 vs. 94.6%, p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Concurrent H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and corporal <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> were not observed in patients with Barrett's <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0546837,C0014859" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">esophageal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our study demonstrated that GEJA has 2 etiologic types; one of these types is associated with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and resembles distal <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo>, and the other one is not associated with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> or Barrett's <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0546837,C0014859" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">esophageal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>