<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The effect of Helicobacter pylori on <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> is poorly understood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We conducted a meta-analysis to summarize the existing literature examining the effect that H. pylori has on <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>DESIGN:  We performed a comprehensive search to identify studies pertaining to the association between H. pylori and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We conducted meta-regression analyses to identify sources of variation in the effect of H. pylori on <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS:  Our analysis included a total of 49 studies that examined the effect of H. pylori on <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and seven studies that examined the effect of cag A positivity on <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Overall, H. pylori, and even more so cag A, tended to be protective for <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> in most studies; however, there was obvious <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo> across studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The effect of H. pylori on <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> varied by geographic location and in the presence of selection and information biases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Only four studies were found without obvious selection and information bias, and these showed a protective effect of H. pylori on <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (Relative risk = 0.46 [95% CI: 0.35, 0.60]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS:  Estimates for the effect of H. pylori on <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> were <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneous</z:hpo> across studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We identified selection and information bias as potential sources of this <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Few studies without obvious selection and information bias have been conducted to examine the effect of H. pylori on <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, but in these, H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> is associated with a reduced risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>