<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>While dietary <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidants</z:chebi> are emerging as potentially modifiable risk factors for esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (EAC), studies on dietary <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidants</z:chebi> and its precursor <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (BE) are limited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The present study extends previous work on BE by investigating risks of nondysplastic BE, dysplastic BE and EAC associated with intake of <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidants</z:chebi> such as <z:chebi fb="122" ids="21241">vitamin C</z:chebi>, vitamin E, β-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="23042">carotene</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="19" ids="27568">selenium</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Age and sex matched control subjects (n=577 for BE; n=1,507 for EAC) were sampled from an Australian population register </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Information on demography, and well established EAC risk factors were obtained using self-administered questionnaires </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Intake of <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidants</z:chebi> for patients newly diagnosed with nondysplastic BE (n=266), dysplastic BE (n=101), or EAC (n=299), aged 18-79 years, were obtained using a food frequency questionnaire </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Odds ratios (OR) and 95% confidence intervals (CI) were estimated using multivariable adjusted logistic regression models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>High intake of β-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="23042">carotene</z:chebi> from food and supplement sources combined was inversely associated with risk of dysplastic BE (OR Q4 vs. Q1=0.45; 95%CI: 0.20-1.00) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>High intake of vitamin E from food sources (OR Q4 vs. Q1=0.43; 95%CI: 0.28-0.67), from food and supplements combined (OR Q4 vs. Q1=0.64; 95%CI: 0.43-0.96), and a high <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> index score were inversely associated with risk of EAC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We found no significant trends between intake of β-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="23042">carotene</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="122" ids="21241">vitamin C</z:chebi>, vitamin E, and <z:chebi fb="19" ids="27568">selenium</z:chebi> and risk of nondysplastic or dysplastic BE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, our data suggest that a high intake of β-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="23042">carotene</z:chebi> may be associated with decreased risk of dysplastic BE </plain></SENT>
</text></document>