<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (BE) is considered a complication of the <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> provoked by acid and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0005403" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bile reflux</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Endothelin-1 (ET-1) expresses in various cells during inflammatory process </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, the role of ET-1 in human inflamed and uninflamed esophageal tissue is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The present study aimed to examine the expression of ET-1 and its receptors in human reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (RE) and BE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Endoscopic biopsies of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> squamous epithelium (NSE) (n = 20), RE (n = 22), and long segment BE (n = 14) were obtained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The segmental degree of endoscopic and histopathological <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> was graded, and immunohistochemistry and real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction were used to determine the expression of ET-1 and endothelin receptor A (ET(A)R) and endothelin receptor B (ET(B)R) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>ET-1 and ET(A)R <z:chebi fb="5" ids="33699">messenger RNA</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi>) levels were higher in RE than in NSE (3.25 ± 1.78 vs. 1.10 ± 0.71, P = 0.000; 2.13 ± 1.06 vs. 1.12 ± 0.64, P = 0.001, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In BE, relative ET-1 mRNA levels in the proximal segment were higher than in the distal segment (3.03 ± 1.83 vs. 1.16 ± 0.70, P = 0.004) and in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> esophageal epithelium (P = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was no significantly difference of ET(A)R <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> levels between the proximal segment and the distal segment (1.99 ± 1.28 vs. 1.14 ± 0.67, P = 0.072) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>ET(B)R <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression was unaltered between the groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, immunohistochemistry demonstrated that ET-1 expression increased significantly in RE (51.18 ± 30.14) compared with those in NSE (21.10 ± 18.17, P = 0.000) and in distal BE segment (28.02 ± 24.92, P = 0.022) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>There were more ET-1 positive cells in proximal BE segment (50.07 ± 25.88) than in distal BE segment (P = 0.030) and in NSE (P = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>ET-1 expression increased in a stepwise manner with the growing degree of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, and there were significant differences between mild, moderate, and marked degree <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (36.08 ± 27.84, 65.86 ± 11.82, 98.00 ± 8.49, P = 0.003, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>However, expression of receptors remained unchanged </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>This study demonstrates that over-expression of ET-1 and ET(A)R in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> may be related to the inflammatory process </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>ET-1 may play a significant role in the progression of Barrett's <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>