<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Practitioners have noted a striking increase in the number of young patients under the age of 40 years old who develop esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to characterize the presentation, pathology and therapeutic outcome of these young patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The records of patients who presented to the Foregut Surgical Service at the University of Southern California with esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> between 2000 and 2007 were retrospectively reviewed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The presentation, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> stage and histology, therapy and outcome of the patients under the age of 40 were compared to those ≥40 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of the 374 patients reviewed, 20 (5 %) were under the age of 40 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There were two patients in their second and 18 in their third decade of life </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The youngest patient was 25 years old </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> was less common in patients &lt;40 than in those ≥40; 15 and 5 % compared to 61 and 46 % </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Similarly, patients &lt;40 had a significantly longer time interval between the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of symptoms and the diagnosis of their <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> than those ≥40; 4.5 vs. 2 months, p = 0.04 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>They also had a higher prevalence of stage IV disease (30 vs. 6 %, p = 0.0003), a shorter time to recurrence (9.5 vs.19 month, p = 0.002), and a poorer median survival (17 vs. 43 month, p = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Esophageal <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> in patients &lt;40 years old commonly presents with an advanced stage of the disease and an associated poor survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>This is likely due to a low index of suspicion that <z:hpo ids='HP_0002015'>dysphagia</z:hpo> seen in younger patients is due to a <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancy</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>