<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Background and study aims: Radiofrequency ablation (RFA) is safe and effective for the eradication of neoplastic <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>; however, occasionally there is minimal regression after initial circumferential balloon-based RFA (c-RFA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to identify predictive factors for a poor response 3 months after c-RFA, and to relate the percentage regression at 3 months to the final treatment outcome.Methods: We included consecutive patients from 14 centers who underwent c-RFA for high grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> at worst </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patient and treatment characteristics were registered prospectively. "Poor initial response" was defined as &lt; 50 % regression of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> 3 months after c-RFA, graded by two expert endoscopists using endoscopic images </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Predictors of initial response were identified through logistic regression analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Results: There were 278 patients included (median Barrett's segment C4M6) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In poor initial responders (n = 36; 13 %), complete response for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo> (CR-<z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo>) was ultimately achieved in 86 % (vs. 98 % in good responders; P &lt; 0.01) and complete response for <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath> (CR-IM) in 66 % (vs. 95 %; P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Poor responders required 13 months treatment (vs. 7 months; P &lt; 0.01) for a median of four RFA sessions (vs. three; P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>We identified four independent baseline predictors of poor response: active reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (odds ratio [OR] 37.4; 95 % confidence interval [CI] 3.2 - 433.2); endoscopic resection scar regeneration with Barrett's epithelium (OR 4.7; 95 %CI 1.1 - 20.0); <z:mp ids='MP_0003276'>esophageal narrowing</z:mp> pre-RFA (OR 3.9; 95 %CI 1.0 - 15.1); and years of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo> pre-RFA (OR 1.2; 95 %CI 1.0 - 1.4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: Patients with a poor initial response to c-RFA have a lower ultimate success rate for CR-<z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo>/CR-IM, require more treatment sessions, and a longer treatment period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A poor initial response to c-RFA occurs more frequently in patients who regenerate their endoscopic resection scar with Barrett's epithelium, and those with ongoing reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> for a longer time, or a <z:mp ids='MP_0010884'>narrow esophagus</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>