<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Endoscopists with extensive experience with confocal endomicroscopy (CEM) have demonstrated that this technology is useful for <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (BE) surveillance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, data on endoscopists with minimal experience with this technique are limited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>HYPOTHESIS: For BE surveillance, an endoscopist with minimal experience in CEM-guided biopsy would achieve a similar diagnostic yield with fewer biopsies when compared to the random 4-quadrant biopsy protocol </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To compare the diagnostic yields of CEM-guided biopsy technique with the random 4-quadrant biopsy protocol </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>DESIGN: Randomized controlled trial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>SETTING: Tertiary care center </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS: Patients with BE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Out of 18 patients who underwent routine BE surveillance, 11 and 7 were randomly assigned to group A (CEM-guided) and to group B (random 4-quadrant biopsy), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The pathologists were blinded to <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> clinical information </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Mean length of endoscopic Barrett was similar in both groups, (5.1 vs. 6.3 cm, p=0.51) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The diagnostic yields for detecting SIM (63.6% vs. 59.5%, p=0.5), low grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> (11 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>6% vs. 11.2%, p=NS), high grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> (10.1% vs. 11.5%, p=0.88) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Although the total number of individual mucosal biopsy performed were 52% lower in the CEM group (129 vs. 269), the overall diagnostic yield (85.3% vs. 82.2%, p=0.53) was similar in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>LIMITATIONS: Small sample size </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: For BE surveillance, limited data suggested that endoscopists with minimal experience in CEM can effective use this technology for "smart" biopsy to decrease the need for intense tissue sampling but without lowering the diagnostic yield in detecting <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>