<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>In order to demonstrate the presence of Helicobacter pylori in the metaplastic epithelium of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> and to evaluate its possible association with this entity, we examined 29 cases of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> where concomitant antral biopsies were also available </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>These cases were compared with an equal number of age and sex matched controls of uncomplicated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>H. pylori was present in 11 of 29 cases of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> (38%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>No increase in the frequency of H. pylori antral <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> was found in patients of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> compared to the control group of uncomplicated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677659,C0014869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">reflux oesophagitis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The positivity of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> for H. pylori correlated with the presence of H. pylori antral <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> (P &lt; 0.05), although in two cases of H. pylori-positive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> antral biopsies were negative for H. pylori </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>No difference was found in the severity of inflammatory and dysplastic changes of H. pylori-positive and H. pylori-negative <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Presence of H. pylori does not seem to alter the natural history of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004763" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CELLO">Barrett's oesophagus</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>