<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To compare esophageal motor function in patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> with controls, and identify patient characteristics that may have a bearing on the severity of esophageal motor dysfunction and acid exposure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Esophageal motor function was assessed in 60 patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients had manometry, 50 had an esophageal transit test, and 23 had an acid clearance test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Forty-eight had dual site [5 and 10 cm above lower esophageal sphincter (LES)] esophageal pH monitoring, four had only distal pH monitoring, and one patient had only proximal pH monitoring </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Thirty-four controls underwent the same tests </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The association between the indices of esophageal function plus the degree of esophageal acid exposure and eight patient characteristics (age, sex, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, smoking, alcohol intake, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002036'>hiatus hernia</z:hpo>, grade of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo>, and Barrett's <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath>) was examined in unifactorial and multifactorial analysis of variance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The patients had significantly lower LES pressure, lower distal and middle esophageal amplitudes, longer duration of contraction, and slower velocity of propagation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>They had longer esophageal transit and acid clearance times </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Barrett's <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> was the only factor that had an association with the magnitude of esophageal motor dysfunction and acid exposure, except age, which had a weak positive association with acid exposure (p = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Compared to the rest of the patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo>, patients with Barrett's had lower LES pressure (median = 10.5 vs. 17.5 mm Hg, p = 0.013), longer supine transit time (median = 180 vs. 13.5 s, p = 0.0001), and higher % of total time pH &lt; 4 (median = 48.2 vs. 8.7 and 23.2 vs. 5.2; p &lt; 0.0001 for distal and proximal esophageal acid exposure, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Ten of the 12 patients with Barrett's had abnormal manometry, compared with 20 of the 48 without (chi 2 = 6.67; p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>There was a strong correlation between the degree of acid exposure in the proximal esophagus and the length of Barrett's segment (r = 0.846, 0.81, 0.725; and p &lt; 0.001, 0.005, 0.018, for the % of times pH &lt; 4 for total, supine, and upright periods, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The development of Barrett's <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> may be determined by the degree of esophageal exposure to the refluxate which, in turn, may be a function of the severity of esophageal motor dysfunction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The length of Barrett's segment may be dependent on the extent of orad transport of the refluxate </plain></SENT>
</text></document>