<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A prospective study was performed in 190 control subjects and in 236 patients with different degrees of endoscopic <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> in order to determine the prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> at duodenal gastric and esophageal mucosa and its correlation with histological findings </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients with pathologic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux</z:hpo> had 24-h pH monitoring studies confirming the presence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017168" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GERD">acid reflux</z:e> into the esophagus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Besides the endoscopic findings, biopsies were taken from the duodenal bulb, gastric antrum, gastric fundus and distal esophagus or at the specialized columnar epithelium in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients with pathological <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux</z:hpo> were divided into three groups: 55 with absence of endoscopic <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> (<z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux</z:hpo>), 81 patients with erosive <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> and 100 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There was no H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> present at duodenal or esophageal mucosa or at the specialized columnar epithelium of the distal esophagus in any case </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> at gastric antrum was similar in controls and in any group of patients with reflux disease (20-25% of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>No differences in age and sex distribution were seen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> at gastric fundus was very low (less than 5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The presence of HP <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> was correlated with the finding of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> active superficial or athrophic <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> while, in the absence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>, gastric mucosa was <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In the presence of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath>, no H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> occurred </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Based on these findings, it seems that there is no significant evidence for an important pathogenic role for H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in the development of pathologic <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux</z:hpo>, erosive <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, and the presence of antral <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> is closely related to the presence of H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>, and probably not related to an increased <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0013299" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">duodenogastric reflux</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>