<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Prospective evaluation of the prevalence of mucosa-associated lymphoid tissue (MALT) within <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> and its association with gastric MALT, gastric MALT <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, and H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: From <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> patients, a minimum of six gastric biopsies were obtained, in addition to Barrett's surveillance biopsies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Additional gastric biopsies were taken from any <z:mpath ids='MPATH_579'>ulcer</z:mpath>(s), nodule(s), <z:mpath ids='MPATH_491'>polyp</z:mpath>(s), or other lesions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux</z:hpo> symptoms without <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> served as controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: One hundred and thirty-nine Barrett's patients were included in the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>One hundred and twenty-two of these patients had gastric biopsies for gastric MALT and H. pylori determination </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>H. pylori was noted in the stomach of 48 patients and within Barrett's mucosa in 14 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Barrett's MALT was noted in seven cases, gastric MALT in 16, and gastric MALT <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> in two </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>None of the 101 control patients had esophageal MALT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Two of the seven patients with Barrett's MALT had gastric MALT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Barrett's MALT was associated with esophageal H. pylori in 57.1% cases and gastric H. pylori in 71.4% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of gastric and esophageal H. pylori in patients with Barrett's MALT was significantly higher compared to patients with Barrett's without MALT (p &lt; 0.0001 and p &lt; 0.007, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Barrett's MALT was very focal and its esophageal location variable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Barrett's MALT was associated with both esophageal and gastric H. pylori colonization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Esophageal MALT was associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Gastric biopsy sampling is warranted in any patient with Barrett's MALT to detect gastric MALT and H. pylori, which, if found, should be eradicated </plain></SENT>
</text></document>