<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Side effects of <z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">omeprazole</z:chebi> therapy include reversible hypergastrinemia, entero chromaffin-like <z:mpath ids='MPATH_134'>hyperplasia</z:mpath>, and possibly acceleration of atrophic <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> in the gastric corpus in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The objective of this report is to describe six cases of fundic gland <z:mpath ids='MPATH_491'>polyps</z:mpath> that developed while <z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">omeprazole</z:chebi> was being used for <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Three women and three men developed fundic gland <z:mpath ids='MPATH_491'>polyps</z:mpath> after 1-5 yr of <z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">omeprazole</z:chebi> therapy, 20 mg/day </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the index case, fundal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_491'>polyps</z:mpath> developed after 2 yr of continuous <z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">omeprazole</z:chebi> therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">Omeprazole</z:chebi> was stopped, but because of poor clinical efficacy with H2-blockers, it was reinstated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: After 4 yr of therapy, multiple large fundal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_491'>polyps</z:mpath> were present </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Histology of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> lesions revealed characteristic fundal gland <z:mpath ids='MPATH_491'>polyps</z:mpath> with multiple cystic dilations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>None of the patients had H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Serum gastrin was <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> in four and slightly increased in two </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: These cases support the possible causal relation between the use of <z:chebi fb="14" ids="7772">omeprazole</z:chebi> and the development of fundic gland <z:mpath ids='MPATH_491'>polyps</z:mpath> in patients without H. pylori <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>