<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Although the role of Helicobacter pylori in the pathogenesis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004398'>peptic ulcer</z:hpo> disease and antral <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> has been well documented, the role of H. pylori in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0014852" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">esophageal disease</z:e> has not been clearly defined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To clarify this issue, we analyzed 141 patients with histologically confirmed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0014852" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">esophageal disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The study group consisted of 82 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, 19 with <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of the esophagus arising in columnar epithelium and 40 patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> without columnar <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> of the esophagus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In each of these cases the presence or absence of H. pylori was assessed histologically </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: H. pylori was present in 19 of 82 patients (23%) with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo>, but was absent in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of the esophagus and in patients with reflux <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo> without Barrett's <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>H. pylori was found only in areas of gastric type <z:mpath ids='MPATH_160'>metaplasia</z:mpath> in the patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> of the 19 <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> group with H. pylori had <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, and in 16 the <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> was severe </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>H. pylori was significantly associated with severity of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> (p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Members of the Barrett's group with evidence of moderate to severe <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> were negative for H. pylori </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: These data confirm that the presence of gastric type mucosa within the esophagus is a prerequisite for H. pylori colonization, and that H. pylori may contribute to the severity of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> in Barrett's epithelium </plain></SENT>
</text></document>