<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Experimental studies have shown that the severity of esophageal mucosal injury in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002020'>gastroesophageal reflux disease</z:hpo> is related to the reflux of both gastric and duodenal juice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to determine whether duodenal juice potentiates esophageal injury in patients with reflux disease or, in fact, causes no harm allowing acid and pepsin to do the damage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A total of 148 consecutive patients who had no previous gastric or esophageal surgery underwent endoscopy and biopsy, manometry, and 24-hour esophageal pH and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16990">bilirubin</z:chebi> monitoring </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Esophageal injury was defined by the presence of erosive <z:hpo ids='HP_0100633'>esophagitis</z:hpo>, stricture, or biopsy-proved <z:hpo ids='HP_0100580'>Barrett's esophagus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Exposure to duodenal juice, identified by the absorbance of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16990">bilirubin</z:chebi>, was defined as an exposure time exceeding the ninety-fifth percentile measured in 35 volunteers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>To separate the effects of gastric and duodenal juice, patients were stratified according to their acid exposure time </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>One hundred patients had documented <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017168" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GERD">acid reflux</z:e> on pH monitoring, and in 63 of them it was combined with reflux of duodenal juice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients with combined reflux (50 of 63) were more likely to have injury than patients without combined reflux (22 of 37; P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>When the acid exposure time was greater than 10%, patients with injury (n = 40) had a greater exposure to duodenal juice (median exposure time 17.2% vs. 1.1%, P = 0.006) than patients without injury (n = 5), but there was no difference in their acid exposure (16.9% vs. 13.4%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> of Barrett's epithelium (n = 9) had a greater exposure to duodenal juice (median exposure time 30.2% vs. 7.2%, P = 0.04) compared to patients without complications (n = 25), whereas acid exposure was the same (16.4% vs. 15%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Duodenal juice adds a noxious component to the refluxed gastric juice and potentiates the injurious effects of gastric juice on the esophageal mucosa </plain></SENT>
</text></document>