<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: To look for the presence and strength of association of cervical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0338585" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid artery dissection</z:e> (CCAD) with a <z:hpo ids='HP_0004036'>long styloid process</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This case-control analysis included 35 patients with 37 affected carotid arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>CT angiograms of these patients were analyzed by two raters blinded to clinical and radiological diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Parameters assessed were styloid process length, its proximity to the cervical internal carotid artery, and its medial and anterior angulations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The same parameters were assessed in 70 CT angiograms in age and sex matched controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Interrater correlations were 0.87, 0.40, 0.71, and 0.79 for styloid process length, contact distance, medial angulation, and anterior angulation, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean styloid process length on the affected side was significantly more than on the contralateral side (37.8 vs. 34.6 mm, p = 0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There were also significant length and contact distance differences between the styloid processes ipsilateral to dissection and ipsilateral styloid processes of controls (38.9 vs. 36.2 mm, p = 0.05 and 3.1 vs. 5.0 mm, p = 0.05, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There were increasing odds ratios (OR) for dissection with increasing styloid process length, with OR of 4.36 (95 % CI = 1.04 to 18.4, p = 0.04) for length more than 50 mm </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>ORs for dissection increased with decreasing contact distance, with OR for distances less than 5 mm being 7.58 (95 % CI = 0.93 to 62.1, p = 0.06) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>There was no significant association of CCAD with angulation of the styloid process </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Length and contact distance of the styloid process are risk factors for CCAD, suggesting mechanical impingement </plain></SENT>
</text></document>