<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A 73-year-old woman with progressive proximal-dominant <z:hpo ids='HP_0003202'>muscular atrophy</z:hpo> and <z:mp ids='MP_0000746'>weakness</z:mp> was described </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>She had been well until 70-year-old, when she found <z:hpo ids='HP_0003698'>difficulty in standing</z:hpo> up from sitting position </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>At age 72 years, she could not raise her arms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Neurological examination showed muscular <z:mp ids='MP_0005150'>wasting</z:mp> and <z:mp ids='MP_0000746'>weakness</z:mp> in the proximal parts of extremities, shoulder and pelvic girdle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In the thigh, the flexors and adductors were severely affected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001324'>Muscular weakness</z:hpo> was also observed in m. tibialis anterior </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Serum CK and aldolase were <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Electromyography showed low voltage short duration motor unit potentials with positive sharp waves and <z:mp ids='MP_0006109'>fibrillations</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0003805'>Rimmed vacuoles</z:hpo> were observed in 4.8% of muscle fibers in biopsy sample obtained from right m. quadriceps femoris </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>No inflammatory cells, <z:chebi fb="61" ids="27565">PAS</z:chebi>-positive materials and inclusion bodies were observed in the sample </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This case differs from distal <z:hpo ids='HP_0003198'>myopathy</z:hpo> with <z:hpo ids='HP_0003805'>rimmed vacuoles</z:hpo>, because the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> was very late and her <z:hpo ids='HP_0001324'>muscular weakness</z:hpo> and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> was proximal dominant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>This case also differs from inclusion body <z:hpo ids='HP_0100614'>myositis</z:hpo>, because muscle biopsy revealed no inflammatory cells or inclusion body </plain></SENT>
</text></document>