<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265202" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Seckel syndrome</z:e> (OMIM 210600) is an <z:hpo ids='HP_0000007'>autosomal recessive</z:hpo> disorder characterized by <z:hpo ids='HP_0001511'>intrauterine growth retardation</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003510'>dwarfism</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000252'>microcephaly</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001249'>mental retardation</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Clinically, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265202" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Seckel syndrome</z:e> shares features in common with disorders involving impaired DNA-damage responses, such as <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0398791" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Nijmegen breakage syndrome</z:e> (OMIM 251260) and LIG4 syndrome (OMIM 606593) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We previously mapped a locus associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0265202" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Seckel syndrome</z:e> to chromosome 3q22.1-q24 in two consanguineous Pakistani families </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Further marker analysis in the families, including a recently born unaffected child with a recombination in the critical region, narrowed the region to an interval of 5 Mbp between markers D3S1316 and D3S1557 (145.29 Mbp and 150.37 Mbp) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The gene encoding <z:hpo ids='HP_0001251'>ataxia</z:hpo>-<z:hpo ids='HP_0001009'>telangiectasia</z:hpo> and Rad3-related protein (ATR) maps to this region </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A fibroblast cell line derived from an affected individual displays a defective DNA damage response caused by impaired ATR function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We identified a synonymous mutation in affected individuals that alters ATR splicing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The mutation confers a phenotype including marked <z:hpo ids='HP_0000252'>microcephaly</z:hpo> (head circumference 12 s.d. below the mean) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003510'>dwarfism</z:hpo> (5 s.d. below the mean) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Our analysis shows that UV-induced ATR activation can occur in non-replicating cells following processing by nucleotide excision repair </plain></SENT>
</text></document>