<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: There is limited information regarding the long-term outcome of children born after in vitro fertilization (IVF), although an increase in rare imprinted gene disorders such as <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004903" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Beckwith-Wiedemann syndrome</z:e> has been reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We recruited healthy, prepubertal children born at term after singleton pregnancy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The children in the study group were conceived using IVF with fresh embryo transfer, whereas controls were naturally conceived </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Anthropometric measurements, bone age, dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry, fasting serum <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile, IGF-I and -II, and IGF-binding proteins 1, 2, and 3 were performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were 69 IVF children aged 5.9 +/- 0.2 yr and 71 control children aged 6.9 yr </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>IVF children were taller than controls when corrected for parents' heights (height sd score of 1.05 +/- 0.1 vs. 0.51 +/- 0.11, P = 0.001) with higher levels of serum IGF-II (850 +/- 24 vs. 773 +/- 24 microg/liter, P = 0.03), higher IGF-I to IGF-binding protein 3 ratio (P = 0.04), and a trend toward higher IGF-I (105 +/- 4 vs. 92 +/- 4 microg/liter, P = 0.06) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>IVF children had higher <z:chebi fb="6" ids="39025">high-density lipoprotein</z:chebi> (1.67 +/- 0.04 mmol/liter vs. 1.53 +/- 0.04 mmol/liter, P = 0.02), lower <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi> (0.65 +/- 0.04 mmol/liter vs. 0.78 +/- 0.04 mmol/liter, P = 0.02), and a lower total to <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47775">high-density lipoprotein cholesterol</z:chebi> ratio (2.58 vs. 2.86, P = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There were no differences in body composition </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: IVF children are taller with higher IGF-I and IGF-II levels and have a slightly more favorable <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We speculate that IVF results in epigenetic change through altered methylation of genes involved in growth and metabolism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>IVF programs should consider long-term longitudinal follow-up of IVF offspring </plain></SENT>
</text></document>