<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To assess the frequency of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004903" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Beckwith-Wiedemann syndrome</z:e> (BWS) among fetuses with an ultrasound diagnosis of isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0001539'>omphalocele</z:hpo> and to examine relevant clinical variables, in particular route of conception </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: An ultrasound and consultation database (1988-2007) was searched and cases were included that met the following criteria: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001539'>omphalocele</z:hpo>, no additional major structural anomaly or autosomal <z:mp ids='MP_0004024'>aneuploidy</z:mp>, and either newborn examination or molecular diagnostic studies for BWS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Medical records were reviewed and a nested case-control analysis matching day of birth assessed the route of conception, given the changing prevalence of assisted reproduction during the study period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Thirty cases of isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0001539'>omphalocele</z:hpo> were identified </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004903" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Beckwith-Wiedemann syndrome</z:e> was diagnosed in six cases (6/30 [20.0%]); four by newborn examination (4/6) and two on prenatal molecular studies (2/6) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Of note, one case of BWS had a karyotype of 47,XXX, the remainder was euploid </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Compared with isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0001539'>omphaloceles</z:hpo>, fetuses with BWS more often were twins (3/6 vs. 1/24; p &lt; 0.001), had <z:hpo ids='HP_0001561'>polyhydramnios</z:hpo> (4/6 vs. 2/24; p &lt; 0.001), were macrosomic at birth (3/6 vs. 4/24 p &lt; 0.001), and had been conceived by assisted reproduction (3/6 vs. 2/22; p = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>When compared with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> controls matched by date of birth, conception by assisted reproductive technique among BWS births was highly significant, (p &lt; 0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004903" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Beckwith-Wiedemann syndrome</z:e> is present in a noteworthy portion of fetuses with isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0001539'>omphalocele</z:hpo> on ultrasound, and prenatal molecular studies are warranted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Even among this small cohort, a recurring theme of conception by assisted reproduction exists </plain></SENT>
</text></document>