<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A role of nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>/reperfusion (I/R) injury of brain in normotensive (Sprague-Dowley rats, SD) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>-prone spontaneously hypertensive rats (SHR-SP) was studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>Cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> was produced in rats by occlusion of the middle cerebral artery (<z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>NO and <z:chebi fb="38" ids="18421,29356">O2-</z:chebi> releases in the brain in response to <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion followed by reperfusion were simultaneously monitored (2h) using electrochemical microsensors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The size of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> was evaluated in the course of I/R from images of brain slices stained with 2,3,5-triphenyltetrazolium <z:chebi fb="76" ids="17996">chloride</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Similar patterns of NO and <z:chebi fb="38" ids="18421,29356">O2-</z:chebi> releases were exhibited for SD and SHR-SP rats in the entire course of the experiments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, the concentration of NO release was significantly lower during I/R in SHR-SP than in SD rats (the maximal NO concentration was 2.61 +/- 0.22 micromol/L for SD and 1.51 +/- 0.16 micromol/L for SHR-SP rats; *P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the concentration of <z:chebi fb="38" ids="18421,29356">O2-</z:chebi> release during <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> was significantly higher in SHR-SP than SD rats (the maximal increase was 122 +/- 24 nmol/L for SD and 220 +/- 44 nmol/L for SHR-SP rats; *P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> sizes revealed in the course of I/R were larger in SHR-SP than SD rats (1.8 +/- 0.4% vs. 1.1 +/- 0.4% at 30 min., 2.84 +/- 0.8% vs. 2.21 +/- 0.6% at 100 min. and 9.20 +/- 1.1% vs. 5.8 +/- 0.6% at 180 min. ofthe brain weights, respectively; *P &lt; 0.01 for each time-point) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>These studies indicate that nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> plays a protective role during I/R and deficiency of NO in SHR-SP rats is due to excess of <z:chebi fb="38" ids="18421,29356">O2-</z:chebi> production </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The deficiency in NO concentration correlates positively with the increase of cerebral I/R injury </plain></SENT>
</text></document>