<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The clinical features, etiology and neurological outcome of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> of unusual cause (ISUC) have rarely been reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We retrospective reviewed <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients with this <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> subtype entered in the Sagrat Cor Hospital of Barcelona <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo> Registry, which includes data from 2000 consecutive first-ever <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> patients admitted to the hospital between 1986 and 1995 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients with previous <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and/or hemorrhagic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> were excluded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Topographic, anamnestic, clinical and neuroimaging characteristics of ISUC were assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Predictors of this <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> subtype were determined by logistic regression analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>Ischemic stroke</z:hpo> of unusual etiology was diagnosed in 70 patients (32 men and 38 women), with a mean +/- SD age of 52 +/- 22.4 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>This <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> subtype accounted for 4.3% of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> first-ever <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>strokes</z:hpo> and 6% of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> first-ever brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Etiologies included <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0947743,C0018939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hematological disorders</z:e> in 17 cases, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in 11, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002076'>migraine</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> in 10, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> secondary to <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo> in nine, primary inflammatory vascular conditions in six and miscellaneous causes in 17 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the multivariate analysis after excluding <z:hpo ids='HP_0005305'>cerebral venous thrombosis</z:hpo> (n = 9) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0005294'>arterial dissection</z:hpo> (n = 4), because of typical clinical and radiological features, independent predictors of ISUC included 45 years of age or less (odds ratio [OR] 14.8), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001250'>seizures</z:hpo> (OR 6.8), <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> (OR 5.2), hemianopia (OR 2.6) and occipital lobe involvement (OR 3.0) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Patients with ISUC presented a lower in-hospital mortality rate (7.1% vs. 14.4%; P &lt; 0.05), were more frequently symptom free at discharge (35.7% vs. 25.80%; P &lt; 0.05) and experienced a longer mean length of hospital stay (23.7 days vs. 18.2 days; P = 0.06) than non-ISUC patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>We conclude that ISUC is infrequent, etiologies are numerous and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1521860" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hematologic disorders</z:e> are the most frequent cause </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>We emphasize the better prognosis and the need to distinguish it from other <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> subtypes which have a different treatment approach and outcome </plain></SENT>
</text></document>