<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="25941">Peroxynitrite</z:chebi> is responsible for nitration in vivo, whereas myeloperoxidase can also catalyze protein nitration in the presence of high <z:chebi fb="4" ids="16301,29423,29424,29785,29786,33101">NO2</z:chebi>(-) levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Recent reports of myeloperoxidase-mediated enzyme inactivation or <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation have suggested a role of myeloperoxidase in various pathological conditions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To clarify the role of myeloperoxidase in ischemic brain injury, the authors measured nitrotyrosine formation and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume in myeloperoxidase-deficient or <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> mice subjected to 2-hour focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>-reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Twenty-four hours after reperfusion, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume was significantly larger in myeloperoxidase-deficient mice than in <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> mice (81 +/- 20 mm(3) vs. 52 +/- 13 mm(3), P &lt; 0.01), and nitrotyrosine levels in the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> region were higher in myeloperoxidase-deficient mice than in <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> mice (13.4 +/- 6.1 microg/mg vs. 9.8 +/- 4.4 microg/mg, P = 0.13) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Fourteen hours after reperfusion, the nitrotyrosine level was significantly higher in myeloperoxidase-deficient mice than in <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> mice (3.3 +/- 2.9 microg/mg vs. 1.4 +/- 0.4 microg/mg, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The authors conclude that the absence of myeloperoxidase increases ischemic neuronal damage in vivo, and that the myeloperoxidase-mediated pathway is not responsible for the nitration reaction in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>-reperfusion </plain></SENT>
</text></document>