<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The objective of the present study was to characterise the neuroprotective activity of the novel glycineB site <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">NMDA</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">N-methyl-D-aspartate</z:chebi>) receptor <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi> MRZ 2/576 (8-chloro-4-hydroxy-l-oxo- 1,2-dihydropyridazino[4,5-b]quinolin-5-<z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="3" ids="15354">choline</z:chebi> salt, CAS 202807-80-5) in a <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1519106" disease_type="Experimental Model of Disease" abbrv="">rodent model</z:e> of focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0917798" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral ischaemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Since the solubility of MRZ 2/576 at a physiological pH, is minimal and adequate concentrations can be achieved only at relatively high basic pH the in vivo use of the substance is substantially limited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Therefore, a special nanoparticle formulation was developed to provide means for lengthy i.v. administration of experimentally relevant doses within the physiological range of pH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischaemia</z:e> of 75 min duration was induced in rats by a reversible occlusion of the middle cerebral artery (MCAo) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>MRZ 2/576 (18 mg/kg over 10 min followed by 18 mg/kg/h over 6 h) or placebo treatment was initiated immediately after <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of MCAo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Neurological deficit was evaluated daily for 3 consecutive days and then brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> analysis was performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>MRZ 2/576 significantly improved the neurological score at 24 h and 72 h post <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> (p &lt; 0.05 vs. placebo) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>It also produced a 53.0% reduction of total <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size, 60.4% of cortical and 42.3% of striatal infarction (p &lt; 0.05 vs. placebo) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Temporary drug-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002045'>hypothermia</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001251'>ataxia</z:hpo> were observed during infusions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This leads to the conclusion that prolonged administration of the glycineB site <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi> MRZ 2/576 in form of the nanoparticle suspension ameliorates ischaemic damage induced by the transient MCAo in rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The results suggest that nanoparticles hold promise as an effective strategy e.g. for substances with physico-chemical characteristics that otherwise would preclude them from pre-clinical development and/or clinical application </plain></SENT>
</text></document>