<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35705">immunosuppressant</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4031">cyclosporin A</z:chebi> (CsA) has been shown to have neuroprotective action </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The inhibition of both calcineurin activation and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> permeability transition pore (mtPTP) opening are considered the primary neuroprotective mechanisms of CsA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Here we have evaluated the effect of CsA on significantly reducing <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size induced by transient middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) in rats, and examined variable therapeutic applications for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0751955" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain infarction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Experimental rats were divided into 12 groups according to: CsA administration time (immediately after occlusion or immediately after reperfusion); dosage (between 10 and 50 mg/kg); route (i.v. or i.p.); and with or without needle insertion, which hypothetically disrupts the blood brain barrier (<z:chebi fb="2" ids="33602">BBB</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Neuroprotective effects of CsA were hardly noticeable when administered immediately after occlusion or by i.v. injection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>By needle insertion, CsA administration significantly reduced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size, although vehicle treatment also reduced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size compared with nontreatment animals, i.e. no needle insertion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These results suggest that needle insertion allows endogenous neuroprotective substances to pass into the brain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, single dosages over 30 mg/kg CsA were excessive and negated potential neuroprotective effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, two i.p. administrations of 20 mg/kg CsA immediately and 24 hrs after reperfusion significantly ameliorated the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size compared to the vehicle-treated group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We conclude that CsA exhibits significant neuroprotective activity, although its therapeutic application for <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> may be limited by very strict and precise management requirements </plain></SENT>
</text></document>