<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Ischemic preconditioning (PC) is a phenomenon whereby a brief exposure to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> renders a tissue more tolerant to a subsequent sustained ischemic insult </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Animals of the Spontaneously Hypertensive (SHR) and the Spontaneously Hypertensive <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo>-Prone (SHR-SP) rat strains produce cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> that are larger and more reproducible in size than <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> of normotensive rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study compared the effects of PC in SHR and SHR-SP rats, under the hypothesis that PC may not be as effective in the SHR-SP, a strain genetically predisposed to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>There were two groups per strain, with between eight and ten animals each </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The Precondition group (PC) had a 10 min occlusion of the middle cerebral artery on day -1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>On the same day the Sham group (Sham) received sham surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>On day 0, both groups underwent permanent occlusion of the middle cerebral artery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The ischemic lesion was measured on day 1 using T(2)-weighted magnetic resonance imaging </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Percent hemispheric <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> was significantly reduced in SHR PC vs. SHR Sham, SHR-SP PC vs. SHR-SP Sham, and SHR PC vs. SHR-SP PC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Thus, rats of the SHR-SP strain respond to PC less markedly than SHR animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Both models may now be used to elucidate the mechanisms underlying PC </plain></SENT>
</text></document>