<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: We examined the seropositivity of specific antibodies IgG and IgA to Chlamydia pneumoniae in the patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> and examined if it has a notability in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> patients with or without silent brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL AND METHOD: The clinical, laboratory and radiological findings of 26 cases with silent brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> (SBI) without <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> and 26 cases with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> without SBI (30 male, 22 female) were prospectively gathered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Risk factors were noted in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Control group was consisted of fifty-three healthy volunteer blood donors (40 male and 13 female) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The presence of C. pneumoniae specific IgG antibody in serum samples was determined by indirect micro-immunofluorescence test according to the method of Wang and Grayston (Euroimmun GmbH in Deustchland) and of specific IgA antibody in serum samples was determined by indirect micro-immunofluorescence test with the manufactured kit Orgenium-Helsinki </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The results were evaluated according to the groups and to the risk factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There was not any correlation between risk factors and C. pneumoniae seropositivity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Seropositivity for specific IgG antibody for C. pneumoniae was observed as 73.8% in SBI, as 61.5% in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> and as 56.3% in control groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Seropositivity for specific IgA antibody for C. pneumoniae was observed in 7 out of 16 SBI cases (43.8%) SBI and in 9 out of 19 <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> cases (47.3%) with positive IgG antiobodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: We could not confirm a relation of C. pneumoniae seropositivity neither with SBI nor with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>