<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor (GDNF) is a transforming growth factor-beta which has shown beneficial effects in rats after <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> (FCI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To study the effects of GDNF on <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> FCI injury in conscious rats, we used fibrin glue (GDNF-fibrin glue) and fibrin glue free (GDNF-only)-GDNF topically applied to the ischemic brain after right middle cerebral artery (<z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>) ligation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>Infarct</z:mpath> brain volume and functional motor deficits were measured before and after FCI injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>After FCI injury induced by right <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> ligation, rats were randomly assigned to one of four treatment groups: (a) sham, (b) control, (c) topically applied GDNF (1 mug)-only, and (d) topically applied GDNF (1 mug)-fibrin glue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The degree of ischemic brain injury was estimated by <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume of right <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> territory at 4 weeks after occlusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The functional motor deficits were quantified with rotarod test and grasping power test once a week </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Topically applied GDNF-fibrin glue at <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> brain tissue after 4 weeks FCI injury significantly reduced the total <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume by 44.3% and 36%, respectively, compared to that of control group and GDNF-only group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The mean latencies for rats to stay on the rotarod were 55.0%, 50.3%, and 92.2% (P &lt; 0.05 vs. control group and GDNF-only group) of baseline, respectively, in the control, GDNF-only, and GDNF-fibrin glue groups at the end of the 1st week after FCI injury but 75.3%, 67.3%, and 106.6% (P &lt; 0.05 vs. control group and GDNF-only group) of baseline at the end of the 4th week after FCI injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The mean values of grasping power were 78.7%, 71.7%, and 101.2% (P &lt; 0.05 vs. control group and GDNF-only group) of baseline, respectively, in the control, GDNF-only, and GDNF-fibrin glue groups at the end of 1st week after FCI injury but 89.6%, 97.6%, and 120.7% (P &lt; 0.05 vs. control group) of baseline at the end of 4th week after FCI injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These results indicate that GDNF-fibrin glue not only reduced the total <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume after FCI injury but can also improve motor deficits after FCI injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>We concluded GDNF-fibrin glue could facilitate delivery of GDNF to the damaged brain tissue with subsequent reduction of ischemic brain injury accompanied by enhancing functional recovery in rats with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> FCI injury </plain></SENT>
</text></document>