<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>UNLABELLED: We performed this study in order to assess the clinical potential of (13)N-ammonia PET in patients with cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0009592'>astrocytoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Dynamic <z:chebi fb="0" ids="36935">13N</z:chebi>-ammonia PET was performed in 25 patients with suspected cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0009733'>gliomas</z:hpo> or recurrent cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0009592'>astrocytomas</z:hpo> (19 male and 6 female patients; age range 18-64 years) detected by MRI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The histopathological diagnoses were made for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cases either by biopsy or craniotomy, except for one patient with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0751955" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain infarction</z:e> and one patient with brain radiation <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> confirmed by repeated MRI imaging </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>PET images were visually inspected, and the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e>-to-white matter count (T/W) ratios and the perfusion index (PI) of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> were determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Six out of nine cases of low-grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0009733'>gliomas</z:hpo> were detected with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="36935">13N</z:chebi>-ammonia PET, and three non-<z:hpo ids='HP_0009592'>astrocytoma</z:hpo> low-grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0009733'>gliomas</z:hpo> were not detected with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="36935">13N</z:chebi>-ammonia PET </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> 11 high-grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0009592'>astrocytomas</z:hpo> exhibited markedly increased uptake of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="36935">13N</z:chebi>-ammonia </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The five non-neoplastic lesions exhibited low uptake, low T/W ratios and low PI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The significant differences were observed between high-grade and low-grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0009733'>gliomas</z:hpo> with respect to both the T/W ratios and PI (T/W ratios: 5.92+/-2.27, n=11 vs. 1.66+/-0.61, n=9, P&lt;0.01; PI: 5.22+/-1.67, n=11 vs. 1.60+/-0.54, n=9, P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There were the significant differences between the T/W ratios and PI in low-grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0009592'>astrocytomas</z:hpo> and that in non-neoplastic lesions (T/W ratios: 2.00+/-0.42, n=6 vs. 0.97+/-0.11, n=5, P&lt;0.01; PI: 1.89+/-0.37, n=6 vs. 0.99+/-0.03, n=5, P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: There is a substantial uptake of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="36935">13N</z:chebi>-ammonia in cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0009592'>astrocytomas</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="36935">13N</z:chebi>-ammonia PET may enable differentiation between low- and high-grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0009592'>astrocytomas</z:hpo>, and has the potential to enable differentiation between low-grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0009592'>astrocytomas</z:hpo> and non-neoplastic lesions </plain></SENT>
</text></document>