<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the characteristics of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000802'>erectile dysfunction</z:hpo> (ED) in old males with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0333559" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lacunar infarction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 38 old patients ages from 60 to 70 years were involved </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The questionnaire of international index of erectile function 5 (IIEF -5) was used to determine the status and severity of ED </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>According to the focus of infarction on MRI, the patients were divided into two groups, Group I with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0333559" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lacunar infarction</z:e> and minor neurological deficits, and Group II with none </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The total IIEF-5 scores were compared between the two groups and repeatedly evaluated six months after discharge </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: According to the total scores of IIEF-5, the prevalence of ED in Group II (95%) was higher, and the incidence of severe ED was significantly increased (60.0% vs. 44.4%, P &lt; 0.05) as compared with Group II </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In both the two groups, severe ED was more often seen in diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At six months after discharge, the total scores of IIEF-5 were significantly increased (11.2 +/- 3.2 vs. 15.6 +/- 2.2, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: ED is significantly increased in old males with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0333559" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lacunar infarction</z:e>, and it is more severe in diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Post-<z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> rehabilitation care helps to improve ED </plain></SENT>
</text></document>