<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We characterized <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001342'>intracerebral hemorrhage</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICH</z:e>) in the rat by sequential magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and correlated MRI findings with neurobehavior and histopathology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In addition, we investigated whether albumin treatment would reduce <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICH</z:e>-induced brain injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICH</z:e> was produced in rats by a double-injection method in which 45 microl of fresh arterial blood was injected into the right striatum </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Susceptibility-weighted (SWI) and T2-weighted (T2WI) MRI was carried out on a 4.7T magnet at 0-1 h, 6 h, 24 h, 72 h, and 7 days after <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICH</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Animals were treated with either 25% human albumin, 1.25 g/kg, or saline vehicle i.v. at 90 min after <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICH</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Neurological status was evaluated before <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICH</z:e> and after treatment (at 4 h, 24 h, 48 h, 72 h, and 7 days) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Brains were then perfusion-fixed, re-imaged on an 11.7T magnet, and studied by histopathology and immunochemistry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>MRI revealed a consistent <z:mp ids='MP_0008817'>hematoma</z:mp> involving the striatum and overlying corpus callosum, with significant volume changes over time </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Lesion volumes computed from T2WI images and by histopathology agreed closely with one another and were highly correlated (p=0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>SWI lesion volumes were also highly correlated to histological volumes (p&lt;0.001) but overestimated histological <z:mp ids='MP_0008817'>hematoma</z:mp> volume by approximately 5-fold </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Albumin treatment significantly improved neurological scores compared to saline at 72 h (3.8+/-0.6 vs. 1.5+/-0.7) and 7 days (3.8+/-0.4 vs. 1.3+/-0.5, respectively, p&lt;0.05), but did not affect histological or MRI lesion volumes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Taken together, sequential MRI plus histopathology provides a comprehensive characterization of experimental <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICH</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Albumin treatment improves neurological deficit after <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICH</z:e> but does not affect MRI or histological <z:mp ids='MP_0008817'>hematoma</z:mp> size </plain></SENT>
</text></document>