<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Production of reactive oxygen species after cerebral blood flow disruption may enhance tissue damage through multiple molecular pathways </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Changes in nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> (NO) metabolism and <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> status were investigated in 47 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> by measuring plasma nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> (NO) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25941">peroxynitrite</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="29330">ONOO</z:chebi>(-)) levels.A correlation was sought between these two parameters and i) baseline <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> severity based on the National Institute of Health <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> scale (NIHSS) and ii) neurological outcome in terms of NIHSS changes from entry (T(0)) to 30 days after symptom <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> (T(1)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The control group consisted of 30 age- and sex-matched healthy subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Mean plasma levels of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29330">ONOO</z:chebi>(-) (arbitrary fluorescence number +/- SD) were significantly higher in patients (7.70 +/- 1.71 vs 5.35 +/- 0.69, p &lt; 0.001), whereas mean NO levels (nmol/mg protein) were significantly higher in controls (115.40 +/- 12.40 vs. 51.10 +/- 12.50, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Plasma <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29330">ONOO</z:chebi>(-) was significantly higher among patients with non-lacunar <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> (8.48 +/- 1.50 vs. 6.95 +/- 1.58 in those with lacunar <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>; p = 0.001), whereas NO levels were significantly higher among lacunar <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> patients (60.00 +/- 7.86, vs. 41.77 +/- 9.29 in patients with nonlacunar <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>; p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> plasma levels were also associated with an unfavorable evolution in non-lacunar <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, since a 10 unit increase in NO predicted a 1 point reduction in the NIHSS score at T1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Findings show that changes in NO metabolism may be considered as markers of brain injury in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Further work is needed to establish whether the amount of biochemical changes related to <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> may influence outcome in these patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>