<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Free radicals are important in causing neural cell injury during <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Although there was a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind study at multiple centers in Japan showing the efficacy of the free radical scavenger, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31530">edaravone</z:chebi>, in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e>, to date the clinical studies are few </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study investigated the effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31530">edaravone</z:chebi> on the outcome of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0333559" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lacunar infarction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We retrospectively evaluated 124 consecutive patients with first-ever <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0333559" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lacunar infarctions</z:e> who were admitted to our hospital within 24 hours after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> between January 2004 and June 2007 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Of these, 59 patients received both <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31530">edaravone</z:chebi> and conventional therapy (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="31530">edaravone</z:chebi> group), and the other 65 underwent conventional therapy only (non-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="31530">edaravone</z:chebi> group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference in patients' baseline characteristics in the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The clinical outcome was assessed by the National Institutes of Health <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo> Scale (NIHSS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The reduction of NIHSS scale during hospitalization (1.5+/-1.0 vs. 1.0+/-1.1; p = 0.007), especially that of the motor palsy scale (1.0+/-1.0 vs. 0.5+/-1.0; p = 0.006) was significantly larger, and the percentage of patients with a favorable outcome (NIHSS at discharge &lt; or =1) (91.5% vs. 78.5%; p = 0.044) was significantly better in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31530">edaravone</z:chebi> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31530">Edaravone</z:chebi> improves the outcomes of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0333559" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lacunar infarction</z:e>, especially motor palsy, without regard to the conventional therapy performed concomitantly </plain></SENT>
</text></document>