<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: Since attention should be paid to <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> patients who may easily worsen, we investigated the predisposing factors for <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> deterioration of minor <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> in Japanese patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We retrospectively investigated 543 patients who were admitted within 7 days of the occurrence of an <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> minor <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> with National Institute of Health <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo> Scale (NIHSS) score of 4 or less, between January 2002 and September 2005 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Deterioration of neurological findings was defined as the worsening by 2 points or more of the NIHSS score during admission to the hospital </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Out of 543 patients, deterioration was noted in 37 patients (6.8%: deterioration group), and not in the other 506 patients (93.2%: non-deterioration group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis demonstrated that the factors associated with worsening were atherothrombotic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0751955" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain infarction</z:e> (deterioration group vs. non-deterioration group: 35.1% vs. 18.0%, P=0.049), <z:hpo ids='HP_0004421'>elevated systolic blood pressure</z:hpo> (170.5+/-32.4 mm Hg vs. 160.4+/-27.4 mm Hg, P=0.033), serum <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> level on admission (146.1+/-60.5mg/dL vs. 121.7+/-54.9 mg/dL, P=0.048), and presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003470'>paralysis</z:hpo> (73.0% vs. 54.9%, P=0.003) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002321'>vertigo</z:hpo> (16.2% vs. 7.9%, P=0.034) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The more factors there were that were associated with worsening (atherothrombotic infarction; systolic blood pressure &gt;140 mm Hg; serum <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> level &gt;140 mg/dL; and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003470'>paralysis</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002321'>vertigo</z:hpo>, and dizziness), the more frequently the deterioration occurred (number of worsening factors 0-2: 4.6%, 3: 12.8%, 4: 32.3%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Although over 80% of patients in the group without deterioration had good functional outcome at discharge, over 90% of patients with deterioration either were discharged to nursing home care or died </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In this study, the predisposing factors for <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> deterioration in minor <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> were atherothrombotic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0751955" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain infarction</z:e>; <z:mp ids='MP_0002842'>high blood pressure</z:mp>; elevated serum <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> level; and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003470'>paralysis</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002321'>vertigo</z:hpo>, and dizziness </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Once patients with minor <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> deteriorated, their functional outcome at discharge was significantly worse than those who had not deteriorated </plain></SENT>
</text></document>