<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="3" ids="27226">Uric acid</z:chebi> (UA) has been reported to be reduced in the serum of patients with multiple <z:mp ids='MP_0000612'>sclerosis</z:mp> (MS) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100653'>optic neuritis</z:hpo> (ON) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, the relationship between UA and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027873" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuromyelitis optica</z:e> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="52093">NMO</z:chebi>) was unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="52093">NMO</z:chebi> was claimed to be a distinct nosologic entity from MS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The aim of our study was to investigate the correlation between serum UA level and the clinical characteristics of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52093">NMO</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The serum UA level was measured in 403 Chinese patients; 69 with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52093">NMO</z:chebi>, 32 ON, 127 MS, 80 cerebral infarction (CI) patients, and 95 healthy controls (CTL) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Serum UA level in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52093">NMO</z:chebi> was significantly lower than that in CI (249.89 +/- 93.74 vs. 315.42 +/- 85.57 micromol/L, p = 0.004) and CTL (249.89 +/- 93.74 vs. 314.33 +/- 102.05 micromol/L, p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, no difference was found between <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52093">NMO</z:chebi> and MS (p = 0.496) or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52093">NMO</z:chebi> and ON (p = 0.858) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>When the analysis was performed in the female cohort separately, UA level was significantly lower in females than in males in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>It was also shown in our study that UA level in patients with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52093">NMO</z:chebi> was not correlated with disease activity revealed by MRI, disease disability or duration of disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Our results indicated a reduced serum UA level in patients with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52093">NMO</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>