<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>HT008-1 is one of the prescriptions used in Traditional Korean Medicine for the treatment of mental and physical <z:mp ids='MP_0000746'>weakness</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It is composed of Panax ginseng, Acanthopanax senticosus, Angelica sinensis and Scutellaria baicalensis, which have been reported to have various pharmacological effects on the central <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The study investigated whether HT008-1 has neuroprotective effects in a focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> rat model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo> was induced in rats by 2 h of middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAo) followed by 22 h of reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>HT008-1 (30, 100 and 300 mg/kg) and the component herbs (300 mg/kg) were administered orally twice at 0 and 2 h after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Oral administration of 300 mg/kg HT008-1 reduced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0751955" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain infarction</z:e> by 45.7%, prolonged the latency time by 24.8% in the rotarod test, and enhanced the score by 17.0% in the balance beam test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Only P. ginseng and S. baicalensis showed protective effects, and HT008-1 showed a greater effect than its component herbs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>HT008-1 down-regulated the COX-2 and OX-42 expression in the penumbra region </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, the results show that HT008-1 may be effective in a rat <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> model by an antiinflammatory mechanism and may improve sensory-motor function by reducing damage in the cortex and caudoputamen </plain></SENT>
</text></document>