<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: the present study was aimed at investigation of neuroprotective effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="30314">alpha-lipoic acid</z:chebi> (LA) and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase (SOD) in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007786" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain ischemia</z:e> in rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: two models were used to produce <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007786" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain ischemia</z:e>: focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> (permanent left middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp>) and permanent ligation of both CCA without subsequent reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Cu/Zn-SOD at a dose 5 mg/kg, i.v. and LA at a dose of 20 mg/kg, i.p. were injected 30 minutes prior or 5 minutes after <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The end-points of the study were histochemically determined: infarction size, ultrastructural changes in the cerebral tissue, and survival rate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: LA administration 30 minutes prior to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> dramatically reduced infarction size (p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Injection of LA 5 minutes after beginning of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> did not affect the infarction size </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Besides, infarction ion size was unchanged after injection of SOD 30 minutes prior to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: the LA treatment regimen used in this study resulted in significant cerebral protection against <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In contrast, SOD did not show any protective effects in focal and forebrain <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>