<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE: Studies on post-<z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001250'>seizures</z:hpo> have produced conflicting results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Our study aim was to further elucidate the incidence and predictive factors of early post-<z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001250'>seizures</z:hpo> (ES) and their relationship with outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: relevant clinical data were prospectively collected in 2,053 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> admitted to the <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo> Unit from 2004 to 2008 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Sixty-six patients (8 hemorrhagic and 58 <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic strokes</z:hpo>) aged 73-88 years (mean age 82 years) presented <z:hpo ids='HP_0001250'>seizures</z:hpo> in the first week after <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The type of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> was atherothrombotic in 10 patients, cardioembolic in 21, lacunar in 4, undetermined in 19, and of other etiology in 4 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Twenty-seven patients had generalized <z:mp ids='MP_0000947'>convulsive</z:mp>, 6 had complex partial, and 33 had <z:hpo ids='HP_0002349'>simple partial seizures</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002133'>Status epilepticus</z:hpo> was observed in 13 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The severity of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>strokes</z:hpo> in patients with ES was greater than in those without (National Institutes of Health <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo> Scale &gt;14 in 50 vs. 25%), so mortality (30 days) was higher (29 vs. 14%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Independent <z:hpo ids='HP_0001250'>seizure</z:hpo> predictors were: total anterior circulation <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath>, hemorrhagic transformation, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo>, and the interaction term <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> × <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: ES may be considered a marker of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> severity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Cortical location of the lesion, hemorrhagic transformation, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> in patients without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> are important predictors of ES </plain></SENT>
</text></document>