<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Cerebral involvement in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0036323" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">schistosomiasis</z:e> is not rare, but it is underdiagnosed because of the lack of clinical suspicion and the frequency of asymptomatic forms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Neurologic complications are generally supported by granuloma formation around ectopic eggs which have migrated to the brain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Moreover, vascular lesions and cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0012089'>arteritis</z:hpo> have been well documented in histopathological studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Nevertheless, <z:hpo ids='HP_0005318'>cerebral vasculitis</z:hpo> in later stages of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0036330" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Schistosoma mansoni infection</z:e> have not yet been described in living subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>CASE PRESENTATION: A 28-year-old french woman had a <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> linked with <z:hpo ids='HP_0005318'>cerebral vasculitis</z:hpo>, 6 monthes after returning from Burkina-Faso </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>At the same time, a S. mansoni disseminated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was diagnosed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>She suffered from a new <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> after undertaking praziquantel therapy, which lead us to associate the S. mansoni <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0005318'>cerebral vasculitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: This is the first report of such association, since <z:hpo ids='HP_0005318'>cerebral vasculitis</z:hpo> has never been described in later stages of the S. mansoni <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Although the causal link between the two pathologies could not be proved, we suggest that S. mansoni is able to cause severe vascular damage in cerebral vessels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0036323" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Schistosomiasis</z:e> must be investigated in the event of a brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> in young people, particularly in patients originating or returning from an endemic area </plain></SENT>
</text></document>