<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Fluid-attenuated inversion recovery (FLAIR) vascular hyperintensities (FVH), initially described on 2D FLAIR images, are a useful imaging marker in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We aimed to compare the sensitivity of the 3D CUBE FLAIR sequence with 2D FLAIR for the detection of FVH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Forty-seven consecutive patients admitted for a suspected <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> were explored by 2D and 3D CUBE FLAIR <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e> sequences at 1.5 and 3 T </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Three blinded readers assessed FVH defined as hyperintensities within cerebral arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Location of FVH, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100545'>arterial stenosis</z:hpo> were also assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>2D images were compared with 3D images for the detection of FVH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Agreement between readers was assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of the 47 patients, 21 FVHs were observed on 2D FLAIR images of 15 patients (11 with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> and 11 with an <z:hpo ids='HP_0100545'>arterial stenosis</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>No FVH was visualised on 3D CUBE FLAIR images for either proximal or distal locations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Agreement between readers was excellent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: FVHs are not visible using 3D CUBE FLAIR images </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>This study suggests that, in suspected <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, the assessment of FVH should only be performed on conventional 2D FLAIR images </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>KEY POINTS : • Fluid-attenuated inversion recovery (FLAIR) vascular hyperintensities (FVH) are of neuroradiological importance. • FVHs are useful imaging markers in patients with an <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>. • FVHs are not visible using 3D CUBE FLAIR images. • Assessment of FVH should be performed on conventional 2D FLAIR images </plain></SENT>
</text></document>