<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The authors assessed hemostasis and fibrinolysis serially: on admission and on the 1st and 7th days after surgery for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> (SAH), examining the complications of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysm</z:hpo> rupture and its surgical repair </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Of 32 patients, 25 with SAH were compared with seven control patients who underwent surgery for an unruptured <z:hpo ids='HP_0004944'>intracranial aneurysm</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>On admission, patients with SAH had higher thrombin-antithrombin III complex (TAT) levels (13.3 +/- 3.8 vs. 3.8 +/- 0.6 ng/ml, p = 0.01), fibrin degradation product, D-dimer levels (1310 +/- 220 vs. 556 +/- 89 ng/ml, p = 0.0001), and leukocyte counts (14.6 +/- 0.7 vs. 10.6 +/- 1.8 x 10(9) cells/L, p &lt; 0.05) than did control patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Postoperative D-dimer values (p = 0.007) remained higher in the SAH group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, admission D-dimer levels were higher in the patients in poor clinical condition than in those in good condition (2017 +/- 377 vs. 934 +/- 208 ng/ml, p = 0.007), and D-dimer levels were associated with the outcome at 3 months after admission </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Additionally, thrombin generation and fibrinolytic markers measured on admission were related to clinical grade, amount of subarachnoid blood seen on computerized tomography (CT) scanning, and patient fatality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients with hypodense lesions verified on follow-up CT scanning or with persistent neurological deficits at 3 months had higher prothrombin fragments 1 and 2, TAT, D-dimer, and plasminogen activator inhibitor-1 values on the 1st day postoperatively than did patients without such lesions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In short, in patients with SAH, activation of coagulation and fibrinolysis was strongly associated with clinical state, patient fatality, and outcome at 3 months, and postoperatively this activation correlated with the development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0751955" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain infarction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>