<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Strategies directed against activated neutrophils have reduced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>-induced brain injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, therapies targeted specially against the neutrophil <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0001511" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">adhesion</z:e> protein L-selectin have not yet been examined in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study therefore examined the effects of a monoclonal antibody directed against L-selectin in a rabbit model of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001727'>thromboembolic stroke</z:hpo> with (n = 16) or without (n = 10) concomitant t-PA therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Rabbits received either the humanized monoclonal antibody DREG200 directed against the L-selectin receptor or humanized control monoclonal antibody HuDREG55 which does not bind to rabbit L-selectin in addition to t-PA therapy (n = 8, each group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>HuDREG200 (2 mg kg-1 i.v.) was given as a bolus 3 h following clot embolization, followed immediately by a 2 h intravenous infusion of t-PA (6.3 mg kg-1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Without t-PA therapy rabbits received HuDREG200 (2 mgkg-1, i.v.; n = 5) or HuDREG55 (n = 5) 1 h following clot embolization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The group receiving HuDREG200 in addition to t-PA demonstrated a moderate improvement in brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size (8.4 +/- 2.4 vs. 13.5 +/- 3.5, %hemisphere, mean +/- sem), ICP (final reading 10.0 +/- 1.6 vs. 12.4 +/- 3.0 torr) and restoration in regional cerebral blood flow (30.2 +/- 7.8 vs. 21.6 +/- 10.9 cc 100 g-1 min-1) when compared to t-PA therapy alone although statistical significance was not achieved </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No efficacy was demonstrated in the group receiving HUDREG200 without concomitant t-PA therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The results suggest the addition of a humanized anti-L-selectin monoclonal antibody HuDREG200 in combination with t-PA may further improve outcome in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001727'>thromboembolic stroke</z:hpo>, although future studies are necessary to support these findings </plain></SENT>
</text></document>