<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Mortality rates attributable to fulminant Clostridium difficile (C. difficile) <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> remain high and are reported to be 38%-80% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Historically, the threshold for surgical intervention has been judged empirically because level I evidence to guide decision making is lacking </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Studies of the surgical management of C. difficile <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> have been limited by small sample size and the lack of a standard definition of fulminancy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Multiple small and medium-sized series have examined the surgical management of C. difficile </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>However, because of a lack of prospective, randomized studies, it has been difficult to identify the optimal point for surgical intervention in patients with severe fulminant C. difficile <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Our goal was to analyze the existing body of literature in an attempt to define host constellations, which would predict the development of the more aggressive form of this disease and hence justify an early or earlier surgical intervention </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A Pubmed search was conducted using the keywords "fulminant", "clostridium difficile", "surgery", and "<z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo>" </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Reviews and meta-analyses proposing indications for surgical consultation or operative management in patients with C. difficile <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>After analyzing current literature, we identified a number of parameters that are associated with unfavorable outcomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The parameters include age greater than 65 years old, peritoneal signs on physical examination, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003270'>abdominal distension</z:hpo>, signs of end-organ failure, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002615'>hypotension</z:hpo> less than 90 mmHg systolic blood pressure, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> greater than 100 bpm, vasopressor requirement, elevated WBC count of greater than at least 16 × 10(9)/μL, serum <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> of greater than 2.2 mmol/L, and lastly, radiologic findings suggestive of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0868908" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pancolitis</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001541'>ascites</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002251'>megacolon</z:hpo>, or colonic <z:mpath ids='MPATH_81'>perforation</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Even though fairly strong evidence exists in contemporary literature, we recommend use of these identified parameters with caution in clinical practice when it comes to the actual decision to treat certain patients more aggressively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The identified risk factors should be used to lower surgeons' threshold for operative treatment early in the course of the disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>