<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>Ulcerative Colitis</z:hpo> [UC] may be exposed to ionising radiation for evaluation of disease with inherent risks from protracted exposure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Meanwhile, bolder definitions of disease control with evolving treatment paradigms have led to earlier introduction of biological therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Our aim was to compare the effective radiation dose prior to and a year and 3 years after initiating anti-TNF therapy or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50858">corticosteroid</z:chebi> in patients with UC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We performed a retrospective review of UC patients treated with anti-TNF therapy (infliximab or adalimumab) or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50858">corticosteroids</z:chebi> at our institution from 2005 to 2013 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Clinical data (demographics, disease characteristics, treatment) were obtained from case notes and electronic patient records </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> instances of imaging in the previous year, 1 and 3 years after initiation of anti-TNF therapy were recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The effective and cumulative radiation doses were calculated from published tables [Royal College of Radiologists, UK] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: We analysed 102 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> (66 anti-TNF and 36 corticosteroid treated) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the anti-TNF group, 68% were males (median age 47 yrs; range 25-76; mean disease duration 9.5 yrs) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Forty seven per cent had left sided disease [Montreal E2] and 55% had <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0868908" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pancolitis</z:e> [Montreal E3] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50858">corticosteroid</z:chebi> treated patients, 55% were males (median age 51 yrs; range 17-90; mean disease duration 7.7 yrs) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Montreal classification of disease was E1 in 11%, E2 in 46% and E3 in 43% respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The anti-TNF cohort had a significant reduction in the number of imaging studies (4.0 vs. 1.5, p &lt; 0.0001) and cumulative radiation dose (4.1 vs. 1.1 mSv, p &lt; 0.0001) a year after treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50858">corticosteroid</z:chebi> group had no significant change in the number of imaging studies (1.9 vs. 1.3, p = 0.1 or cumulative radiation dose (3.2 vs. 2.0 mSv, p = 0.5) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>After 3 years of anti-TNF (n = 22), there was a reduction in the cumulative radiation dose (1.6 vs.1.0 mSv, p = 0.3) and number of imaging studies (2.7 vs.1.9, p = 0.3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>In the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50858">corticosteroid</z:chebi> group, there was a reduction noted in the cumulative radiation dose (2.5 vs. 1.1 mSv, p &lt; 0.3) and no change in the number of imaging studies (1.6 vs. 1.7, p = 0.5) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Linear regression analysis showed a decrease in cumulative radiation dose by 3.1 mSv (CI= -4.9 to +0.2, p = 0.07) and number of CT imaging scans by 1 (CI= +1.5 to -1.2, p &lt; 0.08) in the anti-TNF group compared to the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50858">corticosteroid</z:chebi> group within a year of therapy after adjusting for age, gender, disease duration, disease location and disease behaviour </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Anti-TNF therapy is associated with a significant reduction in cumulative radiation dose and diagnostic imaging studies a year after anti-TNF therapy but not with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50858">corticosteroids</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>The decrease in radiation dose exposure in both groups was similar three years after treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="19" pm="."><plain>DISCLOSURE OF INTEREST: None Declared </plain></SENT>
</text></document>