<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: The role of angioplasty/stenting procedures, neurointerventionist experience, vascular risk factors, medical treatment and blood flow velocities were analysed to identify possible causes of intra-stent restenosis (ISR) following stenting of cervical and/or intracranial arteries, assuming progressive <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> to be the shared mechanism in both territories </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>26 cerebrovascular patients subjected to stenting of severe (≥85%) symptomatic or asymptomatic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007282" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid stenoses</z:e> or moderate-to-severe (≥50%) intracranial or vertebral stenoses were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Clinical, radiological and ultrasonographic follow-up data were analysed retrospectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Overall, stenting of the internal carotid artery (ICA) induced significant reductions in peak systolic velocities at 2 years (96±31 cm/s vs. 358.2±24.9 cm/s at baseline) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The procedure-related ischemic complications rate was 7.4% (one hemispheric <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> and one <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>TIA</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The rate of ISR≤50% was 8% in the ICA at 2 years; was 50% in the common carotid artery (CCA) at 1 year, with concomitant distal ICA stenosis in 75% of CCA stenting, but <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> ISR were asymptomatic </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients with ISR of the ICA were significantly younger (56.8±4.5 vs. 71.3±3.6 years, P=0.042) and had significantly more risk factors (5.5±0.9 vs. 3±0.3, P=0.012) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>No ISR≥70% was detected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: ISR is relatively infrequent and, when present, it is mild and asymptomatic </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Restenosis is more frequent in younger patients and those with several risk factors, and it may also be related to stenting of previous carotid endarterectomy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>