<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Restenosis of carotid arteries after endarterectomy is a rare complication; in our series 1.2% (19 patients - 20 recurrences out of 1658 operations - Dec </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>1985) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>It usually occurs early, i.e. in the first months (12 cases) with features of myointimal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_134'>hyperplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Peroperative angiography should be routinely performed to rule out technical errors that might be mistaken for restenosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At the time of reoperation, 12 patients were symptomatic </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The operation consisted of 6 second endarterectomies, 13 saphenous vein grafts and 1 PTFE graft </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The postoperative period was uneventful in 14 cases, but in the remaining patients there were 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>transient ischemic attacks</z:hpo>, 2 monoplegias and 1 <z:hpo ids='HP_0002357'>dysphasia</z:hpo> (with immediate <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> of the bypass in 3 cases) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Five patients were lost at follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the remaining 14 patients, the follow-up period varied between 3 and 84 months (mean: 20 months) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Presently 11 carotid arteries are patent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In one case involving a venous patch, the artery is dilated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> 12 of these patients are asymptomatic </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>One thrombosed bypass is also asymptomatic </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The two monoplegias occurred in patients whose bypasses occluded immediately </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>The recurrence rate varied according to the imaging technique. i.e. pulsed Doppler, B-mode scanning or angiography, used to detect restenosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Restenosis usually remains asymptomatic even in patients with hemodynamically significant lesions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Restenosis due to myointimal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_134'>hyperplasia</z:mpath> does not carry the risk of embolism and atheromatous stenosis does not have the same prognosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>In our experience immediate and long term results of red are not as good the first endarterectomy.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>