<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>In a 4-year period, 129 asymptomatic high-grade (80-99%) internal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007282" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid artery stenoses</z:e> were identified in 115 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Because we previously demonstrated a strong relation between degree of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100546'>carotid stenosis</z:hpo> and subsequent development of ipsilateral related events (<z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>transient ischemic attack</z:hpo>, and carotid occlusion), we changed our previous policy and began to offer carotid endarterectomy to good surgical risk patients referred to us with asymptomatic high-grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0100546'>carotid stenosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A total of 56 carotid endarterectomies were performed while 73 lesions were followed nonoperatively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Operated and nonoperated groups were similar with regard to age, prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018799" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiac disease</z:e>, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, and aspirin use </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Life table analysis to 24 months revealed a higher rate of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> (19 vs. 4%, p = 0.08), transient focal neurologic deficits (28 vs. 5%, p = 0.008), and carotid occlusion (29 vs. 0%, p = 0.003) in the nonoperated group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Eight of the 9 <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>strokes</z:hpo> in the nonoperated group occurred within 9 months of diagnosis of the high-grade lesion; none were preceded by a <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>transient ischemic attack</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There was 1 perioperative <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> (1.8%) but no in-hospital operative <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> and no difference in the late <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> rates of the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>This suggests that the preservation of neurologic status in patients with asymptomatic high-grade internal carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006135'>artery stenosis</z:mp> can be improved by carotid endarterectomy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>