<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We determined the ionic composition of faecal fluid from 13 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> limited to the colon, 10 with diffuse <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo>, and eight with ulcerative <z:mp ids='MP_0003305'>proctitis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The Crohn's and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> groups had similar proportions of colon surface involved radiographically and similar 24 hour faecal weights </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, Crohn's patients' faecal fluid had arithmetically lower mean <z:chebi fb="199" ids="26708">sodium</z:chebi> and statistically lower mean <z:chebi fb="76" ids="17996">chloride</z:chebi> (34.8 mmol/l +/- 16.2 SD vs. 53.1 mmol/l +/- 23.1 SD) and higher <z:chebi fb="120" ids="26216">potassium</z:chebi> (49.2 mmol/l +/- 20.2 SD vs. 33.0 mmol/l +/- 13.8 SD) concentrations (p less than 0.05 for each) and much higher osmolality (487.1 mOsmol/kg +/- 87.1 SD vs. 341.1 mOsmol/kg +/- 88.9 SD, p less than 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Separation of these patients using the faecal osmotic gap agreed with the clinical classification in 86% of cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The diarrhoea of <z:mp ids='MP_0003305'>proctitis</z:mp> patients had a nearly <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> ionic composition which was clearly distinguishable from that of diffuse <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>These results suggest differences in the composition and perhaps the pathogenesis of the diarrhoea of Crohn's and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The composition of fluid may prove a useful, non-invasive method for classifying patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021390" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory bowel disease</z:e> and, in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo>, determining the extent of the inflammatory process </plain></SENT>
</text></document>