<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0000265'>mastoiditis</z:hpo> (AM) is an uncommon but serious complication of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000371'>acute otitis media</z:hpo> (AOM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In the pre-antibiotic era, AM was seen more frequently than it is today, but it was rare in infants </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, in the last two decades an increase in the incidence of AM in infancy has been reported in the literature </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>During the years 1990-2002, we treated 113 patients with 128 episodes of AM; of them, 24 were infants (median age 6 months; 18 males) who suffered from 26 episodes of AM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Twenty developed AM as a complication of their first episode of AOM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>One of the four infants with a prior history of AOM suffered from common variable <z:hpo ids='HP_0002721'>immunodeficiency</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A significant increase in the incidence of AM in infants was recorded during the study period (P = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The most common presenting clinical signs were post-auricular swelling and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo> &gt;38 degrees C (77% and 77%, respectively, of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Seventeen episodes of AM were not treated with prior antibiotics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Tympanocentesis was performed in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> episodes of AM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Middle ear fluid culture was positive in 17 (65%) of the 26 AM episodes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The most common pathogens cultured were Streptococcus pneumoniae (10 infants, 58% of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> pathogens, 3/10 intermediately susceptible to <z:chebi fb="93" ids="17334">penicillin</z:chebi>) followed by Streptococcus pyogenes (4, 23%), non-typable H. influenzae (2, 12%) and S. aureus (1, 6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Temporal bone CT showed bone destruction in 14 patients; 3 infants had subperiosteal abscesses and 3 lateral sinus <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Ten infants underwent mastoid surgery due to non-resolution of symptoms and signs with antibiotic therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Eight underwent cortical mastoidectomy with two patients undergoing ventilation tube introduction only </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>The remainder of the infants healed with conservative treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: (1) A significant increase in the incidence of AM in infants was recorded over the last decade, though a specific reason for this trend remains uncertain; (2) Most of the cases of AM followed the infant's initial AOM episode, and most of the infants had not received prior antibiotic therapy; (3) The clinical signs and symptoms of AM were more severe in infants than in older patients; (4) While S. <z:hpo ids='HP_0002090'>pneumonia</z:hpo> was the most common pathogen isolated in middle ear fluid cultures, the involvement of S. pyogenes in AM was higher than that reported in AOM </plain></SENT>
</text></document>