<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0598608" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Hyperhomocysteinemia</z:e> (HHcy), a putative independent risk factor for the development of atherotrombosis in the general population, represents a very common finding in orthotopic heart transplantation (OHT) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Starting from previous studies suggesting a pro-arrhythmogenic activity of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">homocysteine</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">Hcy</z:chebi>), we evaluated the possible correlation among <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">Hcy</z:chebi> plasma levels and P wave dispersion (PWD), corrected QT interval (QTc), and QTc dispersion (QTcD) as parameters of electric instability of the myocardium in patients undergone OHT whose hearts are therefore completely denervated, thus unresponsive to autonomic influences </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">Homocysteine</z:chebi> plasma levels, PWD, QTc, QTcD, and QTc dynamics were measured in 32 patients, who underwent OHT, and in 20 control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In OHT patients, PWD (39.5 ± 11 vs. 34 ± 6 ms, p = 0.04) and QTc interval (438 ± 20 vs. 410 ± 10 ms, p &lt; 0.001) were significantly higher in comparison with control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Moreover, OHT subjects with HHcy had higher PWD values than those with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">Hcy</z:chebi> plasma levels (44.1 ± 10.7 vs. 33.9 ± 8.8 ms, p = 0.007), but no difference was found between this latter OHT group and controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Accordingly, in OHT patients, plasma <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">Hcy</z:chebi> level correlated significantly with PWD (Spearman r = 0.70; p &lt; 0.0001), whereas no correlation was found with QTc, QTcD, and QTc circadian dynamics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: HHcy seems associated with an alteration in the electrical atrial conduction, possibly contributing, at least in part, to the increased risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmias</z:hpo> in the denervated hearts of OHT patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>