<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Patients with a history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) have previously been shown to have altered atrial conduction, as seen non-invasively using signal-averaged P-wave analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, little is known about the P-wave <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> in patients in the early phases of AF with structurally <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> hearts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Thirty-six patients with lone AF were included before the age of 40 years (34±4 years, 34 men) and compared with age- and gender-matched control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Standard 12-lead electrocardiogram (ECG) was recorded for at least 10 s </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>P-wave <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> and duration were estimated using signal-averaged P-wave analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Echocardiography was performed in association with the ECG recording </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Heart rate (67±13 vs. 65±7 b.p.m., P=0.800) and PQ-interval (163±16 vs. 164±23 ms, P=0.629) were similar in AF cases and controls, as was P-wave duration (136±13 vs. 129±13 ms, P=0.107) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The distribution of P-wave <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> differed between the AF cases and controls [33/58/0/8 vs. 75/25/0/0% (Type 1/Type 2/Type 3/atypical), P=0.001], with a larger proportion of patients with AF exhibiting signs of impaired interatrial conduction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: A significant difference in P-wave <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> distribution was seen between patients with early-<z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo>, lone paroxysmal AF and age- and gender-matched healthy control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This finding indicates that alterations in atrial electrophysiology are common in the early stage of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo>, and since it occurs in young patients without co-morbidity may well be the cause rather than the consequence of AF </plain></SENT>
</text></document>