<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Electrical storm (ES) adversely affects prognosis of patients and may become a life-threatening event </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Catheter ablation (CA) has been proposed for the treatment of ES </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Our goal was to evaluate the efficacy of CA ablation both in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> and long-term suppression of ES </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Fifty consecutive patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001677'>coronary artery disease</z:hpo> (38), idiopathic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001644'>dilated cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (5), <z:hpo ids='HP_0011663'>arrhythmogenic right ventricular cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (6), and/or with combined aetiology (1) underwent CA for ES </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Mean left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) was 29 ± 11% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients underwent electroanatomical mapping, and CA was performed to abolish <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> inducible <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The ES was suppressed by CA in 84% of patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>During the follow-up of 18 ± 16 months, 24 patients had no recurrences of any <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> (VT; 48%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Repeated procedure was necessary to suppress the recurrent ES in 13 cases (26%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Statistical analysis revealed that low LVEF (22 ± 3 vs. 31 ± 12%; P &lt; 0.001), increased LVend-diastolic diameter (72 ± 9.1 vs. 64 ± 8.9 mm; P = 0.0135), and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000083'>renal insufficiency</z:hpo> (P &lt; 0.001) were the univariate predictors of early mortality or necessity for heart transplantation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Recurrence of ES despite previous CA procedure was associated with a higher risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> or heart transplant during follow-up (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Catheter ablation is effective in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> suppression of ES and often represents a life-saving therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In the long term, it prevents recurrences of any VT in about half of the treated patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>