<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to describe the toxic effects resulting from the administration of Calotropis procera (Aiton) W </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>T </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Aiton latex to rats and C. procera leaves to sheep </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We studied male sheep that received C. procera leaves by gavage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Twenty male rats were separated into 5 groups and were subjected to an intra-peritoneal injection of fresh C. procera latex (without carrier solvent) at 1.0, 0.6, 0.3 or 0.1 ml of latex/kg of body weight, and control animals were injected with 0.9% <z:chebi fb="1" ids="26710">NaCl</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> rats were treated with the highest dose, but none of the rats from the other groups, died </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The histological lesions were restricted to rats dosed with 1.0 ml of latex/kg body weight and included multi-focal coagulation <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> of cardiac fibers and vacuolized hepatocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Subsequently, three groups of two sheep were treated with (1) a single dose of 30 g/kg, (2) a single dose of 60 g/kg or (3) 60 g/kg per day for 10 consecutive days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Exposure to the C. procera leaves was responsible for <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> and transitory <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmias</z:hpo> in sheep from <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Gross pathological analysis of sheep dosed with 60 g/kg per day for 10 days revealed mild <z:hpo ids='HP_0001541'>ascites</z:hpo>, exudates on the trachea, <z:hpo ids='HP_0100598'>pulmonary edema</z:hpo>, mild <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp> in the liver, hydropericardium, flaccid heart, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_579'>ulcers</z:mpath> on the abomasum and kidneys presenting pale juxtamedullary cortex </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The histological findings of the rat and sheep studies were similar and included multi-focal coagulation <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> of cardiac fibers and vacuolized hepatocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, our findings indicate that C. procera is a cardiotoxic and hepatotoxic plant </plain></SENT>
</text></document>