<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: The comparison of patients with long-standing implantable cardioverter-defibrillators (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICDs</z:e>) who have had or never have had appropriate therapy for <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> may offer insight into potential risk factors that may improve patient selection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Records from patients in the Columbia Presbyterian device clinic whose original <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> was implanted before 31 December 2004 were analysed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The patients were divided into those who had never received appropriate therapy for <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> (Group A, n = 188), and those who had received appropriate therapy (Group B, n = 173) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The subset of patients with consistent follow-up greater than 5 years was then analysed (Group A, n = 140; Group B, n = 158) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Demographic, clinical, echocardiographic, and electrocardiographic data were collected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There were no significant differences in age, sex, or type of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018799" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">heart disease</z:e> between the groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were more patients in Group B vs. A who had <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICDs</z:e> implanted for secondary prevention (70.3 vs. 55.7%, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The mean QRS width was similar at implant but increased significantly in Group B vs. A on pre-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> discharge electrocardiograms (134.1 ± 35.0 vs. 125.1 ± 36.2 ms, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>Congestive heart failure</z:hpo> class, comorbidities, use of antiarrhythmic agents, or left ventricular ejection fraction were not discriminators between Groups A and B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In this study of patients with long-standing <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICDs</z:e>, the only discriminating factors for appropriate shocks were implant for secondary prevention or increasing QRS width, suggesting electrical factors are the best predictors of ultimate <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> discharges </plain></SENT>
</text></document>