<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>Obese</z:mp> subjects show several electrocardiographic alterations, including <z:mp ids='MP_0003233'>prolonged QT interval</z:mp>, a marker for fatal <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0003233'>Prolonged QT interval</z:mp> has recently been linked to low <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> levels, a frequent occurrence in male <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients but no study has yet assessed whether <z:hpo ids='HP_0008226'>hypoandrogenism</z:hpo> contributes to QT interval prolongation in this population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Aim of this study was to evaluate whether <z:mp ids='MP_0003233'>prolonged QT interval</z:mp> is linked to <z:hpo ids='HP_0000135'>hypogonadism</z:hpo> in male <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>QT interval corrected for heart rate (QTc) was measured from standard electrocardiogram recordings in 136 <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> men (BMI 30 &gt;kg/m(2), range 30.1-75.4 kg/m(2)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>Obese</z:mp> men were classified as eugonadal or hypogonadal according to serum total <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> levels (i.e., greater or less than 9.9 nmol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Our study showed that QTc measurements corrected by either Bazett (419 ± 3.2 vs. 408 ± 3.4 ms, P &lt; 0.05), Fridericia (406.3 ± 3.39 vs. 396.4 ± 3.03 ms, P &lt; 0.05) or Hodges (407.0 ± 3.12 vs. 397.3 ± 2.84 ms, P &lt; 0.05) were longer in hypogonadal compared with eugonadal <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> men; further, <z:hpo ids='HP_0005184'>prolonged QTc interval</z:hpo> (i.e., &gt;440 ms) was more frequent among hypogonadal compared with eugonadal <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> men (23% vs. 10%, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The degree of weight excess, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0010535'>sleep apnoea</z:hpo> and <z:chebi fb="120" ids="26216">potassium</z:chebi> levels were not associated with prolonged QTc </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> hypogonadal men show a greater prevalence of <z:mp ids='MP_0003233'>prolonged QT interval</z:mp> compared with their eugonadal counterparts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>It appears therefore that low levels of <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> men may contribute to the arrhythmogenic profile of these patients, a heretofore unknown link which warrants further clinical attention </plain></SENT>
</text></document>