<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Patients may suffer from right ventricular (RV) failure and malignant <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmias</z:hpo> after late pulmonary valve replacement correcting <z:mp ids='MP_0006048'>pulmonary regurgitation</z:mp> (PR) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>But the underlying mechanisms of the refractory <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> are not well understood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The aim of present study was to characterize the RV myocardium after percutaneous pulmonary valve implantation (PPVI) in a porcine model after severe PR for 3months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RV histology was evaluated with morphometric methods and RV function was assessed with electrophysiology, echocardiography, and biochemical measures: The results were compared with age-matched sham-operated animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: At euthanasia, RV weight was increased compared to sham-animals, median 127 g (115-137) vs. 71 g (69.5-76.5), p=0.0007 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RV myocyte diameters corrected for individual variation with the RV/LV ratio were enlarged, 1.06 (1.02-1.13) vs. 0.84 (0.80-0.91), p=0.0006 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were no excess collagen tissue (RV/LV ratio), p=0.77 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Electrophysiological stimulation resulted in RV <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> in 67% of the animals compared to 25% in the sham-operated animals, but this difference was not statistically significant, p=0.28 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Echocardiography revealed geometrical dilation in end-systolic RV area, mean ± SD, 11.8 ± 4.9 cm(2) vs. 6.0 ± 3.5 cm(2), p=0.05, and end-diastolic area, 23.3 ± 10.4 cm(2) vs. 12.7 ± 2.5 cm(2), p=0.08 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RV anterior free wall thickness was not increased, 0.7 ± 0.2 cm vs. 0.7 ± 0.1 cm, p=0.66 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Echocardiographic functional parameters and plasma natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptides</z:chebi> were unchanged </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The RV does not completely recover after three months of PR with persistent <z:mp ids='MP_0010633'>myocardial hypertrophy</z:mp> one month after PPVI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Future studies should address whether RV chamber and <z:mp ids='MP_0005482'>cellular hypertrophy</z:mp>, without <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> or interventional scar tissue, may be substrate for <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>