<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) is associated with reverse left ventricular (LV) remodelling </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, the effects of CRT-induced mechanical remodelling on electrical remodelling, and the occurrence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> have not been clearly established </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We studied the relationship between mechanical remodelling, electrical remodelling, and the occurrence of appropriate implantable cardioverter-defibrillator (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>) therapy 1 year after CRT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: We analysed data from 45 patients who underwent <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>-CRT implantation at our centre </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Significant LV reverse remodelling was defined by a minimum 10% decrease in the LV end-diastolic diameter (LVEDd) at 1 year of follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Electrocardiographic indices of dispersion of repolarization [QTc, Tpeak-Tend (Tp-e) and their dispersion] were measured immediately and 1 year post-CRT implantation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The occurrence of appropriate <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> therapy was noted for each patient </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients with (n= 21) and without (n= 24) significant LV reverse remodelling had similar baseline characteristics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>At 1 year of follow-up, patients with mechanical reverse LV remodelling exhibited a significant decrease in QTc (505 ± 42 vs. 485 ± 52 ms, P &lt; 0.05) and Tp-e (107 ± 26 vs. 92 ± 22 ms, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, patients without mechanical LV reverse remodelling exhibited a significant increase in QT dispersion (29 ± 43 vs. 98 ± 47 ms, P = 0.002) and Tp-e dispersion (22 ± 21 vs. 54 ± 36 ms, P = 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Finally patients with mechanical LV reverse remodelling experienced a lower rate of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> therapy (P = 0.0025) after a mean follow-up of 19 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Reverse LV mechanical remodelling is associated with reversal of electrical remodelling and a lower rate of appropriate <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> therapy following CRT </plain></SENT>
</text></document>