<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To study the safety and the effects of early continuous hypertonic saline infusion in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002181'>cerebral edema</z:hpo> and underlying cerebrovascular disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>DESIGN: Retrospective analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>SETTING: University medical center </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS: Neurologic intensive care unit population with mixed cerebrovascular diseases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>INTERVENTIONS: None </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>MEASUREMENTS AND MAIN RESULTS: Between May 2008 and December 2009, 100 patients with severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001342'>intracerebral hemorrhage</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>, or aneurysmal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002138'>subarachnoid hemorrhage</z:hpo> and signs of intracranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> received within ≤72 hrs after symptom <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> a continuous infusion of hypertonic saline (3%, target <z:chebi fb="199" ids="26708">sodium</z:chebi> 145-155 mmol/L, target osmolality 310-320 mOsm/kg) over 13 (4-23) days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We analyzed the frequency of episodes with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0151740" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">elevated intracranial pressure</z:e> (new <z:hpo ids='HP_0009916'>anisocoria</z:hpo> or intracranial pressure &gt;20 mm Hg for ≥20 mins), inhospital mortality, and the occurrence of adverse effects theoretically associated with hypertonic saline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The findings were compared with those of a historical control group (n = 115, 2007-2008) with equal underlying disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the treatment group, fewer episodes of critically <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0151740" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">elevated intracranial pressure</z:e> (92 vs. 167, p = .027) in fewer patients (50 of 100 = 50.0% vs. 69 of 115 = 60.0% patients, p = .091) were observed, and inhospital mortality was significantly decreased (17.0% vs. 29.6%, p = .037) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Adverse events, including <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmia</z:hpo>, heart, liver or <z:hpo ids='HP_0000082'>renal dysfunction</z:hpo>, or <z:hpo ids='HP_0100598'>pulmonary edema</z:hpo>, occurred in both groups to a similar extent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Early and continuous infusion of hypertonic saline in patients with severe cerebrovascular disease and impending intracranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> is safe and might reduce the frequency of intracranial pressure crises and mortality rate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>A randomized controlled trial is warranted to confirm our findings and to evaluate the effects of hypertonic saline on functional outcomes </plain></SENT>
</text></document>