<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: We aimed to evaluate the safety and long-term efficacy of the magnetic navigation system (MNS) in a large number of patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The MNS has the potential for improving safety and efficacy based on atraumatic catheter design and superior navigation capabilities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: In this study, 610 consecutive patients underwent ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients were divided into two age- and sex-matched groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Ablations were performed either using MNS (group MNS, 292) or conventional manual ablation [group manual navigation (MAN), 318] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The following parameters were analysed: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> success rate, fluoroscopy time, procedure time, complications [major: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007177" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pericardial tamponade</z:e>, permanent atrioventricular (AV) block, major <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>; minor: minor <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp> and temporary <z:mp ids='MP_0010519'>AV block</z:mp>] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Recurrence rate was assessed during follow-up (15±9.5 months) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Subgroup analysis was performed for the following groups: <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo>, isthmus dependent and atypical <z:hpo ids='HP_0004749'>atrial flutter</z:hpo>, atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo>, AV nodal re-entrant <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo>, circus movement <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> (VT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Magnetic navigation system was associated with less major complications (0.34 vs. 3.2%, P=0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The total numbers of complications were lower in group MNS (4.5 vs. 10%, P=0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Magnetic navigation system was equally effective as MAN in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> success rate for overall groups (92 vs. 94%, P=ns) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Magnetic navigation system was more successful for VTs (93 vs. 72%, P&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Less fluoroscopy was used in group MNS (30±20 vs. 35±25 min, P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>There were no differences in procedure times and recurrence rates for the overall groups (168±67 vs. 159±75 min, P=ns; 14 vs. 11%, P=ns; respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our data suggest that the use of MNS improves safety without compromising efficiency of ablations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Magnetic navigation system is more effective than manual ablation for VTs </plain></SENT>
</text></document>