<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Patients with persistent or <z:hpo ids='HP_0004754'>permanent atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) often need direct current cardioversion after radiofrequency ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to investigate the effectiveness and safety of ibutilide for cardioversion of persistent or <z:hpo ids='HP_0004754'>permanent atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> after radiofrequency ablation and the factors related to conversion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Patients with persistent or <z:hpo ids='HP_0004754'>permanent atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> were treated with combined ablation strategy including circumferential pulmonary vein isolation, linear ablation and CAFÉ potential ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>If AF was not terminated after ablation, ibutilide was used for cardioversion (1 mg, intravenous injection in 10 minutes) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>These patients were divided into a conversion group and a non-conversion group according to whether AF was converted to sinus rhythm within 30 minutes after administration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>ECG monitoring was performed during the injection of ibutilide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Atrial waves recorded by coronary sinus electrodes were measured for calculating average wavelength of AF waves in six seconds </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The QT interval was measured immediately after conversion and 2 hours after injection of ibutilide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Forty patients whose AF was not converted to sinus rhythm after radiofrequency ablation were given an intravenous injection of ibutilide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Of the 40 patients, 29 cases were converted to sinus rhythm, with a conversion rate of 72.5% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The average conversion time was (13.2 ± 5.5) minutes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Compared with the conversion group, patients in the non-conversion group had a longer history of AF (9.4 ± 5.3) years vs. (4.3 ± 2.8) years, P &lt; 0.05), and a markedly <z:mp ids='MP_0008726'>enlarged left atrium</z:mp> (47.3 ± 2.9) mm vs. (42.1 ± 4.5) mm, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>There were no significant differences in gender, age, body mass index and left ventricular function between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Ibutilide significantly prolonged the average wavelength of the AF wave (171.8 ± 29.5) ms vs. (242.0 ± 40.0) ms, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Two hours after ibutilide treatment, the QT interval was significantly shortened (421.0 ± 24.7) ms vs. (441.0 ± 37.4) ms, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>No cases of serious <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> or other adverse reactions were found </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A single dose of ibutilide for conversion of persistent or permanent AF after radiofrequency ablation is safe and effective </plain></SENT>
</text></document>