<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001645'>Sudden cardiac death</z:hpo> in competitive athletes is rare but it is significantly more frequent than in the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The exact cause is seldom established and is mostly attributed to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001663'>ventricular fibrillation</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0010633'>Myocardial hypertrophy</z:mp> and slow heart rate, both characteristic changes in top athletes in response to physical conditioning, could be associated with increased propensity for <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We investigated conventional ECG parameters and temporal short-term beat-to-beat variability of repolarization (STV(QT)), a presumptive novel parameter for <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> prediction, in professional soccer players </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Five-minute 12-lead electrocardiograms were recorded from professional soccer players (n = 76, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> males, age 22.0±0.61 years) and age-matched healthy volunteers who do not participate in competitive sports (n = 76, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> males, age 22.0±0.54 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The ECGs were digitized and evaluated off-line </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The temporal instability of beat-to-beat heart rate and repolarization were characterized by the calculation of short-term variability of the RR and QT intervals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Heart rate was significantly lower in professional soccer players at rest (61±1.2 vs. 72±1.5/min in controls) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The QT interval was prolonged in players at rest (419±3.1 vs. 390±3.6 in controls, p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>QTc was significantly longer in players compared to controls calculated with Fridericia and Hodges correction formulas </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Importantly, STV(QT) was significantly higher in players both at rest and immediately after the game compared to controls (4.8±0.14 and 4.3±0.14 vs. 3.5±0.10 ms, both p&lt;0.001, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: STV(QT) is significantly higher in professional soccer players compared to age-matched controls, however, further studies are needed to relate this finding to increased <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> propensity in this population </plain></SENT>
</text></document>