<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Percutaneous positioning of closure devices is a well-established treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001631'>atrial septal defects</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ASDs</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, patients who have undergone the procedure are at increased risk for developing <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF), and treatment by catheter ablation is underutilized due to the perceived difficulty of obtaining transseptal access in the presence of the closure device </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The purpose of this study was to report the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> and long-term results of radiofrequency catheter ablation of AF in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ASD</z:e> closure devices </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Thirty-nine patients (age 54 ± 6 years, 72% males) with drug-refractory AF (33% paroxysmal, 51% persistent, 16% long-standing persistent) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ASD</z:e> closure devices (82% Amplatzer, 18% CardioSEAL) underwent radiofrequency catheter ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A double transseptal access guided by intracardiac echocardiography was obtained in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In 35 of 39 patients (90%), the transseptal access was obtained in a portion of the native septum, whereas in 4 of 39 patients (10%), a direct access through the device was required </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The latter group had a significantly longer time for achieving the double transseptal access (73.6 ± 1.1 minutes vs. 4.3 ± 0.4 minutes, P &lt; .001), longer fluoroscopy time (122 ± 5 minutes vs. 80 ± 8 minutes, P &lt; .001), and total procedural time (4.1 ± 0.2 hours vs. 3.1 ± 0.3 hours, P &lt; .001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At follow-up of 14 ± 4, months the overall success rate was 77% (85% in paroxysmal AF, 73% in nonparoxysmal AF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Transthoracic contrast-enhanced echocardiography with the Valsalva maneuver, performed between 3 and 6 months after the procedure, failed to detect shunt in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Radiofrequency catheter ablation of AF is feasible, safe, and effective in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ASD</z:e> closure devices </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Transseptal access can be obtained in portions of the native septum in the majority of cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Direct transseptal puncture of the device is feasible and safe but requires longer time for each transseptal access </plain></SENT>
</text></document>