<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Early inward motion and thickening/thinning of the ventricular septum associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011713'>left bundle branch block</z:hpo> is known as the septal flash (SF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Correction of SF corresponds to response to cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that SF was associated with a specific left ventricular (LV) activation pattern predicting a favourable response to CRT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We sought to characterize the spatio-temporal relationship between electrical and mechanical events by directly comparing non-contact mapping (NCM), <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> haemodynamics, and echocardiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Thirteen patients (63 ± 10 years, 10 men) with severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> (ejection fraction 22.8 ± 5.8%) awaiting CRT underwent echocardiography and NCM pre-implant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Presence and extent of SF defined visually and with M-mode was fused with NCM bull's eye plots of endocardial activation patterns </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>LV-dP/dt(max) was measured during different pacing modes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Five patients had a large SF, four small SF, and four no SF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Large SF patients had areas of conduction block in non-infarcted regions, whereas those with small or no SF did not </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Patients with large SF had greater <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> response to LV and biventricular (BIV) pacing vs. those with small/no SF (% increase dP/dt 28 ± 14 vs. 11 ± 19% for LV pacing and 42 ± 28 vs. 22 ± 21% for BIV pacing) (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This translated into a more favourable <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> response to CRT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The lines of conduction block disappeared with LV/BIV pacing while remaining with right ventricle pacing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: A strong association exists between electrical activation and mechanical deformation of the septum </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Correction of both mechanical synchrony and the functional conduction block by CRT may explain the favourable response in patients with SF </plain></SENT>
</text></document>