<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: In this study, our aim was to evaluate the effect of a higher dose of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> on the recurrence rate of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) after electrical cardioversion (EC) in addition to antiarrhythmic therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>SUBJECTS AND METHODS: 48 patients with persistent AF were included in this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The patients were randomized to an <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> 40-mg treatment group and a control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">Atorvastatin</z:chebi> was started 3 weeks before EC and was continued for 2 months after EC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>EC was performed using biphasic shocks after 3 weeks of treatment with the orally administered <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50249">anticoagulant</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="8" ids="10033">warfarin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">Lipid</z:chebi> and inflammatory parameters (high-sensitivity C-reactive protein, white blood cell count and fibrinogen level) were evaluated at the baseline and before EC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The endpoint of this study was electrocardiographically confirmed recurrence of AF of &gt;10 min </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were no significant differences in baseline characteristics and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> and inflammatory marker levels between the treatment and control groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Total cholesterol and <z:chebi fb="2" ids="39026">low-density lipoprotein</z:chebi> levels were significantly decreased in patients taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> for 2 months compared with baseline values (174 ± 31 vs. 129 ± 25 mg/dl, p = 0.001, and 112 ± 23 vs. 62 ± 20 mg/dl, p = 0.001, respectively), while no significant change occurred in control patients (168 ± 26 vs. 182 ± 29 mg/dl, p = 0.07, and 99 ± 18 vs. 108 ± 26 mg/dl, p = 0.1, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>At the end of the 2-month follow-up period, 9 patients (20.5%) experienced AF recurrence, and there was no significant difference in AF recurrence rate between the treatment and control groups (26 vs. 13%; p = 0.2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">Atorvastatin</z:chebi> therapy prior to EC does not prevent the recurrence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> in patients with persistent AF who are receiving antiarrhythmic therapy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>