<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: The purpose of this study was to evaluate whether electrocardiographic characteristics of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> distinguish patients with arrhythmogenic right ventricular <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>/<z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (ARVD/C) from those with right ventricular outflow tract <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> (RVOT-VT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>Ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> in RVOT-VT and ARVD/C-VT patients can share a <z:hpo ids='HP_0011713'>left bundle branch block</z:hpo>/inferior axis <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We compared the electrocardiographic <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0006682'>premature ventricular contractions</z:hpo> with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011713'>left bundle branch block</z:hpo>/inferior axis pattern in 16 ARVD/C patients with that in 42 RVOT-VT patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: ARVD/C patients had a significantly longer mean QRS duration in lead I (150 ± 31 ms vs. 123 ± 34 ms, p = 0.006), more often exhibited a precordial transition in lead V(6) (3 of 17 [18%] vs. 0 of 42 [0%] with RVOT-VT, p = 0.005), and more often had at least 1 lead with notching (11 of 17 [65%] vs. 9 of 42 [21%], p = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The most sensitive characteristics for the detection of ARVD/C were a QRS duration in lead I of ≥120 ms (88% sensitivity, 91% negative predictive value) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>QRS transition at V(6) was most specific at 100% (100% positive predictive value, 77% negative predictive value) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The presence of notching on any QRS complex had 79% sensitivity and 65% specificity of (55% positive predictive value, 85% negative predictive value) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In multivariate analysis, QRS duration in lead I of ≥120 ms (odds ratio [OR]: 20.4, p = 0.034), earliest <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> QRS in lead V(1) (OR: 17.0, p = 0.022), QRS notching (OR: 7.7, p = 0.018), and a transition of V(5) or later (OR: 7.0, p = 0.030) each predicted the presence of ARVD/C </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Several electrocardiographic criteria can help distinguish right ventricular outflow tract <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> originating from ARVD/C compared with RVOT-VT patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>