<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: The arrhythmogenic relationship between the presence of J-waves during sinus rhythm and idiopathic <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> (VT) or pre-mature ventricular contractions (<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVCs</z:mp>) originating from the right ventricular outflow tract (RVOT) has not been reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to investigate the prevalence and characteristics of idiopathic RVOT-VT/<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVCs</z:mp> associated with J-waves </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: The study enrolled 138 consecutive idiopathic RVOT-VT/<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> patients undergoing radiofrequency catheter ablation (RFCA) and 276 age- and gender-matched control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of J-waves was assessed in each cohort, and the clinical and electrophysiological data were compared between the RVOT-VT/<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> patients with J-waves (J-RVOT-VT/<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> group) and those without (non-J-RVOT-VT/<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>J-waves were more common among patients with idiopathic RVOT-VT/<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVCs</z:mp> than among the matched control subjects (40 vs. 16% P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The J-RVOT-VT/<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> group had a higher incidence of sustained VT (25 vs. 5%, P &lt; 0.01), shorter VT cycle length (302 ± 57 vs. 351 ± 58 ms, P &lt; 0.001), and more episodes of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> (25 vs. 2%, P &lt; 0.001) than did the non-J-RVOT-VT/<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, no patients demonstrated any <z:hpo ids='HP_0001663'>ventricular fibrillation</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">VF</z:e>) or cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0001699'>sudden death</z:hpo> in either group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: There was a high prevalence of J-waves in the idiopathic RVOT-VT/<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> patients referred for RFCA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Although patients with idiopathic RVOT <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> associated with J-waves might have a more enhanced arrhythmogenicity than those without J-waves, the significance of those J-waves was limited in terms of the prognosis and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">VF</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>