<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: The SHIFT echocardiographic substudy evaluated the effects of ivabradine on left ventricular (LV) remodelling in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> (HF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Eligible patients had <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> HF and systolic dysfunction [LV ejection fraction (LVEF) ≤35%], were in sinus rhythm, and had resting heart rate ≥70 bpm </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients were randomly allocated to ivabradine or placebo, superimposed on background therapy for HF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Complete echocardiographic data at baseline and 8 months were available for 411 patients (ivabradine 208, placebo 203) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Treatment with ivabradine reduced LVESVI (primary substudy endpoint) vs. placebo [-7.0 ± 16.3 vs. -0.9 ± 17.1 mL/m(2); difference (SE), -5.8 (1.6), 95% CI -8.8 to -2.7, P&lt; 0.001] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The reduction in LVESVI was independent of beta-blocker use, HF aetiology, and baseline LVEF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Ivabradine also improved LV end-diastolic volume index (-7.9 ± 18.9 vs. -1.8 ± 19.0 mL/m(2), P= 0.002) and LVEF (+2.4 ± 7.7 vs. -0.1 ± 8.0%, P&lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The incidence of the SHIFT primary composite outcome (cardiovascular mortality or hospitalization for worsening HF) was higher in patients with LVESVI above the median (59 mL/m2) at baseline (HR 1.62, 95% CI 1.03-2.56, P= 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Patients with the largest relative reductions in LVESVI had the lowest event rates </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Ivabradine reverses cardiac remodelling in patients with HF and LV systolic dysfunction </plain></SENT>
</text></document>