<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Pulmonary vein isolation alone is ineffective in maintaining sinus rhythm in up to one third of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004757'>paroxysmal atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We compared pulmonary vein antral isolation plus additional limited ablation along the inferoposterior left atrium and epicardially within the adjacent coronary sinus (PVAI + CS) to pulmonary vein antral isolation (PVAI) alone in patients with paroxysmal AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Forty-two consecutive patients with paroxysmal AF were prospectively randomized to PVAI vs. PVAI + CS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients were seen 3, 6, 12, and 18 months after ablation and underwent 24-h ambulatory Holter monitoring </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Following a single procedure, 17 out of 22 patients (77%) remained <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> free off antiarrhythmic medication after PVAI at 18 months vs. 10 out of 20 (50%) after PVAI + CS (p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After PVAI, three patients had recurrent paroxysmal AF, and two had atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo>, whereas after PVAI + CS, three patients had recurrent paroxysmal AF, and seven had atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients in the PVAI + CS group with atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> who underwent a second procedure were found to have peri-mitral macro-reentry as the underlying mechanism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Eighty-one percent of patients remained <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> free off medication after 1.09 procedures in the PVAI group vs. 80% after 1.35 procedures in the PVAI + CS group (p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The addition of limited ablation along the inferoposterior left atrium and within the adjacent coronary sinus to PVAI alone did not reduce the recurrence rate of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004757'>paroxysmal atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> and was associated with an increased rate of peri-mitral macro-reentrant atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>