<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: To investigate the atrial electromechanical delay (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EMD</z:e>) duration that is a non-invasive predictor of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet's disease</z:e> (BD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Thirty-eight <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet</z:e>'s patients (24 females, 14 males; mean age: 43.6 ± 10.3 years) who were being followed in the dermatology or internal medicine department and 29 demographically matched controls (13 females, 16 males; mean: age 42.6 ± 11.1 years) were included in the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The inclusion criteria were <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0554021" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">recurrent oral ulcerations</z:e> and two of the following features: recurrent <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0151281" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">genital ulceration</z:e>, eye lesions, <z:mp ids='MP_0001212'>skin lesions</z:mp> or positive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0878631" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pathergy</z:e> skin test for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet</z:e>'s group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Using tissue Doppler imaging, atrial electromechanical coupling [time interval from the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of P wave on surface electrocardiogram to the beginning of A wave interval with tissue Doppler echocardiography (PA)] were measured from the lateral mitral annulus (PA lateral), septal mitral annulus (PA septum), and right ventricular tricuspid annulus (PA tricuspid) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The mean disease duration was 10.5 ± 7.7 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The inter-atrial and intra-atrial <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EMD</z:e> were significantly higher in the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet</z:e> group than those in the controls (19.8 ± 8.2 vs. 13.1 ± 4.4 ms, P = 0.001; 11.5 ± 7.4 vs. 6.9 ± 3.7 ms, P = 0.02; respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The left atrial <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EMD</z:e> was similar in both of the groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, the P(max) and PWD values were significantly higher in the BD group compared with those in the controls (120.5 ± 10.1 vs. 112.1 ± 5.9 ms, P &lt; 0.0001; 44.9 ± 10.7 vs. 28.4 ± 5.9 ms, P &lt; 0.0001; respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Atrial electromechanical conduction times were increased in the BD patients compared with those in the controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The tendency of BD patients to go into AF can be easily and non-invasively detected using tissue Doppler echocardiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>These findings may be indicators for subclinical cardiac involvement </plain></SENT>
</text></document>