<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Bartonella vinsonii subsp. berkhoffii is a recognized cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> in dogs and human patients and has been associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmias</z:hpo>, <z:mp ids='MP_0001856'>myocarditis</z:mp>, granulomatous <z:hpo ids='HP_0002840'>lymphadenitis</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0162323" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">polyarthritis</z:e>, and granulomatous <z:mp ids='MP_0001867'>rhinitis</z:mp> in dogs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Little is known regarding the mode of transmission or cellular localization of this bacteria following <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> of a canine host </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of the current study was to determine whether erythrocytes may serve as a site of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> by B. vinsonii subsp. berkhoffii </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the study, we successfully demonstrate the invasion of canine erythrocytes by a B. vinsonii subsp. berkhoffii genotype III strain using an in vitro model system </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Dog erythrocytes were incubated with B. vinsonii subsp. berkhoffii after which tubes were treated with gentamicin at 12, 24, and 48 h post-inoculation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After gentamicin elimination of extracellular bacteria, there was a gradual increase in intra-erythrocytic bacteria, as assessed by colony forming units per ml, at each collection time point </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The largest recovery of intracellular bacteria occurred at 48 h post-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These results suggest that canine erythrocytes may serve in the maintenance of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004610" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bacteremia</z:e> due to B. vinsonii subsp. berkhoffii within an infected host </plain></SENT>
</text></document>