<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Catheter ablation of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> (VT) can be limited by <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948268" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">haemodynamic instability</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In these cases, substrate-based ablation is typically performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>An alternative is to perform activation and entrainment mapping during VT supported by a percutaneous left ventricular assist device (pVAD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We sought to compare the complication and success rates of pVAD-assisted VT ablation with scar-based techniques </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Thirteen consecutive patients with haemodynamically unstable VT underwent pVAD-assisted ablation (pVAD group) and were retrospectively compared with 18-matched patients undergoing a substrate-based VT ablation (non-pVAD group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference in age or ejection fraction between the groups although pVAD patients tended to have more shocks in the preceding months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Procedure times were longer for the pVAD group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The number of monomorphic VTs induced was greater in the pVAD group (3.2 vs. 1.6, P= 0.04); however, after ablation, there was no difference in inducibility between the pVAD and non-pVAD group (10 of 13 vs. 12 of 18; 77 vs. 67%, P = 0.69) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was no difference in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> complications including <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>At 9 ± 3 months, 1-year freedom from implantable cardioverter-defibrillator (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>) shocks/therapies for sustained VT were similar (P= 0.96) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In multivariable analysis, the absence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (hazard ratio=0.15, P= 0.04) was associated with a lower incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> shocks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In high-risk patients, pVAD-assisted VT ablation guided by activation and entrainment mapping is a feasible alternative to substrate mapping and allows outcomes comparable to substrate mapping </plain></SENT>
</text></document>