<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>CD36 fatty acid translocase plays a key role in supplying heart with its major energy substrate, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15904">long-chain fatty acids</z:chebi> (FA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Previously, we found that the spontaneously hypertensive rat (SHR) harbors a deletion variant of Cd36 gene that results in reduced transport of long-chain FA into cardiomyocytes and predisposes the SHR to <z:mp ids='MP_0001625'>cardiac hypertrophy</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In the current study, we analyzed the effects of mutant Cd36 on susceptibility to ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> in adult SHR-Cd36 transgenic rats with <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> Cd36 compared with age-matched SHR controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Using an open-chest model of coronary <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp>, we found that SHR-Cd36 transgenic rats showed profound arrhythmogenesis resulting in significantly increased duration of tachyarrhythmias (207 ± 48 s vs. 55 ± 21 s, P &lt; 0.05), total number of premature ventricular complexes (2,623 ± 517 vs. 849 ± 250, P &lt; 0.05) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> score (3.86 ± 0.18 vs. 3.13 ± 0.13, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>On the other hand, transgenic SHR compared with SHR controls showed significantly reduced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size (52.6 ± 4.3% vs. 72.4 ± 2.9% of area at risk, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Similar differences were observed in isolated perfused hearts, and the increased susceptibility of transgenic SHR to <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> was abolished by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28487">reserpine</z:chebi>, suggesting the involvement of <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33567">catecholamines</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>To further search for possible molecular mechanisms of altered ischemic tolerance, we compared gene expression profiles in left ventricles dissected from 6-wk-old transgenic SHR vs. age-matched controls using Illumina-based sequencing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Circadian rhythms and oxidative phosphorylation were identified as the top KEGG pathways, while circadian rhythms, VDR/RXR activation, IGF1 signaling, and HMGB1 signaling were the top <z:chebi fb="23" ids="17824,30802">IPA</z:chebi> canonical pathways potentially important for Cd36-mediated effects on ischemic tolerance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>It can be concluded that transgenic expression of Cd36 plays an important role in modulating the incidence and severity of ischemic and reperfusion <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> and myocardial <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size induced by coronary <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The proarrhythmic effect of Cd36 transgene appears to be dependent on adrenergic stimulation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>