<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: The aim of this prospective study was to evaluate left atrial (LA) function for the prediction of increased risk of new-<z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> non-valvular <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Risk stratification for new-<z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> AF based on LA remodelling may have a major public health impact </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Although left atrial volume (LAV) or LA dimension have been proposed as predictors of AF, other predictive parameters of LA function have not yet been fully examined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: LA emptying function (EF), strain rate (SR), and LAV were evaluated in the apical four-chamber view by speckle tracking echocardiography in 580 consecutive adults (age 64 ± 17, 303 men) without a history of atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>During a follow-up period of 28 months, 32 subjects (age 73 ± 9, 18 men) developed electrocardiographically confirmed AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Subjects with new-<z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> AF had lower LA active EF (16 ± 5 vs. 28 ± 8%, P&lt; 0.001) and lower LA SR at atrial contraction (-0.9 ± 0.2 vs. -1.4 ± 0.5 S(-1), P&lt; 0.001), but larger maximum LAV index (59 ± 12 vs. 46 ± 16 mL/m(2), P&lt; 0.001) compared with non-AF subjects at baseline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In multivariate logistic regression analysis, LA active EF was the only independent predictor of new-<z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Using an LA active EF cut-off of ≤20%, the sensitivity and specificity for new-<z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> AF based on receiver operator characteristic curve analysis were 88 and 81%, respectively (area under the curve: 0.92) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Reduced LA active EF (booster pump function) assessed by speckle tracking echocardiography independently predicts the risk of new-<z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> AF, suggesting a stronger association between LA functional remodelling and AF than between LA size and AF </plain></SENT>
</text></document>