<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: An age of 60 years is often used as cut-off for the diagnosis of idiopathic <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We investigated the importance of age and atrial size in patients with idiopathic AF and AF patients with isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Out of 3978 AF patients in the Euro Heart Survey on AF with known follow-up, 119 (3%) patients had idiopathic AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We disregarded age and atrial size when selecting idiopathic AF patients since the atria may enlarge by AF itself </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>For comparison, we selected 152 patients with isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> from the database </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A total of 57 (48%) of the patients were older than 60 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Persistent or permanent AF was more prevalent in the older idiopathic AF patients (34% in the age &lt;60 vs. 66% in the age &gt;60 years group, P= 0.002) but mean duration of known AF did not differ between these groups [310 days (inter-quartile range, IQR) 60-1827) vs. 430 days (IQR 88-1669), P= 0.824] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Left atrial size did not differ significantly in relation to age (1.50 ± 0.29 mm/kg/m² in the age &lt;60 vs. 1.56 ± 0.31 mm/kg/m² in the age &gt;60 years group, P= 0.742) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Only two paroxysmal AF patients progressed to permanent AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>No cardiovascular events occurred during the 1-year follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In contrast, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>strokes</z:hpo> occurred in five patients (6%) with isolated <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> despite similar clinical profile and comparable atrial size as idiopathic AF patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Idiopathic AF may present at advanced age and is even then not associated with significant atrial enlargement, AF progression, or an adverse short-term prognosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In contrast, elevated blood pressure even when found in the absence of significant atrial remodelling, seems of prognostic importance </plain></SENT>
</text></document>