<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:mp ids='MP_0010514'>Fragmented QRS complex</z:mp> (<z:mp ids='MP_0010514'>fQRS</z:mp>) is associated with increased morbidity and mortality, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001645'>sudden cardiac death</z:hpo> and recurrent cardiovascular events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, its prognostic role has not been studied comprehensively in patients undergoing coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In this study, we investigated the relationship between the presence of <z:mp ids='MP_0010514'>fQRS</z:mp>, and the prognostic markers and in-hospital major adverse cardiovascular events (MACE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Two hundred and forty two eligible patients who underwent CABG surgery at our institution were enrolled consecutively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In analysis of fragmentations on electrocardiograms, presence of <z:mp ids='MP_0010514'>fQRS</z:mp> was defined as various <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16385">RSR</z:chebi>' patterns (≥ 1 R' or notching of S wave or R wave) with or without Q waves without a typical <z:hpo ids='HP_0011710'>bundle-branch block</z:hpo> in two contiguous leads corresponding to a major coronary artery territory </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>MACE was defined as cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, recurrent <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>, cerebrovascular event, sustained <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> or <z:mp ids='MP_0006109'>fibrillation</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients with fragmented QRS had older age (64 ± 10 vs. 61 ± 9 years, p = 0.03), prolonged QRS time (99 ± 11 vs. 87 ± 11 ms, p &lt; 0.001), higher rate of Q wave on ECG (29% vs. 12%, p = 0.001), higher European system for cardiac operative risk evaluation (EUROSCORE) (4.0 ± 1.9 vs. 2.6 ± 1.6, p &lt; 0.001) and lower left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF)% (43 ± 12 vs. 60 ± 12, p &lt; 0.001) in comparison to patients with non-fragmented QRS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In addition, the patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0010514'>fQRS</z:mp> had longer cross-clamp time (67 ± 23 vs. 55 ± 20 minutes, p = 0.001) and extracorporeal circulation (105 ± 31 vs. 91 ± 30 minutes, p = 0.003), increased inotropic usage (p &lt; 0.001) and prolonged cardiac surgery intensive care unit (53 ± 25 vs. 35 ± 12 hours, p &lt; 0.001) and in-hospital stay after CABG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: <z:mp ids='MP_0010514'>FQRS</z:mp> may have additional value in the assessment of cardiac function and in prediction of intra- and post-operative <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948268" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hemodynamic instability</z:e> and adverse cardiovascular events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Fragmentations on admission ECG may be useful for identifying patients with higher risk who will need additional support after CABG surgery </plain></SENT>
</text></document>