<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>UNLABELLED: BACKGROUD AND AIM: Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002204'>pulmonary embolism</z:hpo> (APE) present with highly variable symptoms and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>ECG abnormalities</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>As ST-elevation in lead aVR has recently been described to predict right ventricular dysfunction (RVD), we aimed to correlate this sign to the severity of APE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Three-hundred ninety-six consecutive patients (in centers a and b) with proven APE were retrospectively analysed with respect to 12-lead-ECG, symptoms, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> location, echocardiograpy, troponin T, initial therapy and outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Data were then compared between patients with and without aVR-ST-elevation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: On admission aVR-ST-elevation was present in 34.3% (n = 136) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Presence of aVR-ST-elevation was assossiated with more severe clinical presentation (dyspnoea at rest 44.9 vs. 29.2%; p = 0.002, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002615'>hypotension</z:hpo> 17.0 vs. 6.5%; p = 0.001, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> 16.2 vs. 6.5%; p = 0.002), higher median troponin T levels (0.035 [0.01-0.2] versus 0.01 [0.01-0.02]; p &lt; 0.001), more frequent RVD (74.5 vs. 46.6%; p &lt; 0.001) and central located <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">thrombi</z:e> (50.8 vs. 29.2; p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Thrombolysis was used more frequently (29.1 vs. 7.5%; p &lt; 0.001) and in-hospital-mortality was increased (10.3 vs. 5.4%; p = 0.07) when compared to patients without that sign </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Mortality in intermediate-risk APE patients with aVR-ST-elevation was 8.9% compared to 0% in those without (p = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the presence of other classical ECG pattern of APE did not further increase mortality in intermediate-risk patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: ST-elevation in lead aVR is associated with a more severe course of APE, especially in patients with intermediate-risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Therefore, aVR-ST-elevation might be useful in risk stratification of APE </plain></SENT>
</text></document>