<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to evaluate, in swimming, the agreement between the anaerobic threshold (AT) as determined from the analysis of blood <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> concentration (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="33336">[La]</z:chebi>) and from a new method based on the heart rate (HR) variability (HRV) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Fourteen high-level swimmers completed an incremental 7 × 200-m front crawl test, during which the HRV was measured continuously and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33336">[La]</z:chebi> was collected after each step </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To individuate the AT, the trends of the high-frequency HRV spectral power (HFPOW) and of the fraction of HFPOW relative to the respiratory sinus <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> (HFPOW-RSA) were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> the subjects, an abrupt increase of both HFPOW and HFPOW-RSA was observed and associated with the AT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The AT parameters determined, respectively, from <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33336">[La]</z:chebi> and HFPOW-RSA were similar (p &gt; 0.05) and highly correlated (HR: 182.0 ± 8.1 vs. 181.1 ± 8.2 b·min, r = 0.93, 95% limits of agreement [LoA]: -6.7 to 4.9 b·min; velocity: 1.47 ± 0.11 vs. 1.47 ± 0.11 m·s, r = 0.98, 95% LoA: -0.05 to 0.05 m·s) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Instead, the AT HR and velocity obtained from HFPOW (179.2 ± 8.4 b·min; 1.45 ± 0.11 m·s) were correlated to the corresponding parameters determined from <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33336">[La]</z:chebi> (HR: r = 0.84; velocity: r = 0.94) but underestimated them slightly (95% LoA: -11.9 to 6.3 b·min and -0.11 to 0.05 m·s) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These results demonstrate that the AT can be assessed from the HRV in swimming, providing an important testing tool for coaches </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, using the actual respiratory spectral component, rather than the total HF spectral power, allows us to obtain a more accurate estimate of AT parameters </plain></SENT>
</text></document>