<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: It is unknown as to whether the result of <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> testing for the diagnosis of sinus node dysfunction (SND) depends on the clinical presentation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We investigated whether <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> or presyncope are associated with a more pronounced sinus nodal inhibition by <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> in SND </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: We studied 46 patients with SND, 33 with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> or presyncope and 13 without such history </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Controls were 30 subjects undergoing electrophysiological studies for <z:hpo ids='HP_0004755'>supraventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> or unexplained <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We calculated the corrected sinus node recovery time after intravenous <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> 0.15 mg/kg (ADSNRT) as well as after atrial pacing (CSNRT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Corrected sinus node recovery time values &gt;525 ms were considered abnormal </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Corrected sinus node recovery time after <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> injection was more prolonged in SND patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> or presyncope as compared with those without such history [median: 4900 inter-quartile range (IQR): 920-8560 ms vs. median: 280 IQR: 5-908 ms; P&lt; 0.005] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In SND patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> or presyncope ADSNRT was more prolonged than CSNRT (median: 4900 IQR: 920-8560 ms vs. median: 680 IQR: 359-1650 ms, P&lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In SND patients without <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> or presyncope no statistical difference was noted between ADSNRT and CSNRT (median: 280 IQR: 5-908 ms vs. median: 396 IQR: 270-600 ms, P = 0.80) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The sensitivity of CSNRT for SND diagnosis was 57% and the specificity was 100% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>A cut-off of 1029 ms for ADSRNT yields the same sensitivity with a specificity of 96.6% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In patients with SND <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> or presyncope relate to an exaggerated sinus nodal suppression by <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Prolonged ADSNRT can diagnose cases with severe underlying SND where a more aggressive management strategy is probably warranted </plain></SENT>
</text></document>