<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: We investigate the role of left atrial volume (LAV) as a predictor of outcome following pulmonary vein isolation (PVI) in patients with exclusive <z:hpo ids='HP_0004757'>paroxysmal atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: PVI was performed in 213 patients (80 females, aged 60 ± 10 years) with paroxysmal AF using either the pulmonary vein ablation catheter (PVAC, n = 78) or conventional single-tip ablation (n = 135) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>LAV was assessed by multi-detector computed tomography (n = 39) or cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (n = 174) prior to ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>LA diameter (LAD) and LA area were determined by echocardiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients were followed up for 12 months clinically and with 72-h Holter ECG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The mean LAV was 85 ± 28 ml (range, 22-189 ml) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Mean LAD and mean LA area were 43 ± 6 mm and 23 ± 6 cm² </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>After a follow-up period of 18 ± 5 months, 202 patients were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>AF recurrence was documented in 50 (23%) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Univariate analysis showed age (59 ± 11 vs. 65 ± 6 years, p = 0.049), LA area (23 ± 5 vs. 27 ± 6 cm², p = 0.03), and LAV (80 ± 27 vs. 96 ± 28 ml, p = 0.04) to be significantly associated with the outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis revealed that none of these parameters were statistically significant (hazards ratio LAV, 0.52-1.12, p = 0.058; LA area, 0.63-1.14, p = 0.069; and age, 0.90-1.09, p = 0.41) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In the case of AF recurrence, patients with LAV &gt;95 ml showed a significantly higher probability for the occurrence of persistent AF (24% vs. 8%, p = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The assessment of LA size should not be incorporated as a main factor with regard to predicted ablation success in patients with paroxysmal AF being considered for PVI, as PVI may be successful even with considerable LA enlargement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Ablation should be performed promptly in patients with LAV ≤ 95 ml to prevent further LA <z:mpath ids='MPATH_66'>dilatation</z:mpath>, as patients with LAV &gt;95 ml have an increased probability to develop persistent AF in the case of ablation failure </plain></SENT>
</text></document>