<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Among the electrocardiographic alterations used for stratifying the cardiovascular risk of life threatening <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> (LFA) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001699'>sudden death</z:hpo> (SD) there is the increment of the corrected QT(QTc) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This increment is usually observable in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients (OP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Therefore, a study has been planned to investigate the possibility to predict QTc values in OP simply by detecting the best fitting regression method that represents the relationship between QTc and Body Mass Index (BMI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: The study has been carried on 144 individuals classified as a function of their BMI in normoponderal subjects (NPS, No. 24; F/M=15/9; BMI=21.8± 1.7 kg/m(2)), Class I OP (No. 24; F/M=17/7; BMI=32.5± 1.1 kg/m(2)); Class II OP (No. 24; F/M=17/7; BMI=37.7± 1.5 kg/m(2)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Class IIIa (No. 24, F/M=15/9; BMI=44.4± 27 kg/m(2)), Class IIIb (No. 24; F/M=14/10; BMI 54.3± 2.7 kg/m(2)); Class IIIc (No. 24; F/M=14/10; BMI=63.3± 4.5 kg/m(2)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Both linear and non-linear fitting modes have been tested </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: While the BMI progressively increases in classified OP, the QTc shows an intergroup difference that is not only not constant but also declining in Class IIIc <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The optimal regressive model was found to be the following fourth order degree polynomial: QTc=317,15+(7,47xBMI)+(-0,28*BMI(2))+(0,005xBMI(3))+ (-0,00003xBMI(4)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: By entering the BMI of a given OP into the above-cited formula, the QTc can be easily predicted and compared to that of NPS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Importantly, to have the possibility for a pre-electrocardiographic estimation of QTc allows <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> the medical and paramedical personnel, involved in the multidisciplinary treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, to immediately establish the cardiovascular risk in the OP under observation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>