<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Aging increases the risk for <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001645'>sudden cardiac death</z:hpo> (SCD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We aimed at elucidating aging-related electrical, functional, and structural changes in the heart and vasculature that account for this heightened arrhythmogenic risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Young (5-9 mo) and old (3.5-6 yr) female New Zealand White (NZW) rabbits were subjected to in vivo hemodynamic, electrophysiological, and echocardiographic studies as well as ex vivo optical mapping, high-field magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), and histochemical experiments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Aging increased aortic stiffness (baseline pulse wave velocity: young, 3.54 ± 0.36 vs. old, 4.35 ± 0.28 m/s, P &lt; 0.002) and diastolic (end diastolic pressure-volume relations: 3.28 ± 0.5 vs. 4.95 ± 1.5 mmHg/ml, P &lt; 0.05) and systolic (end systolic pressure-volume relations: 20.56 ± 4.2 vs. 33.14 ± 8.4 mmHg/ml, P &lt; 0.01) myocardial elastances in old rabbits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Electrophysiological and optical mapping studies revealed age-related slowing of ventricular and His-Purkinje conduction (His-to-ventricle interval: 23 ± 2.5 vs. 31.9 ± 2.9 ms, P &lt; 0.0001), altered conduction anisotropy, and a greater inducibility of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001663'>ventricular fibrillation</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">VF</z:e>, 3/12 vs. 7/9, P &lt; 0.05) in old rabbits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Histochemical studies confirmed an aging-related increased <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> in the ventricles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>MRI showed a deterioration of the free-running Purkinje fiber network in ventricular and septal walls in old hearts as well as aging-related alterations of the myofibrillar orientation and myocardial sheet structure that may account for this slowed conduction velocity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Aging leads to parallel stiffening of the aorta and the heart, including an increase in systolic stiffness and contractility and diastolic stiffness </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Increasingly, anisotropic conduction velocity due to <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> and altered myofibrillar orientation and myocardial sheet structure may contribute to the pathogenesis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">VF</z:e> in old hearts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The aging rabbit model represents a useful tool for elucidating age-related changes that predispose the aging heart to <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> and SCD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>