<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>To reduce long-term morbidity after revascularised <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo>, different therapeutic strategies have been investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Cell therapy with mononuclear cells from bone marrow (BMMC) or peripheral blood (PBMC) has been proposed to attenuate the adverse processes of remodelling and subsequent <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Previous trials have suggested that cell therapy may facilitate arrhythmogenesis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the present substudy of the HEBE cell therapy trial, we investigated whether intracoronary cell therapy alters the prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> after 1 month or the rate of severe arrhythmogenic events (SAE) in the first year </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In 164 patients of the trial we measured function and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size with cardiovascular magnetic resonance (CMR) imaging </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Holter registration was performed after 1 month from which the number of triplets (3 successive <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVCs</z:mp>) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardias</z:hpo> (VT, ≥4 successive <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVCs</z:mp>) was assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Thirty-three patients (20%) showed triplets and/or VTs, with similar distribution amongst the groups (triplets: control n = 8 vs. BMMC n = 9, p = 1.00; vs. PBMC n = 10, p = 0.67 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>VT: control n = 9 vs. BMMC n = 9, p = 0.80; vs. PBMC n = 11, p = 0.69) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>SAE occurred in 2 patients in the PBMC group and 1 patient in the control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, intracoronary cell therapy is not associated with an increase in <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> or SAE </plain></SENT>
</text></document>