<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: This study aims to determine the impact of preprocedural imaging using computerized tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) with 3-D reconstruction on procedural efficiency, efficacy, complications and clinical outcome in patients who undergo radiofrequency catheter ablation (RFA) to eliminate <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In this registry, a CT (n = 161) or MRI (n = 37) was obtained prior to RFA in 198 of 333 consecutive patients (age 61 ± 10 years) with paroxysmal (172) or persistent (161) AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Antral pulmonary vein isolation was performed in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients using an open-irrigation-tip catheter with a 3-D electroanatomical navigation system </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Procedural and clinical outcomes were compared among patients who underwent RFA with and without preprocedural imaging </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The mean duration of the procedure (246 ± 47 vs. 242 ± 40 min, P = 0.55), fluoroscopy (47 ± 13 vs. 50 ± 10 min, P = 0.16), and total RF application (83 ± 27 vs. 78 ± 23 min, P = 0.17) were similar among patients who did and did not have preprocedural imaging </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The likelihood of a complication also was similar (5/198 [3%] vs. 4/135 [3%], P = 1.0) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A repeat ablation was performed in 95/198 (48%) and 61/135 (45%) of the patients who did and did not have imaging study, respectively (P = 0.62) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At 22 ± 9 months, after a mean of 2 ± 1 procedures, 140/198 (71%) and 101/135 (75%) of the patients who did and did not have preprocedural imaging were in sinus rhythm (P = 0.4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Preprocedural awareness of pulmonary venous and left atrial <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>anatomy</z:mp> does not appear to have an effect on procedural efficiency or clinical outcomes in patients who undergo catheter ablation for AF </plain></SENT>
</text></document>