<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: The purpose of this study was to compare the efficacy of focused ultrasound circumferential pulmonary vein ablation (CPVa) and BOX ablation (BOXa) in an <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Twenty mongrel dogs were divided into either CPVa or BOXa groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>CPV or BOX focused ultrasonic ablation was conducted in each group after successful establishment of the AF model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Before-and-after ablation left atrial effective refractory period (LAERP), AF inducibility, and induced AF lasting time were measured in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The LAERP after AF model establishment was significantly shorter than that before establishment (102 ± 10 vs. 140 ± 10 ms, p &lt; 0.01, in the CPVa group; 105 ± 8 vs. 139 ± 11 ms, p &lt; 0.01, in the BOXa group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The AF inducibility after ablation was significantly lower than that before ablation in the two groups (98% vs. 28%, p &lt; 0.01, in the CPVa group; 97% vs.14%, p &lt; 0.01, in the BOXa group), and the induced AF lasting time after ablation was significantly shorter than that before ablation in both groups (233 ± 40 vs. 70 ± 29 s, p &lt; 0.01, in the CPVa group; 240 ± 41 vs. 34 ± 22 s, p &lt; 0.01, in the BOXa group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>On intergroup comparison, AF inducibility and induced AF lasting time after ablation were significantly lower/shorter in the BOXa group than those in the CPVa group (14% vs. 28%, p = 0.021; 34 ± 22 vs. 70 ± 29 s, p = 0.048, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In the experimental AF model, the epicardial focused ultrasound BOX ablation may be more effective to prevent the recurrence of AF compared with the CPV approach </plain></SENT>
</text></document>