<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Reentry accounts for most life-threatening <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo>, complicating <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo>, and therapies that consistently prevent reentry from occurring are lacking </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In this study, we compare antiarrhythmic effects of gene transfer of green fluorescent protein (GFP; sham), the skeletal muscle <z:chebi fb="199" ids="26708">sodium</z:chebi> channel (SkM1), the liver-specific connexin (Cx32), and SkM1/Cx32 in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011011'>subacute</z:hpo> canine <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Immediately after ligation of the left anterior descending artery, <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> constructs were implanted in the epicardial border zone (EBZ) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Five to 7 days later, efficient restoration of impulse propagation (narrow QRS and local electrogram duration) occurred in SkM1, Cx32, and SkM1/Cx32 groups (P&lt; 0.05 vs. GFP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Programmed electrical stimulation from the EBZ induced sustained <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> (VT)/<z:hpo ids='HP_0001663'>ventricular fibrillation</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">VF</z:e>) in 15/22 GFP dogs vs. 2/12 SkM1, 6/14 Cx32, and 8/10 SkM1/Cx32 (P&lt; 0.05 SkM1 vs. GFP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>GFP, SkM1, and SkM1/Cx32 had predominantly polymorphic VT/<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">VF</z:e>, whereas in Cx32 dogs, monomorphic VT predominated (P&lt; 0.05 for Cx32 vs. GFP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Tetrazolium red staining showed significantly larger <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> in Cx32- vs. GFP-treated animals (P&lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Whereas SkM1 gene transfer reduces the incidence of inducible VT/<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">VF</z:e>, Cx32 therapy to improve gap junctional conductance results in larger <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size, a different VT <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp>, and no antiarrhythmic efficacy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>