<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Air pollution exposure increases <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1301700" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiovascular morbidity</z:e> and mortality and is a major global public health concern </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: We investigated the benefits of reducing personal exposure to urban air pollution in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010068" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary heart disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In an open randomized crossover trial, 98 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010068" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary heart disease</z:e> walked on a predefined route in central Beijing, China, under different conditions: once while using a highly efficient face mask, and once while not using the mask </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Symptoms, exercise, personal air pollution exposure, blood pressure, heart rate, and 12-lead electrocardiography were monitored throughout the 24-hr study period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Ambient air pollutants were dominated by fine and ultrafine particulate matter (PM) that was present at high levels [74 μg/m³ for PM(2.5) (PM with aerodynamic diamater &lt;2.5 µm)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Consistent with traffic-derived sources, this PM contained organic carbon and <z:chebi fb="6" ids="33848">polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons</z:chebi> and was highly oxidizing, generating large amounts of free radicals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The face mask was well tolerated, and its use was associated with decreased self-reported symptoms and reduced maximal ST segment <z:hpo ids='HP_0000716'>depression</z:hpo> (-142 vs. -156 μV, p = 0.046) over the 24-hr period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>When the face mask was used during the prescribed walk, mean arterial pressure was lower (93 ± 10 vs. 96 ± 10 mmHg, p = 0.025) and heart rate variability increased (high-frequency power: 54 vs. 40 msec², p = 0.005; high-frequency normalized power: 23.5 vs. 20.5 msec, p = 0.001; root mean square successive differences: 16.7 vs. 14.8 msec, p = 0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, mask use did not appear to influence heart rate or energy expenditure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Reducing personal exposure to air pollution using a highly efficient face mask appeared to reduce symptoms and improve a range of cardiovascular health measures in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010068" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary heart disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Such interventions to reduce personal exposure to PM air pollution have the potential to reduce the incidence of cardiovascular events in this highly susceptible population </plain></SENT>
</text></document>