<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: The aim of this study was to evaluate the relationship between cigarette smoking and atrial rhythm disorders with the use of noninvasive methods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The study population consisted of 50 healthy volunteer smokers and 40 healthy volunteer non-smokers who had <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> echocardiographic parameters and similar sex and age profiles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>P-wave dispersion (PWD) was calculated from the 12-lead surface ECG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Left ventricle (LV) end-systolic and end-diastolic diameters, LV ejection fraction, and interatrial and intraatrial electromechanical delay were measured by tissue Doppler imaging and conventional echocardiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Isovolumetric relaxation time and deceleration time were significantly higher (91.5 ± 11 vs. 82.35 ± 8.6, p &lt; 0.0001; 215.7 ± 37.1 vs. 175.3 ± 17.7, p &lt; 0.0001, respectively), and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> was significantly lower in smokers (39.34 ± 7.5 vs.44.3 ± 8.07, p = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There were no significant differences between the groups with respect to Sm and Em values, Am value, and E/A and E/Em ratios </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, the Em/Am ratio was significantly lower in smokers (1.28 ± 0.21 vs. 1.44 ± 0.33, p &lt; 0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Inter- and intraatrial electromechanical delay were significantly higher in smokers when compared with non-smokers (51.11 ± 1.54 vs. 27.30 ± 3.36, p &lt; 0.0001, and 30.63 ± 3.2 vs. 12.24 ± 3.26, p &lt; 0.0001, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The amount of smoking was strongly correlated with interatrial electromechanical delay (r = 0.567, p &lt; 0.0001), and a significant correlation was detected between PWD and interatrial electromechanical delay (r = 0.653, p = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: We have demonstrated the relationship between inter- and intraatrial electromechanical delay and PWD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>These parameters may be useful predictive markers for the development of AF in the asymptomatic period before <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac rhythm disturbances</z:hpo> occur </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>This finding may indicate that smokers have an increased risk of developing atrial rhythm disturbances </plain></SENT>
</text></document>