<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Ankyrin-B (AnkB) loss-of-function may cause <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001645'>sudden cardiac death</z:hpo> in humans </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Cardiac myocytes from AnkB heterozygous mice (AnkB(+/-)) show reduced expression and altered localization of Na/Ca exchanger (NCX) and Na/K-ATPase (NKA), key players in regulating <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29102">[Na]</z:chebi>(i) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="22984,29320">[Ca]</z:chebi>(i) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Here we investigate how AnkB reduction affects cardiac <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29102">[Na]</z:chebi>(i), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="22984,29320">[Ca]</z:chebi>(i) and SR Ca release </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We found reduced NCX and NKA transport function but unaltered <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29102">[Na]</z:chebi>(i) and diastolic <z:chebi fb="0" ids="22984,29320">[Ca]</z:chebi>(i) in myocytes from AnkB(+/-) vs. <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> (WT) mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Ca transients, SR Ca content and fractional SR Ca release were larger in AnkB(+/-) myocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The frequency of spontaneous, diastolic Ca sparks (CaSpF) was significantly higher in intact myocytes from AnkB(+/-) vs. WT myocytes (with and without <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6046">isoproterenol</z:chebi>), even when normalized for SR Ca load </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, total <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8925">ryanodine</z:chebi> receptor (RyR)-mediated SR Ca leak (tetracaine-sensitive) was not different between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Thus, in AnkB(+/-) mice SR Ca leak is biased towards more Ca sparks (vs. smaller release events), suggesting more coordinated openings of RyRs in a cluster </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This is due to local cytosolic RyR regulation, rather than intrinsic RyR differences, since CaSpF was similar in saponin-permeabilized myocytes from WT and AnkB(+/-) mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The more coordinated RyRs openings resulted in an increased propensity of pro-arrhythmic Ca waves in AnkB(+/-) myocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, AnkB reduction alters cardiac Na and Ca transport and enhances the coupled RyR openings, resulting in more frequent Ca sparks and waves although the total SR Ca leak is unaffected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>This could enhance the propensity for triggered <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> in AnkB(+/-) mice </plain></SENT>
</text></document>