<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Studies evaluating a possible survival advantage from sudden <z:hpo ids='HP_0001695'>cardiac arrest</z:hpo> (SCA) in women have produced mixed results possibly due to a lack of comprehensive analyses </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that race, socioeconomic status (SES), and elements of the lifetime clinical history influence gender effects and need to be incorporated within analyses of survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Cases of SCA were identified from the ongoing, prospective, multiple-source Oregon Sudden Unexpected <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>Death</z:hpo> Study (population approximately one million) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Subjects included were age ≥18 years who underwent attempted resuscitation by EMS providers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Pearson's chi-square tests and independent samples t tests or analysis of variance were used for univariate comparisons </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We evaluated gender and race differences in survival adjusted for age, circumstances of arrest, disease burden, and socioeconomic status using a logistic regression model predicting survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 1,296 cases had resuscitation attempted (2002-2007; mean age 65 years, male 67%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Women were older than men (68 vs. 63 years, p &lt; 0.0001) and were more likely to have return of spontaneous circulation (41% vs. 33%, p = 0.004) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Women were more likely to present with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0340861" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="EMD">pulseless electrical activity</z:e> (PEA) and <z:mp ids='MP_0004086'>asystole</z:mp> (p &lt; 0.0001), and overall, PEA was more common among African Americans (p = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Higher survival to hospital discharge was observed in women compared to men presenting with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001663'>ventricular fibrillation</z:hpo>/<z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> (34% vs. 24%, p = 0.02) or with PEA (10% vs. 3%, p = 0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In a multivariate model adjusting for age, race, presenting <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo>, arrest circumstances, arrest location, disease burden, and SES, women were more likely than men to survive to hospital discharge [odds ratio 1.85; 95% confidence interval (1.12-3.04)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Despite older age, higher prevalence of SCA in the home, and higher rates of PEA, women had a survival advantage from <z:hpo ids='HP_0001663'>ventricular fibrillation</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0340861" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="EMD">pulseless electrical activity</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>