<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Coexisting long QT gene mutations/polymorphisms in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001636'>Tetralogy of Fallot</z:hpo> (TOF) patients may aggravate the repolarization abnormality from cardiac repair </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We investigated the impact of these genes on the risk of life-threatening events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Genetic variants of the three common long QT genes were identified from patients with repaired TOF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Life-threatening events were defined as <z:hpo ids='HP_0001645'>sudden cardiac death</z:hpo> and hemodynamic unstable <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Biophysical characterization of the alleles of the genetic variants was performed using a whole-cell voltage clamp with expression in Xenopus oocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A total of 84 patients (56.0 % male with 1,215 patients-year follow-up) were enrolled </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Six rare variants and six non-synonymous single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) were found in 40 (47.6 %) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Life-threatening events occurred in five patients; four received implantable cardioverter defibrillator and one died of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001645'>sudden cardiac death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Life-threatening events occurred more often in those with genetic variants than those without (5/40 vs. 0/44, P = 0.021); particularly, the hERG or SCN5A gene mutations/polymorphisms (2/5 vs. 3/79, P = 0.027 and 5/27 vs. 0/57, P = 0.003, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Among the five patients with life-threatening events, three had compound variants (hERG p.M645R/SCN5A p.R1193Q, hERG p.K897T/SCN5A p.H558R, and KVLQT1 p.G645S/SCN5A p.P1090L), that also increased the risk of events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Their QTc and JTc were <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> prolonged </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Functional study of the novel variant (hERG gene p.M645R) from patients with life-threatening events revealed a dominant negative effect </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, in repaired TOF patients, coexisting long QT mutations/polymorphisms might have additive effects on the repolarization abnormality from surgery and thereby increase the risks of life-threatening events </plain></SENT>
</text></document>