<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: The aim of this study was to examine <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1145628" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">autonomic disorders</z:e> in patients with different types of vasovagal syndrome by performing both a cardiac sympathetic innervation evaluation and a head-up tilt-test with heart rate variability (HRV) analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: We enrolled 60 patients with vasovagal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> (32 women, mean age 40 ± 16 years), and 20 age-matched controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We assessed the integrity and function of the myocardial pre-synaptic nerve endings and in the sympathovagal activity, using (123)I-metaiodobenzylguanidine (MIBG) scintigraphy and time-domain indexes of HRV </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A significantly lower heart/mediastinum ratio was found in the syncopal patients compared with the control group, both at 10 min (1.9 ± 0.25 vs. 3.6 ± 1.7, P = 0.02) and at 4 h (1.79 ± 0.12 vs. 2.07 ± 0.19, P = 0.04), whereas washout rate was significantly greater in syncopal patients (5.5 ± 3.7 vs. 2 ± 0.19, P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There were no significant differences in any of the above parameters between patients with different types of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In addition, the majority of the patients showed multiple adrenergic innervation defects in the left ventricular myocardium </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>No significant difference was found in any of the HRV time-domain indexes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, a correlation was found between root-mean-square of the difference between successive RRs and washout rate in syncopal patients (r = -0.256, P = 0.48) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Patients with vasovagal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> induced by tilt testing reveal a high degree of disturbance of myocardial adrenergic innervation and multiple adrenergic innervation defects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This suggests a possible predominance of cardiac adrenergic activity in those with abnormal cardiac MIBG scintigraphy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>