<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Previous studies indicate that ventricular pacing may precipitate <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> (HF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We investigated occurrence of HF during long-term follow-up among patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011704'>sick sinus syndrome</z:hpo> (SSS) randomized to AAIR or DDDR pacing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, we investigated effects of percentage of ventricular pacing (%VP) and pacing site in the ventricle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: We analysed data from 1415 patients randomized to AAIR (n = 707) or DDDR pacing (n = 708) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Ventricular pacing leads were recorded as located in either an apical or a non-apical position </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The %VP and HF hospitalizations were recorded during follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients were classified with new HF, if in New York Heart Association (NYHA) functional class IV or if presence of ≥2 of: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>oedema</z:hpo>; dyspnoea; NYHA functional class III </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Mean follow-up was 5.4 ± 2.4 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>Heart failure</z:hpo> hospitalizations did not differ between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In the AAIR group, 170 of the 707 (26%) patients developed HF vs. 169 of the 708 (26%) patients in the DDDR group, hazard rate ratio (HR) 1.00, 95% confidence interval (CI) 0.79-1.22, P = 0.87 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In DDDR patients, 146 of the 512 patients (29%) with ventricular leads in an apical position developed HF vs. 28 of the 161 patients (17%) with the leads in a non-apical position, HR 0.67, CI 0.45-1.00, P = 0.05 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>After adjustments this difference was non-significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The incidence of HF was not associated with %VP (P = 0.57) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In patients with SSS, HF was not associated with pacing mode, %VP, or ventricular lead localization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>This suggests that DDDR pacing is safe in patients with SSS without precipitating HF </plain></SENT>
</text></document>