<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Introduction: Patients with ST elevation <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">STEMI</z:e>) comprise a <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneous</z:hpo> population with respect to the risk for adverse events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) has shown to be better, mainly in high-risk patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Objective: The purpose of this study was to determine if the Thrombolysis in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>Myocardial Infarction</z:hpo> (TIMI) risk score for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">STEMI</z:e> applied to patients undergo primary PCI identifies a group of patients at high risk for adverse events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Methods: We identified patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">STEMI</z:e> without cardiogenic shock on admission, who were treated with primary PCI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The TIMI and CADILLAC (Controlled Abciximab and Device Investigation to Lower Late Angioplasty Complications) risk scores were calculated to determine their predictive value for in hospital mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Patients were divided into two groups according to their TIMI riisk score, low risk being 0-4 points and high risk .5 points, and the frequency of adverse events was analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Results: We analyzed 572 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">STEMI</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The c-statistics predictive value of the TIMI risk score for mortality was 0.80 (p=0.0001) and the CADILLAC risk score was 0.83, (p=0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Thirty-two percent of patients classified as high risk (TIMI .5) had a higher incidence of adverse events than the low-risk group: mortality 14.8% vs. 2.1%, (p=0.0001); <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> 15.3% vs. 4.1%, (p=0.0001); development of cardiogenic shock 10.9% vs. 1.5%, (p=0.0001); <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> 14.8% vs. 5.9%, (p=0.001); and no-reflow phenomenon 22.4% vs. 13.6%, (p=0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: The TIMI risk score for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">STEMI</z:e> prior to primary PCI can predict in hospital mortality and identifies a group of high-risk patients who might develop adverse events </plain></SENT>
</text></document>