<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The objective of this study was to investigate the effect of selective fat pad ablation on the spatial and temporal stability of the complex fractionated atrial electrogram (CFAE) in <z:chebi fb="9" ids="15355">acetylcholine</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi>)-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> was applied to fat pads in 10 dogs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Effective refractory periods (ERPs) at 5 different sites, AF inducibility and AF duration were obtained before and after fat pad ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>During the first two induced AFs, the number of sites with continuous CFAEs and the duration of continuous CFAEs at every site were measured before and after fat pad ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The average ERP was shortened by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> application (138 14 vs 100 15 ms, P &lt; 0.001) and increased after fat pad ablation (100 +/- 15 vs. 115 +/- 14 ms, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>AF inducibility (76 +/- 9% vs. 4 +/- 6%, P &lt; 0.001) and AF duration (56 +/- 11 vs. 187 +/- 56 s, P = 0.01) increased after <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> application compared to baseline; while fat pad ablation reduced AF inducibility (76% +/- 9% vs. 54% +/- 6%, P &lt; 0.001) and AF duration (187 +/- 56 vs. 144% +/- 35 s, P = 0.015) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The percentage of sites with continuous CFAE decreased after fat pad ablation compared with that before fat pad ablation (24% vs. 82%, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>On average, fat pad ablation reduced the duration of continuous CFAEs (188 +/- 63 vs. 139 +/- 31 s, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Selective fat pad ablation can affect the spatial and temporal stability of CFAEs in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi>-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> in dogs </plain></SENT>
</text></document>