<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) can result in profound reverse remodelling </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The goal of this study was to identify factors predictive of such beneficial response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Super-response to CRT was defined as normalization or near normalization of left ventricular systolic function without recognized reversible causes of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In a retrospective study, we compared baseline demographic, electrocardiogram, and echocardiographic characteristics of super-responders (n = 21) with a population of unselected consecutive cardiac CRT patients (Control 1, n = 330) and another sex-, age-, and aetiology-matched control group (Control 2, n = 43) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Compared with Control 1, super-responders had significantly smaller left ventricular end-diastolic diameter (65.4 ± 6.4 vs. 73.4 ± 9.3 mm, P = 0.0001), higher ejection fraction (0.25 ± 0.05 vs. 0.22 ± 0.04, P = 0.004), smaller degree of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001653'>mitral regurgitation</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e>; mean value 1.9 ± 0.9 vs. 2.6 ± 0.8, P = &lt;0.0001), and smaller left atrium (LA; 42.8 ± 4.6 vs. 50.0 ± 6.5 mm, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Septal flash and inter-ventricular mechanical dyssynchrony were both more frequent among super-responders than in Control 2 subjects (93.8 vs. 69.8%; P = 0.01, and 93.8 vs. 62.8%; P = 0.01, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In a multivariate analysis, smaller LA diameter and milder <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e> remained independent predictors of super-response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Super-response to cardiac CRT was associated with less advanced left-sided structural involvement as described by echocardiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In particular, smaller LA and milder <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e> were independent predictors of pronounced reverse remodelling </plain></SENT>
</text></document>