<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Infections</z:e> of cardiac implantable electronic devices (CIED) can cause significant morbidity, mortality, and financial burden </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Although staphylococcal organisms account for most <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> of these cardiac devices, approximately 20% of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> CIED-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> are caused by non-Staphylococcus species </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Herein we describe and compare the demographics, clinical presentation, and outcomes of Staphylococcus aureus and non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0038160" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">staphylococcal infections</z:e> of CIED.We performed a retrospective, multicenter, observational study of patients from 4 academic hospitals in Houston between 2002 and 2009 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> 80 identified non-staphylococcal CIED-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> were matched, at a 1:1 ratio, to S. aureus <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e>.Although the demographics and general comorbidities in the 2 study groups were relatively similar, the S. aureus group had a higher proportion of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001677'>coronary artery disease</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003774'>end-stage renal disease</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Additionally, 81% of S. aureus compared with only 48.5% of the non-staphylococcal CIED-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> were health care-associated (p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, when compared to non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0038160" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">staphylococcal infections</z:e>, the S. aureus group had more indwelling intravascular foreign material (p &lt; 0.001), more rapid clinical progression (p &lt; 0.001), and overall worse clinical presentation (p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, after stratifying by clinical presentation, the mortality rates in the 2 groups were similar (p = 0.45).Since approximately one-fifth of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> CIED-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> are caused by non-staphylococcal organisms, and untimely antibiotic treatment can result in serious complications, it may be prudent to broaden empiric antimicrobial therapy to cover both <z:mp ids='MP_0001796'>Gram-positive</z:mp> and -negative bacteria, until the causative organism is identified </plain></SENT>
</text></document>