<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Data about the long-term outcome after cryoablation for atrioventricular nodal reentrant <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> (AVNRT) in the paediatric population indicate that recurrence rates are higher with cryo than with radiofrequency energy (RF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to review our institutional long-term outcome after cryoablation for AVNRT and to seek for predictors of recurrence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Forty-nine patients (28 female, age 14 ± 2.7 years) undergoing slow-pathway modulation or ablation for AVNRT at our institution from 2004 to 2008 were included in the study.  <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> success was obtained in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients (100%) with a mean procedure time of 164 ± 50 min and a mean fluoroscopy time of 13 ± 8 min </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>During a follow-up time of 30 ± 1.9 months, AVNRT recurrence occurred in 11/49 patients (22.4%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Age, sex, number of cryomappings or ablations, catheter tip (4 mm vs. 6 mm), or ablation endpoint (slow-pathway ablation vs. modulation) were not predictive for recurrence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In eight patients, reablation using cryo was performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> these patients remained free of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> symptoms during a follow-up of 30 ± 8 months following the second procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Although cryoablation for the treatment for AVNRT in paediatric and adolescent patients is safe and associated with a high <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> success rate, AVNRT recurrence occurs in 22% of patients during long-term follow-up without identifiable predictors for recurrence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A second cryoablation procedure leads to a success rate of 100% during long-term follow-up </plain></SENT>
</text></document>