<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Infection</z:e> with Trypanosoma cruzi is a major risk in Latin America, and dogs are believed to be good models for evaluating <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Here, we evaluated the clinical and immunopathological alterations developed by mongrel dogs experimentally infected with different infective doses (2,000, 20,000, and 200,000 metacyclic trypomastigotes of Sylvio X10/4 strain kg(-1) via intraperitoneal) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Clinical and electrocardiographic parameters, as well as antibody production and pathologic lesions were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> three doses of this strain of T. cruzi induced a similar pattern of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> characterized by <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmias</z:hpo> and severe and diffuse <z:mp ids='MP_0001856'>myocarditis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Specific anti-T. cruzi IgG indicated seroconversion by day 14 after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>, and IgG levels increased during the period of evaluation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mortality was observed only in dogs infected with the medium or high parasite doses, but not in the group infected with a low dose of 2,000 parasites kg(-1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Infection</z:e> with a low dose of parasites provides an excellent nonlethal model to evaluate the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_188'>immunopathology</z:mpath> of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> disease in dogs infected with the Sylvio X10/4 strain of T. cruzi </plain></SENT>
</text></document>