<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: To compare the safety and efficacy of a new dilator method vs the traditional needle method for transseptal puncture (TSP) in a large cohort study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: From February 1995 to December 2010, 4443 consecutive patients undergoing TSP done either by a needle method or by a new dilator method were reviewed retrospectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Data as procedure-related time and complications were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>For the standard needle method, TSP was performed by extending out the needle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In comparison, for the new dilator technique, TSP was performed without an outer sheath and with the needle kept within the dilator; the blunt tip of the dilator was used to help locating the position of the fossa ovalis on purpose </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Transseptal puncture was performed by the new dilator method in 2151 patients (48.4%) and by the traditional needle method in 2292 patients (51.6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The average TSP time needed by the dilator method was longer than that needed by the needle method (5.6 ± 3.9 vs. 3.8 ± 2.9 min, P&lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Additional left atrial angiography was required in seven (0.33%) patients for the dilator and in 39 patients (1.70%) for the needle method (P&lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The total rate of severe complications and obvious TSP-related complications was significantly lower in patients who underwent the dilator method than in those who underwent the needle method (0.33 vs. 1.18%, and 0.20 vs. 1.00%, respectively, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our data suggest that the new dilator technique is much safer than that of the standard needle method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>It needs relatively longer procedure time but results in significantly fewer episodes of severe complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Particularly, the blunt tip of the dilator can be used to help locate the fossa ovalis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Therefore, the new dilator technique might be a better choice for relatively less-experienced operators </plain></SENT>
</text></document>