<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: The aim of this study was to determine the incidence and clinical characteristics of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001645'>sudden cardiac death</z:hpo> (SCD) in patients with human <z:hpo ids='HP_0002721'>immunodeficiency</z:hpo> virus (HIV) <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: As the HIV-infected population ages, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> prevalence and mortality are increasing, but the incidence and features of SCD have not yet been described </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The records of 2,860 consecutive patients in a public HIV clinic in San Francisco between April 2000 and August 2009 were examined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Identification of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo>, causes of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, and clinical characteristics were obtained by search of the National <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>Death</z:hpo> Index and/or clinic records </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>SCDs were determined using published retrospective criteria: 1) the International Classification of Diseases-10th Revision, code for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cardiac causes of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>; and (2) circumstances of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> meeting World Health Organization criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of 230 <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> over a median of 3.7 years of follow-up, 30 (13%) met SCD criteria, 131 (57%) were due to acquired <z:hpo ids='HP_0002721'>immune deficiency</z:hpo> syndrome (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AIDS</z:e>), 25 (11%) were due to other (natural) diseases, and 44 (19%) were due to overdoses, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0812393,C0038661" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction;Injury or Poisoning" abbrv="">suicides</z:e>, or unknown causes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>SCDs accounted for 86% of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> (30 of 35) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The mean SCD rate was 2.6 per 1,000 person-years (95% confidence interval: 1.8 to 3.8), 4.5-fold higher than expected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>SCDs occurred in older patients than did <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AIDS</z:e> <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> (mean 49.0 vs. 44.9 years, p = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Compared with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AIDS</z:e> and natural <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> combined, SCDs had a higher prevalence of prior <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (17% vs. 1%, p &lt; 0.0005), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (23% vs. 3%, p &lt; 0.0005), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> (30% vs. 9%, p = 0.004), and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> (20% vs. 3%, p = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: SCDs account for most cardiac and many non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AIDS</z:e> natural <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> in HIV-infected patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Further investigation is needed to ascertain underlying mechanisms, which may include <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, antiretroviral therapy interruption, and concomitant medications </plain></SENT>
</text></document>