<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> exacerbations of <z:hpo ids='HP_0006510'>chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</z:hpo> (COPD) sometimes appear to occur without a precipitating cause </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>Heterogeneous</z:hpo> repolarization and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> occur in COPD patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Given the close inter-relation between heart and lung, we hypothesized that unrecognized <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> might be precipitants of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> exacerbations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Electrocardiograms (ECG) of thirty patients during <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> exacerbations were compared with ECG during stable phase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>P wave dispersion was used to assess atrial depolarization <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo>, and dispersion of QT interval to assess ventricular repolarization. p &lt; 0.05 was considered significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Frequent exacerbations were defined as two or more exacerbations in a year </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Mean age of patients was 70.3 ± 11.8 SD years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>P wave dispersion was greater during <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> exacerbation than during stable phase (56.7 ± 19.2 vs 47.7 ± 15.9 ms, p = 0.009) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was a trend toward greater QTc dispersion (108.3 ± 61.7 vs 90.3 ± 47.0 ms, p = 0.13) in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> exacerbation compared to stable phase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Sixteen (53%) had frequent exacerbations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>There was a significant difference in PR interval during stable phase between those with frequent exacerbations and those without (163.9 + 17.4 vs. 145.1 + 22.8; p = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The P wave dispersion during stable phase was greater in those with frequent exacerbations, but did not reach statistical significance (52.6 + 18.8 vs. 42.2 + 9.8 ms; p = 0.06) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: P wave dispersion is more in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> phase than in stable phase, and is greater in patients with more frequent exacerbations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>This does not prove, but suggests an intriguing possibility that P wave dispersion predates <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> exacerbations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>This might be a new target for prediction, prevention and therapy of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> exacerbations of COPD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>