<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Although cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) reduces morbidity and mortality in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>, a significant minority of patients do not respond adequately to this therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to examine the impact of a 'multidisciplinary care' (MC) approach on the clinical outcome in CRT patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: The clinical outcome in patients prospectively receiving MC (n = 254) was compared with a control group of patients who received conventional care (CC, n = 173) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The MC group was followed prospectively in an integrated clinic setting by a team of subspecialists from the <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>, electrophysiology, and echocardiography service at 1-, 3-, and 6-months post-implant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients had echocardiographic-guided optimization at their 1-month visit </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The proportional hazards model (adjusting for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> covariates) and Kaplan-Meier time to first event curves were compared between the two groups, over a 2-year follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The long-term outcome was measured as a combined endpoint of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> hospitalization, cardiac transplantation, or <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The clinical characteristics between the MC and CC groups at baseline were comparable (age, 68 ± 13 vs. 69 ± 12; NYHA III, 90 vs. 82%; ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001638'>cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> 55 vs. 64%, P = NS, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The event-free survival was significantly higher in the multidisciplinary vs. the CC group (P = 0.0015) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A significant reduction in clinical events was noted in the MC group vs. the CC group (hazard ratio: 0.62, 95% CI: 0.46-0.83, P = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Integrated MC may improve 2-year event-free survival in patients receiving cardiac resynchronization therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Prospective randomized studies are needed to validate our findings </plain></SENT>
</text></document>