<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: The objective is to assess electrocardiographic characteristics predicting the precise location of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> (VA) origin within the right ventricle (RV) close to the His bundle (HB) region </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Twenty-five patients (14 men, age 65 ± 14 years) underwent successful catheter ablation of para-Hisian VA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>Ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> were considered to arise in the vicinity of the HB region based on the criteria that mapping exhibited the earliest RV activation before QRS <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> in the HB region </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Surface 12-lead electrocardiogram during the para-Hisian VAs was analysed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Of the 25 patients, 8 originated from the RV antero-septum just above the HB region, and 17 arose from the RV mid-septum just below the HB region </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference in precedence of the local ventricular electrogram of the HB region from the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of surface QRS during VAs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Surface electrocardiographic findings were characterized according to R-wave amplitude in lead I (0.43 ± 0.18 vs. 0.67 ± 0.19 mV, P = 0.005), mean R-wave amplitude in inferior leads (1.12 ± 0.32 vs. 0.71 ± 0.24 mV, P = 0.002), R-wave amplitude ratio of leads III/II (0.77 ± 0.10 vs. 0.50 ± 0.23, P = 0.005), incidence of S-wave in lead III [1/8 (13%) vs. 16/17 (94%), P &lt; 0.001], and QS <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> in lead V1 [3/8 (38%) vs. 17/17 (100%), P = 0.001] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Despite their adjacent locations, para-Hisian VAs could be classified into two subgroups with distinctive electrocardiographic characteristics according to origin either above or below the HB region </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The present findings can be helpful for planning catheter ablation of para-Hisian VAs, and can reduce the risk of inadvertent <z:hpo ids='HP_0001678'>atrioventricular block</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>