<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To investigate the feasibility of using a prospective ECG-gated wide-volume protocol in CT angiography (CTA) of the whole aorta and coronary arteries (CA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 61 consecutive patients with suspected <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0003493" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">aortic diseases</z:e> underwent CTA of the whole aorta using a prospective ECG-gated wide-volume CT protocol without heart rate (HR) control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The exposure window was set at 40-50 % of R-R interval (HR ≥70 bpm) or 70-80 % of R-R interval (HR &lt;70 bpm) in a single heartbeat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The image quality of the ascending aorta, aortic valve and CA was evaluated for motion artefacts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The mean attenuation was measured at different levels of the aorta </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The radiation dose and contrast medium volume were recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> of the examinations were performed successfully </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The image quality was acceptable in the ascending aorta, aortic valve (100 %) and CA (94.4 %) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The mean radiation dose was 18.42 ± 5.02 mSv </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Of 61 patients, 14 were diagnosed with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004942'>aortic aneurysm</z:hpo> and 35 were diagnosed with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002647'>aortic dissection</z:hpo> or intramural haematoma </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0005145'>Coronary artery stenosis</z:hpo> was detected in 12 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: For patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0003493" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">aortic diseases</z:e>, CTA of the whole aorta using a prospective ECG-gated wide-volume protocol has the potential to provide additional information about the CA and aortic valve with lower radiation exposure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>KEY POINTS : • Computed tomography is increasingly used to assess the coronary arteries and the aorta. • This novel study investigates prospective ECG-gated wide-volume 320-row CT angiography. • Heart rate variation did not influence the image quality of coronary arteries. • Abnormalities in the coronary arteries and aorta can be simultaneously assessed noninvasively </plain></SENT>
</text></document>