<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The use of n-3 fatty acids may prevent cardiovascular events in patients with recent <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Their effects in patients with (or at risk for) type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> are unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In this double-blind study with a 2-by-2 factorial design, we randomly assigned 12,536 patients who were at high risk for cardiovascular events and had impaired fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo>, or <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> to receive a 1-g capsule containing at least 900 mg (90% or more) of ethyl <z:chebi fb="21" ids="35701">esters</z:chebi> of n-3 fatty acids or placebo daily and to receive either insulin glargine or standard care </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The primary outcome was <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> from cardiovascular causes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The results of the comparison between n-3 fatty acids and placebo are reported here </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: During a median follow up of 6.2 years, the incidence of the primary outcome was not significantly decreased among patients receiving n-3 fatty acids, as compared with those receiving placebo (574 patients [9.1%] vs. 581 patients [9.3%]; hazard ratio, 0.98; 95% confidence interval [CI], 0.87 to 1.10; P=0.72) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The use of n-3 fatty acids also had no significant effect on the rates of major vascular events (1034 patients [16.5%] vs. 1017 patients [16.3%]; hazard ratio, 1.01; 95% CI, 0.93 to 1.10; P=0.81), <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> from any cause (951 [15.1%] vs. 964 [15.4%]; hazard ratio, 0.98; 95% CI, 0.89 to 1.07; P=0.63), or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> from <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> (288 [4.6%] vs. 259 [4.1%]; hazard ratio, 1.10; 95% CI, 0.93 to 1.30; P=0.26) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">Triglyceride</z:chebi> levels were reduced by 14.5 mg per deciliter (0.16 mmol per liter) more among patients receiving n-3 fatty acids than among those receiving placebo (P&lt;0.001), without a significant effect on other <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Adverse effects were similar in the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Daily supplementation with 1 g of n-3 fatty acids did not reduce the rate of cardiovascular events in patients at high risk for cardiovascular events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>(Funded by Sanofi; ORIGIN ClinicalTrials.gov number, NCT00069784.) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>