<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Knowledge about potential differences in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> tissue characteristics between patients with prior life-threatening <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> versus patients receiving prophylactic implantable cardioverter-defibrillator (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>) might help to improve the current risk stratification in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (MI) patients who are considered for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> implantation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In a consecutive series of (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>) recipients for primary and secondary prevention following MI, we used contrast-enhanced (CE) cardiovascular magnetic resonance (CMR) imaging to evaluate differences in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> tissue characteristics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Cine-CMR measurements included left ventricular end-diastolic and end-systolic volumes (EDV, ESV), left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF), wall motion score index (WMSI), and mass </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>CE-CMR images were analyzed for core, peri, and total <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> localization (according to coronary artery territory), and transmural extent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In this study, 95 ICD recipients were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In the primary prevention group (n = 66), LVEF was lower (23 ± 9% vs. 31 ± 14%; P &lt; 0.01), ESV and WMSI were higher (223 ± 75 ml vs. 184 ± 97 ml, P = 0.04, and 1.89 ± 0.52 vs. 1.47 ± 0.68; P &lt; 0.01), and anterior <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> localization was more frequent (P = 0.02) than in the secondary prevention group (n = 29) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were no differences in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> tissue characteristics between patients treated for primary versus secondary prevention (P &gt; 0.6 for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>During 21 ± 9 months of follow-up, 3 (5%) patients in the primary prevention group and 9 (31%) in the secondary prevention group experienced appropriate <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> therapy for treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> (P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was no difference in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> tissue characteristics between recipients of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> for primary versus secondary prevention, while the secondary prevention group showed a higher frequency of applied <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> therapy for <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>