<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Research on <z:hpo ids='HP_0004757'>paroxysmal atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) assumes that <z:mp ids='MP_0006109'>fibrillation</z:mp> induced by rapid pacing adequately reproduces spontaneously occurring paroxysmal AF in humans </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We aimed to compare the spectral properties of spontaneous vs. induced AF episodes in paroxysmal AF patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Eighty-five paroxysmal AF patients arriving in sinus rhythm to the electrophysiology laboratory were evaluated prior to ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>Atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> was induced by rapid pacing from the pulmonary vein-left atrial junctions (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PV</z:e>-LAJ), the coronary sinus (CS), or the high right atrium (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">HRA</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Simultaneous recordings were obtained using multipolar catheters </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Off-line power spectral analysis of 5 s bipolar electrograms was used to determine dominant frequency (DF) at recording sites with regularity index &gt;0.2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Sixty-eight episodes were analysed for DF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Comparisons were made between spontaneous (n = 23) and induced (n = 45) AF episodes at each recording site </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>No significant differences were observed between spontaneous and induced AF episodes in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">HRA</z:e> (5.18 ± 0.69 vs. 5.06 ± 0.91 Hz; P = 0.64), CS (5.27 ± 0.69 vs. 5.36 ± 0.76 Hz; P = 0.69), or LA (5.72 ± 0.88 vs. 5.64 ± 0.75 Hz; P = 0.7) regardless of pacing site </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Consistent with these results, paired analysis in seven patients with both spontaneous and induced AF episodes, showed no regional DFs differences </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Moreover, a left-to-right DF gradient was also present in both spontaneous (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PV</z:e>-LAJ 5.71 ± 0.81 vs. <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">HRA</z:e> 5.18 ± 0.69 Hz; P = 0.005) and induced (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PV</z:e>-LAJ 5.62 ± 0.72 vs. <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">HRA</z:e> 5.07 ± 0.91 Hz; P = 0.002) AF episodes, with no differences between them (P = not specific) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In patients with paroxysmal AF, high-rate pacing-induced AF adequately mimics spontaneously initiated AF, regardless of induction site </plain></SENT>
</text></document>