<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate whether grid-tag myocardial strain evaluation can characterise 'border-zone' peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> region and identify patients at risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> as the peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> myocardial zone may represent an important contributor to <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> following ST-segment elevation <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">STEMI</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Forty-five patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">STEMI</z:e> underwent cardiac magnetic resonance (CMR) imaging on days 3 and 90 following primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Circumferential peak circumferential systolic strain (CS) and strain rate (CSR) were calculated from grid-tagged images </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Myocardial segments were classified into '<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath>', 'border-zone', 'adjacent' and 'remote' regions by late-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="33375">gadolinium</z:chebi> enhancement distribution </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The relationship between CS and CSR and these distinct myocardial regions was assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Ambulatory Holter monitoring was performed 14 days post <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (MI) to estimate <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> risk via evaluation of heart-rate variability (HRV) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: We analysed 1,222 myocardial segments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Remote and adjacent regions had near-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> parameters of CS and CSR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Border-zone regions had intermediate CS (-9.0 ± 4.6 vs -5.9 ± 7.4, P &lt; 0.001) and CSR (-86.4 ± 33.3 vs -73.5 ± 51.4, P &lt; 0.001) severity compared with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> regions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Patients with 'border-zone' peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> regions had reduced very-low-frequency power on HRV analysis, which is a surrogate for <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> risk (P = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Grid-tagged CMR-derived myocardial strain accurately characterises the mechanical characteristics of 'border-zone' peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> region </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Presence of 'border-zone' peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> region correlated with a surrogate marker of heightened <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> risk following <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">STEMI</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>KEY POINTS: • Grid-tagged cardiac magnetic resonance (CMR) offers new insights into myocardial mechanical function. • Grid-tagged CMR identified different characteristics in 'border-zone' and 'adjacent' peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> myocardial regions. • Reduced very-low-frequency (VLF) power is associated with arrhythmic and mortality risk. • The presence of 'border-zone' peri-<z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> region correlated with reduced VLF power </plain></SENT>
</text></document>