<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: The results of an investigation of serum <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> concentrations (SMCs) after i.v. versus oral delivery of <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> in cardiovascular critical care are presented </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A retrospective case review was conducted to compare the net gain of <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> after i.v </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>(n = 188) or oral (n = 164) <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> therapy for the prevention of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001663'>ventricular fibrillation</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> in patients hospitalized for serious <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disorders</z:e>, as determined by assessing SMCs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The primary study outcome was the change from baseline SMC values 6-24 hours after the completion of <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> courses; secondary outcomes included the impact of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0341697" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">renal impairment</z:e>, concomitant medication use, and other clinical variables on SMC changes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Although consistent elevations in SMC were produced by oral <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> delivery, i.v. administration resulted in greater and more rapid elevations relative to baseline SMC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The degree of change in SMC was significantly influenced by the timing of SMC measurement after a <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> course, by renal function, and by concomitant use of i.v. loop <z:chebi fb="40" ids="35498">diuretics</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: A comparison of 24-hour courses of <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi> replacement therapy showed that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="32599">magnesium sulfate</z:chebi> 2 g i.v. was associated with larger changes in SMC than <z:chebi fb="4" ids="31794">magnesium oxide</z:chebi> 800, 1200, or 1600 mg orally when the baseline SMC was 1.4-1.8 mg/dL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At baseline SMCs of 1.4-1.8 mg/dL, oral <z:chebi fb="4" ids="31794">magnesium oxide</z:chebi> provided a consistent median increase in SMC of 0.1 mg/dL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The change in the number of bowel movements did not differ significantly between courses of i.v. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="32599">magnesium sulfate</z:chebi> and oral <z:chebi fb="4" ids="31794">magnesium oxide</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>