<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011703'>Inappropriate sinus tachycardia</z:hpo> (IST) is a clinical syndrome characterized by excessive resting heart rate (HR) or disproportional increasing HR during exercise </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The treatment of IST symptoms using beta-blockers or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38215">calcium channel-blockers</z:chebi> is often non-effective or not well tolerated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Ivabradine is a new agent inhibiting sinus node I(f) current, resulting in a decrease of HR without haemodynamic compromise </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: We enrolled 20 patients (36 ± 10 years; 14 women) affected by IST and resistant to previous administered therapy by using beta-blockers or <z:chebi fb="1" ids="9948">verapamil</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After 4 weeks of treatment with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6904">metoprolol</z:chebi> succinate (up to 190 mg once a day) the therapy was switched to ivabradine up to 7.5 mg twice daily </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Holter monitoring and treadmill stress test were performed after 1 and 2 months following start of the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We observed a significant reduction of resting HR both for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6904">metoprolol</z:chebi> and for ivabradine compared with baseline (92.8 vs. 90.2 vs. 114.3 b.p.m.; P&lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>During daily activity there was an even larger decrease of HR on ivabradine (mean daytime HR 94.6 vs. 87.1 vs. 107.3 b.p.m.; P&lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Ivabradine was very well tolerated whereas in 10 patients on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6904">metoprolol</z:chebi> we observed <z:hpo ids='HP_0002615'>hypotension</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0001662'>bradycardia</z:hpo> requiring dose reduction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Significantly lower incidence of IST-related symptoms were registered on ivabradine therapy than on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6904">metoprolol</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Fourteen patients (70%) treated with I(f) blocker were free of IST-related complaints </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6904">Metoprolol</z:chebi> and ivabradine exert a similar effect on resting HR in patients with IST </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Ivabradine seems to be more effective to relieve symptoms during exercise or daily activity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>