<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: It remains unclear as to whether regional atrial substrates of certain areas of the atrium in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) can be related to sinoatrial node dysfunction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We investigated the relationship between the biatrial substrate characteristics and sinus node function in these patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: The study enrolled 34 patients (aged 57 ± 11 years old; 20 males) who underwent catheter ablation for symptomatic paroxysmal AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Sinus node dysfunction was defined as having corrected sinus node recovery time longer than 550 ms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Atrial substrate analyses of both atria and atrial conductive properties were investigated in patients with (Group 1) and without sinus node dysfunction (Group 2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The mean global bipolar voltage of both atria and the atrial refractory period were similar between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Regional analysis showed that the mean bipolar voltage for patients in Group 1 was lower than in Group 2 (1.0 ± 0.3 vs. 2.1 ± 0.7 mV, P &lt; 0.001) only in the sinus node region, while the electrophysiological properties were similar for both groups in other anatomic regions of both atria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The right atrial total activation time was significantly longer (97 ± 9 vs. 89 ± 10 ms, P = 0.023) and the conduction velocity along the crista terminalis was significantly slower (1.0 ± 0.2 vs. 1.2 ± 0.3 m/s, P = 0.019) in Group 1 patients than in Group 2 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In patients with AF, regional atrial remodelling near the sinus node area was associated with sinus node dysfunction </plain></SENT>
</text></document>