<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the alterations of cardiac electrophysiological properties and substantial mechanism and find the stable <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> mouse model in Kunming (KM) and C57BL6/J (C57) mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Electrocardiogram recordings were used to analyze the QT interval in vivo, and mono- phasic action potential of right and left ventricular epicardium was recorded to elicit changes of action potential duration (APD) in conventional and programmed electrical stimulation (PES) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Transient outward <z:chebi fb="120" ids="26216">potassium</z:chebi> current (Ito) was recorded via whole-cell patch-clamp technique in single right and left epicardial myocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: QT interval was prolonged in KM mice relative to C57 mice (62.51±4.47 ms vs. 52.59±4.85 ms, P&lt;0.05) The APD at 50% repolarization of the left ventricular epicardium (18.60±0.91 ms vs. 12.90±0.35 ms), and APDs at 50% (17.31±6.05 ms vs. 12.00±3.24 ms) and 70% repolarization (36.13±5.32 ms vs. 21.95±8.06 ms) of the right ventricular epicardium in KM mice were more sensitive to PES-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> (25%, 3 of 12 hearts), and especially to Burst-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> (50%, 6 of 12 hearts)compared with C57 mice, which were 20% (2 of 10 hearts) and 30% (3 of 10 hearts) respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Ito densities both in the left and right ventricular epicardial myocytes from KM mice were significantly decreased compared with C57 mice, respectively (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our data showed that KM mice with the <z:mp ids='MP_0003233'>prolonged QT interval</z:mp> and APD are vulnerabilities to <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo>, which are attributed to lower Ito densities in ventricular myocytes obtained from KM mice than that from C57 mice </plain></SENT>
</text></document>