<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Cleistanthus collinus, a toxic shrub, is used for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085271" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">deliberate self-harm</z:e> in rural South India </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MEDLINE (PUBMED) and Google were searched for published papers using the search/ MeSH terms "Cleistanthus collinus," "Euphorbiaceae," "Diphyllin," "Cleistanthin A," Cleistanthin B" and "Oduvanthalai." Non-indexed journals and abstracts were searched by tracing citations in published papers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The toxic principles in the leaf include arylnaphthalene <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25036">lignan</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25000">lactones</z:chebi> - Diphyllin and its <z:chebi fb="0" ids="24400">glycoside</z:chebi> derivatives Cleistanthin A and B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Toxin effect in animal models demonstrate <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0700323,C0234119" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuromuscular blockade</z:e> with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002460'>muscle weakness, distal</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001947'>renal tubular acidosis</z:hpo> (dRTA) and type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0002093'>respiratory failure</z:hpo> with conflicting evidence of cardiac involvement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Studies suggest a likely inhibition of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29256">thiol</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="29256">thiol</z:chebi> enzymes by the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25036">lignan</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="25000">lactones</z:chebi>, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_63'>depletion</z:mpath> of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> and ATPases in tissues </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>V-type H+ ATPase inhibition in the renal tubule has been demonstrated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Mortality occurs in up to 40% of C. collinus poisonings </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Human toxicity results in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000124'>renal tubular dysfunction</z:hpo>, commonly dRTA, with resultant <z:hpo ids='HP_0002900'>hypokalemia</z:hpo> and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="5" ids="22563">anion</z:chebi> gap <z:hpo ids='HP_0001942'>metabolic acidosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Aggressive management of these metabolic derangements is crucial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002098'>respiratory distress</z:hpo> syndrome (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ARDS</z:e>) is seen in severe cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Cardiac rhythm abnormalities have been demonstrated in a number of clinical studies, though the role of temporary cardiac pacemakers in reducing mortality is uncertain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Consumption of decoctions of C. collinus leaves, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002900'>hypokalemia</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000083'>renal failure</z:hpo>, severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001942'>metabolic acidosis</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ARDS</z:e> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmias</z:hpo> occur in severe poisonings and predict mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Further study is essential to delineate mechanisms of organ injury and interventions, including <z:chebi fb="183" ids="50247">antidotes</z:chebi>, which will reduce mortality </plain></SENT>
</text></document>