<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: RF ablation for cavotricuspid isthmus (CTI) dependent flutter is an established therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Right atrial <z:mpath ids='MPATH_159'>hypertrophy</z:mpath> and enlargement are associated with the occurrence of cavotricuspid isthmus dependent flutter </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Therefore, patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002092'>pulmonary hypertension</z:hpo> (<z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi>) are prone to atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> like cavotricuspid isthmus dependent flutter </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>However, the influence of <z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi> on typical <z:hpo ids='HP_0004749'>atrial flutter</z:hpo> ablation procedure has not been systematically examined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In a retrospective single-centre analysis data of patients undergoing an ablation procedure for cavotricuspid isthmus dependent flutter between January 2007 and October 2009 at Hannover Medical School, Germany were analysed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Only procedures performed by experienced electrophysiologists with an 8mm RF-ablation catheter were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Data for 196 patients were analysed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Thirty-eight patients were identified with <z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi> and were compared to 158 patients without <z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi> for procedural ablation parameters, procedure time, ablation time, ablation points and fluoroscopy time </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A bidirectional block of the CTI was achieved in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Patients with severe <z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi> had a significantly longer procedure time (78±40 min vs. 62±29 min; p=0.033), total ablation time (20±11 min vs. 15±9 min; p=0.02) and more ablation lesions (26±16 vs. 19±12; p=0.018) as compared to patients without <z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Cavotricuspid isthmus dependent flutter ablation in patients with <z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi> is associated with longer procedure duration and a greater amount of cumulative tissue ablation needed to achieve bidirectional block of the CTI compared to patients without <z:hpo ids='HP_0002092'>pulmonary hypertension</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>