<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: The EVOCAV(DS) trial aimed to quantify the paradoxal atrioventricular (AV) conduction time lengthening in sinus node (SD) patients (pts) paced in AAIR-based pacing mode </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: SD pts, implanted with dual-chamber pacemaker programmed in AAIR-based pacing mode, were randomized in two arms for a 1-month period: the low atrial pacing (LAP; basic rate at 60 bpm, dual sensor with minimal slope) and the high atrial pacing (HAP; basic rate at 70 bpm, dual sensor with optimized slope, overdrive pacing) arm </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>At 1 month, crossover was performed for an additional 1-month period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>AV conduction time, <z:mp ids='MP_0010519'>AV block</z:mp> occurrence and AV conduction time adaptation during exercise were ascertained from device memories at each follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Seventy-nine pts participated to the analysis (75 ± 8 years; 32 male; PR = 184 ± 38 ms; <z:hpo ids='HP_0011710'>bundle branch block</z:hpo> n = 12; AF history n = 36; antiarrhythmic treatment n = 53; beta-blockers n = 27; class III/Ic n = 18; both n = 8) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The mean AV conduction time was significantly greater during the HAP (275 ± 51 ms) vs. LAP (263 ± 49 ms) period (p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Class III/Ic drugs were the only predictors of this <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0852552,C0233514" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">abnormal behaviour</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Degree II/III <z:mp ids='MP_0010519'>AV blocks</z:mp> occurred in 49 % of pts in the HAP vs. 19 % in the LAP period (p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Fifty-two patients (66 %) presented a lengthening of AV conduction time during exercise </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: AAIR-based pacing in SD pts may induce a significant lengthening of pts' AV conduction time, including frequent abnormal adaptation of AV conduction time during exercise </plain></SENT>
</text></document>