<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: We investigated the efficacy and safety of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> for preventing venous spasm during contrast-guided axillary vein puncture for pacemaker or defibrillator leads implantation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: A total of 40 consecutive patients referred for contrast-guided axillary vein puncture for pacemaker or defibrillator implantations were included in the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients were randomly assigned to control group and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> group were given 200 µg (2 mL) <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> via ipsilateral peripheral vein about 3 min before puncture </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The degree of venous spasm was evaluated by the reduction in lumen calibre of the axillary vein after puncture </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mild venous spasm and severe venous spasm were defined as a reduction in lumen calibre of 50-90% and ≥90%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean degree of venous spasm of axillary vein was lower in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> group than in the control group (23.0 ± 22.3 vs. 45.5 ± 33.6%, P = 0.018) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The incidence of mild or severe venous spasm was lower in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> group than in the control group (3/20 vs. 11/20, P = 0.019) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> group, the systolic blood pressure had a significant decrease after puncture (129.5 ± 23.7 vs. 143.0 ± 24.1 mmHg, P = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There was no <z:hpo ids='HP_0002615'>hypotension</z:hpo> and other adverse reaction of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Intravenous <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> is effective and safe for preventing venous spasm during contrast-guided axillary vein puncture for pacemaker or defibrillator leads implantation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>