<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Sport activity is an important issue in many patients with a pacemaker either because they performed sport activities before pacemaker implantation to reduce the cardiovascular risk or to improve the course of an underlying <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> (e.g. <z:hpo ids='HP_0001677'>coronary artery disease</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>) by sports </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Compared to patients with an implantable cardioverter defibrillator (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>) the risks from underlying <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> (e.g. <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>), <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo>, lead dysfunction or inappropriate therapy are less important or absent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Sport is contraindicated in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002094'>dyspnea</z:hpo> at rest, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>, new complex <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:mp ids='MP_0001856'>myocarditis</z:mp> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo>, valvular disease with indications for intervention and surgery and comorbidities which prevent physical activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients with underlying <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> (including <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>) should preferably perform types and levels of physical activity that are aerobic (with dynamic exercise) such as running, swimming, cycling instead of sport with high anaerobic demands and high muscular workload </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>, studies demonstrated advantages of isometric sport that increases the amount of muscle, thereby preventing cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0004326'>cachexia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Sport with a risk of blows to the chest or physical contact (e.g. boxing, rugby, martial arts) should be avoided </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Implantation, programming and follow-up should respect specific precautions to allow optimal physical activity with a pacemaker including implantation of bipolar leads on the side contralateral to the dominant hand, individual programming of the upper sensor and tracking rate and regular exercise testing </plain></SENT>
</text></document>