<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Background: The proinflammatory cytokine Interleukin-1β (IL-1β), which increases in the heart post <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (MI), has been shown to cause loss of Connexin43 (Cx43) function, an event known to underlie formation of the arrhythmogenic substrate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="6" ids="25681">Omega 3 Fatty acids</z:chebi> exhibit antiarrhythmic properties and impact IL-1β signaling </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We hypothesize that <z:chebi fb="6" ids="25681">Omega-3 fatty acids</z:chebi> prevent <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> in part, by inhibiting IL-1β signaling thus maintaining functional Cx43 channels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Methods: Rat neonatal myocytes or Madin-Darby Canine Kidney Epithelial (MDCK) cells grown in media in the absence (Ctr) or presence of 30 μM <z:chebi fb="0" ids="36005">docosahexaenoic acid</z:chebi> (DHA, an <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25681">Omega-3 Fatty acid</z:chebi>) were treated with 0.1 μM activated IL-1β </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We determined Cx43 channel function using a dye spread assay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Western blot and immunostaining were used to examine Cx43 levels/localization and downstream effectors of IL-1β </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In addition we used a murine model of MI for 24 h to determine the impact of an <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25681">Omega-3 fatty acid</z:chebi> enriched diet on Cx43 levels/localization <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856742" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">post MI</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Results: IL-1β significantly inhibited Cx43 function in Ctr cells (200.9 ± 17.7 μm [Ctr] vs. 112.8 ± 14.9 μm [0.1 uM IL-1β], p&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, DHA-treated cells remained highly coupled in the presence of IL-1β [167.9 ± 21.9 μm [DHA] vs. 164.4 ± 22.3 μm [DHA + 0.1 uM IL-1β], p&lt;0.05, n = 4] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Additionally, western blot showed that IL-1β treatment caused a 38.5% downregulation of Cx43 [1.00 au [Ctr] vs. 0.615 au (0.1 μM IL-1β) which was completely abolished in DHA-treated cells (0.935 au [DHA] vs. 1.02 au [DHA + 0.1 μM IL-1β), p &lt; 0.05, n = 3] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Examination of the downstream modulator of IL-1β, NFκβ showed that while <z:mp ids='MP_0005039'>hypoxia</z:mp> caused translocation of NFκβ to the nucleus, this was inhibited by DHA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Additionally we found that a diet enriched in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="25681">Omega-3 Fatty acids</z:chebi> inhibited lateralization of Cx43 in the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856742" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">post-MI</z:e> murine heart as well as limited activation of fibroblasts which would lead to decreased <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> overall </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25681">Omega 3 Fatty acid</z:chebi> treatment inhibited IL-1β-stimulated loss of Cx43 protein, and more importantly, inhibited loss of Cx43 function by inhibiting translocation of NFκβ </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In the intact heart a diet enriched in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="25681">Omega 3 Fatty Acids</z:chebi> limited loss of Cx43 at the intercalated disk in the heart following MI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>These data suggest that one of cardio-protective mechanisms by which <z:chebi fb="6" ids="25681">Omega 3 Fatty acids</z:chebi> work includes prevention of the pro-arrhythmic loss of Cx43 <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856742" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">post MI</z:e> and the attenuation of <z:mp ids='MP_0003141'>cardiac fibrosis</z:mp> after injury </plain></SENT>
</text></document>