<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Cardiovascular implantable electronic device (CIED) <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> may present as pocket <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> or as infective <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> (CIED-IE) with vegetation on device leads or heart valves </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>As aspirin has both anti-inflammatory properties and interferes with platelet aggregation, we hypothesized that ongoing anti-platelet therapy with aspirin may impact clinical and echocardiographic manifestations of CIED <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: We retrospectively reviewed 415 cases of CIED <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> admitted to Mayo Clinic Rochester from 1991 to 2008 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Information regarding aspirin use was available in 392 (94.5%) cases and 178 (45%) had received aspirin therapy prior to clinical <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of CIED <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Although there were no significant differences in pathogen distribution between patients who had received prior aspirin therapy as compared with those who did not, patients on aspirin therapy were less likely to report chills (25% vs. 35%, P = 0.04), sweats (9% vs.18%, P = 0.01), or have peripheral <z:hpo ids='HP_0001974'>leukocytosis</z:hpo> on admission (33% vs. 46%, P = 0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Overall, 82 (21%) of 392 patients met the clinical criteria for CIED-IE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients on prior aspirin therapy were significantly less likely to have vegetations on CIED leads or heart valves than those who had not received it (15% vs. 26%, P = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, despite the lower frequency of CIED-IE in the aspirin group, there was no significant difference (P = 0.97) in the overall survival between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Aspirin therapy prior to <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of CIED <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was associated with a lower likelihood of vegetation formation on CIED leads or heart valves and associated systemic manifestations of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>