<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The aim of our study was to investigate total atrial conduction time and left atrial (LA) mechanical function in patients with isolated coronary artery <z:mpath ids='MPATH_474'>ectasia</z:mpath> (ICAE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Sixty patients with ICAE without any visible <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242231" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary stenosis</z:e> were enrolled to this cross-sectional observational study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The control group consisted of 40 age- and gender-matched patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Left atrial mechanical functions were measured by the method of discs in the apical-four chamber echocardiographic view </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>LA mechanical function parameters were calculated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>P wave dispersion was measured on electrocardiography (ECG) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The total atrial conduction time (PA-tissue Doppler imaging (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="53555">TDI</z:chebi>) duration) was assessed by measuring the time interval between the beginning of the P wave on the surface ECG and point of the peak A wave on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53555">TDI</z:chebi> from LA lateral wall just over the mitral annulus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Student t, Mann-Whitney U, Pearson's, and Spearman's correlation analysis and multiple regression analysis were used for statistical analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The clinical and laboratory characteristics were similar in two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Both groups were similar in terms of Vmax and LA total emptying volume (29.0 ± 7.3 vs. 31.9 ± 6.5 mL/m², p=0.082 and 19.9 ± 5.1 vs. 20.0 ± 5.2 mL/m², p=0.821) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>However, LA passive emptying volume and LA passive emptying fraction were significantly decreased with ICAE patients (11.1 ± 3.2 vs. 13.5 ± 3.8 ml/m², p=0.005 and 35.2 ± 7.2 vs. 47.8 ± 9.4 mL/m², p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>But LA active emptying volume and LA active emptying fraction were significantly increased in ICAE patients (9.1 ± 2.6 vs. 6.4 ± 3.0 mL/m², p&lt;0.001 and 45.3 ± 8.1 vs. 40.7 ± 6.7 mL/m², p=0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>PA-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="53555">TDI</z:chebi> duration was measured significantly higher in patients with ICAE than control group (131.8 ± 5.7 vs. 114.4 ± 9.1 ms, p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Multiple linear regression analyses showed that ectatic segment number was an independent factor of PA-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="53555">TDI</z:chebi> duration (β=0.581, 95% CI=4.046-6.295, p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our study demonstrated presence of LA electrical and mechanical dysfunction in patients with ICAE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>LA dysfunction may be associated with cardiac pathologies as <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo>, decrease in cardiac output and congestive failure </plain></SENT>
</text></document>