<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Right atrial (RA) appendage (RAA) pacing is reported to impair hemodynamic benefits of cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) through a considerable delay of left atrial (LA) contraction, which compromises appropriate balance of atrioventricular (AV) and left ventricular (LV) synchrony </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Potential usefulness of Bachmann's bundle (BB) pacing to solve the problem remains to be confirmed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Atrial synchrony and LV performance was investigated by echocardiography in 25 patients undergoing pacemaker implantation with preserved AV conduction and LV function (Group I), and 15 patients receiving CRT (Group II) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In Group I, RAA pacing (AAI mode, n=10) increased P-wave duration (PWD) and RA-to-LA contraction delay (IAMD) compared with sinus rhythm (132±14 and 35±12 ms vs. 108±16 and 13±13 ms, P&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The delayed LA contraction was associated with early interruption of LV filling, leading to an impairment of LV performance (Tei index: 0.43±0.12 vs. 0.34±0.09, P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>BB pacing (AAI, n=15) did not cause such undesirable effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In Group II, RA (BB)-paced biventricular pacing (<z:chebi fb="12" ids="27841">DDD</z:chebi>) reduced PWD and IAMD compared with RA-sensed biventricular pacing (VDD) (102±14 and -3±13 ms vs. 117±10 and 21±18 ms, P&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>This restoration of atrial synchrony was associated with significant improvement of LV performance (Tei index: 0.56±0.18 vs. 0.62±0.16, P&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: BB pacing preserves atrial synchrony, and might be more favorable than RAA pacing for maximizing hemodynamic efficacy of CRT </plain></SENT>
</text></document>