<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to investigate homogeneity disorders of ventricular repolarization and atrial conduction via QT dispersion and P-wave dispersion in children with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002564'>congenital heart disease</z:hpo> (CHD) and pulmonary arterial <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (<z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Three groups of 20 each were generated and involved in this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The first group included 20 children with both CHD and <z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The second group consisted of 20 children with CHD but no <z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi>, and the third group was composed of 20 age- and sex-matched healthy children </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Electrocardiographic records were used to determine P-wave, QT, and corrected QT (QTc) dispersions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The <z:hpo ids='HP_0002092'>pulmonary hypertension</z:hpo> group compared with the group having no <z:hpo ids='HP_0002092'>pulmonary hypertension</z:hpo> and the control group showed a significantly longer P-wave dispersion duration (39.10 ± 9.54 vs. 26.30 ± 4.99 ms, p &lt; 0.001; and 24.80 ± 6.94 ms, p &lt; 0.001, respectively) and QT dispersion duration (52.80 ± 15.11 vs. 37.60 ± 6.00 ms, p &lt; 0.001; and 35.00 ± 7.77 ms, p &lt; 0.001, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In addition, the durations of maximum QTc and QTc dispersion were significantly longer in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002092'>pulmonary hypertension</z:hpo> group than in the other two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The risk of atrial and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> was found to be increased in the patients with both CHD and <z:chebi fb="11" ids="104011,31204,33848,53305">PAH</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Physicians should pay close attention to possible atrial and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> during the treatment and follow-up evaluation of these patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>