<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Increased dispersion of repolarization has been suggested to underlie increased arrhythmogenesis in human <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> (HF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, no detailed repolarization mapping data were available to support the presence of increased dispersion of repolarization in failing human heart </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In the present study, we aimed to determine the existence of enhanced repolarization dispersion in the right ventricular (RV) endocardium from failing human heart and examine its association with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> inducibility </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RV free wall preparations were dissected from five failing and five nonfailing human hearts, cannulated and coronary perfused </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RV endocardium was optically mapped from an ∼6.3 × 6.3 cm(2) field of view </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Action potential duration (APD), dispersion of APD, and conduction velocity (CV) were quantified for basic cycle lengths (BCL) ranging from 2,000 ms to the functional refractory period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We found that RV APD was significantly prolonged within the failing group compared with the nonfailing group (560 ± 44 vs. 448 ± 39 ms, at BCL = 2,000 ms, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Dispersion of APD was increased in three failing hearts (161 ± 5 vs. 86 ± 19 ms, at BCL = 2,000 ms) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>APD alternans were induced by rapid pacing in these same three failing hearts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CV was significantly reduced in the failing group compared with the nonfailing group (81 ± 11 vs. 98 ± 8 cm/s, at BCL = 2,000 ms) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>Arrhythmias</z:hpo> could be induced in two failing hearts exhibiting an abnormally steep CV restitution and increased dispersion of repolarization due to APD alternans </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Dispersion of repolarization is enhanced across the RV endocardium in the failing human heart </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>This dispersion, together with APD alternans and abnormal CV restitution, could be responsible for the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> susceptibility in human HF </plain></SENT>
</text></document>