<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: The implantation of an implantable loop recorder (ILR) leads to the diagnosis in about 35% of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> of unknown origin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Information on outcome of patients in whom a diagnosis is not reached during the lifetime of the device is scarce </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of our study is to determine the outcome of these patients in terms of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> recurrence and survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: An ILR was implanted to 97 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> of unknown origin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients were classified in groups A and B depending on their high or low risk, respectively, of having arrhythmic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Diagnosis had not been reached in 60 patients (62%) when the ILR battery reached end operational life </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Five patients were lost to follow up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>During a median follow-up of 48 months after ILR explantation (interquartile range 36-56), 22 patients (40%) had recurrence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> (32% in group A vs. 48% in group B, P = 0.3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>Syncopes</z:hpo> with no neurally mediated profile were more frequent in group A (18 vs. 0%, P = 0.05) and neurally mediated profile <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncopes</z:hpo> were more frequent in group B (44 vs. 11%, P = 0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Five patients died, four of them in group A and 1 in group B (P = 0.4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>No sudden or cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> were detected during follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> were due to non-cardiac causes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Recurrent <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> is common in patients in whom a diagnosis is not established after the full battery life of an ILR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The prognosis of these patients seems to be good, without observed sudden or cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>