<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Late <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33375">gadolinium</z:chebi> enhancement (LGE) with cardiac magnetic resonance (CMR) can predict <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> and poor prognosis in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001639'>hypertrophic cardiomyopathy</z:hpo> (HCM) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Although myocardial T2-high signal has been reported to appear within LGE in those patients, its clinical significance remains unclear </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We investigated the relationship between the T2-high signal and nonsustained <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> (NSVT) in HCM patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Eighty-one HCM patients who underwent Holter ECG and CMR including T2-weighted and LGE imaging were retrospectively recruited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>They were divided into NSVT-positive and NSVT-negative groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We compared the clinical and CMR characteristics between both of the groups, and assessed predictors of NSVT with multivariate analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Myocardial T2-high signal was observed in 15/81 (18.5 %) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Each T2-high signal was localized within LGE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Significantly in the NSVT-positive group, the prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> [5/17 (29.4 %) vs. 2/64 (3.1 %), p = 0.0006] and T2-high signal [9/17 (52.9 %) vs. 6/64 (9.4 %), p &lt; 0.0001] and the left ventricular (LV) end-systolic volume index (32.2 ± 15.9 ml/m(2) vs. 23.3 ± 14.9 ml/m(2), p = 0.034) and the number of segments with LGE (5.8 ± 3.3 vs. 2.7 ± 2.7, p &lt; 0.0001) was increased, and the LV ejection fraction (54.8 ± 10.9 % vs. 65.1 ± 10.6 %, p = 0.0007) was decreased, compared to the NSVT-negative group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>On multivariate analysis, the presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (OR 29.49, p = 0.0025) and DM (OR 7.36, p = 0.0455) and T2-high signal (OR 14.96, p = 0.0014) and reduced LV ejection fraction (OR 0.93, p = 0.0222) were significantly associated with NSVT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The presence of myocardial T2-high signal is a significant independent predictor of NSVT in HCM patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>