<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Insulation breaches with externalization of conductor cables have been described for St-Jude Medical Riata™ defibrillation leads </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Published data on the incidence of Riata lead abnormalities are quite <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneous</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to estimate systematically the prevalence of lead abnormalities using a postero-anterior (PA) and lateral chest X-ray (CXR) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: From 2002 to 2008, 552 Riata defibrillation leads were implanted at our centre </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We evaluated patients for potential insulation breaches </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A PA and lateral CXR was obtained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Chest X-rays were reviewed by two electrophysiologists using a zooming function with magnification up to factor 7.5 and were classified as <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> or abnormal for the presence of conductor externalization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A total of 284 patients were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Riata lead models were 1570, 1580, 1582, 1590, 1592, 7000, 7002, and 7022 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The total frequency of radiological lead defects was 24.3% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Insulation breaches occurred at zones of major lead curvature </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Mean maximal spacing between extruding lead components was 3.6 ± 1.9 mm (range 2.0-12.4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Abnormal CXRs were more frequent in 8F leads (31.4% vs. 6.3%; P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Most defects occurred with lead models 1582 (41.2%) and 1580 (31.4%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Mean time since implantation was longer in abnormal leads (6.7 vs. 5.9 years; P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Abnormal leads had higher pacing thresholds (1.1 ± 0.8 V vs. 0.9 ± 0.4 V; P = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The incidence of insulation breach in Riata leads is much higher than quoted by the manufacturer or reported by most of the literature </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>A PA and lateral CXR with zooming appears adequate to identify lead breaches when reviewed by an electrophysiologist </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>Riata lead breaches without electrical abnormalities present a management dilemma and will require further studies </plain></SENT>
</text></document>