<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To assess the image quality and effective radiation dose of prospectively electrocardiogram (ECG)-gated high-pitch spiral acquisition mode (flash mode) of dual-source CT (DSCT) coronary angiography (CTCA) in patients with high heart rates (HRs) as compared with retrospectively ECG-gated spiral acquisition mode </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: Two hundred and sixty-eight consecutive patients (132 female, mean age: 55 ± 11 years) with mean HR &gt; 65 beats per minute (bpm) were prospectively included in this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The patients were divided into two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Collection was performed in group A CTCA using flash mode setting at 20-30% of the R-R interval, and retrospectively ECG-gated spiral acquisition mode in group B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The image noise, contrast-to-noise ratio (<z:chebi fb="11" ids="50807">CNR</z:chebi>), image quality scores, effective radiation dose and influencing factors on image quality between the two groups were assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were no significant differences in image quality scores and proportions of non-diagnostic coronary artery segments between two groups (image quality scores: 1.064 ± 0.306 [group A] vs. 1.084 ± 0.327 [group B], p = 0.063; proportion of non-diagnostic coronary artery segments: segment-based analysis 1.52% (group A) vs. 1.74% (group B), p = 0.345; patient-based analysis 7.5% (group A) vs. 6.7% (group B), p = 0.812) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The estimated radiation dose was 1.0 ± 0.16 mSv in group A and 7.1 ± 1.05 mSv in group B (p = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In conclusion, in patients with HRs &gt; 65 bpm without <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmia</z:hpo>, the prospectively high-pitch spiral-acquisition mode with image-acquired timing set at 20-30% of the R-R interval provides a similar image quality and low rate of non-diagnostic coronary segments to the retrospectively ECG-gated low-pitch spiral acquisition mode, with significant reduction of radiation exposure </plain></SENT>
</text></document>