<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: To assess short and long-term outcomes for patients aged ≥80 years undergoing esophagectomy for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancy</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients undergoing esophagectomy for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> between 1991 and 2011 had information prospectively entered into a database; patients were divided into elderly (≥80 years) and younger (&lt;80 years) groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of the 500 patients included, 32 (6.4%) were ≥80 years of age </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Octogenarians had increased Charlson comorbidity index and were less likely to receive neoadjuvant chemoradiotherapy (6.3 vs. 39.7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Analysis of operative time, estimated blood loss, and length of intensive care unit and hospital stay revealed no significant differences between the groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Patients ≥80 years old had increased total postoperative morbidity (68.8 vs. 44.9%), specifically <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> (31.3 vs. 16.7%) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002090'>pneumonia</z:hpo> (18.8 vs. 8.3%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were no in-hospital mortalities in patients ≥80 years (0 vs. 0.4%), and there was no significant difference in overall survival between the groups (53.2 ± 9.1 vs. 77.6 ± 4.8 months; P = 0.58) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Subset analysis demonstrated similar morbidity and length of hospital stay for patients between 70 and 79 years (n = 132) and those ≥80 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Elderly patients undergoing esophagectomy are at greater risk of postoperative complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, there were no significant differences in other major parameters, including length of hospital stay, mortality, and survival, indicating that selected patients ≥80 years old can and should be assessed by an experienced surgeon </plain></SENT>
</text></document>