<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The implantable cardioverter-defibrillator (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>) is highly effective in reducing mortality among patients at risk for fatal <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo>, but inappropriate <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> activations are frequent, with potential adverse effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We randomly assigned 1500 patients with a primary-prevention indication to receive an <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> with one of three programming configurations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The primary objective was to determine whether programmed high-rate therapy (with a 2.5-second delay before the initiation of therapy at a heart rate of ≥200 beats per minute) or delayed therapy (with a 60-second delay at 170 to 199 beats per minute, a 12-second delay at 200 to 249 beats per minute, and a 2.5-second delay at ≥250 beats per minute) was associated with a decrease in the number of patients with a first occurrence of inappropriate antitachycardia pacing or shocks, as compared with conventional programming (with a 2.5-second delay at 170 to 199 beats per minute and a 1.0-second delay at ≥200 beats per minute) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: During an average follow-up of 1.4 years, high-rate therapy and delayed <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> therapy, as compared with conventional device programming, were associated with reductions in a first occurrence of inappropriate therapy (hazard ratio with high-rate therapy vs. conventional therapy, 0.21; 95% confidence interval [CI], 0.13 to 0.34; P&lt;0.001; hazard ratio with delayed therapy vs. conventional therapy, 0.24; 95% CI, 0.15 to 0.40; P&lt;0.001) and reductions in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause mortality (hazard ratio with high-rate therapy vs. conventional therapy, 0.45; 95% CI, 0.24 to 0.85; P=0.01; hazard ratio with delayed therapy vs. conventional therapy, 0.56; 95% CI, 0.30 to 1.02; P=0.06) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There were no significant differences in procedure-related adverse events among the three treatment groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Programming of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e> therapies for tachyarrhythmias of 200 beats per minute or higher or with a prolonged delay in therapy at 170 beats per minute or higher, as compared with conventional programming, was associated with reductions in inappropriate therapy and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause mortality during long-term follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>(Funded by Boston Scientific; MADIT-RIT ClinicalTrials.gov number, NCT00947310.) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>