<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Beta-adrenoceptors (β-AR) play an important role in the neurohumoral regulation of cardiac function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Three β-AR subtypes (β(1), β(2), β(3)) have been described so far </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Total deficiency of these adrenoceptors (TKO) results in cardiac hypotrophy and negative inotropy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>TKO represents a unique mouse model mimicking total unselective medical β-blocker therapy in men </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Electrophysiological characteristics of TKO have not yet been investigated in an animal model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In vivo electrophysiological studies using right heart catheterisation were performed in 10 TKO mice and 10 129SV <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild type</z:mp> control mice (WT) at the age of 15 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Standard surface ECG, intracardiac and electrophysiological parameters, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> inducibility were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The surface ECG of TKO mice revealed a <z:mp ids='MP_0005333'>reduced heart rate</z:mp> (359.2±20.9 bpm vs. 461.1±33.3 bpm; p&lt;0.001), <z:mp ids='MP_0004071'>prolonged P wave</z:mp> (17.5±3.0 ms vs. 15.1±1.2 ms; p = 0.019) and PQ time (40.8±2.4 ms vs. 37.3±3.0 ms; p = 0.013) compared to WT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Intracardiac ECG showed a significantly prolonged infra-Hisian conductance (HV-interval: 12.9±1.4 ms vs. 6.8±1.0 ms; p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Functional testing showed prolonged atrial and ventricular refractory periods in TKO (40.5±15.5 ms vs. 21.3±5.8 ms; p = 0.004; and 41.0±9.7 ms vs. 28.3±6.6 ms; p = 0.004, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In TKO both the probability of induction of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (12% vs. 24%; p&lt;0.001) and of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardias</z:hpo> (0% vs. 26%; p&lt;0.001) were significantly reduced </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: TKO results in significant prolongations of cardiac conduction times and refractory periods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>This was accompanied by a highly significant reduction of atrial and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Our finding confirms the importance of β-AR in arrhythmogenesis and the potential role of unspecific beta-receptor-blockade as therapeutic target </plain></SENT>
</text></document>