<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Orthodromic atrioventricular reentrant <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> (ORT) is the most common <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> at electrophysiological study (EPS) in patients with pre-excitation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The purpose of the study was to determine the clinical significance and the electrophysiological characteristics of patients with inducible antidromic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> (ADT).METHODS AND RESULTS: Electrophysiological study was performed in 807 patients with a <z:hpo ids='HP_0004309'>pre-excitation syndrome</z:hpo> in control state and after <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6046">isoproterenol</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Antidromic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> was induced in 63 patients (8%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Clinical and electrophysiological data were compared with those of 744 patients without ADT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients with and without ADT were similar in term of age (33 ± 18 vs. 34 ± 17), male gender (68 vs. 61%), clinical presentation with spontaneous atrioventricular reentrant <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> (AVRT) (35 vs. 42%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) (3 vs. 3%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> (16 vs. 12%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In patients with induced ADT, asymptomatic patients were less frequent (24 vs. 37%; &lt;0.04), spontaneous ADT and spontaneous malignant form more frequent (8 vs. 0.5%; &lt;0.001) (16 vs. 6%; &lt;0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Left lateral accessory pathway (AP) location was more frequent (51 vs. 36%; P &lt; 0.022), septal location less frequent (40 vs. 56%; P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>And 1/1 conduction through AP was more rapid </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Orthodromic AVRT induction was as frequent (55.5 vs. 55%), but AF induction (41 vs. 24%; P &lt; 0.002) and electrophysiological malignant form were more frequent (22 vs. 12%; P &lt; 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The follow-up was similar; four <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> and three spontaneous malignant forms occurred in patients without ADT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>When population was divided based on age (&lt;20/≥20 years), the older group was less likely to have criteria for malignant form.CONCLUSION: Antidromic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> induction is rare in <z:hpo ids='HP_0004309'>pre-excitation syndrome</z:hpo> and generally is associated with spontaneous or electrophysiological malignant form, but clinical outcome does not differ </plain></SENT>
</text></document>