<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine effects of activating protein kinase C (PKC) on ventricular action potential duration restitution (APDR) and Burst stimulus induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> in Langendorff-perfused rabbit hearts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Male rabbits were equally divided into three groups randomly: control group (Tyrode's solution perfusion), PKC <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8116">phorbol</z:chebi>-12-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="30807">myristate</z:chebi>-13-<z:chebi fb="49" ids="30089,47622">acetate</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="1" ids="53780">PMA</z:chebi>, 100 nmol/L) group and PKC inhibitor bisindolylmaleimide (BIM, 500 nmol/L) group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Thirty minutes after perfusion, the monophasic action potential (MAP) and effective refractory period (ERP) were determined in right basal ventricle (RB), right apex (RA), left basal ventricle (LB) and left apex (LA) of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> the animals, and APDR curve was drawn </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Burst stimulus method was used to induce <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> in perfused rabbit hearts; Real-time PCR was used to detect the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression of PKC in four different areas of ventricle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Compared with the control group, the ERP, 90% of monophasic action potential duration (MAPD(90)) and ERP/MAPD(90) were significantly shortened (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P &lt; 0.01), the max slopes (S(max)) of APDR curve were significantly steeper (RB: 1.22 ± 0.23 vs. 0.65 ± 0.19; RA: 2.99 ± 0.29 vs. 1.02 ± 0.18; LB: 1.84 ± 0.21 vs. 0.85 ± 0.12; LA: 4.02 ± 0.32 vs.1.12 ± 0.23, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P &lt; 0.01) and the incidences of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> were significantly increased in the <z:chebi fb="1" ids="53780">PMA</z:chebi> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> parameters were similar between the BIM group and the control group (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P &gt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Activating PKC could enhance the max slopes of APDR curve at various ventricular areas and subsequently increase <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> susceptibility in Langendorff-perfused rabbit hearts </plain></SENT>
</text></document>