<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: The beneficial effects of cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) are thought to result from favorable left ventricular (LV) reverse remodeling, however CRT is only successful in about 70% of patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Whether response to CRT is associated with a decrease in <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> (VA) is still discussed controversially </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Therefore, we investigated the incidence of VA in CRT responders in comparison with non-responders </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In this nonrandomized, two-center, observational study patients with moderate-to-severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>, LV ejection fraction (LVEF) ≤35%, and QRS duration &gt;120 ms undergoing CRT were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After 6 months patients were classified as CRT responders or non-responders </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Incidence of VA was compared between both groups by Kaplan-Meier analysis and Cox regression analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>ROC analysis was performed to determine the aptitude of LVEF cut-off values to predict VA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In total 126 consecutive patients (64±11 years; 67%male) were included, 74 were classified as responders and 52 as non-responders </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>While the mean LVEF at baseline was comparable in both groups (25±7% vs. 24±8%; P = 0.4583) only the responder group showed an improvement of LVEF (36±6% vs. 24±7; p&lt;0.0001) under CRT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In total in 56 patients VA were observed during a mean follow-up of 28±14 months, with CRT responders experiencing fewer VA than non-responders (35% vs. 58%, p&lt;0.0061) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Secondary preventive CRT implantation was associated with a higher likelihood of VA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>As determined by ROC analysis an increase of LVEF by &gt;7% was found to be a predictor of a significantly lower incidence of VA (AUC = 0.606) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Improvement of left ventricular function under cardiac resynchronization therapy goes along with a reduced incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>