<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The development of malignant <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> is a possible feature in Emery-Dreifuss <z:hpo ids='HP_0003560'>muscular dystrophy</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EDMD</z:e>) patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> left ventricular systolic function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This event may be the cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001645'>sudden cardiac death</z:hpo> in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EDMD</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>QTc dispersion (QTc-D), JTc dispersion (JTc-D) and Tpeak-end dispersion (TDR) could reflect the physiological variability of regional and transmural ventricular repolarisation and could provide a substrate for life-threatening <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>AIM: The current study was designed to evaluate the <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo> of ventricular repolarisation in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EDMD</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Echocardiograms and electrocardiograms from 40 EDMD patients (age 20 ± 13) were evaluated and compared to those of 40 healthy age-matched controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EDMD</z:e> group, compared to the healthy control group, presented increased values of QTc-D (82.8 ± 44.1 vs. 53.3 ± 13.9, p = 0.003), JTc-D (73.6 ± 32.3 vs. 60.4 ± 11.1 ms, p = 0.001) and TDR (100.54 ± 19.06 vs. 92.15 ± 15.5 ms, p = 0.004) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>No correlation between QTc dispersion and ejection fraction (R = 0.2, p = 0.3) was found </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EDMD</z:e> is associated with significantly increased regional and transmural <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo> of ventricular repolarisation, in the absence of impaired systolic and diastolic cardiac function </plain></SENT>
</text></document>