<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: It is not known if successful catheter ablation for <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) improves the patient's long-term cardiovascular outcomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study investigated the long-term outcomes and mortality of AF patients at high risk who received antiarrhythmic medication and catheter ablation.METHODS AND RESULTS: The propensity scores for AF were calculated for each patient and were used to assemble a cohort of 174 AF patients with ablation who were compared with an equal number of AF patients without ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Composite cardiovascular end points (major adverse cardiovascular event, MACE), including mortality and vascular events in the medically treated patients representing the control group (group 1), were compared with those in the ablation-treated patients (group 2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The rates of the total mortality (2.95% vs. 0.74% per year; P &lt; 0.01), cardiovascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> (1.77% vs. 0% per year; P = 0.001), and ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>/<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007787" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="tia|TIA|T.I.A.">transient ischaemic attack</z:e> (2.21% vs. 0.59% per year; P = 0.02) were higher in group 1 than group 2, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A multivariate Cox regression analysis of the MACE scores showed that a higher CHA(2)DS(2)-VASc score [hazard ratio (HR) = 1.309 per increment of score, 95% confidence interval (CI) = 1.06-1.617; P = 0.01] and the performance of the ablation procedure (HR = 0.225, CI = 0.076-0.671; P = 0.007) were independent predictors of a MACE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In patients who received catheter ablation, recurrence of any atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> was a predictor of vascular events and total mortality (P &lt; 0.05).CONCLUSION: In AF patients with CHA(2)DS(2)-VASc score ≥1, catheter ablation of AF reduced the risk of the total/cardiovascular mortality and total vascular events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>Atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> recurrence predicts long-term cardiovascular outcomes, as well as the CHA(2)DS(2)-VASc score </plain></SENT>
</text></document>