<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: The mechanism responsible for premature ventricular complex (<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp>)-mediated left ventricular (LV) dysfunction remains unclear </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We sought to determine the electrocardiographic and electrophysiological characteristics of <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp>-mediated LV dysfunction.METHODS AND RESULTS: One hundred and twenty-seven patients who underwent radiofrequency catheter ablation (RFCA) for frequent <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVCs</z:mp> (<z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVCs</z:mp> burden ≥10%/24 h) and had no significant structural <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018799" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">heart disease</z:e> were investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Left ventricular dysfunction (ejection fraction &lt; 50%) was present in 28 of 127 patients (22.0%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The mean <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> burden (31 ± 11 vs. 22 ± 10%, P &lt; 0.001), the presence of non-sustained <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> (53.6 vs. 33.3%, P = 0.05), and the presence of a retrograde P-wave following a <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> (64.3 vs. 30.3%, P = 0.001) were significantly greater in those with LV dysfunction than in those with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> LV function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The cut-off <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> burden related to LV dysfunction was 26%/day, with a sensitivity of 70% and a specificity of 78% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp>, QRS axis, QRS width, coupling interval, the presence of interpolation, and <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> emergence pattern during exercise electrocardiogram were not significantly different between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The origin sites of <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVCs</z:mp>, the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> success rate, and the recurrence rate during follow-up after RFCA were similar </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In a multivariate analysis, the <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> burden (odds ratio 2.94, 95% confidence interval 0.90-3.19, P = 0.006) and the presence of retrograde P-waves (odds ratio 2.79, 95% confidence interval 1.08-7.19, P = 0.034) were independently associated with <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp>-mediated LV dysfunction.CONCLUSION: A higher <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp> burden (&gt;26%/day) and the presence of retrograde P-waves were independently associated with <z:mp ids='MP_0010018'>PVC</z:mp>-mediated LV dysfunction </plain></SENT>
</text></document>