<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The presence of pre-infarction <z:mp ids='MP_0006112'>angina</z:mp> (PIA) has been shown to confer cardioprotection after ST-segment elevation <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">STEMI</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, the clinical impact of PIA in non-ST-segment elevation <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (NSTEMI) remains to be determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: From the obseRvatoire des Infarctus de Côte d'Or (RICO) survey, 1541 consecutive patients admitted in intensive care unit with a first NSTEMI were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients who experienced <z:hpo ids='HP_0100749'>chest pain</z:hpo> &lt;7 days before the episode leading to admission were defined as having PIA and were compared with patients without PIA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Incidence of in-hospital <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> (VAs), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> and 30-day mortality were collected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Among the 1541 patients included in the study, 693 (45%) patients presented PIA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>PIA was associated with a lower <z:chebi fb="2" ids="16919">creatine</z:chebi> kinase peak, as a reflection of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size (231(109-520) vs. 322(148-844) IU/L, p&lt;0.001) when compared with the group without PIA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients with PIA developed fewer VAs, by 3 fold (1.6% vs. 4.0%, p = 0.008) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> (18.0% vs. 22.4%, p = 0.040) during the hospital stay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Overall, there was a decrease in early CV events by 26% in patients with PIA (19.2% vs. 25.9%, p = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>By multivariate analysis, PIA remained independently associated with less VAs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: From this large contemporary prospective study, our work showed that PIA is very frequent in patients admitted for a first NSTEMI, and is associated with a better prognosis, including reduced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size and in hospital VAs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Accordingly, protecting the myocardium by ischemic or pharmacological conditioning not only in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">STEMI</z:e>, but in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> type of MI merits further attention </plain></SENT>
</text></document>