<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Epicardial Access Techniques. Epicardial mapping and ablation is increasingly being performed for the treatment of complex <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Right ventricular (RV) puncture remains the most common complication, with damage to surrounding non-cardiac structures also a concern </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We describe the standard techniques used in our lab essential for safe epicardial access, as well as a novel technique incorporating electroanatomic mapping (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EAM</z:e>) guidance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In a series of 8 patients referred for <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardia</z:hpo> ablation, an RV endocardial voltage map was created using <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EAM</z:e> systems </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EAM</z:e> images were fused with preprocedure CT scans when available </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A 17G Tuohy needle was integrated with the <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EAM</z:e> system by attaching the needle to <z:mp ids='MP_0001924'>sterile</z:mp> electrode clamps </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EAM</z:e> location points were used in conjunction with standard access techniques until epicardial access was obtained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Epicardial access was successfully obtained in 8/8 (100%) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Successful access without RV puncture was achieved in 7/8 (88%) cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This proof of concept study demonstrates that <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EAM</z:e> systems can be used as an adjunct to standard access techniques to visualize and facilitate pericardial access </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>(J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol, Vol. pp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>1-4) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>