<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: We evaluated the effects of cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) on skeletal muscle pathology and <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>.METHODS AND RESULTS: Stable patients (n = 21, 14 males, mean age 70 ± 7 years) with symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> (mean left ventricular ejection fraction 24 ± 6%) and an indication for CRT were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Ergospirometry, skeletal muscle open biopsy, and blood sampling were performed prior to implantation and after 6 months of CRT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>After CRT there was a reduction in both left ventricular end-diastolic diameter (LVEDD; 6.8 ± 0.8 vs. 6.3 ± 0.7 cm, P &lt; 0.001) and native QRS duration (D) minus biventricular paced QRSD (172.9 ± 23 vs. 136.3 ± 23 ms, P ≤ 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>These changes were associated with an increase in peak slope oxygen uptake (consumption) (VO(2)) (13.3 ± 2.2 vs. 14.5 ± 2.6 mL/kg/min, P = 0.07) and an improvement in the minute ventilation/carbon dioxide production slope (VE/VCO(2)) slope (41.6 ± 7.4 vs. 39.1 ± 5.6, P = 0.012) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There were no statistically significant changes in levels of pro-inflammatory cytokines, in mediators of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> biosynthesis or skeletal muscle pathology, except for an increase in skeletal muscle capillary density (4.5 ± 2.4 vs. 7.7 ± 3.3%, P = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Both the reduction of QRS duration and the increase in peak VO(2) correlated significantly with the change in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> density (r = 0.57, P = 0.008 and r = 0.54, P = 0.027, respectively).CONCLUSION: Cardiac resynchronization therapy, with improved functional status and reduced LVEDD resulted in increased peak VO(2), improvement in VE/VCO(2) slope and capillary density in skeletal muscle, with no reduction in systemic pro-inflammatory cytokines, increase in intramuscular levels of mediators of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> biosynthesis or improvement in skeletal muscle ultrastructure per se.ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT01019915 </plain></SENT>
</text></document>