<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>Ventricular arrhythmia</z:hpo> (VA) in the setting of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> coronary syndrome (ACS) carries an ominous prognosis; however, long-term prognosis associated with VA in ACS in the Middle East is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Accordingly, we sought to assess the incidence, in-hospital outcomes, and 1-year mortality of in-hospital VA in patients with ACS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: The Second Gulf Registry of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> Coronary Events (Gulf RACE-2) is a multinational observational study of patients with ACS, which enrolled 7930 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Of these, 333 (4.2%) developed VA during hospitalization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients with VA were significantly older (mean age 58.3 vs. 56.8 years), and had a significantly higher rate of prior <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>/<z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>transient ischemic attack</z:hpo> (7.5 vs. 4.2%), smoking (36.6 vs. 35.6%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>congestive heart failure</z:hpo> (11.0 vs. 6.5%), and peripheral artery disease (6.5 vs. 1.7%), compared with patients without VA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>They had significantly less <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (35.4 vs. 40.3%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (43.2 vs. 47.9%), percutaneous coronary intervention (6.1 vs. 9.4%), and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e> (22.4 vs. 38.2%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The adjusted odds ratios for in-hospital, 30-day, and 1-year mortality in VA complicating <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> ACS were 25.8, 11.1, and 7.3; ST-elevation <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarctions</z:hpo> were 18.3, 11.7, and 6.3; and unstable <z:mp ids='MP_0006112'>angina</z:mp> and non-ST elevation <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarctions</z:hpo> were 47.4, 10.3, and 18.7, respectively (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In-hospital VA in patients with ACS with and without ST elevation was associated with significantly higher in-hospital, 30-day, and 1-year mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Noticeably higher long-term mortality among Middle Eastern patients with ACS having VA compared with other reports requires further study and warrants immediate attention </plain></SENT>
</text></document>