<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: For most elderly pacemaker patients, evaluation of rate-adaptive pacing using treadmill and bicycle tests is impractical and not representative of typical daily activities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study was designed to compare the performance and physiological response of the closed-loop stimulation (CLS) rate-adaptive sensor to accelerometer (XL) and no rate sensor (<z:chebi fb="12" ids="27841">DDD</z:chebi>) during typical daily activity testing.METHODS AND RESULTS: Subjects recently implanted with a Cylos pacemaker completed timed activities of daily life testing, which included walking, sweeping, and standing from a seated position </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Activity performance and physiological response from each sensor mode was evaluated for subjects requiring ≥80% pacing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Overall, 74 subjects needed ≥80% pacing during at least one test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>An increase in the area swept (CLS vs. XL, 1.67 m(2) difference, P = 0.009; CLS vs. <z:chebi fb="12" ids="27841">DDD</z:chebi>, 1.59 m(2) difference, P = 0.025) and a decrease in the prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001278'>orthostatic hypotension</z:hpo> <z:chebi fb="2" ids="29191">(OH)</z:chebi> after standing 1 min (CLS vs. XL, odds ratio = 0.16, P = 0.006; CLS vs. <z:chebi fb="12" ids="27841">DDD</z:chebi>, odds ratio = 0.18, P = 0.012) was observed in the CLS mode as compared with XL and <z:chebi fb="12" ids="27841">DDD</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>No statistical difference in walk distance was observed between CLS and XL or CLS and <z:chebi fb="12" ids="27841">DDD</z:chebi>.CONCLUSION: In <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> testing, as compared with XL and <z:chebi fb="12" ids="27841">DDD</z:chebi>, CLS provides a more physiological response during the performance of activities of daily living for subjects with ≥80% pacing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>This is clinically reflected in better performance during the sweep test as well as a decrease in the prevalence of OH in our elderly population.Clinicaltrials.gov identifier: NCT00355797 </plain></SENT>
</text></document>