<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Electroanatomic mapping (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EAM</z:e>) systems are an important tool to identify cardiac chamber voltage and assess channels of slow conduction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To assess the correlation between <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">EAM</z:e> voltage maps obtained during macro-reentrant <z:hpo ids='HP_0001649'>tachycardia</z:hpo> compared to sinus rhythm (SR) with a contact mapping system </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We retrospectively evaluated patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004749'>atrial flutter</z:hpo> (AFL) referred for radiofrequency ablation with electroanatomic voltage maps obtained during AFL and SR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The atrium was divided into predetermined segments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Overall atrial and segmental peak-to-peak bipolar voltages in AFL and SR were assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>To directly compare a region within the same patient, tissue voltage differences during AFL and SR was assessed based on mean voltage difference </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Sixteen patients (87% male) had available voltage maps </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Eighty-one percent had typical cavo-tricuspid isthmus-dependent right AFL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A mean of 441.7±153.9 vs 398.1±125.4 total points (p=0.22) were sampled during AFL and SR; with a mean of 99.5±58.9 vs. 91.2±60.4 points (p=0.45) sampled per region </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Overall RA mean voltage was significantly higher during AFL than SR, (0.554±0.092 mV vs 0.473±0.079 mV, p=&lt;0.001), with the lateral wall (0.707±0.120 mV vs. 0.573±0.097 mV, p=0.0004) and the CTI (0.559±0.100 mV vs. 0.356±0.066 mV, p&lt;0.0001) also showing higher mean voltage during AFL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>When compared within an individual patient, nineteen percent (14/75) of patient regions had a &gt;0.5 mV mean voltage difference and 40% (30/75) had a &gt;0.25 mV mean voltage difference </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These data suggest that voltage maps performed during macro-reentrant atrial <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> often vary significantly from maps obtained during SR </plain></SENT>
</text></document>