<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">American trypanosomiasis</z:e>, or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e>, is caused by Trypanosoma cruzi, and a vaccine would greatly improve disease control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>While some studies in mice suggest that a vaccine is feasible, limited efficacy has been observed in dogs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We evaluated here the safety and efficacy of a DNA vaccine encoding TSA-1 and Tc24 antigens in a dog model of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> T. cruzi <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Mongrel dogs were immunized with two doses of 500μg of DNA vaccine, two weeks apart, and infected with T. cruzi (SylvioX10/4 strain) two weeks after the second vaccine dose </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Another group of dogs was infected first and treated with the vaccine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Disease progression was monitored for up to 70 days post-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The vaccine did not induce any critical change in blood parameters, nor exacerbation of disease in vaccinated animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>On the contrary, it prevented <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anemia</z:hpo> and a decrease in lymphocyte counts following T. cruzi <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in vaccinated dogs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Both preventive and therapeutic vaccination significantly reduced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242723" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">parasitemia</z:e>, <z:mp ids='MP_0001853'>cardiac inflammation</z:mp> and cardiac parasite burden, and tended to reduce the development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These results indicate that a preventive or therapeutic DNA vaccine encoding TSA-1 and Tc24 antigens is safe and may reduce both parasite transmission and the clinical progression of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> in vaccinated dogs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This DNA vaccine may thus be an excellent veterinary vaccine candidate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>These data also further strengthen the feasibility of a <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0041234" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chagas disease</z:e> vaccine for humans </plain></SENT>
</text></document>