<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: The long-term clinical value of the optimization of atrioventricular (AVD) and interventricular (VVD) delays in cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) remains controversial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We studied retrospectively the association between the frequency of AVD and VVD optimization and 1-year clinical outcomes in the 199 CRT patients who completed the Clinical Evaluation on Advanced Resynchronization study.METHODS AND RESULTS: From the 199 patients assigned to CRT-pacemaker (CRT-P) (New York Heart Association, NYHA, class III/IV, left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;35%), two groups were retrospectively composed a posteriori on the basis of the frequency of their AVD and VVD optimization: Group 1 (n = 66) was composed of patients 'systematically' optimized at implant, at 3 and 6 months; Group 2 (n = 133) was composed of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> other patients optimized 'non-systematically' (less than three times) during the 1 year study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The primary endpoint was a composite of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause mortality, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>-related hospitalization, NYHA functional class, and Quality of Life score, at 1 year </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Systematic CRT optimization was associated with a higher percentage of improved patients based on the composite endpoint (85% in Group 1 vs. 61% in Group 2, P &lt; 0.001), with fewer <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> (3% in Group 1 vs. 14% in Group 2, P = 0.014) and fewer hospitalizations (8% in Group 1 vs. 23% in Group 2, P = 0.007), at 1 year.CONCLUSION: These results further suggest that AVD and VVD frequent optimization (at implant, at 3 and 6 months) is associated with improved long-term clinical response in CRT-P patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>