<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: After initial catheter ablation, repeat procedures could be necessary </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study evaluates the efficacy of the magnetic navigation system (MNS) in repeat catheter ablation as compared with manual conventional techniques (MANs).METHODS AND RESULTS: The results of 163 repeat ablation procedures were analysed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Ablations were performed either using MNS (n = 84) or conventional manual ablation (n = 79) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Procedures were divided into four groups based on the technique used during the initial and repeat ablation procedure: MAN-MAN (n = 66), MAN-MNS (n = 31), MNS-MNS (n = 53), and MNS-MAN (n = 13) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Three subgroups were analysed: <z:hpo ids='HP_0004755'>supraventricular tachycardias</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVTs</z:e>, n = 68), <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF, n = 67), and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004756'>ventricular tachycardias</z:hpo> (VT, n = 28) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Recurrences were assessed during 19 ± 11 months follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Overall, repeat procedures using MNS were successful in 89.0% as compared with 96.2% in the MAN group (P = ns) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The overall recurrence rate was significantly lower using MNS (25.0 vs. 41.4%, P = 0.045) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> success and recurrence rates for the MAN-MAN, MAN-MNS, MNS-MNS, and MNS-MAN groups were comparable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>For the <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVT</z:e> subgroup a higher <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> success rate was achieved using MAN (87.9 vs. 100.0%, P = 0.049) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The use of MNS for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVT</z:e> is associated with longer procedure times (205 ± 82 vs. 172 ± 69 min, P = 0.040) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>For AF procedure and fluoroscopy times were longer (257 ± 72 vs. 185 ± 64, P = 0.001; 59.5 ± 19.3 vs. 41.1 ± 18.3 min, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Less fluoroscopy was used for MNS-guided VT procedures (22.8 ± 14.7 vs. 41.2 ± 10.9, P = 0.011).CONCLUSION: Our data suggest that overall MNS is comparable with MAN in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> success after repeat catheter ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>However, MNS is related to fewer recurrences as compared with MAN </plain></SENT>
</text></document>