<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: This study aims to investigate whether the use of a novel inner lumen circular mapping catheter (IMC) can shorten the procedural duration and fluoroscopic exposure of the single transseptal big cryoballoon (CB) pulmonary vein isolation (PVI) procedures in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This is a prospective non-randomized case-control study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Forty-two patients (28 men, mean age 55.7 ± 12.1) with drug-refractory paroxysmal or persistent AF and underwent CB PVI procedures were divided into Group A (conventional single transseptal big CB approach, n = 21) and Group B (IMC-facilitated approach, n = 21) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>They were compared in the co-primary endpoints: (1) procedural duration and (2) fluoroscopic exposure and secondary endpoints: (1) 6-month AF-free survival and (2) number of cryo-applications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Both the procedural duration (162 ± 26 vs. 215 ± 25 min; p &lt; 0.001) and fluoroscopic exposure (44.1 ± 10.4 vs. 56.8 ± 11.7 min; p = 0.001) were significantly shorter in Group B than Group A patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>With multivariate stepwise regression, only the use of IMC was an independent predictor for procedural duration (β = -59; 95 % CI, -84.1 to -33.8; p &lt; 0.001) and fluoroscopic exposure (β = -16.9; 95 % CI, -28.4 to -5.4; p = 0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The number of cryo-applications was significantly fewer in Group B than Group A patients (median 8 vs. 11; p = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference in the 6-month AF-free survival between the two approaches (57 % vs. 71 %; p = 0.351) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Compared to conventional single transseptal big CB PVI procedures, the use of IMC may reduce procedural duration, fluoroscopic exposure and the number of cryo-applications with comparable mid-term efficacy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>