<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: The aim of the study was to investigate the resting levels of novel cardiovascular biomarkers in common types of noncardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>DESIGN AND SETTING: An observational study was conducted including 255 patients (mean age 60 years, range 15-93; 45% men) with unexplained syncopal attacks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Subjects underwent an expanded head-up tilt test including carotid sinus massage, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> provocation if indicated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Using logistic regression, we explored the associations between specific diagnoses of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> and resting levels of circulating biomarkers: C-terminal pro-arginine vasopressin (CT-proAVP), C-terminal endothelin-1 precursor fragment (CT-proET-1), midregional fragments of pro-atrial natriuretic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e>-proANP) and pro-adrenomedullin (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e>-proADM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 142 (56%) patients were diagnosed with vasovagal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo> (VVS), 85 (33%) with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001278'>orthostatic hypotension</z:hpo> <z:chebi fb="2" ids="29191">(OH)</z:chebi> and 47 (18%) with carotid sinus hypersensitivity (CSH); in addition, 74 (29%) patients had more than one diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Thirty-five patients (14%) demonstrated a cardioinhibitory reflex </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The probability of VVS was highest in the first quartile of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e>-proANP [Q1 vs. Q4: odds ratio (OR) 5.57, 95% confidence interval (CI) 1.86-16.74; P &lt; 0.001] and CT-proET-1 (OR 7.17, 95% CI 2.43-21.13; P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>By contrast, the probability of OH was highest in the fourth quartile of CT-proET-1 (Q4 vs. Q1: OR 8.66, 95% CI 2.49-30.17; P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, CSH was most frequently observed in the first quartile of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e>-proANP (Q1 vs. Q4: OR 6.57, 95% CI 1.62-26.62; P = 0.008) among those over 60 years of age, whereas the cardioinhibitory reflex was strongly associated with low CT-proET-1 levels (Q1 vs. Q4: OR 69.7, 95% CI 6.97-696.6; P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Moreover, in patients with VVS, a high concentration of CT-proET-1 was predictive of OH (OR per 1 SD 2.4, 95% CI 1.15-5.02; P = 0.02), whereas low CT-proET-1 suggested involvement of the cardioinhibitory reflex (OR per 1SD 0.42, 95% CI 0.25-0.70; P = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The levels of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e>-proANP and CT-proET-1 are markedly changed in common forms of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001279'>syncope</z:hpo>, suggesting the involvement of novel neurohormonal mechanisms in syncopal attacks </plain></SENT>
</text></document>