<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Tiotropium <z:chebi fb="25" ids="15858">bromide</z:chebi> is an effective therapy for COPD patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Comparing across programs tiotropium Respimat® Soft Mist™ inhaler was at least as efficacious as tiotropium HandiHaler®, however, concerns have been raised about tiotropium's safety when given via Respimat® </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The TIOSPIR® trial (NCT01126437) compares the safety and efficacy of tiotropium Respimat® 5 μg once daily (marketed) and 2.5 μg once daily (investigational) with tiotropium HandiHaler® 18 μ once daily (marketed) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The hypotheses to be tested are 1). that tiotropium Respimat® 5 μg once daily and Respimat® 2.5 μg once daily are non-inferior to HandiHaler® in terms of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause mortality, and 2). that tiotropium Respimat® 5 μg once daily is superior to HandiHaler® in terms of time to first exacerbation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A spirometry substudy evaluates the <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35523">bronchodilator</z:chebi> efficacy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The trial is a randomized, double-blind, double dummy, event-driven, parallel group study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Participants can use any background treatment for COPD except inhaled <z:chebi fb="0" ids="48873">anticholinergic agents</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The study encompasses a wide range of COPD patients, e.g. patients with stable <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018799" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiac diseases</z:e> including <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmia</z:hpo> can be included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Clinical sites are international and include both primary care as well as specialists </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: To date, over 17,000 participants have been randomized from over 1200 sites in 50 countries with an anticipated treatment duration of 2-3 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: TIOSPIR® will provide precise estimates of the relative safety and efficacy of the Respimat® and HandiHaler® formulations of tiotropium, assess potential dose-dependence of important outcomes and provide information on the clinical epidemiology of COPD in a large international patient cohort </plain></SENT>
</text></document>