<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To determine whether the detection of unrecognised <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (MI) using late <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33375">gadolinium</z:chebi>-enhanced (LGE)-magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) can provide prognostic information in diabetic patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> ECG as well as <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> global and regional left ventricular (LV) function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: From 449 diabetic patients who had complete cine- and LGE-MRI, 321 patients with histories of CAD, ischaemic ECG changes and abnormal cine MRI findings (LV ejection fraction &lt;50 % or presence of regional wall motion abnormality) were excluded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The presence and extent of LGE were determined in the remaining 128 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Follow-up information was obtained for the occurrence of major adverse cardiovascular events (MACE) defined as cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> MI, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo>, unstable <z:mp ids='MP_0006112'>angina</z:mp> and significant <z:hpo ids='HP_0004308'>ventricular arrhythmias</z:hpo> in 120 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of 120 patients, 18 (15 %) had LGE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>During follow-up (median, 27 months), six patients with LGE (33.3 %) and four patients without LGE (3.9 %) experienced MACE, resulting in an annualised event rate of 7.7 % and 0.9 %, respectively (log-rank P &lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The presence of LGE was associated with an eight-fold increased hazard for MACE (HR, 8.84; P = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: LGE-MRI can detect unrecognised MI and may improve the risk stratification of diabetic patients with no CAD history, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> ECG and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> LV systolic function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>KEY POINTS: • Late <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33375">gadolinium</z:chebi>-enhanced magnetic resonance imaging (LGE-MRI) can identify subtle myocardial abnormalities. • LGE-MRI can detect <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> missed by ECG and cine-MRI. • Unrecognised MI detected by LGE-MRI was associated with adverse cardiac events. • LGE-MRI helps clinicians to assess diabetic patients with unrecognised MI </plain></SENT>
</text></document>