<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AimsSeveral studies have reported a poor outcome with cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) in non-<z:hpo ids='HP_0011713'>left bundle branch block</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e>) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Although the left ventricular (LV) lead location is an important determinant of the clinical outcome, there is scant information regarding its role in non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study sought to examine the impact of electrical and anatomical location of the LV lead in relation to baseline QRS <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> on the CRT outcome.Methods and resultsA left ventricular lead electrical delay (LVLED) was measured intra-procedurally as an interval between QRS <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> on the surface electrocardiogram (ECG) to the peak of sensed electrogram on LV lead and corrected for QRS width </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The impact of the LVLED on time to first <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> hospitalization (HFH), and composite outcome of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause mortality, HFH, LVAD implantation, and cardiac transplantation at 3 years was assessed.Among 144 patients (age 67 ± 12 years, QRS duration 156 ± 28 ms, non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e> 43%), HFH was higher in non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e> compared with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e> (43.5 vs. 24%, P = 0.015) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Within <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e>, patients with the long LVLED (≥50%) had 17% HFH vs. 53% in the short LVLED (&lt;50%), P = 0.002 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Likewise in non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e>, patients with the long LVLED compared with the short LVLED had a lower HFH (36 vs. 61%, P = 0.026) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In adjusted Cox proportional hazards model, the long LVLED in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e> and non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e> was associated with an improved outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Specifically, in non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e>, LVLED ≥50% was associated with improved event-free survival with respect to time to first HFH (HR: 0.34; P = 0.011) and composite outcome (HR: 0.41; P = 0.019).ConclusionCardiac resynchronization therapy delivered from an LV pacing site characterized by the long LVLED was associated with the favourable outcome in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e> and non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LBBB</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>