<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: In this retrospective study we compared different lead extraction techniques.METHODS AND RESULTS: Between January 2009 and December 2012 we performed transvenous lead extraction procedures on 206 leads in 122 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Mean implant duration (MID) was 69.6 months (1-384 months) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Leads with lead implant duration ≥ 12 months were assigned to groups according to the extraction technique: Group A: no extraction tool; Group B: laser approach; and Group C: mechanical approach </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Overall clinical success was 93.3% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Group A showed a significantly lower MID [38.1 (19-122) months] compared with Groups B and C [83.1 (13-168) months; P &lt; 0.0001 vs. 95.4 (12-384) months; P &lt; 0.0001] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mean implant duration between Groups B and C did not differ significantly (P = 0.28) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Clinical and complete procedural success was 100% in Group A </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Clinical success rate was higher in Group C than in Group B (97.0 vs. 76.9%, P = 0.018) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Complete procedural success did not differ significantly between Groups B and C (88.9 vs. 76.9%; P = 0.132) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In Groups B and C, absence of complete procedural success occurred in long implanted leads (MID 107.8 ± 36.4 and 137.6 ± 89.2 months) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Relative costs per extracted lead were 49% higher in Group B than in Group C.CONCLUSION: In case of long implanted leads a laser and a mechanical approach are comparable in complete procedural success and safety </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Clinical success and cost effectiveness analysis favours the mechanical approach </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Regardless of the extraction technique efficacy and safety optimization has to focus on long implanted leads </plain></SENT>
</text></document>