<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>Atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) is one of the most common <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> observed in clinical practice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The frequency of AF is increased in patients with impaired interatrial conduction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We aimed to investigate whether tissue Doppler echocardiography could be used for the evaluation of atrial conduction characteristics instead of an electrophysiological study, and to examine the predictive accuracy of tissue Doppler echocardiography for the inducibility of sustained AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We enrolled 86 consecutive patients who underwent an electrophysiological study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We performed electrocardiographic P wave dispersion, M-mode, two-dimensional, Doppler, and tissue Doppler echocardiography as well as an electrophysiological study (EPS) to evaluate the intra- and interatrial conduction times </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We tried to induce AF, and the patients were categorized according to the inducibility of sustained (&gt; 120 s) AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: We found a good correlation between intra-left atrial conduction time detected by tissue Doppler echocardiography (ILCT-echo) and by EPS (ILCT-eps; r = 0.744, p &lt; 0.001), and a weak correlation between interatrial conduction times (IACT-echo and IACT-eps, r = 0.396, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In patients with inducible sustained AF, P wave dispersion (46 ± 19 ms vs. 27 ± 18, p &lt; 0.001), ILCT-echo (29 ± 10 ms vs. 17 ± 7 ms, p &lt; 0.001), and IACT-eps (47 ± 11 ms vs. 36 ± 13 ms, p &lt; 0.001) were found to be higher than those of the noninducible/nonsustained AF group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>These three parameters were independent predictors of the inducibility of sustained AF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: We demonstrated that ILCT-echo could be used instead of ILCT-eps for the evaluation of left atrial conduction characteristics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>We also showed that ILCT-eps could be a valuable parameter for predicting the development of long-lasting AF </plain></SENT>
</text></document>