<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>There is controversy regarding the impact of <z:hpo ids='HP_0006510'>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</z:hpo> (COPD) in clinical outcomes in elderly patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002090'>pneumonia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Comorbidities such Cardiovascular (CV) disease have been reported to play an important role in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> exacerbations of COPD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, limited data are available regarding the impact of CV disease in elderly COPD patients who required hospitalization for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002090'>pneumonia</z:hpo>.We examined a cohort of subjects with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002090'>pneumonia</z:hpo> and pre-existing COPD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Prior CV disease was defined as history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>congestive heart failure</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmia</z:hpo>, unstable <z:mp ids='MP_0006112'>angina</z:mp> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Outcomes examined included 30-day, 90-day, 6-month and 1-year mortality.We included 17,140 elderly COPD patients who were hospitalised for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002090'>pneumonia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Prior CV disease was present in 10,240 patients (59.7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Prior CV disease was independently associated with 90-day mortality (21.3% vs. 19.4%; Hazard Ratio [HR] 1.29, 95% confidence interval [CI] 1.02-1.17), 6-month mortality (29.0% vs. 26.1%; HR, 1.28, 95%CI 1.07-1.50) and at 12-month mortality (39.2% vs. 34.5%; HR, 1.33, 95%CI 1.15-1.54) when compared to no prior CV disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Temporal differential effect between groups increases from 1.0% at 30-days to 4.7% at 1-year.Prior CV disease is associated with increased long-term mortality in elderly COPD patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002090'>pneumonia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Differences in mortality rates increased over time </plain></SENT>
</text></document>