<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: Although rare, children and young adults can suffer from significant <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>cardiac arrhythmia</z:hpo>, especially in the context of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1705254" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">congenital malformations</z:e> and after cardiac surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 62 patients (32 female, median age 20 years) underwent an invasive electrophysiology study between 2008-2011: half had <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> cardiac <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>anatomy</z:mp>, whereas the remaining patients had various types of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002564'>congenital heart disease</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients were treated using either conventional techniques (CVN) or remote magnetic navigation (RMN) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients treated with the RMN system differed substantially from patients in the CVN group with respect to presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002564'>congenital heart disease</z:hpo> (67 % vs. 37 %), previous cardiac surgery (59 % vs. 20 %) or failed previous conventional ablation (22 % vs. 9 %), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Although these more complex <z:hpo ids='HP_0011675'>arrhythmias</z:hpo> resulted in longer median procedure duration (180 vs. 130 min, p = 0.034), the median overall fluoroscopy exposure in the RMN group was significantly lower (4.1 vs. 5.2 min, p = 0.020) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Clinical outcome was comparable in both groups without complications caused by the ablation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Catheter ablation using remote magnetic navigation is safe and feasible in children and young adults and is especially valuable in patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0000266'>abnormal cardiac morphologies</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RMN resulted in significantly lower radiation exposure compared with the conventional technique </plain></SENT>
</text></document>