<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>Oxidative stress</z:mp> is associated with Alzheimer's (DAT) and vascular (VD) <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementias</z:hpo>, as well as <z:hpo ids='HP_0005978'>Type II diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (DIAB) and affected by hypoglycemic therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The population (n = 122; males = 60; mean age = 72.57 +/- 7.06) consisted of controls (CTR), DAT and VD patients, with (DAT + DIAB, VD + DIAB) and without concomitant DIAB, resulting in six groups where the <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> profile was determined: copper-zinc <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase (SOD), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33202">thiobarbituric acid</z:chebi> reactive substances (TBARS), and total <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> capacity (TRAP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The results were analyzed using a two-way ANOVA design and Bonferroni statistic </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The ANOVAs yielded significant differences between groups for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> components of the profile: SOD, p = 0.00000006; TBARS, p = 0.0000012; TRAP, p = 0.0000003 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The significance level for comparisons between groups was set at alpha = 0.05 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The comparisons DIAB vs. CTR, DAT+DIAB vs. DAT, and DIAB <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0860630" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">demented</z:e> vs. DIAB non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0860630" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">demented</z:e> resulted significant for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> variables </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>VD + DIAB vs. VD resulted significant for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> variables except TRAP </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> profiles of DIAB and CTR are different </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The differences cannot be directly related with what is observed in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The differences in profiles of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0860630" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">demented</z:e> and non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0860630" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">demented</z:e> are somewhat hidden when <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0860630" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">demented</z:e> patients are affected by a concomitant DIAB condition and/or hypoglycemic treatment, thus conditioning the diagnostic value for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementias</z:hpo> of the profiles </plain></SENT>
</text></document>