<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: The magnetization transfer ratio (MTR) is a <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e>-based neuroimaging procedure aiming at the quantification of the structural integrity of brain tissue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Its contribution to the differential diagnosis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementias</z:hpo> was examined and discussed in relation to the pathogenesis of age-related <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: Sixty-one patients from a memory clinic were diagnosed by general physical and neuropsychiatric examination, and underwent neuropsychologic testing and neuroimaging using MRI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Their clinical diagnoses were based on standard operational research criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Additionally, the MTR in 10 defined regions of interest (ROI) was determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This investigation was performed using a T1-weighted SE sequence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Average MTR values were determined in the individual ROI and their combinations and correlated with the age, gender, <z:hpo ids='HP_0100543'>cognitive impairment</z:hpo> and clinical diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Sensitivity, specificity, positive and negative predictive value were determined, as well as the rate of correct classifications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: For cognitive healthy subjects, the MRT values correlate only mildly, though significantly, with age in the hippocampus and with gender in the dorsal corpus callosum </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the MTR in the frontal white matter correlates strongly and highly significantly with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100543'>cognitive impairment</z:hpo> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The differential diagnostic assignment of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="SDAT">Alzheimer's disease</z:e> versus vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> by MTR provides a correct classification of approximately 50 % to 70 % </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="53261">PPV</z:chebi> for no <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> vs. vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> or the NPV for vascular vs. <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="SDAT">Alzheimer's disease</z:e> are considerably higher exceeding 80 % </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>For no <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> vs. <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="SDAT">Alzheimer's disease</z:e>, the NPV was over 90 % </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: MTR values indicate functional changes in the brain tissue between cognitive healthy and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0860630" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">demented</z:e> patients, and correlate with the cognitive loss, but not with age and gender </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>In principle, the MTR is suitable for the diagnosis of age-related <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementias</z:hpo>, but does not contribute substantially to the differential diagnosis of vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> vs. <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="SDAT">Alzheimer's disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>The present results support the assumption of a synergy between vascular and degenerative components of age-related <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementias</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>