<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To determine the relationships between <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1096584" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Chlamydia pneumoniae infection</z:e>, carotid <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo>, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e> in patients with vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> (VaD) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="SDAT">Alzheimer's disease</z:e> (AD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>DESIGN: Case control study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>SETTING: Showa University Karasuyama Hospital, Tokyo, Japan </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>PARTICIPANTS: One hundred twenty-four elderly subjects: 31 with VaD, 61 with AD, and 32 age-matched controls without <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>MEASUREMENTS: Presence of antibodies to C. pneumoniae (immunoglobulin G (IgG) and IgA), the serum concentrations of high-sensitive C-reactive protein (hs-CRP) and atherogenic <z:chebi fb="2" ids="6495">lipoproteins</z:chebi>, and the carotid artery intima-media thickness (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e>) and plaques were determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Age; body mass index; systolic and diastolic blood pressures; and fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> A(1c), <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47775">high-density lipoprotein cholesterol</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> A-I, B, and E concentrations did not differ significantly between the three groups, but the mean <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e> and frequency of atherosclerotic plaques in the carotid arteries, as well as the serum concentrations of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47774">low-density lipoprotein cholesterol</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="47774">LDL-C</z:chebi>), <z:chebi fb="1" ids="6495">lipoprotein</z:chebi>(a), and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="39" ids="44785">peroxides</z:chebi> were significantly greater in VaD patients than in AD patients or nondemented controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Hs-CRP concentrations and prevalence of C. pneumoniae IgG and IgA antibodies also were significantly higher in VaD patients than in AD patients and nondemented controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Multiple logistic regression analysis revealed that carotid <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e> and plaques, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="47774">LDL-C</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="39" ids="44785">peroxides</z:chebi>, hs-CRP, and IgG and IgA C. pneumoniae seropositivity were independent risk factors for VaD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: These results suggest that carotid <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo>, atherogenic <z:chebi fb="2" ids="6495">lipoproteins</z:chebi>, and C. pneumoniae <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> (as documented by the IgG and IgA seropositivity together with increased hs-CRP) may be VaD risk factors </plain></SENT>
</text></document>