<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVE: There are currently no drugs approved to treat vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> (VaD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to determine if treatment with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53289,53290,53292">donepezil</z:chebi>, an <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38462">acetylcholinesterase inhibitor</z:chebi>, may provide benefit for VaD patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Combined analysis of 2 identical randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, 24-week studies involving 1,219 patients enrolled at 109 investigational sites in the USA, Europe, Canada and Australia </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients were randomized to receive <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53289,53290,53292">donepezil</z:chebi> 5 mg/day (n = 406) or 10 mg/day (after brief titration; n = 421) or placebo (n = 392) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients were assessed on cognition [<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="SDAT">Alzheimer's Disease</z:e> Assessment Scale-cognitive subscale (ADAS-cog), Mini-Mental State Examination (MMSE)], global function [Clinician's Interview-Based Impression of Change plus (CIBIC-plus), Clinical <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>Dementia</z:hpo> Rating-Sum of the Boxes (CDR-SB)] and function [<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="SDAT">Alzheimer's Disease</z:e> Functional Assessment and Change Scale (ADFACS); instrumental activities of daily living (ADFACS-IADL)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Both <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53289,53290,53292">donepezil</z:chebi> groups showed significant improvements in cognition compared with placebo (ADAS-cog, MMSE, p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Significant global function benefits were seen on the CIBIC-plus in the 5 mg/day group (placebo vs. 5 mg/day, p &lt; 0.001; vs. 10 mg/day, p = 0.006) and on the CDR-SB in the 10 mg/day group (placebo vs. 5 mg/day, p = 0.09; vs. 10 mg/day, p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Significant functional benefits were also seen (ADFACS, placebo vs. 5 mg/day, p = 0.08; vs. 10 mg/day, p = 0.02; ADFACS-IADL, p &lt; 0.05 for both <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53289,53290,53292">donepezil</z:chebi> groups) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="53289,53290,53292">Donepezil</z:chebi> was well tolerated, with low withdrawal rates due to adverse events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This combined analysis of the largest trial on VaD to date showed that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53289,53290,53292">donepezil</z:chebi>-treated patients had significant benefits in cognition, global function and ability to perform IADL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Based on these findings and reported tolerability, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53289,53290,53292">donepezil</z:chebi> should be considered as an important therapeutic element in the overall management of patients with VaD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>