<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Previous studies have demonstrated that Z-Ligustilide (LIG), a characterized phthalide constituent present in numerous medical Umbelliferae plants, has significant neuroprotective effects in transient forebrain <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and permanent cerebral focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The present study further investigated the effect of LIG on <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1695782" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral hypoperfusion</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Male Wistar rats were subjected to permanent ligation of both common carotid arteries (2VO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>On Days 8-12 postsurgery, rat cognition was assessed in the <z:mp ids='MP_0001465'>Morris water maze</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Rats with significantly impaired acquisition of spatial information were randomly allocated to three groups and orally administered LIG (10 or 40 mg/kg/day) or volume-matched vehicle on Days 13-40 post-2VO surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The sham-operated group served as controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>After long-term treatment with LIG, the impaired animals' behavioral, biochemical, and histopathological features were examined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Compared to the sham-operated group, significant <z:hpo ids='HP_0100543'>cognitive impairment</z:hpo> was observed in the vehicle-treated group 40 days after 2VO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Shortened mean escape latency was detected in the <z:mp ids='MP_0001465'>Morris water maze</z:mp> in rats treated with LIG (p&lt;0.01 vs. vehicle-treated group) during the same trial days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>Chronic</z:hpo> 2VO-induced pathological changes included <z:hpo ids='HP_0002529'>neuronal loss</z:hpo> and an increase of glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP)-immunoreactive astrocytes in the hippocampus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>These effects were prevented with LIG treatment (p&lt;0.01 vs. vehicle-treated group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>LIG also significantly reduced malondialdehyde levels and increased <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase activity in ischemic brain tissue (p&lt;0.05 and p&lt;0.01 vs. vehicle-treated group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In addition, LIG significantly increased <z:chebi fb="3" ids="15354">choline</z:chebi> acetyltransferase activity and inhibited acetylcholinesterase activity in ischemic brain tissues (p&lt;0.05 and p&lt;0.01 vs. vehicle-treated group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The present data demonstrate that LIG significantly prevented chronically hypoperfused <z:hpo ids='HP_0100543'>cognitive deficits</z:hpo> and brain damage at least partly through an <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> effect and improved cholinergic activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>The present findings suggest that LIG may have therapeutic potential in treating vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0241832" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebrovascular insufficiency</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>