<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Our earlier study demonstrated that Coeloglossum viride (L.) Hartm. var. bracteatum (Willd.) extract (CE) significantly improved the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0233794" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">impaired memory</z:e> in mice caused by permanent two-vessel occlusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To investigate whether <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> treatment with CE could influence <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>-induced neuronal and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100543'>cognitive impairments</z:hpo>, we examined the effects of CE on two different kinds of cerebral injury: transient middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> model of focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>; four-vessel occlusion model of transient global forebrain <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>CE treatment (5 mg/kg, orally) significantly reduced lesion volume, and improved the performance of passive avoidance and rotarod motor tasks in transient middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the four-vessel occlusion model, neuronal cell loss in CA1 of hippocampus was significantly decreased and the performance in the <z:mp ids='MP_0001465'>Morris water maze</z:mp> was significantly improved in rats administered CE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We conclude that treatment with CE attenuated learning and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0233794" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">memory deficits</z:e>, motor functional disability, and neuronal cell loss induced by global or focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>These results suggest that CE may be a potential candidate for the treatment of vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>