<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND/AIMS: To evaluate the ApoE gene polymorphism among patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> from southern India </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Persons with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> attending a geriatric clinic in a hospital setting located in southern India and matched controls were recruited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> subjects were evaluated on standard assessments and were diagnosed according to the <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>-10; genotyping was done at the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> E (ApoE) locus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The study comprised 212 cases and 195 controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The ApoE4 allele was significantly more prevalent in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> (λ = 0.18 vs. λ = 0.07; p = 0.0018), especially in the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="SDAT">Alzheimer's disease</z:e> subgroup (n = 137; λ = 0.21 vs. λ = 0.07; p &lt; 0.001), with a trend in vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> subtype (n = 31; λ = 0.17 vs. λ = 0.07) in comparison with the control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>ApoE4 carrier status did not differ between the other <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> group (n = 44) and controls (p &gt; 0.20), or between the Alzheimer's group and vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Cognitive and functional deficits were not correlated to the presence ApoE4 polymorphism in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The study confirmed the positive association of the ApoE4 polymorphism in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo>, both in the Alzheimer's and vascular etiology subgroups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Influence of this polymorphism on various clinical phenotypes, including extent of cognitive and functional deficits, needs further evaluation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>