<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Small vessel disease (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVD</z:e>) is a frequent cause of vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0100543'>cognitive impairment</z:hpo> (VCI), encompassing vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVD</z:e> is characterised by vasculopathy in deep penetrating arteries, diffuse white matter lesions (seen radiologically as leukoaraiosis) and focal, lacunar <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Risk factors are age and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> but the pathogenic mechanism is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Recent systematic reviews assessed experimental models of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVD</z:e> or VCI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Chronically hypertensive animals (e.g. <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>-prone spontaneously hypertensive rats) display some features of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVD</z:e> vasculopathy, such as vessel wall thickening </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>White matter lesions are seen in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> hypoperfusion states (e.g. carotid occlusion/stenosis models) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Small focal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> are induced by targeted ischemic challenge (surgical occlusion of a small artery, or stereotaxic endothelin-1 injection) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Some degree of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100543'>cognitive impairment</z:hpo> is detectable in most cerebrovascular models, probably reflecting the broad neuroanatomical mapping of cognitive function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Important confounds to be considered in animal models of VCI are somatosensory impairment and hippocampal damage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Advances in clinical understanding will come from targeting specific questions on some aspect of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVD</z:e> (e.g. vasculopathy, white matter damage) to the appropriate model in vivo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In vivo models of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SVD</z:e> are likely to benefit experimental studies of pathological processes, interactions with other brain <z:mp ids='MP_0002054'>disease states</z:mp> (such as <z:hpo ids='HP_0002511'>Alzheimer disease</z:hpo>), and therapeutic strategies </plain></SENT>
</text></document>