<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Some CSF protein abnormalities have been proposed as a possible marker for vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We studied the CSF protein levels and albumin ratio in 21 patients (mean age 64.04 +/- 7.5) with progressive bilateral motor impairment, and a CT picture of leucoaraiosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Seven of these patients also presented with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Twenty-seven <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="SDAT">Alzheimer's disease</z:e> patients (mean age 59.59 +/- 5.30) without leucoaraiosis were taken as controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We also evaluated the correlations of the albumin ratio values with the diagnosis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo>, the severity of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100543'>cognitive impairment</z:hpo>, the degree of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002059'>cerebral atrophy</z:hpo> and presence of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> on CT, and the abnormalities in CSF circulation, found on isotopic cisternography, in the leucoaraiosis group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After controlling for age and sex, the patients with leucoaraiosis showed greater CSF albumin levels (0.27 g/l +/- 0.11 vs. 0.21 g/l +/- 0.06; covariance analysis P = 0.066), CSF IgG values (4.68 mg/100 ml +/- 1.45 vs. 2.85 mg/100 ml +/- 1.03; covariance analysis P &lt; 0.001), and a higher albumin ratio (0.0078 +/- 0.0027 vs. 0.0058 +/- 0.0019; covariance analysis P = 0.013) than those with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002395" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="SDAT">Alzheimer's disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The variations of these parameters were not apparently related to the presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> in the leucoaraiosis group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A significantly higher albumin ratio was observed in patients with a slowed CSF circulation compared to those with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> CSF circulation (0.0086 +/- 0.0028 vs. 0.0059 +/- 0.0019; covariance analysis P = 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We conclude that, independently from the presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo>, patients with leucoaraiosis have CSF abnormalities consistent with functional blood-brain barrier alterations </plain></SENT>
</text></document>