<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The neuropathology of <z:mp ids='MP_0005279'>narcolepsy</z:mp> is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Recently, Plazzi et al </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>(1) reported magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) abnormalities in the pontine tegmentum of three patients with long-standing idiopathic <z:mp ids='MP_0005279'>narcolepsy</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Considering the localization of the neuroradiological findings in the pontine reticular formation, where rapid eye movement (REM) sleep is generated, the authors suggested a causal relationship between <z:mp ids='MP_0005279'>narcolepsy</z:mp> and MRI abnormalities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Frey and Heiserman, however, found pontine MRI abnormalities in only two of 12 patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0005279'>narcolepsy</z:mp> both of whom had long-standing <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Pullicino et al. noted similar pontine MRI abnormalities in patients with subcortical arteriosclerotic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001298'>encephalopathy</z:hpo>-like ischemic rarefaction of the pons (3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Thus, the changes noted by Plazzi et al. may have been caused by small-vessel disease rather than <z:mp ids='MP_0005279'>narcolepsy</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>To assess whether altered pontine MRI signals are a regular feature of idiopathic <z:mp ids='MP_0005279'>narcolepsy</z:mp>, we selected randomly from our database seven patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0005279'>narcolepsy</z:mp> with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002524'>cataplexy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Of these seven, three agreed to have brain MRIs; their cases are described below </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>None had pontine MRI abnormalities </plain></SENT>
</text></document>