<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> E (APOE) epsilon4 allele is a risk factor in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002511'>Alzheimer disease</z:hpo> (AD), but not in vascular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> (VaD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We have investigated whether the epsilon4 allele is more common in twin pairs concordant for AD, compared with those discordant for AD, and whether the epsilon4 allele is more common in AD twins than in VaD twins </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In addition, we have investigated the relationship of the epsilon4 allele and the age at <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> in AD and VaD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>APOE genotype was analysed in 29 senile <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0860630" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">demented</z:e> twin pairs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The epsilon4 allele was associated with AD and not with VaD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, there was no difference in the frequency of the APOE epsilon4 allele in concordant (33.3%) and discordant (31.3%) AD dizygotic twin pairs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Age at <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> in AD was significantly lower in epsilon4 homozygotes than in individuals with one or no copies of epsilon4 (62.4 vs. 73.5, p&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In concordant AD twin pairs, the epsilon4 allele frequency was somewhat higher in the twins with earlier <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> (41.7% vs. 25%), but the difference was not statistically significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the VaD group the age at <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> was not significantly different between individuals with or without epsilon4 in their genotypes </plain></SENT>
</text></document>