<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: An <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> perfusion-diffusion mismatch is known to be the strongest predictor of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> growth </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, the differential patterns of clinical and radiological evolution according to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> mechanism are unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The study retrospectively reviewed consecutive patients who had 1) <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> middle cerebral artery (<z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>) territory infarction, 2) diffusion- and perfusion-weighted imaging (DWI and PWI) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e> angiography within 24 h of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo>, and follow-up DWI 5 days later, 3) stenosis (&gt; or =50%) or occlusion of <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> on baseline imaging, 4) a baseline PWI-DWI mismatch &gt;20%, and 5) either atherosclerotic <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> disease (MCAD) or cardioembolism (CE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>National Institutes of Health <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo> Scale (NIHSS) scores and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume at baseline and 5 days were obtained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of 90 patients, 52 had MCAD and 38 had CE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>At baseline, CE group had more severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> (median NIHSS, 9 vs. 5; p=0.001) and larger <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume (median 8.32 cc vs. 3.0 cc; p=0.034) than MCAD group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>During the 1-week period, CE group had larger <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume growth (median 12.85 cc vs. 3.02 cc; p=0.004) than MCAD group, although clinical improvement based on NIHSS (baseline minus 5-day) tended to be higher for CE than MCAD group (median 3 vs. 1; p=0.08) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The correlation between <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume and NIHSS score was stronger in CE (r=0.841) compared to MCAD (r=0.582) group at 5-day </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Substantial differences in the clinico-radiological evolution of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> exist according to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> mechanism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These data emphasize the importance of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> mechanism in the design of MRI-based <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> trials </plain></SENT>
</text></document>