<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Decompressive hemicraniectomy (DHC) has proven efficacious for the treatment of malignant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0740392" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">middle cerebral artery infarction</z:e> (mMCAI) only in patients less than 60 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to assess the effectiveness of DHC in patients up to 80 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This is a prospective, randomized, controlled trail comparing the outcomes with or without DHC in patients aged 18-80 with mMCAI (ChiCTR-TRC-11001757) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The primary outcome measure was the modified Rankin Scale (mRS) scores at 6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The secondary outcome measures included the 6- and 12-month mortality and the mRS scores after 1 year </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The prognosis of patients was evaluated independently by two blinded investigators </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In addition, subgroup analyses were done for those above 60 years of age </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> analyses were by intention-to-treat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A significant reduction in the poor outcome (mRS &gt; 4) following DHC was reached after 36 patients had completed the follow-up period of 6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The trial was then terminated when 47 participants (24 in the surgical group vs. 23 in the medical group) had been recruited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The final analysis, based on the outcome data of the 47 patients, showed that DHC significantly reduced mortality at 6 and 12 months (12.5 vs. 60.9 %, P = 0.001 and 16.7 vs. 69.6 %, P &lt; 0.001, respectively), and significantly fewer patients had a mRS score &gt;4 after surgery (33.3 vs. 82.6 %, P = 0.001 and 25.0 vs. 87.0 %, P &lt; 0.001, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Similar results were present in the subgroup analyses of elderly participants CONCLUSIONS: For patients up to 80 years who suffered mMCAI, DHC within 48 h of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> not only is a life-saving treatment, but also increases the possibility of surviving without severe disability (mRS = 5) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>