<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Cryopyrin-associated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0585274" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">periodic syndrome</z:e> (CAPS), a rare hereditary auto-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C1290884" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory disease</z:e>, is associated with mutations in the NLRP3 gene resulting in elevated interleukin-1β (IL-1 β) release </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>CAPS generally occurs in early childhood with most patients presenting with periodic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000988'>skin rash</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0263661" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">osteoarthropathy</z:e>, aseptic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001287'>meningitis</z:hpo>, <z:mp ids='MP_0004740'>sensorineural hearing loss</z:mp> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100653'>optic neuritis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Canakinumab, a fully human anti-IL-1β monoclonal antibody which binds selectively to IL-1β, has demonstrated good efficacy with CAPS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>This is the first study to evaluate the safety and efficacy of canakinumab in Japanese patients with CAPS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In this open-label study, 19 Japanese CAPS patients aged ≥2 years received canakinumab either 150 mg s.c. or 2 mg/kg for patients with a body weight ≤ 40 kg every 8 weeks for 24 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The primary objective was to assess the proportion of patients who were free of relapse at week 24 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A complete response was achieved in 18 (94.7%) patients with some requiring a dose and/or a frequency adjustment to attain full clinical response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The majority of patients (14/18; 77.8%) were in remission, i.e. free of relapse at week 24 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Auto-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C1290884" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory disease</z:e> activity as assessed by physician's global assessment declined from baseline to end of the study (score of absent in 10.5% at baseline versus 31.6% at end of the study) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Two patients had serious adverse events (SAEs), which resolved with standard treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>One patient reported a mild injection-site reaction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>No <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancies</z:e> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> were reported during the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Canakinumab 150 mg s.c. every 8 weeks was well-tolerated, highly efficacious and offered a convenient dosing regimen for treating Japanese patients with CAPS </plain></SENT>
</text></document>