<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="15414">S-adenosyl-L-methionine</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="15414">SAMe</z:chebi>) has been shown to increase hepatocyte membrane fluidity thereby relieving signs of <z:chebi fb="67" ids="50114">oestrogen</z:chebi>-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001396'>cholestasis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="15414">S-adenosyl-L-methionine</z:chebi> might therefore prove effective in improving the efficiency of the transport of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25696">organic anions</z:chebi> such as <z:chebi fb="5" ids="15940">nicotinic acid</z:chebi> (NA) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16990">bilirubin</z:chebi> which is impaired in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017551" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Gilbert's syndrome</z:e> (GS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In this study the effects on the metabolization rate of NA and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16990">bilirubin</z:chebi> of two dosages of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15414">SAMe</z:chebi> were evaluated in respect to placebo in ten male inpatients (mean age 24 years, range 16-31) with GS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Each patient received both <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15414">SAMe</z:chebi> (800 and 200 mg/day, respectively) and placebo treatment i.v. over a period of 10 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The NA test (5.9 mumol/kg b.w. i.v.) was carried out in the same volunteers after each treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Unconjugated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16990">bilirubin</z:chebi> (UCB) levels were significantly lower (p less than 0.01) after 800 mg/day <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15414">SAMe</z:chebi> than after placebo while the lower dosage of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15414">SAMe</z:chebi> did not affect UCB values </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16990">bilirubin</z:chebi> time curve concentration, expressed as area under the curve (AUC), was significantly reduced (p less than 0.01) after 800 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15414">SAMe</z:chebi> in comparison with the values obtained after placebo and 200 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15414">SAMe</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Also plasma NA half-life was significantly reduced (p less than 0.01) by the higher dose of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15414">SAMe</z:chebi> in respect to placebo and not by the lower dose </plain></SENT>
</text></document>