<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>172 adolescent and adult patients with low grade nonhemolytic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0268306" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">unconjugated hyperbilirubinaemia</z:e> (n.u.h) were examined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Authors have come to the conclusion of the absence of an acquired (posthepatic) form of n.u.h., i.e of the existence of a single --constitutional--form (<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017551" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Gilbert's disease</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0006562'>Viral hepatitis</z:hpo> is not likely to play the role of an etiological factor of n.u.h. but of a factor which manifests a congenital defect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16990">bilirubin</z:chebi> metabolism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The study of the glucuronidisation found out that its decrease is an important factor in the pathogenesis of the low grade n.u.h. that therefore cannot opposed to the n.u.h. with glucuronyl transferase deficiency group II according to Arias et al </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In 61% of patients a moderately shortened erythrocyte life span has been revealed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However the increased bile pigment production in these cases does not speak against <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017551" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Gilbert's disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The results of biochemical assays have shown that in n.u.h not only the intrahepatic <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16990">bilirubin</z:chebi> metabolism is disturbed but other functions of the liver cell as well </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The morphological study of hepatocytes has revealed certain signs of their <z:mpath ids='MPATH_554'>dystrophy</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Based on their investigation the authors propose to single out a group of hereditary pigment hepatoses which include besides <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017551" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Gilbert's disease</z:e> the syndromes of Crigler-Najjar, Dubin-Johnson and Rotor </plain></SENT>
</text></document>