<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The aetiology of <z:hpo ids='HP_0010534'>transient global amnesia</z:hpo> (<z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp>) is still unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to identify potential risk factors for <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp>, vascular risk factors, the role of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001655'>patent foramen ovale</z:hpo> (<z:mp ids='MP_0004225'>PFO</z:mp>) and of retrograde jugular venous flow </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: 138 subjects entered the study, including 48 patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp>, 42 age-matched patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007787" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="tia|TIA|T.I.A.">transient ischaemic attack</z:e> (<z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>TIA</z:hpo>) and 48 controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0004225'>PFO</z:mp> was studied by contrast transcranial duplex sonography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Retrograde jugular venous flow was tested with air contrast ultrasound venography (ACUV) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients and controls showed a lower prevalence for vascular risk factors than <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>TIA</z:hpo> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>No statistical difference was found between the 3 groups with regard to <z:mp ids='MP_0004225'>PFO</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>ACUV detected jugular valve incompetence in 72.9% <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp>, 35.7% <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>TIA</z:hpo> and 39.5% controls (<z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> vs. <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>TIA</z:hpo> and <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> vs. controls p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients have fewer vascular risk factors than <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>TIA</z:hpo> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0238096" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Paradoxical embolism</z:e> due to <z:mp ids='MP_0004225'>PFO</z:mp> as a cause of <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> is not confirmed in our study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Cerebral venous <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> due to incompetence of the internal jugular valve may play a role in the pathogenesis of <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>