<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND/AIMS: Different etiologies for <z:hpo ids='HP_0010534'>transient global amnesia</z:hpo> (<z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp>) have been proposed, such as venous flow abnormalities, spreading <z:hpo ids='HP_0000716'>depression</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002076'>migraine</z:hpo>-related mechanisms like focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Jugular vein valve incompetence (JVI) is commonly described in <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients, but its contributing role in <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> pathogenesis is still unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We investigated the possible relationship between JVI and pathogenetic mechanisms in <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: 243 <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients underwent clinical and neurological assessment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Demographic characteristics, <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp>-precipitating factors and vascular comorbidities were carefully recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In each patient, JVI was assessed by Doppler ultrasonography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients were grouped according to the presence (n = 171, 70.4%) or absence (n = 72, 29.6%) of JVI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients with JVI showed a higher presence of precipitating factors, namely a Valsalva-like maneuver (JVI-positive vs. JVI-negative, 35.8 vs. 17.1%, p = 0.004) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0086209" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">emotional stress</z:e> (36.6 vs. 21.4%, p = 0.023), but had fewer vascular comorbidities, namely <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (37.2 vs. 51.4%, p = 0.047) and carotid <z:hpo ids='HP_0002634'>arteriosclerosis</z:hpo> (20.5 vs. 31.9%, p = 0.050) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These findings support the argument for the existence of at least 2 different <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp>-associated mechanisms defined by JVI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>On the one hand, JVI associated with a Valsalva-like maneuver and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0086209" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">emotional stress</z:e> supported the venous blood <z:mpath ids='MPATH_107'>congestion</z:mpath> hypothesis, and on the other, the JVI-negative group may have another vascular basis, unrelated to venous <z:mpath ids='MPATH_107'>congestion</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>