<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND/AIM: <z:hpo ids='HP_0010534'>Transient global amnesia</z:hpo> (<z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp>) could be related to <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> ischemic disturbances in mesial parts of temporal lobes, which are important for memory </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Incompetence of internal jugular vein (IJV) valve with venous <z:mpath ids='MPATH_107'>congestion</z:mpath> causes venous microthrombosis of hippocampus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to investigate the frequency of IJV valve incompetence, as well as other hemodynamic and structural properties of cerebral circulation in <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: IJV valve competence was investigated in 40 <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients and 30 persons of the control group (matched by age and sex), as well as detection of microembolic signals and detection of right to left cardiopulmonal shunt, cerebral vasomotor reactivity and echocardiography by color triplex ultrasonography and transcranial doppler </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A significant difference in frequency of IJV valve incompetence was found between the <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients and the control persons (55% <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> vs. 30% controls; p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We did not find a significant structural (plaques frequency) or hemodynamic (flow velocity, pulsatility index) differences on arteries of the neck and cerebral arteries between the <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients and the controls, except for the increased pulsatility index on the basilar artery (40% <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> vs. 16.6% controls; p &lt; 0.01) and decreased vasomotor reactivity in <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients (50% <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> vs 26.6% controls;p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Microembolic signals were detected very rarely (17.5% <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients vs. 13.3% controls; p &gt; 0.05), as well as right to left cardiopulmonal shunt (15% <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> vs. 16.6% controls; p &gt; 0.05), indicating that embolism was not important for pathogenesis of <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Transesophageal echocardiography confirmed it, because only one <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patient had a potent foramen ovale </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: We found a significantly increased frequency of IJV incompetence in the <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> patients, which confirmed the role of vein drainage disturbances in pathogenesis of <z:mp ids='MP_0004110'>TGA</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>