<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Non-Hodgkin <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> (NHL) represent an important complication of primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002721'>immunodeficiency</z:hpo> (ID), posing new therapeutic challenges in this patient population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study analyzes clinical data and therapy results of pediatric patients with primary ID and NHL in three consecutive NHL-BFM trials </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>PROCEDURE: Retrospective analysis of children with primary ID and NHL, treated according to protocol NHL-BFM, was performed regarding clinical presentation, diagnostic features, therapy, and outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: From October, 1986, to April, 1997, 19 of 1,413 newly diagnosed patients with NHL were registered as suffering from primary ID </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Age at diagnosis of NHL was lower in patients with ID </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Six patients suffered from humoral ID, 13 patients from combined ID (<z:hpo ids='HP_0001251'>ataxia</z:hpo> teleangiectasia n = 3; <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0398791" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Nijmegen breakage syndrome</z:e> n = 4; <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0268125" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">PNP deficiency</z:e> n = 1; IL2 receptor defect n = 1, other combined ID n = 4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Thirteen <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> were of B-cell and six of T-cell-lineage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Four of thirteen patients with combined ID were diagnosed with T-NHL, nine with B-NHL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Two of six patients with humoral ID presented with T-NHL and four with B-NHL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>NHL entities differed significantly between ID and non-ID patients (P &lt; or = 0.01): <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1516391" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">centroblastic</z:e> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1521815" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">immunoblastic</z:e> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> (31.6% vs. 8.1%), anaplastic large cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (26.3% vs. 10.7%), Burkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0023435" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">B-ALL</z:e> (21% vs. 47 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>8%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Seventeen patients received polychemotherapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Therapy-related toxicity was increased in ID- compared to non-ID-patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Three patients died of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100806'>sepsis</z:hpo>; three died of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0178874" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor progression</z:e>; one patient relapsed; one died of BMT-related toxicity; one died of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085183" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">second malignancy</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Ten patients are in first continuous remission after a median follow-up of 4 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Curative treatment of NHL in the presence of primary ID is possible and should be attempted </plain></SENT>
</text></document>