<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>L-asparaginase (EC 3.5.1.1) was purified to homogeneity from Thermus thermophilus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The apparent molecular mass of L-asparaginase was found to be 33 kDa by <z:chebi fb="26" ids="8984">SDS</z:chebi>-PAGE, whereas by Sephacryl S-300 superfine column it was found to be 200 kDa, indicating that the enzyme in the native stage acts as hexamer </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>It is a thermostable enzyme and keeps <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> of its activity at 80 degrees C for 10 min </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The antiproliferative activity of the purified L-asparaginase from T. thermiphilus was tested against the following human cell lines: K-562 (<z:hpo ids='HP_0005506'>chronic myelogenous leukemia</z:hpo>), Raji (Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>), SK-N-MC (<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0279980,C0206663" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primitive neuroectodermal tumor</z:e>), HeLa (<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302592" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cervical cancer</z:e>), BT20 and MCF7 (<z:hpo ids='HP_0003002'>breast cancers</z:hpo>), HT-29 (human <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo>), and OAW-42 (<z:e sem="disease" ids="C1140680" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">ovarian cancer</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The antiproliferative activity of T. thermophilus enzyme was compared with Erwinase, the commercially available L-asparaginase from Erwinia corotovora </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The potency difference between the two L-asparaginases was greater in HeLa and SK-N-MC than in other cell lines </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The fact that L-asparaginase from T. thermophilus does not hydrolyse <z:chebi fb="0" ids="18050,30011">L-glutamine</z:chebi> makes it advantageous for future clinical trials </plain></SENT>
</text></document>