<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>FMNL (NM_005892.2) is a 5'-truncated partial cDNA encoding a Formin-homology protein related to DAAM1, DAAM2, DIAPH1 and DIAPH2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Here, we identified three members of FMNL gene family in the human genome by using bioinformatics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>FMNL1 gene, corresponding to 5'-truncated KW-13 and FMNL cDNAs, was located within reference genomic contig NT_010748.9 (nucleotide position 100576-125849, forward orientation) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>FMNL2 gene, corresponding to KIAA1902 and FHOD2 cDNAs, was located within NT_005151.10 (nucleotide position 122465-436828, forward orientation) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>FMNL3 gene, corresponding to 5'-truncated DKFZp762B245 and KIAA2014 cDNAs, was located within NT_026397.10 (nucleotide position 209769-279037, reverse orientation) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>FMNL1, FMNL2 and FMNL3 genes encode A and B isoforms with the C-terminal divergence due to alternative splicing (cassette splicing of exon 26) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>FMNL1A (1100 aa), FMNL1B (1114 aa), FMNL2A (1087 aa), FMNL2B (1093 aa), FMNL3A (1028 aa) and FMNL3B (1027 aa) consist of FDD, FH1 and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50314">FH2</z:chebi> domains </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Total amino-acid identity were as follows: FMNL1A vs. FMNL2A, 59.3%; FMNL1A vs. FMNL3A, 56.1%; FMNL2A vs. FMNL3A, 68.6% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>FMNL1 gene was mapped to human chromosome 17q21 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>FMNL2 gene was linked to FNBP3/HYPA gene on chromosome 2q23.3, while FMNL3 gene was linked to FNBP3L/HYPC gene on chromosome 12q13 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>FMNL1 <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> was expressed in natural killer cells, Burkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002894'>pancreatic cancer</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0012125'>prostate cancer</z:hpo>, and <z:mp ids='MP_0008718'>lung large cell carcinoma</z:mp>, FMNL2 <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> in several <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> tissues, diffuse-type <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003002'>breast cancer</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0006765'>chondrosarcoma</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002861'>melanoma</z:hpo>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100843'>glioblastoma</z:hpo>, and FMNL3 <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>FMNL1, FMNL2 and FMNL3 might be implicated in polarity control, invasion, migration, or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> through regulation of the Rho-related signaling pathway </plain></SENT>
</text></document>