<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Human Burkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (Daudi) cells grow as disseminated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> in mice with severe combined <z:hpo ids='HP_0002721'>immune deficiency</z:hpo> (<z:mp ids='MP_0002536'>SCID</z:mp>) after either i.v. or i.p. injection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>These cells are lysed in vitro by human V gamma 9/V delta 2 T-cells that recognize the groEL homologue on the Daudi cell surface </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We report that both Daudi cell-stimulated peripheral blood mononuclear cells (Daudi-PBMC) containing 41-95% of V gamma 9/V delta 2 T-cells and V gamma 9/V delta 2 T-cell clones prolong the survival of <z:mp ids='MP_0002536'>SCID</z:mp> mice given inoculations of a lethal dose of Daudi cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Groups of 6-8-week-old <z:mp ids='MP_0002536'>SCID</z:mp> mice were given inoculations i.v. or i.p. of 10(5) Daudi cells followed (through different injection sites) by: (a) 10(7) Daudi-PBMC; or (b) 10(7) unstimulated PBMC; or (c) 0.9% saline solution </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> animals in groups (b) and (c) died of disseminated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, and their survival was significantly shorter than that of mice in group (a) (P &lt; 0.001 for both i.v. and i.p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>routes) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Significant antitumor effects were also detected when Daudi-PBMC were injected 4 days before or 4 days after Daudi cells (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In vivo <z:mpath ids='MPATH_63'>depletion</z:mpath> of murine natural killer cells by anti-asialo GM-1 rabbit antiserum did not affect survival, suggesting that these cells did not contribute to <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> killing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Daudi-PBMC did not exert in vivo antitumor activity against the control Raji <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Mice receiving i.p. injections of Daudi cells followed by cytotoxic V gamma 9/V delta 2 T-cell clones also survived significantly longer (P &lt; 0.05 for 3 different clones) than animals given Daudi cells alone or Daudi cells followed by noncytotoxic gamma delta T-cell clones </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Our results indicate that this model system can be used for studies of human antilymphoma T-cell responses in vivo </plain></SENT>
</text></document>