<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: This retrospective study was designed to estimate the incidence of primary gastric non-Hodgkin <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (NHL) in childhood and the possible association with Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>PROCEDURE: We reviewed and analyzed the charts of 135 patients with NHL that were diagnosed and treated in a single <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>oncology</z:hpo> unit during the last 20 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Only two patients, 5 and 12 years old, with primary gastric NHL were found </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Upper gastroduodenal endoscopy detected an <z:mpath ids='MPATH_579'>ulcer</z:mpath> in the lesser curvature of the body of the stomach, in both cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Endoscopy revealed a moderate <z:hpo ids='HP_0005231'>chronic gastritis</z:hpo> in the antrum of both patients that was H. pylori associated in one of them who also suffered from <z:hpo ids='HP_0005231'>chronic gastritis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Biopsy specimens demonstrated infiltration by Burkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The two patients received chemotherapy for 6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Additionally, one of the two patients received a triple therapy regimen with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="33301">bismuth</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2676">amoxicillin</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="6909">metronidazole</z:chebi> for H. pylori </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Fifteen and six years later they are in complete remission, free of symptoms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Primary gastric NHL in childhood is rare </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>It was found in fewer than 2% of our NHL patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The temporal relationship between the H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> suggest a causative link between these two events </plain></SENT>
</text></document>