<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Although Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e>) is classified as one entity in the World Health Organisation (WHO) classification, we wondered whether <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> should not be considered as a different disease in children compared with adults </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Netherlands <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Registry (NCR) data were obtained from 1994 to 1998 (n=203) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Detailed clinical data from two treatment protocols were compared: one for adults up to the age of 65 years (n=27) and one for children (n=80) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> slides of the two clinical studies were centrally reviewed which included immunophenotyping and when necessary breakpoint analysis of MYC/8q24 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Only cases with an unambiguous diagnosis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> (classical and atypical <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e>) were accepted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The age distribution of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e>-patients showed a bimodal distribution with a peak at the paediatric age and a steady increase after approximately 60 years of age </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Most of the patients were males (89% for children and 78% for adults) and only male patients showed this bimodality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Children more often had extranodal disease (81% vs. 59%), whereas adults more often had nodal disease (89% vs. 53%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Based on epidemiology and clinical presentation, the concept that <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> is one disease should be re-challenged </plain></SENT>
</text></document>