<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Herpesvirus (h.) saimiri, an infectious agent of squirrel monkeys, is capable of persisting in T lymphocytes of various primate species </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It has been used as a vector for the functional analysis of regulatory genes in primary human T lymphocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>As it is not yet known whether other cell types are capable of supporting <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> persistence, various human cell lines were investigated using selectable h. saimiri recombinants </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The lines chosen represent cells from the epithelium and connective tissue as well as from <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> haematopoietic lineages, i.e. cells of B and T lymphoid origin as well as myeloid-, fibroblast- and <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp>-derived cultures converted to Geneticin or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16976">hygromycin B</z:chebi> resistance, and harbouring episomal DNA of the selectable recombinants </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>-derived cell line Raji also contained simultaneously persisting episomes of the Epstein-Barr virus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Most of the cell cultures except a pancreatic <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> line and foreskin fibroblasts did not produce infectious virus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These observations show that a herpesvirus genome can persist episomally in a broad range of cultured cell types </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The variety of infectable cell types and species suggests the presence of a widely distributed and well conserved virus receptor for h. saimiri </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Thus the h. saimiri genome could be applied more generally as a vector </plain></SENT>
</text></document>