<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We aimed to estimate the frequency of association between non-Hodgkin <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (NHL) with abdominal, gastric, or intestinal involvement and Helicobacter pylori in childhood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Between February 2003 and June 2006, we evaluated 15 children with newly diagnosed NHL who were diagnosed and treated at the Pediatric <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>Oncology</z:hpo> Department of Hacettepe University </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients who were given chemotherapy previously or who received H. pylori eradication therapy were excluded from the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Routine procedures were done for staging </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Pathologic diagnosis was made by examining the biopsy samples </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The presence of H. pylori was confirmed by H. pylori IgG serology with <z:chebi fb="20" ids="16199">urea</z:chebi> breath test (UBT) in cooperated children </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Endoscopic examination was also planned for patients with positive test results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Twelve male and 3 female patients, with a median age of 7 (range: 3 to 16), were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>They had extensive abdominal, gastric, and/or intestinal involvement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Six had stage IV characteristics, whereas another 9 patients had stage III disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Ten had high-grade B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Only 3 patients had H. pylori IgG and UBT positivity (20%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>First patient had T-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and stage IV disease with involvement in stomach, mediastinum, peripheral lymph nodes, and bone marrow </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The second one had anaplastic large cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> exclusively in abdominal lymph nodes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Last patient had Burkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and stage IV disease, with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e> localization in abdominal lymph nodes, liver, and kidneys </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>The H. pylori IgG and UBT were both positive in 3 patients on admission </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>We did not find any positive test results in the other 12 patients with intestinal, stomach, or abdominal disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>Preliminary results of our study suggest that H. pylori may not be the responsible agent for NHL involved the abdomen in childhood </plain></SENT>
</text></document>