<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The overlap in geographical distribution of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024535" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Plasmodium falciparum malaria</z:e> and endemic Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (eBL)--an aggressive Epstein-Barr virus (EBV)-associated B-cell <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e> occurring almost exclusively in the tropics--strongly suggests a link between the two diseases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It is suspected that the polyclonal B-cell activation in P. <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024535" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">falciparum malaria</z:e> may precipitate a breakdown in homeostatic T-cell control of EBV-immortalized B-cell proliferation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Previous studies have suggested that a particular T-cell subset, characterized by expression of Vdelta1+ gammadelta T-cell receptors, is important for maintaining B-cell homeostasis, both in P. falciparum- exposed populations and in individuals subject to polyclonal B-cell activation of other aetiology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The objective of the present study was, therefore, to characterize lymphocyte phenotypes and to investigate possible differences in T-cell subset composition and activation status in P. falciparum-exposed Ghanaian children with and without eBL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Venous blood samples in <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> from 21 eBL patients (mean age: 7.0 years; range: 3-11 years), referred to the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0006413" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="BL">Burkitt's Tumour</z:e> Centre at Korle-Bu Teaching Hospital, Accra and 15 healthy, age and sex matched children, were stained with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37926">fluorescein isothiocyanate</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="37926">FITC</z:chebi>)-, phycoerythrin (PE)-, R-phycoerythrin (RPE)- and RPE-Cy5-conjugated antibodies (CD3, CD4, CD8, CD25, CD69, CD95, HLA-DR, TCR-gammadelta, Vdelta1, Vdelta3, Vgamma9 and B-cells) and acquired on a flow cytometer </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A reduction in the proportion of CD3+ cells in eBL patients, due mainly to perturbations among TCR-gammadelta+ cells was observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the proportions of CD4+ or CD8+ cells were relatively unaffected, as were the mean numbers of peripheral blood mononuclear cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Selective changes in numbers and activation status of TCR-gammadelta+ cells occurs in Ghanaian children with eBL, a pattern which is similar to P. falciparum-induced changes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The data supports the hypothesis of a regulatory role for Vdelta1+ TcR-gammadelta T-cells in maintaining B-cell homeostasis and provides insights into the pathogenesis of eBL </plain></SENT>
</text></document>