<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>An in vitro line was derived from an American Burkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, designated Ra No. 1, which produced <z:mp ids='MP_0002018'>malignant tumors</z:mp> when inoculated into thymus-deficient <z:mp ids='MP_0003815'>nude</z:mp> mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The cells have B-lymphocyte characteristics, with surface-associated mu and kappa chains and Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) receptors, and can be readily infected with EBV in vitro </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>B95-8 virus induced EBV-determined nuclear antigen (EBNA) but not early antigen (EA) in Ra No. 1 cells, whereas P3HR-1 virus induced both EBNA and EA, but the EA level was much lower than in the prototype Raji strain, EBNA and EA levels were comparable in Ra No. 1 and in the previously established, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0149678" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">EBV-infection</z:e>-sensitive BJA-B <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The two lines differed, however, because BJA-B could be converted into a permanent EBV-carrying line by the B95-8 but not by the P3HR-1 virus strain, whereas Ra No. 1 could be converted by the P3HR-1 virus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>This demonstrates that different B-lymphocyte-derived <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> lines can vary with regard to the restrictive control they can exert on the same virus strain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, virus strains vary in their sensitivity to the restrictions of the same host cell </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Permanent EBV conversion of the Ra No. 1 cell did not appear to change the cellular controls, as judged by the unchanged sensitivity of the cell to <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> antigen (EA, <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> capsid antigen) induction by P3HR-1 virus <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0038826" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">superinfection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>