<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Endemic Burkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e>) is etiologically associated with Epstein-Barr virus and ecologically linked to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024535" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Plasmodium falciparum malaria</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, these <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> imperfectly correlate with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> epidemiology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To obtain recent epidemiological data, we studied district- and county-specific <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> incidence and standardized incidence ratios using data collected from 1997 to 2006 at Lacor Hospital in northern Uganda, where studies were last done more than 30 years ago </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Among 500 patients, median age was 6 years (interquartile range 5-8) and male-to-female ratio was 1.8:1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Among those known, most presented with abdominal (56%, M:F 1.4:1) vs. only facial <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> (35%, M:F 3.0:1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0000735" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Abdominal tumors</z:e> occurred in older (mean age: 7.0 vs. 6.0 years; p &lt; 0.001) and more frequently in female children (68% vs. 50%; OR 2.2, 95% CI 1.5-3.5) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The age-standardized incidence was 2.4 per 100,000, being 0.6 in 1-4 year olds, 4.1 in 5-9 year olds and 2.8 in 10-14 year olds and varied 3- to 4-fold across districts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The incidence was lower in districts that were far from Lacor and higher in districts that were close to Lacor </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Although districts close to Lacor were also more urbanized, the incidence was higher in the nearby perirural areas </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We highlight high-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> incidence and geographic variation in neighboring districts in northern Uganda </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Although distance from Lacor clearly influenced the patterns, the incidence was lower in municipal than in surrounding rural areas </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Jaw <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> were characterized by young age and male gender, but presentation has shifted away from facial to mostly abdominal </plain></SENT>
</text></document>