<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The risk factors and co-factors for <z:hpo ids='HP_0003745'>sporadic</z:hpo> childhood <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> are unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We investigated demographic and age-specific characteristics of childhood <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> (0-14 years) in the U.S </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>PROCEDURE: <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> age-standardized incidence rates (2000 U.S. standard population), were calculated using data obtained from 12 registries in the NCI's Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results program for cases diagnosed from 1992 to 2005 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Incidence rate ratios and 95% confidence intervals (95% CI) were calculated by gender, age-group, race, ethnicity, calendar-year period, and registry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of 296 cases identified, 56% were diagnosed in lymph nodes, 21% in abdominal organs, not including retroperitoneal lymph nodes, 14% were Burkitt cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo>, and 9% on face/head structures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The male-to-female case ratio was highest for facial/head <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> (25:1) and lowest for Burkitt cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> (1.6:1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> incidence rate was 2.5 (95% CI 2.3-2.8) cases per million person-years and was higher among boys than girls (3.9 vs. 1.1, P &lt; 0.001) and higher among Whites and Asians/Pacific Islanders than among Blacks (2.8 and 2.9 vs. 1.2, respectively, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>By ethnicity, <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> incidence was higher among non-Hispanic Whites than Hispanic Whites (3.2 vs. 2.0, P = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Age-specific incidence rate for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> peaked by age 3-5 years (3.4 cases per million), then stabilized or declined with increasing age, but it did not vary with calendar-year or registry area </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our results indicate that early childhood exposures, male-sex, and White race may be risk factors for <z:hpo ids='HP_0003745'>sporadic</z:hpo> childhood <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> in the United States </plain></SENT>
</text></document>