<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>There are reports on the presence of various compounds exerting different biological activities in Ruta graveolens, a plant of Rutaceae family </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of the present study was to evaluate in vitro cytotoxicity of the total extract of R. graveolens against <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> cell lines of different origin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Aerial parts of the plant was extracted with 70% <z:chebi fb="37" ids="16236,44730">ethanol</z:chebi> by sonication method and cytotoxic activity was examined on RAJI, RAMOS, RPMI8866, U937, Jurkat, <z:chebi fb="14" ids="32506">MDA</z:chebi>-MB-453, MCF-7, LNCap-FGC-10, 5637, HeLa, SK-OV-3, A549, Mehr-80 and also peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) by the use of WST-1 assay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Results were expressed as IC(50) values </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>R. graveolens extract showed high cytotoxic activity against RAJI and RAMOS, two Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> cell lines, with an IC(50) equal to 24.3 microg/ml and 35.2 microg/ml respectively and LNCap-FGC-10, a <z:mp ids='MP_0009220'>prostate adenocarcinoma</z:mp> cell line with an IC(50) equal to 27.6 microg/ml as well as Mehr-80, a newly established Large Cell <z:mp ids='MP_0008714'>Lung Carcinoma</z:mp> (IC(50)=46.2 microg/ml) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>No significant anti-proliferative activity was observed on other cell lines including MCF-7, <z:chebi fb="14" ids="32506">MDA</z:chebi>-MB-453, SK-OV-3, HeLa, 5637, JURKAT and RPMI8866 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Adverse cytotoxic effect of R. graveolens was investigated against PBMCs and a significantly lower effect of this extract (IC(50)=104 microg/ml) was seen on <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> cells compared with RAJI and RAMOS, two haematopoietic cell lines </plain></SENT>
</text></document>