<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>This study was undertaken in order to evaluate possible antioxidative and antiproliferative activities of three Helleborus taxa </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The dry leaves and roots of three Helleborus taxa were extracted with <z:chebi fb="37" ids="16236,44730">ethanol</z:chebi> and water </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A phytochemical evaluation of the selected extracts was performed using spectrophotometric methods and a 1,1-diphenyl-2-picrylhydrazyl (DPPH) radical scavenging activity assay was used for measuring the antioxidative activity of extracts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The antiproliferative activity of the three Helleborus taxa was studied using Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> B cells (BJAB) cell lines </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The phytochemical evaluation showed that the leaves contain high levels of total phenolic and <z:chebi fb="5" ids="47916">flavonoid</z:chebi> content </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Results from the DPPH assay indicated that the activity of the <z:chebi fb="37" ids="16236,44730">ethanol</z:chebi> and water extracts of the leaves was higher than that of positive control (<z:chebi fb="1" ids="27607">thymol</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Extracts from the roots of H. odorus also displayed higher <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> activity than the positive probe, while H. mulifidus and H. hercegovinus root extracts were less effective </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A statistically significant correlation between total phenolic content and antioxidative properties indicates that these compounds contribute to the <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The highest percentage of cell growth inhibition was observed when testing the water root extracts of H. multifidus (50.14%) and H. hercegovinus (49.04%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the water leaf extract of H. hercegovinus exhibited the lowest inhibition of cell growth (8.59%), although it showed strong <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> activity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>