<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Extranodal involvement is common in patients with Burkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We evaluated the pattern of extranodal involvement and its impact on clinical outcomes in a single center cohort of adult Korean patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0003745'>sporadic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We retrospectively identified 64 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> in the registry of non-Hodgkin <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> of the Asan Medical Center between 1996 and 2009 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We assessed their clinical features and distribution of extranodal sites and analyzed clinical outcomes, including complete response rate after chemotherapy, overall survival, and progression-free survival, relative to baseline characteristics and involved extranodal sites </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Extranodal involvement was found in 57 patients (89 %), with 34 (53.1 %) having two or more extranodal sites </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The stomach (26.6 %) was the most common site, followed by the small and large intestines (25 %), bone marrow (23.4 %), genitourinary tract (21.9 %), and bones (18.8 %) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Two patients (3.1 %) showed central <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system (<z:chebi fb="7" ids="29425,29426,29441,29447">CNS</z:chebi>) involvement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Complete response rates to chemotherapy were not related to sites of extranodal involvement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Two-year overall survival rates were lower in patients with bone marrow (33.3 vs. 74.6 %, p = 0.010) and <z:chebi fb="7" ids="29425,29426,29441,29447">CNS</z:chebi> (0.0 vs. 66.6 %, p = 0.048) involvement than in patients with involvement at other extranodal sites </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The stomach, genitourinary tract, and bones were the most commonly involved extranodal sites in Korean <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e> patients, but site had no prognostic significance </plain></SENT>
</text></document>