<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Data are presented to support a relationship between <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024530" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">malaria</z:e> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> in African children </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>IgG, IgM and IgA levels were measured in sera from Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> patients and from sex- and age-matched, nearest-neighbour controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> three classes of immunoglobulins were present in significantly lower amounts in the sera from Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> patients than in the sera from controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The mechanism of this apparent B-cell suppression is not yet clear </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024530" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Malaria</z:e>-specific IgG and IgM antibody titres were determined in the indirect immunofluorescence test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>No significant difference in the IgG <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024530" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">malaria</z:e>-specific antibodies was detected between the two groups of sera </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024530" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Malaria</z:e> antibody levels measured using IgM specific conjugates were significantly lower in the sera from Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> patients in reactions with Plasmodium falciparum antigen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No significant difference was observed when P. malariae was used </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Confirmation of this finding would serve as a positive link between Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and P. falciparum <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>