<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>L-Asparaginase sensitivity and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="22653">asparagin</z:chebi>-deficiency of 5 tumor cell populations, i.e. mouse <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> L-1210, LI0-1, LTL, Berkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and human <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1140680" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">ovary cancer</z:e>, line CaOv were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Radiometric estimation of 3H-thimidine incorporation into the cells of DNA served a criterion of cytotoxicity. "Krasnitin" (FDR) was used as L-asparaginase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The cells of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> L-1210, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0079734" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">lymphosarcoma</z:e> LIO-1 and line CaOv were asparagine-independent and non-sensitive to L-asparaginase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The cells of mouse lympholeukemia LTL and the cultures of Berkitt human <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> proved to be <z:chebi fb="0" ids="22653">asparagin</z:chebi>-dependent and highly sensitive to L-asparaginase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In concentration of 50 IU/ml the drug inhibited incorporation of 3H-thimidine in the cells of LTL and Berkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> by 97-98 and 75-80 per cent respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Inhibition of 3H-thimidine incorporation in the cells of LTL and Berkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> was more pronounced after incubation with the drug for 8 and 24 hours respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Two out of the 5 tumor cell populations were chosen as a result of the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>One of these 2 populations, i.e. the cells of Berkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> was <z:chebi fb="0" ids="22653">asparagin</z:chebi>-dependent and highly sensitive to L-asparaginase, the other, i.e. the cells of line CaOv was <z:chebi fb="0" ids="22653">asparagin</z:chebi>-independent and resistant to the specific antitumor effect of the enzyme </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The use of a system of these two cell lines provided estimation of the ratio of the specific <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35610">cytostatic</z:chebi> (antitumor activity) and non-specific <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35610">cytostatic</z:chebi> properties in the preparations with L-asparaginase activity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>