<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>This essay on prognosis in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> diagnosis pathology resp. <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> etiology, cancerogenesis and molecular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>oncology</z:hpo> is the authors personal opinion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Generally <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> diagnosis improves with progress in histo- and cytological methods for example in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> of the APUD-system and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0940937" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">precancerous lesions</z:e> especially of the breast </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Fundamental principle of developed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> diagnosis is the knowledge of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1608408" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignant transformation</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Its profits favours the etiology in cancerogenesis and e.g. non Hodgkin <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> (Burkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, adult T-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>) and to result from new methods in molecular biology and <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> genetics (<z:chebi fb="3" ids="16991">DNS</z:chebi>-hybridizing, -recombination and gene technology) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>With the beginning century a stepwise fitted diagnosis of malignant <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> is evident up to monoclonal dedifferentiated lymphoid cells and their multifarious phenotypical markers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This concept may be of general significance in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> diagnosis already indicated in prelymphomas </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Finally the present prognosis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> diagnosis is evaluated by contents, tasks and strategies of its corresponding research lines in clinical and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027659" disease_type="Neoplastic Process;Experimental Model of Disease" abbrv="">experimental tumor</z:e> pathology resp. its organization </plain></SENT>
</text></document>