<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The effect of interferon (IFN) on protein synthesis was studied in the Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> cell line P3HR-1 by [<z:chebi fb="0" ids="37983">35S</z:chebi>]methionine labelling of the cells, followed by two-dimensional gel electrophoresis of cell extracts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>De novo synthesis of three proteins (mol. wts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>33 000, 62 000, and 98 000, respectively) and alterations in the rate of synthesis for a small number of additional proteins were observed during the first 12 h of treatment, while the rate of overall protein synthesis was unaffected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Treatment of P3HR-1 cells with 12-O-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="25456">tetradecanoyl</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="45127">phorbol-13-acetate</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="6" ids="15702,53394">TPA</z:chebi>) or <z:chebi fb="2" ids="17650">hydrocortisone</z:chebi> (HC), which induce similar changes in cell cycle distribution as does IFN, did not induce comparable changes in the rates of protein synthesis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Thus, the effects were specific for IFN and not induced by the change in cell cycle distribution per se, i.e., accumulation in G0 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Treatment of cells with 2'-5' pA core did not mimic the effect of IFN at the translational level </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A substrain of P3HR-1 cells, selected for resistance to the anti-proliferative effect of IFN, lacked six proteins found in the <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The 62 000 mol. wt. protein was induced in this substrain as well as in native P3HR-1 cells on addition of IFN </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The resistant substrain still developed an anti-<z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> effect in response to IFN </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Thus, it seems as if the anti-proliferative and anti-<z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> effects of IFN, at least in some cells are mediated by different intracellular molecular mechanisms </plain></SENT>
</text></document>