<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Because of the presence of a No 14 chromosome marker abnormality in EB virus-carrying cells from African Burkitt's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e>) but not from other origins, and the association of EB virus with nasopharyngeal <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> (NPC) as well as <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">BL</z:e>, both the malignant epithelial cells and the non-malignant lymphoid cells of NPC have been investigated cytogenetically </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Chromosome spreads from seven NPC-derived lymphoblastoid lines were examined after banding; five lines were diploid and two were tetraploid </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>No consistent no. 14 chromosome abnormalities were found </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Apart from a secondary constriction near the centromere of both no. 1 chromosomes in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cells of one diploid line, no consistent significant abnormalities were seen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Five NPC <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e>, freed of infiltrating lymphoid cells by passage through <z:mp ids='MP_0003815'>nude</z:mp> mice, were similarly examined after spindle arrest in vivo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Two <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e> were near-diploid, and three were hypo-tetraploid </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Near-diploid cells had only minor chromosomal changes, but the hypotetraploid spreads from <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e> showed gross changes of uncertain origin, including frequent, major translocations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No. 14 chromosome marker changes were not seen, and there was no other consistent pattern of abnormality in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e> cells </plain></SENT>
</text></document>