<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We addressed the question whether the in vitro interaction of two Epstein-Barr virus (EBV)-genome-positive B cell lines (EB-3 and HilB-gamma) with either Mycoplasma pneumoniae or M. hominis, with the &lt;&lt;<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AIDS</z:e>-related&gt;&gt; mycoplasma species (M. fermentans, M. fermentans subsp. incognitus, M. penetrans, M. genitalium) or with mycoplasma species known to be mere commensals of the respiratory tract (M. orale and M. salivarium) would result in expression of <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNAs</z:chebi> for IL-2, IL-2R, IL-4 and IL-6 as determined by reverse transcriptase (RT)-PCR after 4 and 24 h of cocultivation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The pattern of cytokine gene expression observed depended on (i) the origin of the transformed cell line, (ii) the pathogenicity of the Mycoplasma species, and (iii) the length of cocultivation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The EBV-immortalized lymphoblastoid cell line HilB-gamma showed <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression for IL-2, IL-2-receptor, IL-4 and IL-6 peaking 24 h after stimulation with M. pneumoniae and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AIDS</z:e>-related mycoplasma species tested </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The Burkitt <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> cell line EB-3 showed a distinct and isolated strong II-2/IL-2 R-<z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression within 4 h after contact with the pathogenic and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AIDS</z:e> related mycoplasma species </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In neither EBV-containing cell line cytokine was gene expression detectable after stimulation with the commensal mycoplasma species, M. orale and M. salivarium, indicating species differences in the ability of mycoplasmas to interact with and stimulate B-cell lines </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Our data suggest that some mcyoplasma species may act as immunomodulatory cofactors by eliciting inappropriate cytokine gene expression in B cells latently infected with EBV </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Therefore, this cultivation model may prove useful in evaluating the pathogenetic potential of novel isolated mycoplasma species </plain></SENT>
</text></document>