<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Invasive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004030" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">aspergillosis</z:e> is a life-threatening <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0026946" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">fungal infection</z:e> which, in neutropenic patients, is associated with an extremely high mortality rate despite optimal treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In order to investigate microbiological risk factors for treatment failures in more detail, Aspergillus spp. obtained from 29 patients with haematological diseases after myelo-ablative chemotherapy and bone marrow transplantation were analysed for their susceptibility to <z:chebi fb="1" ids="2682">amphotericin B</z:chebi> in vitro and this was compared with clinical outcome to see if there was a correlation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Aspergillus flavus was present in 12 (41 %) of the 29 patients, Aspergillus terreus in nine (31%) and Aspergillus fumigatus in eight (28%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The susceptibility of these isolates to <z:chebi fb="1" ids="2682">amphotericin B</z:chebi> varied between and within the three species </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A. terreus was the only organism against which the MIC was consistently high, A. fumigatus and A. flavus showing variation between isolates in the degree of resistance to <z:chebi fb="1" ids="2682">amphotericin B</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The degree of in-vitro resistance was the only parameter correlating with clinical outcome in a univariate analysis and the only prognostic value in a multivariate analysis considering known risk factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Irrespective of the species, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> six patients with isolates against which the MIC was &lt;2 mg/L survived, whereas most (22/23) of those with isolates resistant to &gt; or = 2 mg/L died </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Infections</z:e> among the six survivors were caused by <z:chebi fb="1" ids="2682">amphotericin B</z:chebi>-susceptible A. fumigatus and A. flavus, but not A. terreus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We conclude that the outcome of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0851807" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">aspergillus infection</z:e> depends on the in-vitro susceptibility of the isolates to <z:chebi fb="1" ids="2682">amphotericin B</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Survival was poor in patients with isolates resistant to <z:chebi fb="1" ids="2682">amphotericin B</z:chebi> and good in those with <z:chebi fb="1" ids="2682">amphotericin B</z:chebi>-susceptible specimens </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>A. terreus was always associated with high resistance to <z:chebi fb="1" ids="2682">amphotericin B</z:chebi> and with poor survival </plain></SENT>
</text></document>