<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: In patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysm</z:hpo> of the ascending aorta, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_66'>dilatation</z:mpath> of the sinotubular junction is the major cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001659'>aortic valve regurgitation</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Valve sparing aortic root replacement in patients without valvular structural defects offers a new form of treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was the assessment of the perioperative course and early complications of this method compared to composite replacement in a large single center cohort </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: From 1992 to 1999, valve sparing replacement of the ascending aorta (recon) has been performed in 78 patients, while 269 patients underwent replacement by a composite graft (comp) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A comparison of matched pairs (n=52) with respect to age, gender, presence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan's syndrome</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002647'>aortic dissection</z:hpo> as well as date of surgery, was chosen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001659'>Aortic insufficiency</z:hpo> was 2.8+/-0.7 for recon vs. 2.2+/-1.1 for comp preoperatively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Course and length of hospitalization, echocardiographic follow-up, complications, and mortality were compared at 1-year follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were no operative <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>During follow-up, one patient (2%) died 5 months postoperatively (recon) vs. two patients (3.9%) in the comp group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Bypass-time (123+/-31 vs. 153+/-31 min, P&lt;0.0001) and cross-clamp-time (82+/-22 vs. 120+/-23 min, P&lt;0.0001) were significantly shorter in comp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Stay in ICU (1.9+/-1.6 for recon vs. 2.3+/-2.1 days for comp) and post-op hospitalization (18.3+/-5.7 vs. 21.2+/-11.1 days) were comparable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Improvement of NYHA-class was significant after both operations (recon 2.6+/-0.8 vs. 1.3+/-0.5 and for comp 2.4+/-0.6 vs. 1.5+/-0.7, both P&lt;0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>One patient (1.9%) in the recon group had to be reoperated for valve failure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Thrombembolic or <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp> complications were observed in 6 patients (12%) in comp, zero in recon (P=0.027) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Valve sparing aortic root reconstruction is feasible with low perioperative morbidity and mortality and good early results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Major advantages of recon are significant reduction of thrombembolic and anticoagulation related complications as opposed to longer cross-clamp and bypass times as well as a valve failure in one patient </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Further follow-up is needed to confirm our data in a long-term perspective </plain></SENT>
</text></document>