<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The extracellular matrix tissue of the myocardium importantly contributes to left ventricular (LV) performance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Inherited <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0009782" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">connective tissue disorders</z:e> related to the FBN1 gene could involve cardiac interstitium resulting in functional abnormalities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>HYPOTHESIS: To disclose a primary involvement of myocardium, LV function was studied in 28 patients affected by <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> or Marfan-related disorders: 20 Marfan and 8 MASS (<z:hpo ids='HP_0001634'>Mitral valve prolapse</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000545'>Myopia</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001724'>Aortic dilatation</z:hpo>, Skeletal involvement, Skin <z:hpo ids='HP_0001065'>striae</z:hpo>) and in 28 healthy, age and gender-matched controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>No valvular regurgitation or any other cardiac alterations were present </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Echocardiographic study was performed to investigate LV systolic and diastolic function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: No statistically significant differences were observed between patients and the control group in LV dimensions, systolic function parameters (ejection and shortening fraction), and some diastolic function parameters (E peak, A peak, E/A), while statistically significant differences were found between patients and the control group in LV mass (128.7 +/- 46.6 vs. 83.7 +/- 14.5 g/m2, p&lt;0.008), in isovolumic relaxation time (102.0 +/- 24.0 vs. 80.1 +/- 11.2 ms, p&lt;0.016), and in deceleration time of the E wave (127.5 +/- 19.3 vs. 208.6 +/- 24.5 ms, p&lt;0.001) and the A wave (66.4 +/- 8.2 vs. 87.5 +/- 23.4 ms, p &lt;0.008) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These data show an unusual pattern of transmitral diastolic flow in which a decreased ventricular compliance and reduced myocardial relaxation coexist </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Thus, in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> and in Marfan-related disorders, subclinical diastolic alterations are present independent of valvular disease and might represent an early marker of primary myocardial involvement </plain></SENT>
</text></document>