<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Hypothermic bypass with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0444720" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">circulatory arrest</z:e> for thoracoabdominal <z:hpo ids='HP_0004942'>aortic aneurysm</z:hpo> (TAAA) repair is employed for its protective effect on spinal cord function and because it avoids clamping the diseased aorta </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, organ dysfunction caused by reperfusion injury as well as <z:hpo ids='HP_0001892'>bleeding tendencies</z:hpo> due to deep <z:hpo ids='HP_0002045'>hypothermia</z:hpo> have been described </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In this paper we compared the efficacies of the hypothermic and normothermic operations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Between February 1996 and June 2000, 28 patients underwent thoracoabdominal aortic repair </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Twenty-three patients were men, 5 were women, and the median age was 55.3 (range 23 to 75 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Fourteen patients had <z:hpo ids='HP_0002647'>aortic dissection</z:hpo>, and 7 had <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Fourteen patients required reconstruction of visceral arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Twelve patients underwent TAAA repair under deep hypothermic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0444720" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">circulatory arrest</z:e> (H group), and 15 under normothermic distal perfusion (N group), while 1 patient underwent a simple clamp procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Perioperative data and early outcomes were compared between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The overall 30-day mortality rate was 0%, but 3 patients (25.0%) in II group, and 1 patient (6.3%) in N group died during hospital stay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Operation time and bypass time were longer in H group than N group (operative time 793 min vs. 481 min (p &lt; 0.05): cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB) time 255 min vs. 102 min (p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Also, more intraoperative <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>bleeding</z:mp> was found in H group than in N group (3,506 ml vs. 1,220 ml) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Spinal cord neurologic deficit did not occur in either group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002093'>Respiratory failure</z:hpo> occurred in 3 patients (25.0%) in H group and one (6.3%) in N group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000083'>Renal failure</z:hpo> occurred in 3 (25.0%) in H group, and none in N group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Early and mid-term outcome of TAAA repair was almost satisfactory and without neurospiral complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>The deep hypothermic operation is more likely to induce postoperative respiratory and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000082'>renal dysfunction</z:hpo> than the normothermic operation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>TAAA repair using deep hypothermic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0444720" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">circulatory arrest</z:e> should be limited to patients with TAAA involving the distal arch or a severely calcified aortic wall </plain></SENT>
</text></document>