<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND AIM OF THE STUDY: <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>Endocarditis</z:hpo> due to Abiotrophia sp. is rare and often associated with negative blood cultures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The rates of treatment failure, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> relapse and mortality are higher than in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> caused by other viridans streptococci </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A retrospective review of A. defectiva <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> in a patient with prosthetic aortic valve and in a patient with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> was performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A. defectiva, susceptible to <z:chebi fb="93" ids="17334">penicillin</z:chebi> (MIC 0.064 mg/l and 0.016 mg/l, respectively) was isolated from blood cultures of both patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Treatment with <z:chebi fb="93" ids="17334">penicillin</z:chebi> and gentamicin was started in both patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Since the first patient developed a macular <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0015230" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">rash</z:e> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001882'>leukopenia</z:hpo>, <z:chebi fb="93" ids="17334">penicillin</z:chebi> was substituted with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29007">ceftriaxone</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Both patients responded well to antibiotic treatment, did not need prosthetic valve insertion or reinsertion, and were without any sequelae at one year follow up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Standard treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0006689'>bacterial endocarditis</z:hpo> with <z:chebi fb="93" ids="17334">penicillin</z:chebi> and gentamicin was effective in both patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In contrast to previous reports, the present patients had a favorable outcome on completion of treatment and at one-year follow up </plain></SENT>
</text></document>