<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002835'>Aspiration</z:hpo> to reduce the risks of athletic field <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> prompted the American Heart Association and European Society of Cardiology (ESC) to establish consensus guidelines for eligibility/disqualification decisions in competitive athletes with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001626'>cardiovascular abnormalities</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Since 2005, the Bethesda Conference #36 and the ESC consensus documents have been relied upon by physicians from different parts of the world </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The 2 consensus documents emanate from largely different cultural, social, and legal backgrounds existing in the U.S. and Europe and, although several recommendations are similar, in some instances the Bethesda Conference #36 and the ESC consensus documents suggest different approaches to disqualification decisions and implications for clinical practice, raising the possibility that <z:hpo ids='HP_0001289'>confusion</z:hpo> and discrepancies will contaminate the management of competitive athletes with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the present article, the differences between the 2 documents are critically viewed, with special attention to genetic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular diseases</z:e> relevant to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001699'>sudden death</z:hpo> in young athletes, through the prism of different cultural backgrounds, societal attitudes, and also perceptions regarding exposure to legal liability in the U.S. and Europe </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, it seems appropriate at some time to consider assembling updated recommendations for sports eligibility/disqualification that assimilate both the U.S. and European perspectives, with the <z:hpo ids='HP_0002835'>aspiration</z:hpo> of creating a unique and authoritative document applicable to the global sports medicine community </plain></SENT>
</text></document>