<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e>) continue to elude diagnosis until well into adulthood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to compare the clinical characteristics and outcomes of adult survivors with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e> diagnosed during adulthood (age, &gt;or=18 years) with those of adult survivors with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e> diagnosed in childhood (&lt;18 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We conducted a retrospective review of 66 adult (age, &gt;18 years) <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e> patients seen at a combined pediatric and adult multidisciplinary <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e> clinic from 2004 to 2006 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Demographic, clinical, and cardiac variables were collected and a comparative analysis was performed between the two groups: patients diagnosed with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e> during childhood and patients diagnosed in adulthood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The primary outcome measures were the presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002647'>aortic dissection</z:hpo> and the need for urgent cardiovascular surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Despite a similar incidence of clinical characteristics, 39 of the 66 MFS patients were not diagnosed until adulthood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The overall incidence of major cardiac involvement was comparable between the two groups, although the patients diagnosed at a younger age were found to have a reduced need for aortic surgery (33% vs. 59%; P &lt; 0.04) and fewer adverse cardiac outcomes (0% vs. 46%; P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Moreover, the patients diagnosed with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e> in adulthood were more likely to require repeated surgical intervention for distal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0003493" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">aortic disease</z:e> (13% vs. 0%; P = 0.07) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e> who remain undiagnosed until adulthood have well-established <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0741949" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiovascular pathology</z:e> frequently requiring surgical intervention </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Due to this delay in diagnosis and management, they often suffer from a suboptimal clinical outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Our research demonstrates the importance of educating pediatric clinicians in early <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e> diagnosis in hopes of improving the long-term outcome of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>