<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: The aim of the study is to compare mid-term results of Bentall aortic root replacement with composite mechanical valved conduit and aortic valve reimplantation procedure using the Valsalva graft for the treatment of aortic root <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysm</z:hpo> in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We retrospectively compared data of 23 patients (mean age 38 + or - 14 years) who had undergone the Bentall procedure (group B) to those of 24 patients (mean age 36 + or - 12 years) who had undergone aortic valve reimplantation (group R) during a 14-year period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Follow-up (mean duration 65 + or - 44 months) was 100% complete </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were no operative <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> in either group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In group B, as compared with group R, preoperative <z:hpo ids='HP_0001659'>aortic insufficiency</z:hpo> (3.2 + or - 1.1/4 vs. 1.7 + or - 1.4/4, P &lt; 0.001), ascending aorta diameter (55.8 + or - 4.9 vs. 44.1 + or - 8.7 mm, P = 0.001) were prevailing; cardiopulmonary bypass (107 + or - 51 vs. 145 + or - 32 min, P &lt; 0.05) and aortic cross-clamp (77 + or - 17 vs. 116 + or - 30 min, P = 0.005) times were shorter </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Eight-year survival and freedom from cardiac <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> and reoperation were 91 + or - 6, 96 + or - 4 and 100% in group B and 100, 100 and 91 + or - 6% in group R, respectively (P = NS for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> comparisons) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At follow-up, echocardiography showed significant improvement of left ventricular ejection fraction (0.60 + or - 0.10 vs. 0.52 + or - 0.09 preoperatively, P = 0.01) and end-systolic diameter (34 + or - 5 vs. 47 + or - 14 mm, P = 0.001) in group B and significant reduction of preoperative <z:hpo ids='HP_0001659'>aortic insufficiency</z:hpo> (0.7 + or - 1.0/4 vs. 1.7 + or - 1.4/4, P = 0.01) and aortic annulus (24 + or - 2.4 vs. 33 + or - 5 mm, P = 0.01) in group R </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In Marfan patients, the Bentall procedure is associated with excellent mid-term outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The reimplantation technique, adopted for less dilated aortas, provides similarly satisfactory results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The Valsalva graft seems, with time, to allow a stable aortic valve function </plain></SENT>
</text></document>