<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> type A <z:hpo ids='HP_0002647'>aortic dissection</z:hpo> (AAAD) is rare in young people </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The early- and long-term outcomes after surgery for AAAD in patients aged ≤ 45 years was investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: Subjects were 355 patients who had undergone emergency surgery for AAAD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The patients were grouped as those aged ≤ 45 years (n=30; mean age, 38.3 years; younger group) and those aged &gt; 45 years (n = 325; mean age, 65.3 years; older group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Clinical and prognostic variables were compared between the groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Male sex, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e>, and severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001659'>aortic regurgitation</z:hpo> were more prevalent in the younger group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In-hospital mortality (16.7% vs. 8.6%, P = 0.15) and postoperative patency of the distal aorta (90.8% vs. 59.1%, P &lt; 0.01) were more frequent in the younger group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The leading causes of late <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> were <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0003496" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">aortic rupture</z:e> in the younger group (75.0%) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancy</z:e> in the older group (27.5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Although actuarial survival at 10 years was similar (64.5% vs. 62.5%), freedom from aortic reoperation at 10 years was decreased in the younger group (49.4% vs. 85.0%, P = 0.012) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A distal aorta &gt; 45 mm (P&lt;0.001), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> (P &lt; 0.01), and age ≤ 45 years (P = 0.045) were shown to be independent risk factors for reoperation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Early- and long-term surgical outcomes are not better for patients ≤ 45 years, and the risk for reoperation is high in this group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Careful follow up is important in young patients with AAAD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>