<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001724'>Aortic dilatation</z:hpo> and dissection are severe <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0032962" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">complications of pregnancy</z:e> that may cause maternal <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The purpose of the present study was to investigate risk factors for <z:hpo ids='HP_0001724'>aortic dilatation</z:hpo> or dissection in pregnant Japanese women with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: A total of 28 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> were investigated retrospectively during pregnancy and after delivery at 1 institution </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>These patients were divided into 2 groups: those who experienced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001724'>aortic dilatation</z:hpo> or dissection (group D, n=11) and those who did not (group ND, n = 17) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In group D, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001724'>aortic dilatation</z:hpo> or dissection occurred in 7 cases during pregnancy (2 in the 2(nd) trimester, 5 in the 3(rd) trimester) and 4 cases after birth </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The 2 cases in the 2nd trimester involved <z:hpo ids='HP_0001724'>aortic dilatation</z:hpo> &gt; 60mm and those patients underwent hemiarch replacement and a David operation, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Delivery by cesarean section (64% vs. 18%, P &lt; 0.05), sinus of Valsalva ≥ 40mm (86% vs. 21%, P &lt; 0.05), aortic size index (size of sinus of Valsalva/body surface area) ≥ 25 mm/m² (7/7, 100% vs. 0/14, 0%, P &lt; 0.0001), and faster growth of the sinus of the Valsalva (median, [interquartile range]: 0.41 mm/month [0.23-0.66 mm/month] vs. 0.05 mm/month [-0.13 to 0.22 mm/month]; P &lt; 0.05) were significantly higher in group D than in group ND </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A large sinus of Valsalva, increased aortic size index, and rapid growth of the sinus of Valsalva are risk factors for <z:hpo ids='HP_0001724'>aortic dilatation</z:hpo> or dissection in pregnant Japanese women with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>