<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>STUDY DESIGN: Retrospective case control study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To compare patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> and matched patients with adolescent idiopathic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002650'>scoliosis</z:hpo> (AIS) to illustrate the differences and identify areas for potential surgical improvement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>SUMMARY OF BACKGROUND DATA: Patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> commonly require spinal deformity surgery, but practice guidelines and results are not as established as those for patients with AIS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We matched 34 adolescents with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> with patients with AIS (ratio, 1:2) for age, sex, and degree of major deformity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Overall mean age was 14 ± 2 years and mean curves were 51° thoracic and 46° lumbar </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mean follow-up was 5.3 and 3.6 years, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> group had significantly more <z:hpo ids='HP_0005619'>thoracolumbar kyphosis</z:hpo> correction (9.5° vs. 0.1°, P = 0.05), significantly more levels fused (12 ± 2 vs. 9 ± 3, P ≤ 0.01), significantly more fusions to the pelvis (7 vs. 0, P = 0.01), and significantly more correction of sagittal imbalance (2.4 vs. -0.6 cm, P = 0.035) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> group also had more intraoperative cerebrospinal fluid leaks (3 vs. 0, P = 0.01), significantly more instrumentation complications (3 vs. 1, P = 0.007), more reoperations for indications [such as fixation failure, distal degeneration, and spine fracture (9 vs. 0, P = 0.01)], and lower SRS-22 total (3.9 vs. 4.5, P = 0.01) and partial (P &lt; 0.015) subscores </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There were no significant differences between the groups in progression of unfused proximal thoracic curves, blood loss, neurological deficit, hospital stay, percent correction, or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> rate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> differ in several ways from those with AIS: they require more levels of surgical correction, more distal fusion, greater correction of sagittal balance, and more reoperations, and they have more intraoperative cerebrospinal fluid leaks and instrumentation-related complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Knowledge of these differences is important for planning surgery </plain></SENT>
</text></document>