<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: To evaluate the effect of spatial (ie, number of sampling locations along the aorta) and temporal sampling density on aortic pulse wave velocity (PWV) assessment from velocity-encoded MRI in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: Twenty-three <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MFS</z:e> patients (12 men, mean age 36 ± 14 years) were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Three PWV-methods were evaluated: 1) reference PWV(i.p.) from in-plane velocity-encoded MRI with dense temporal and spatial sampling; 2) conventional PWV(t.p.) from through-plane velocity-encoded MRI with dense temporal but sparse spatial sampling at three aortic locations; 3) EPI-accelerated PWV(t.p.) with sparse temporal but improved spatial sampling at five aortic locations with acceleration by echo-planar imaging (EPI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Despite inferior temporal resolution, EPI-accelerated PWV(t.p.) showed stronger correlation (r = 0.92 vs. r = 0.65, P = 0.03) with reference PWV(i.p.) in the total aorta, with less error (8% vs. 16%) and variation (11% vs. 27%) as compared to conventional PWV(t.p.)  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In the aortic arch, correlation was comparable for both EPI-accelerated and conventional PWV(t.p.) with reference PWV(i.p.) (r = 0.66 vs. r = 0.67, P = 0.46), albeit 92% scan-time reduction by EPI-acceleration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Improving spatial sampling density by adding two acquisition planes along the aorta results in more accurate PWV assessment, even when temporal resolution decreases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For regional PWV assessment in the aortic arch, EPI-accelerated and conventional PWV assessment are comparably accurate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Scan-time reduction makes EPI-accelerated PWV assessment the preferred method of choice </plain></SENT>
</text></document>