<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND CONTEXT: <z:hpo ids='HP_0100775'>Dural ectasia</z:hpo> in the lumbosacral spine is a common feature of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> and is associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0003419'>low back pain</z:hpo> and surgical complications, but its natural history is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: To evaluate the natural history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100775'>dural ectasia</z:hpo> in adults with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> by determining if, over time, symptoms associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100775'>dural ectasia</z:hpo> worsen, <z:hpo ids='HP_0100775'>dural ectasia</z:hpo> imaging findings worsen, or <z:hpo ids='HP_0003302'>spondylolisthesis</z:hpo>/<z:hpo ids='HP_0003304'>spondylolysis</z:hpo> develops or worsens </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>STUDY DESIGN: Prospective cohort study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>PATIENT SAMPLE: For our prospective follow-up study, we enrolled 20 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100775'>dural ectasia</z:hpo> who, from 1998 through 1999, had undergone magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and computed tomography (CT) of the lumbosacral spine and had completed the Oswestry Disability Index (ODI) questionnaire </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Of the 20, five did not meet the inclusion criterion of a completed 2009 ODI questionnaire and were excluded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The remaining 15 patients (mean age, 49.6 years; mean follow-up, 10.5 years) formed our study group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>OUTCOME MEASURES: The ODI, MRI-based qualitative and quantitative measurements, CT-based quantitative measurements </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We performed matched-pair analyses via Student t test and Wilcoxon signed-rank test of the ODI scores (15 pairs), dural volume of L5-S2 (eight pairs), dural sac ratio (DSR) of L4-S2 (nine pairs), development/progression of spondolysthesis/<z:hpo ids='HP_0003304'>spondylolysis</z:hpo> (11 pairs), and Fattori qualitative grading of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100775'>dural ectasia</z:hpo> size (10 pairs) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Significance was set at p&lt;.05 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: We found no statistical differences in the 1998/1999 and 2009 ODI scores (25.8 vs. 22.2 points), dural volume (70.4 vs. 73.9 cm(3)), or DSR (0.68, 0.78, 2.04, and 58.1 vs. 0.69, 0.83, 2.30, and 70.20) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>There was also no development or progression of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003302'>spondylolisthesis</z:hpo>/<z:hpo ids='HP_0003304'>spondylolysis</z:hpo> and no increase in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100775'>dural ectasia</z:hpo> size </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: During this 10-year period, the natural history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100775'>dural ectasia</z:hpo> in adults with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e> was not associated with a significant increase in ODI scores, <z:hpo ids='HP_0100775'>dural ectasia</z:hpo> size, or with the development/progression of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003302'>spondylolisthesis</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0003304'>spondylolysis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>