<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Currently, cell cultures are used for 3 kinds of applications in orthopaedics: diagnosis: they can help to diagnose <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019247" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hereditary diseases</z:e> like <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024796" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MFS|MFS1">Marfan syndrome</z:e>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0029434" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">osteogenesis imperfecta</z:e>, or some <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0029422" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">osteochondrodysplasia</z:e>. biomaterial evaluation: cell cultures bring information to ensure safety and efficacy of medical devices following the European Community's directive concerning medical devices </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Results of in vitro biomaterial evaluation must be related to cell types (osteoblasts or fibroblasts), cell species (human or rat) and methods used (primary cell line or immortalised cell line). therapy: first clinical applications of cell cultures have been published recently </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>They concern cultured autologous chondrocytes reimplantation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Bone cells cultured on biomaterials have been tested in animal reimplantation experiments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Animal cells mediated gene therapy experiments are now developed on muscle cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Cell cultures allow also to determine the best therapeutic way to cure <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0005967" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">bone tumors</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For the moment, these applications are still limited but in the next years, they could develop considerably </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Therefore, orthopaedic surgeons must keep interest in this new field </plain></SENT>
</text></document>