<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The efficacy and safety of generic and brand name levofolinate injectable drugs were evaluated in 42 chemotherapy-naïve patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> who received the combination chemotherapy of levofolinate, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="46345">5-fluorouracil</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi> with or without bevacizumab </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> response rate was similar between generic drug group and brand drug group, in which the efficacy rate (complete response plus partial response) was 50% for generic drug group and 42% for brand name drug (odds ratio: 1.400, 95% confidence intervals: 0.409-4.788, P = 0.756) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The rates of the decrease in plasma <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> markers such as carcinoembryonic antigen and carbohydrate antigen 19-9 were not different between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The incidence of adverse drug reactions was not significantly different between the two groups, although the incidence rates of adverse events associated predominantly with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="46345">5-fluorouracil</z:chebi> such as <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0852711" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hand-and-foot syndrome</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002014'>diarrhea</z:hpo>, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1568868" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">oral mucositis</z:e> were rather higher, though not significantly, in generic drug group than in brand drug group (16 vs. 4% for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0852711" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hand-and-foot syndrome</z:e>; 33 vs. 25% for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002014'>diarrhea</z:hpo>; 33 vs. 25% for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1568868" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">oral mucositis</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>These findings suggest that both the effectiveness and safety profiles of the generic name levofolinate are comparable to those of the brand name drug, when used in combination with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="46345">5-fluorouracil</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi> in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>