<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A regimen consisting of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="46345">5-fluorouracil</z:chebi>/leucovorin plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi> (FOLFOX-6) is widely used in France in the first-line treatment of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> (MCRC) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of our study was to demonstrate the non-inferiority of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31348">capecitabine</z:chebi> plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi> (XELOX) versus FOLFOX-6 for this indication </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients were randomly assigned to receive XELOX or FOLFOX-6 for 6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The primary endpoint was overall response rate (ORR) in the per-protocol (PP) population; however, progression-free and overall survival (OS), time to response and response duration were also assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A total of 306 patients were enrolled (XELOX n = 156; FOLFOX-6 n = 150) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>ORR was 42 and 46% with XELOX and FOLFOX-6, respectively, in the PP population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The difference between groups was 4.7%; the upper limit of the unilateral 95% confidence interval (14.4%) was below the non-inferiority margin of 15% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In the intent-to-treat population, median progression-free survival was 8.8 months with XELOX and 9.3 months with FOLFOX-6, and median OS was 19.9 and 20.5 months, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>XELOX patients had significantly more grade 3/4 <z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>thrombocytopenia</z:hpo> (12% vs. 5%) and diarrhoea (14% vs. 7%), but significantly less grade 3/4 <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> (5% vs. 47%), febrile <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> (0% vs. 6%) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e> (11% vs. 26%) than FOLFOX-6 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We conclude that XELOX is non-inferior in terms of efficacy to FOLFOX-6 in the first-line treatment of MCRC, but has a different toxicity profile </plain></SENT>
</text></document>