<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the expression of reversion-inducing cysteine-rich protein with Kazal motifs (RECK), matrix metalloproteinase-9 (MMP-9), and vascular endothelial growth factor-C (VEGF-C) in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: S-P immunohistochemistry was used to detect the expression of RECK, MMP-9 and VEGF-C in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> specimen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Colorectal mucosal tissue at least 10 cm away from the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> was used as control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The positive expression of RECK in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> was significantly lower than that in the controls(53.3% vs. 100%, P&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Both MMP-9 and VEGF-C were over expressed compared with the controls(86.7% vs. 23.3% and 71.7% vs. 13.3% respectively, P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The expression of RECK was negatively correlated with that of MMP-9 and VEGF-C, and the expression of MMP-9 was positively correlated with that of VEGF-C </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were significant associations between the expression of these proteins and lymph node <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e>, distant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e>, and TNM staging (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: RECK expression is low in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, while MMP-9 and VEGF-C expressions are high </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Combined testing of these 3 markers is important in the evaluation of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">tumor metastasis</z:e> and invasion, and is helpful in the prediction of the prognosis </plain></SENT>
</text></document>