<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) in young patients is associated with a poor outcome due to advanced stage at diagnosis and poor differentiation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>AIM: The aim of this study is to compare clinicopathological characteristics, overall survival (OS) and disease-free survival (DFS) of young (≤40 years) and older patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 2,538 patients including 59 young patients (age ≤40 years) with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> were identified over 20 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The clinicopathological variables of young patients were compared with a group of consecutive older patients (n = 416) spanning both decades </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Survival analysis was done using Kaplan-Meier, log-rank and Cox regression models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The frequency in young patients increased from 1.4% to 3.0% from first to second decade (overall -2.3%, p = 0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There was a higher frequency of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e> with poor differentiation (43% vs. 16%, p = &lt; 0.001), T4 stage (47% vs. 30%, p = 0.005) and vascular invasion (VI; 38% vs. 29%, p = 0.13) in younger group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference in OS (p = 0.116) and DFS (p = 0.261) between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Node-negative young patients had a significantly better OS (p = 0.046) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Young patients with VI had significantly reduced OS (p = 0.043), whereas young patients without VI had significantly better OS (p = 0.012) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis showed T4 status (p = 0.001) and vascular invasion (p = 0.002) as independent prognostic factors for OS and T4 status (p = 0.004) as independent factor influencing DFS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The frequency of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> in young patients increased significantly </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Vascular invasion is the single most important prognostic factor in young <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Along with vascular invasion, high proportion of T4 status in young patients increases the chances of recurrence and negates any survival advantage in young patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>