<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001888'>Lymphopenia</z:hpo> is a predictor of the efficacy and hematological toxicity of chemotherapy in various <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0877373" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">advanced cancers</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>There is little data about this relationship in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In this retrospective study, the influence of pretreatment <z:hpo ids='HP_0001888'>lymphopenia</z:hpo> on hematological toxicity and the efficacy of chemotherapy was investigated in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: In total, 260 patients were included in the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Correlations between pre-treatment <z:hpo ids='HP_0001888'>lymphopenia</z:hpo> (lymphocyte count &lt; 1,000/μl) and the occurrence of hematological toxicity and efficacy of first-line palliative chemotherapy were investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001888'>Lymphopenia</z:hpo> was found in 49/260 (19%) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Ten of these patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001888'>lymphopenia</z:hpo> (20.4%) experienced severe hematological toxicity compared with 17 of the remaining 211 (8%) patients (P = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001888'>Lymphopenia</z:hpo> was identified as an independent factor for hematological toxicity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Among patients who received palliative chemotherapy, the objective response rate was significantly lower in lymphopenic patients than in the other patients (12.5% vs. 40.2%; P = 0.004) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001888'>Lymphopenia</z:hpo> was strongly associated with shorter progression-free survival (median 4 vs. 7 months; P = 0.033) and shorter overall survival (median 16 vs. 24 months, P = 0.024) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis revealed that <z:hpo ids='HP_0001888'>lymphopenia</z:hpo> had an independent effect on survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our findings show that <z:hpo ids='HP_0001888'>lymphopenia</z:hpo> is an independent predictive factor for both hematological toxicity and efficacy of chemotherapy in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Pre-treatment lymphocyte count may represent a simple and new predictive biomarker of chemotherapy effects in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>