<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To review the application of nutrition support in patients after surgery for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, and to propose appropriate nutrition strategies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 202 consecutive surgical patients admitted to our hospital with a diagnosis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007113" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">rectal cancer</z:e> from January 2010 to July 2010, meeting the requirements of Nutrition Risk Screening 2002, were enrolled in our study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Laboratory tests were performed to analyze the nutrition status of each patient, and the clinical outcome variables, including postoperative complications, hospital stay, cost of hospitalization and postoperative outcome, were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The "non-risk" patients who did not receive postoperative nutrition support had a higher rate of postoperative complications than patients who received postoperative nutrition support (2.40 ± 1.51 vs. 1.23 ± 0.60, P = 0.000), and had a longer postoperative hospital stay (23.00 ± 15.84 d vs. 15.27 ± 5.89 d, P = 0.009) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There was higher cost of hospitalization for patients who received preoperative total parenteral nutrition (TPN) than for patients who did not receive preoperative TPN (62 713.50 ± 5070.66 RMB Yuan vs. 43178.00 ± 3596.68 RMB Yuan, P = 0.014) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Applying postoperative enteral nutrition significantly shortened postoperative fasting time (5.16 ± 1.21 d vs. 6.40 ± 1.84 d, P = 0.001) and postoperative hospital stay (11.92 ± 4.34 d vs. 15.77 ± 6.03 d, P = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The patients who received postoperative TPN for no less than 7 d had increased serum <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels (7.59 ± 3.57 mmol/L vs. 6.48 ± 1.32 mmol/L, P = 0.006) and cost of hospitalization (47 724.14 ± 16 945.17 Yuan vs. 38 598.73 ± 8349.79 Yuan, P = 0.000) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The patients who received postoperative <z:chebi fb="6" ids="25681">omega-3 fatty acids</z:chebi> had a higher rate of postoperative complications than the patients who did not (1.33 ± 0.64 vs. 1.13 ± 0.49, P = 0.041) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>High level of serum <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> was associated with a high risk of postoperative complications of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Appropriate and moderate nutritional intervention can improve the postoperative outcome of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>