<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES: En bloc bladder resection is often required for treating <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> with suspected urinary bladder invasion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Our aim was to review our institutional experience in en bloc resection of locally advanced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> involving the urinary bladder over a period of 17 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The hospital records of 72 patients with locally advanced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> who underwent en bloc urinary bladder resection at our institution between July 1987 and December 2004 were retrospectively reviewed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Clinical and oncologic outcomes were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The mean duration of follow-up was 64.3 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Genuine <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> invasion into the urinary bladder was confirmed in 34 patients (47%) by histopathology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Forty patients (56%) underwent primary closure of the urinary bladder, while 32 patients (44%) required various kinds of urologic reconstructive procedures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Operative mortality occurred in four patients (6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The overall postoperative morbidity rate was significantly higher in patients undergoing urologic reconstruction (81% vs. 45%, p = 0.002) when compared to that in patients undergoing primary closure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This was mostly attributable to significantly higher rates of urinary anastomotic leak (21.9% vs. 0%, p = 0.002) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000010'>urinary tract infection</z:hpo> (50% vs. 18%, p = 0.003) in the urologic reconstruction group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>For the 57 patients (79%) who underwent curative resection, the 5-year overall survival rate was 59%, and the local recurrence at 5 years was 15% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Both parameters were not significantly affected by the presence of pathologic bladder invasion or the extent of surgical procedures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: En bloc bladder resection for locally advanced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> involving the urinary bladder can produce reasonable long-term local control and patient survival </plain></SENT>
</text></document>