<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The objective of the study was to compare the clinical value of preoperative serum carbohydrate antigen 19-9 (CA19-9) and carbohydrate antigen 242 (CA242) in diagnosis and prognosis for 5-year recurrence-free survival (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e>) in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Preoperative serum CA19-9 and CA242 concentrations were detected by C12 protein chip diagnostic system in 185 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>, and informative data were collected during 5-year follow-up periods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The value of CA19-9 and CA242 in diagnosis and prognosis for 5-year <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e> as well as their consistencies and correlations were comparatively analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The sensitivities of CA19-9 and CA242 were only 19.5 and 20%, respectively; the efficiencies of two TMs were 53.9 and 54.2%, respectively; and two TMs increased significantly with advancing clinical stages (P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Preoperative CA19-9 and CA242 levels correlated with stage (r, 0.411 and 0.408) and CEA concentration (r, 0.553 and 0.630) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The concentrations of two TMs closely correlated with each other (r = 0.829), and two TMs had a very strong consistency in diagnosis (κ = 0.931) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Among 88 of 185 cases with complete follow-up information on <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e>, patients with positive preoperative serum CA19-9 or CA242 had higher 5-year recurrent rates (72.2% vs. 44.3%, P = 0.034; 76.5% vs. 43.7%, P = 0.015) and reduced median <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e> (14 vs. 36 months, 12 vs. 36 months) compared with those with negative TMs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The consistency of predicting prognosis for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e> of two TMs was extremely strong (κ = 0.964) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>ROC curves analysis showed that CA242 test performed better than CA19-9 test (AUC, 0.648 vs. 0.605) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Univariate analysis showed that preoperative serum status of both TMs was correlated with 5-year <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e> (P &lt; 0.05), whereas multivariate Cox regression model analysis revealed that none of them were independent prognostic factors for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Both CA19-9 and CA242 had strong consistencies in diagnosis and prognosis for predicting 5-year <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CA242 demonstrated superior value to CA19-9 in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>