<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>TSU-68 is a novel multiple <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38637">tyrosine kinase inhibitor</z:chebi> that inhibits VEGFR-2, FGF and PDGF receptors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We conducted a phase I study to evaluate the safety and pharmacokinetic of TSU-68 when used with S-1 and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi> (SOX) in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> (mCRC) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients with mCRC were treated with TSU-68 200 mg (Level 1) or 400 mg (Level 2) b.i.d. daily, S-1 35 mg/m(2) b.i.d. on Days 1-14 and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi> 130 mg/m(2) i.v. on Day 1 repeatedly every 3 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Of eleven patients enrolled, two patients were excluded from dose limiting toxicity (DLT) assessment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Six patients at Level 1 experienced no DLT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Of three patients at Level 2, two patients experienced DLTs (one patient: grade 3 hiccup and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0549410" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">palmar-plantar erythrodysaesthesia syndrome</z:e>, another one: grade 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> which prevented the initiation of next cycle within 14 days) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The maximal tolerated dose (MTD) and recommended dose (RD) of TSU-68 was 200 mg b.i.d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>C(max) and AUC(0-t) of TSU-68 at Level 2 were higher than those at Level 1, but doubling the dose of TSU-68 increased C(max) and AUC(0-t) less than two-fold </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was no appreciable difference in the PK of S-1 components (FT, CDHP and Oxo), 5-FU and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi>-derived <z:chebi fb="240" ids="33364,33400">platinum</z:chebi> between Levels 1 and 2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A significant decrease in PDGF after TSU-68 treatment was identified and it might serve as pharmacodynamic marker of TSU-68 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Administration of TSU-68 in combination with SOX is generally well tolerated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The MTD and RD of TSU-68 in this study was 200 mg b.i.d. daily </plain></SENT>
</text></document>