<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: Curative surgical resection is of great importance and some trials have been performed to identify free undetectable <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> cells using molecular markers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="?"><plain>The aim of this study is to investigate <z:hpo ids='HP_0002861'>melanoma</z:hpo>-associated antigen (MAGE) expression in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> mucosa around <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> and its clinical significance. </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL AND METHOD: From October 2003 to June 2004, we collected 46 colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> and matched <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> mucosal tissues within 20 mm, 20 to 50 mm and more than 50 mm from <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> after the curative operation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Twenty-two mucosal tissues were harvested from patients with benign colorectal diseases as controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="?"><plain>MAGE expression was assayed using nested RT-PCR of MAGE A1-6 mRNA. </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The MAGE expression rates in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> tissue and adjacent <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> mucosa were 65.2%, 6.5% (&lt;20 mm), 2.2% (20-50 mm) and 0.0% (&gt;50 mm), respectively, while MAGE was not expressed in the mucosa of benign diseases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="?"><plain>The MAGE-positive cases in the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> mucosa around <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> were located in the left colon or rectum, and one patient showed anastomotic mucosal site recurrence. </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: MAGE expression in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath>-appearing mucosa around <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> showed some clinical findings suggesting the presence of undetectable free <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> cells after curative resection </plain></SENT>
</text></document>