<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The KRAS mutation is not responsible for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cases of resistance to anti-epidermal growth factor receptors (EGFRs) in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> (mCRC), and new predictive and prognostic factors are actively being sought </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: We retrospectively evaluated the efficacy of a cetuximab-containing treatment in 73 patients with mCRC according to KRAS and BRAF mutational status as well as PTEN, c-MET, and insulin-like growth factor receptor (IGF1R) expression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Overall response rate (ORR), median progression-free survival (mPFS), and median overall survival (mOS) were significantly lower in patients with KRAS mutation than in patients with KRAS <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp>; among the population with KRAS <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp>, only 2 patients with BRAF mutations were found and neither of them achieved a response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>No significant association was found between PTEN and clinical outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Compared with low/<z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> expression, c-MET overexpression significantly correlated with shorter mPFS and mOS: 3 vs. 5 months (P = .018) and 11 vs. 10 months (P = .037), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In patients with high IGF1R expression, mOS was significantly longer than in those with low/<z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> expression (14 vs. 8 months; P = .015) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: KRAS mutation significantly correlates with a worse outcome in patients treated with cetuximab, whereas no definitive inference can be drawn about the role of BRAF mutation and PTEN loss of expression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Instead, c-MET overexpression might represent a negative prognostic factor in mCRC and may have a role in resistance to anti-EGFR therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, IGF1R overexpression seems a favorable prognostic factor in mCRC </plain></SENT>
</text></document>