<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: In recent years, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> surgery has benefitted from new techniques such as laparoscopy and robotic surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, many treatment disparities exist among different centers for patients affected by the same kind of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Forty-five (41%) open (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="48397">OCO</z:chebi>) vs. 30 (28%) laparoscopic (LCO) vs. 34 (31%) robotic-assisted (RCO) colectomies and 34 (40%) open (ORR) vs. 52 (60%) robotic (ROR) rectal resections performed during a 15-month period, in elective setting, were compared </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients presenting contraindications for minimally invasive procedures were excluded from the study, so that <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> the enrolled patients were suitable for either of the surgical procedures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Overall morbidity rates were similar among groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Perioperative mortality was nil </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>No significant differences were noted as for total number of lymph nodes harvested between arms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Mean time (days) to first bowel movement to gas was 3.3 vs. 2.3 vs. 2.6 for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="48397">OCO</z:chebi>, LCO, and RCO, respectively (p &lt; 0.001), and 3.3 vs. 2.0 for ORR and ROR, respectively (p = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Among several European Organization in Research and Treatment of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> QLQ-C30 functional scales considered only physical functioning was significantly better at 30 days for RCO vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29325">OCO </z:chebi>(96.3 ± 10 RCO vs. 85.5 ± 12.6 OCO; p = 0.015) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Robotic surgery was much more expensive in comparison to open as well as laparoscopic procedures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Laparoscopic and robotic surgeries for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> present both the same advantages in comparison to open procedures in terms of faster recovery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>However, our data do not seem to support the routine use of RCO as a cost-effective procedure </plain></SENT>
</text></document>