<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: An association of Streptococcus bovis <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004610" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bacteremia</z:e> with <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> of colon has been reported, but data regarding peritoneal dialysis (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PD</z:e>) <z:hpo ids='HP_0002586'>peritonitis</z:hpo> caused by S. bovis is scarce </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In this study, we examined the clinical characteristics, associations, and outcomes of this disease entity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The case records of patients with S. bovis <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PD</z:e> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002586'>peritonitis</z:hpo> presenting to 2 renal centers between January 2000 and September 2010 were reviewed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Clinical features and outcomes were identified and analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of cultures from 23 episodes of S. bovis <z:hpo ids='HP_0002586'>peritonitis</z:hpo> in 20 patients (1.28% of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002586'>peritonitis</z:hpo> episodes at our center), 19 (82.6%) showed S. bovis alone, and 4 (17.4%) showed mixed growth </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In 7 episodes, the S. bovis was moderately resistant to <z:chebi fb="93" ids="17334">penicillin</z:chebi> G </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Rates of resistance to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="3745">clindamycin</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="2" ids="42355,48923">erythromycin</z:chebi> were 43.5% and 47.8% respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In 18 episodes (78.3%), a primary response was achieved with a first-generation <z:chebi fb="2" ids="23066">cephalosporin</z:chebi> and an <z:chebi fb="0" ids="47779">aminoglycoside</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In 4 episodes, a secondary response was achieved after a switch from <z:chebi fb="2" ids="23066">cephalosporin</z:chebi> to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28001">vancomycin</z:chebi>, and in 1 episode with mixed growth, the Tenckhoff catheter had to be removed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Repeat <z:hpo ids='HP_0002586'>peritonitis</z:hpo> occurred in 3 patients at a mean of 50.0 months (range: 24.2 - 83.1 months) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Of the 20 patients of S. bovis <z:hpo ids='HP_0002586'>peritonitis</z:hpo>, 10 (50%) underwent either a <z:chebi fb="8" ids="32594,32595">barium</z:chebi> enema or a colonoscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>One patient had history of colonic <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> 2 years before the <z:hpo ids='HP_0002586'>peritonitis</z:hpo>, and a subsequent work-up revealed no recurrence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Three patients had <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1510475" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">diverticulosis</z:e>, and one had a concomitant sigmoid <z:mpath ids='MPATH_491'>polyp</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Findings in the other 6 patients were <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>No colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancy</z:e> had developed in the remaining 10 patients after a mean follow-up of 76.6 months (range: 0.8 - 125.1 months) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Outcomes in S. bovis <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PD</z:e> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002586'>peritonitis</z:hpo> were favorable, and an association with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> was not found in our patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Routine colonoscopy in these patients remains controversial and should be individualized </plain></SENT>
</text></document>