<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The objective of this study is to determine whether neoadjuvant chemotherapy reveals occult disease precluding surgical extirpation of initially resectable <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastases</z:e> (CRCLM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Demographics, clinicopathologic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> characteristics, treatments, and post-operative outcomes of patients aged 18-80 years, with one to four initially resectable CRCLM, and without concurrent extra-hepatic (EHMD) or previous <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastatic disease</z:e> were reviewed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Two hundred and two patients evaluated from 2000 to 2010 met study criteria; 88 (43.6%) were given neoadjuvant chemotherapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients treated with neoadjuvant chemotherapy were younger (median 58 years vs. 65 years, P = 0.0096), had shorter disease free interval from resection of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e> to CRCLM diagnosis (median 0 months vs. 12 months, P &lt; 0.0001), and had more CRCLM (median 1 [1-3] vs. 1 [1-2], P = 0.0096) compared to untreated counterparts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There were no differences in rates of concurrent EHMD noted intra-operatively and not on pre-operative imaging (4.5% vs. 3.5%, P = 0.7290), greater intra-operatively observed CRCLM compared to pre-operative imaging (25.3% vs. 17.5%, P = 0.2449), hepatic resection and/or ablation (97.7% vs. 100.0%, P = 0.9853), or 6-month disease recurrence after surgical treatment (25.6% vs. 14.9%, P = 0.0882) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Only two (2.3%) patients treated with neoadjuvant chemotherapy had disease progression precluding surgical extirpation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Neoadjuvant chemotherapy for initially resectable CRCLM does not reveal occult disease precluding surgical treatment </plain></SENT>
</text></document>