<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to determine the cost-effectiveness of testing for KRAS mutations before administering EGFR inhibitors such as cetuximab and panitumumab for patients with advanced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> (mCRC) in the United States and Germany </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We developed a lifetime Markov model of costs and survival associated with treating mCRC patients to assess the impact of KRAS testing before administering EGFR inhibitor-containing chemotherapy regimens </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Overall, combination therapies involving cetuximab plus irinotecan/FOLFIRI had a better life expectancy (25.83 weeks) than cetuximab or panitumumab alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Use of KRAS testing (assuming KRAS mutant patients receive only irinotecan) was equally effective and saved $12,428 per patient in the United States </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>When KRAS mutant patients received best supportive care, the life expectancy decreased slightly (24.26 weeks vs. 25.83 weeks) and the costs decreased by $13,501 in the United States and €9,560 in Germany </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>For patients treated with cetuximab alone, use of KRAS testing to identify mutations lowered costs by $8,040 per patient in the U.S. analysis and €3,856 per patient in the German analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For patients treated with panitumumab alone, use of KRAS testing to identify mutations lowered costs by $7,546 per patient in the U.S. analysis and €4,612 per patient in the German analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Model results were sensitive to the cost of chemotherapy regimens and the prevalence of KRAS mutations in the population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Under most scenarios, using KRAS testing to select patients for EGFR inhibitor therapy saved $7,500-$12,400 per patient in the United States and €3,900-€9,600 per patient in Germany with equivalent clinical outcomes </plain></SENT>
</text></document>