<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The association between polymorphism of DNA methyltransferases 3B and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> risk has been widely studied recently, and no consensus conclusion is available up to now </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We perform a comprehensive search using the databases of Medline, ISI Web of Knowledge and Embase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The odds ratio (OR) and its 95% confidence interval (95% CI) are used to investigate the strength of the association </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A total of 24 case-control studies with 15,647 individuals are included in this meta-analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>For -149C &gt; T (17 studies, 5229 cases and 6910 controls), no evidence indicate that individuals carrying the variant genotypes (CC + CT), relative to those carrying the wild homozygote TT genotype, have an increased risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> (OR = 1.03; 95% CI = 0.84-1.26; P = 0.76) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Similarly, no <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> risk is found in the subgroup analyses </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For -579G &gt; T (11 studies, 3513 cases and 3714 controls), significantly decreased risks of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> are observed, and the ORs (95% CI) are 0.70 (0.56-0.87) for GT versus TT, 0.70 (0.57-0.85) for GG + GT versus TT and 0.76 (0.63-0.93) for G-allele versus T-allele, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Subgroup analyses stratified by ethnicity and types of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> are also performed, and results indicated that -579G &gt; C polymorphism is associated with risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> in Asians [0.68 (0.53-0.87) for GT vs. TT] but not in Europeans [0.82 (0.63-1.07) for GT vs. TT] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We also observe that the -579G is associated with decreased risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> [0.49(0.38-0.62) for GT vs. TT] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>More studies with larger sample size were needed to provide more precise evidence </plain></SENT>
</text></document>