<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND AIMS: Current efforts to prevent <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> focus on the detection and removal of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasms</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Nonpolypoid colorectal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasms</z:hpo> (NP-CRN) have a subtle appearance that can be difficult to recognize during colonoscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Endoscopists must first be familiar with the patterns of NP-CRN in order to detect and diagnose them </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We studied the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> detection rates of endoscopists who had trained to detect NP-CRN, versus endoscopists who had not </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: Design: Retrospective Nested Case Control Study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Setting: Outpatient Screening Colonoscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Participants: Adult Veterans </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Intervention: Proficiency in the features and diagnosis of NP-CRN </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Main Outcomes Measurements: <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>Adenoma</z:mpath> detection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In total, 462 patients had screening colonoscopies-267 by colonoscopists who had trained in the features and diagnosis of NP-CRN </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Patient characteristics were similar between groups-the majority were men with a mean age of 62 ± 6 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>Neoplasia</z:hpo> was more prevalent (45.7 vs. 34.9%; p = 0.02) in patients evaluated by the trained compared to the conventionally trained group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Trained colonoscopists had a higher <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> detection rate (0.76 vs. 0.54 <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath> per patient, p &lt; 0.001); removed a higher proportion of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo> (77 vs. 35%, p &lt; 0.001); and more frequently diagnosed NP-CRN lesions (OR 2.98, 95% CI: 1.46-6.08) compared to colonoscopists without supplemental training </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Endoscopists who are proficient in the detection of NP-CRN had significantly higher <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> detection rates-of both polypoid and flat <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath>-compared to endoscopists without training, and were more specific in resection of adenomatous over hyperplastic lesions </plain></SENT>
</text></document>