<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The Pleckstrin and Sec7 domain-containing (PSD) gene, which regulates skeletal rearrangements, has been found to be more frequently methylated both in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> (UC)-associated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> tissues (5 of 7; 71.4%) and matched <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> epithelia (4 of 7; 57.1%) compared to non-neoplastic UC epithelia (6 of 22; 27.3%) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003745'>sporadic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> tissues (6 of 32; 18.8%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The levels of PSD <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> were positively correlated with the methylation status of PSD, as shown by both MSP and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17137">bisulfite</z:chebi> sequencing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To determine the potential role of PSD silencing in the mechanisms underlying UC-associated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0596263" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">carcinogenesis</z:e>, the levels of senescence, proliferation and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> were evaluated in a <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> human fibroblast cell line (NHDF) in which 93% of PSD expression was knocked down by a small-interfering <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi> (si-<z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Although there were no significant differences in the levels of senescence and proliferation caused by PSD knockdown, the level of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> was significantly decreased by PSD knockdown (5.3% in siControl-treated cells vs. 0.67% in siPSD-treated cells, p=0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In addition, reactive oxygen species inducers accelerated <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> in NHDF and a neutrophil-like cell line, which was significantly reduced by PSD knockdown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>To verify the effect of PSD methylation in tissue sections including 21 samples from UC patients with or without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e>, we elucidated PSD promoting accumulation of filamentous-actin (F-actin) and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> by immunohistochemistry and TUNEL assay, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Both levels of accumulation of F-actin and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> were significantly decreased in specimens from UC patients with PSD methylation compared to those without PSD methylation (F-actin: 0.69±0.86 with vs. 1.57±0.51 without, p=0.0031, apoptotic index: 0.31±0.63 with vs. 1.0±0.88 without, p=0.0277) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, our results indicate that PSD methylation plays a significant role in the mechanisms underlying UC-associated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0596263" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">carcinogenesis</z:e> through its inhibitory effect on <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> in the interaction between colorectal mucosa and neutrophils </plain></SENT>
</text></document>