<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Laparoscopic resection for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> has become popular </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, no previous studies have compared the laparoscopic and open approaches for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> adherent to adjacent organs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study analyzed the short- and long-term survival outcomes after laparoscopic multivisceral resection of the locally advanced primary <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> compared with open procedure in an effort to address appropriate patient selection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: From a prospectively collected database, 54 patients with locally advanced primary <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> who had undergone multivisceral resection from March 2001 to September 2009 were identified </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Laparoscopic and open surgeries were selectively performed for 38 and 16 patients, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The two groups had similar demographics, with no differences in age, sex, and comorbidity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, five emergency or urgency operations were included in the open group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No differences existed between the two groups in terms of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> node <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> (TNM) staging, histologic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> infiltration rates, or curative resection rates </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Three patients (7.9%) in the laparoscopic group required conversion to open procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In the laparoscopic group, the operation time was longer (330 vs. 257 min; p = 0.018), the volume of blood loss was less (269 vs. 638 ml; p = 0.000), and the time until return of bowel movement was shorter (3.7 vs. 4.7 days; p = 0.029) than in the open group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The perioperative morbidity rates were similar in the two groups (21.1% vs. 43.7%; p = 0.107), and no perioperative mortality occurred in either group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The mean follow-up period after curative resection was 40 months in the laparoscopic group and 35 months in the open group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The two groups showed similar rates for local recurrence (7.7% vs. 27.3%; p = 0.144) and distant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> (15.4% vs. 45.5%; p = 0.091) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The overall 5-year survival rate was 60.5% for the laparoscopic group and 47.7% for the open group (p = 0.044, log-rank test) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>In terms of TNM stages, the overall 5-year survival rate for pathologic stage 3 disease was 58.3% for the laparoscopic group and 25% for the open group (p = 0.022, log rank test), but no difference was noted for the stage 2 patients (p = 0.384) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: No adverse long-term oncologic outcomes of laparoscopic resection were observed in this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Although inherent limitations exist in this nonrandomized study, laparoscopic multivisceral resection seems to be a feasible and effective treatment option for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> for carefully selected patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> should be much more carefully selected for laparoscopic multivisceral resection than patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007113" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">rectal cancer</z:e> because anatomic uncertainty can make oncologic en bloc resection incomplete </plain></SENT>
</text></document>