<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Radiolabeled somatostatin analogs have become important agents for molecular imaging and targeted radiotherapy of somatostatin receptor-positive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Here we determine the effect of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> suppressor protein, p53, on trafficking (64)Cu to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> cell nuclei from DOTA vs. CB-TE2A-conjugated <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi> Y3-TATE and the <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi> (64)Cu-CB-TE2A-sst2-ANT in cell lines that are positive or negative for p53 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Receptor binding, internalization, cyclic <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> monophosphate (cAMP) and nuclear localization studies were performed with the somatostatin receptor subtype 2 (SSTr2) <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonists</z:chebi>, (64)Cu-CB-TE2A-Y3-TATE and (64)Cu-DOTA-Y3-TATE vs. <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, (64)Cu-CB-TE2A-sst2-ANT, in SSTr2-transfected p53 +/+ and -/- HCT116 colorectal <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, (64)Cu-CB-TE2A-sst2-ANT, bound 8-9-fold more SSTr2 binding sites than did the (64)Cu-labeled <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonists</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>(64)Cu-CB-TE2A-Y3-TATE was more efficiently internalized than (64)Cu-DOTA-Y3-TATE, while (64)Cu-CB-TE2A-sst2-ANT showed lower yet significant levels of internalization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CB-TE2A-Y3-TATE acted as a full <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi>, inhibiting cAMP production, whereas CB-TE2A-sst2-ANT showed no inhibition of cAMP production </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The (64)Cu from <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonists</z:chebi> (64)Cu-DOTA-Y3-TATE and (64)Cu-CB-TE2A-Y3-TATE showed greater nuclear localization at 24 h in p53 +/+ vs. -/- cells; however, there was no difference in the levels of (64)Cu from the <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi> based on p53 status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Surprisingly, the DOTA and CB-TE2A-conjugated <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonists</z:chebi> showed similar nuclear localization in the p53 +/+ and -/- cells, suggesting no difference in (64)Cu release from these <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38161">chelators</z:chebi> in the HCT116 cell lines </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Based on these in vitro data, the <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi> (64)Cu-CB-TE2A-Y3-TATE demonstrates the most promise as an agent for targeted radiotherapy in p53 positive, SSTr2-positive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>