<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The ability of molecular targeting agents to improve overall survival (OS) in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> (MCRC) patients who underwent <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi>-based chemotherapy remains controversial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We retrospectively analyzed 331 patients with MCRC who underwent first-line <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi>-based chemotherapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Treatment outcomes were compared between patients who started chemotherapy from April 2005 to March 2007 (cohort A; n = 157) and those who started it from April 2007 to March 2009 (cohort B; n = 174) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>To evaluate the impact of exposure to agents, we applied time-varying covariate analysis to avoid possible lead-time bias </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Median OS of cohorts A and B was 21.3 and 28.6 months, respectively (HR 0.66, 95% CI 0.50-0.87, p = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Exposure to bevacizumab (25 vs. 76%), anti-epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) (18 vs. 33%) or curative surgery after chemotherapy (4 vs. 10%) was significantly higher in cohort B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>According to a multivariate Cox model with exposure to each agent or treatment as a time-varying covariate, hazard ratios of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> were 0.71 (95% CI, 0.51-0.96; p = 0.03) for bevacizumab, 0.62 (95% CI, 0.40-0.89; p = 0.01) for anti-EGFR and 0.22 (95% CI, 0.06-0.57; p = 0.004) for surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Increased exposure to molecular targeting agents or surgery after chemotherapy appears to contribute to an improvement in OS in recent patients with MCRC who have undergone <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi>-based chemotherapy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>