<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Cistanche deserticola has commonly been used in traditional Chinese medicine to treat many health problems including <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022104" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IBS">irritable bowel syndrome</z:e> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002019'>constipation</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study was designed to test the efficacy of a water-extract of C. deserticola in the prevention of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> in a mouse model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="5" ids="18154">Polysaccharide</z:chebi>-rich water-extract of C. deserticola was prepared by boiling its stem powder in distilled water </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Tgfb1Rag2 null mice were used as an experimental model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Here we showed that feeding of water-extract of C. deserticola significantly reduced the number of mucosal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_134'>hyperplasia</z:mpath> and intestinal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0079487" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">helicobacter infection</z:e> in mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This beneficial effect correlated with significant stimulation of the immune system, evidenced by the enlargement of the spleens with increased number of splenic macrophage and natural killer cells, and with more potent cytotoxicity of splenocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In vitro water-extract of C. deserticola enhanced the cytotoxicity of naïve splenocytes against a human <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> cell line, and in macrophage cultures up-regulated nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> synthase II expression and stimulated phagocytosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, our data indicate that oral administration of C. deserticola extract reduces inflammatory <z:mpath ids='MPATH_140'>hyperplastic polyps</z:mpath> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0079487" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">helicobacter infection</z:e> in mice by its immune-stimulatory activity, suggesting that C. deserticola extract may have potential in preventing <z:mp ids='MP_0001858'>intestinal inflammation</z:mp> disorders including <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>