<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Kinase domains are the type of protein domain most commonly found in genes associated with <z:mp ids='MP_0002006'>tumorigenesis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Because of this, the human kinome (the protein kinase component of the genome) represents a promising source of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> biomarkers and potential targets for novel anti-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> therapies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Alterations in the human colon kinome during the progression from <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> colon (NC) through <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> (AD) to <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (AC) were investigated using integrated transcriptomic and proteomic datasets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Two hundred thirty kinase genes and 42 kinase proteins showed differential expression patterns (fold change ≥ 1.5) in at least one tissue pair-wise comparison (AD vs. NC, AC vs. NC, and/or AC vs. AD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Kinases that exhibited similar trends in expression at both the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> and protein levels were further analyzed in individual samples of NC (n = 20), AD (n = 39), and AC (n = 24) by quantitative reverse transcriptase PCR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Individual samples of NC and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> tissue were distinguishable based on the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> levels of a set of 20 kinases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Altered expression of several of these kinases, including chaperone activity of bc1 complex-like (CABC1) kinase, bromodomain adjacent to zinc finger domain protein 1B (BAZ1B) kinase, calcium/calmodulin-dependent protein kinase type II subunit delta (CAMK2D), serine/threonine-protein kinase 24 (STK24), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042214" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vaccinia</z:e>-related kinase 3 (VRK3), and TAO kinase 3 (TAOK3), has not been previously reported in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> tissue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These findings may have diagnostic potential and may lead to the development of novel targeted therapeutic interventions for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>