<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND/AIMS: Patients with severe co-morbidities and oncological conditions would not be denied a reconstruction of anastomosis and Hartmann's procedure would be undertaken </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study is to examine the feasibility and safety of laparoscopic Hartmann's procedure compared to open Hartmann's procedure for high risk patients in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODOLOGY: Nine hundred and eighty five primary <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> resections were performed from April 2007 to December 2010 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Thirty six patients (3.6%) who underwent Hartmann's procedure by the same surgical team were investigated retrospectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Twenty six patients (72%) in the open surgery (OS) and 10 patients (28%) in the laparoscopic surgery (LS) were undertaken Hartmann's procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The reason of selected Hartmann's procedure was defined as high risk with severe co-morbidities (OS 8: LS 8, n=16), oncological conditions (OS 14: LS 2, n=16), urgent situations (OS 4, n=4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean operation time was not significantly different (p=0.504) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The median blood loss count was significantly different between both groups (OS 327.5g vs. LS 16.5g; p=0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The incidence of postoperative complications was similar (OS 38% vs. LS 40%; p=0.763) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The median postoperative hospital stay was not significantly different (OS 10.5 vs. LS 12; p=0.216) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Laparoscopic Hartmann's procedure is feasible and safe with a low invasiveness for high risk patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>