<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Observational studies demonstrate an association between physical activity and improved outcomes in breast and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> survivors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To test these observations with a large, randomized clinical trial, an intervention that significantly impacts physical activity in these patients is needed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The Active After <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Trial (AACT) was a multicenter pilot study evaluating the feasibility of a telephone-based exercise intervention in a cooperative group setting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Sedentary (engaging in &lt;60 min of recreational activity/week) breast and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> survivors were randomized to a telephone-based exercise intervention or usual care control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The intervention was delivered through the University of California at San Diego; participants received ten phone calls over the course of the 16-week intervention </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> participants underwent assessment of physical activity, fitness, physical functioning, <z:mp ids='MP_0002899'>fatigue</z:mp> and exercise self-efficacy at baseline and after the 16-week intervention </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>One hundred and twenty-one patients were enrolled through ten <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>Leukemia</z:hpo> Group B (CALGB) institutions; 100 patients had <z:hpo ids='HP_0003002'>breast cancer</z:hpo> and 21 had <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Participants randomized to the exercise group increased physical activity by more than 100 versus 22% in controls (54.5 vs. 14.6 min, P = 0.13), and experienced significant increases in fitness (increased 6-min walk test distance by 186.9 vs. 81.9 feet, P = 0.006) and physical functioning (7.1 vs. 2.6, P = 0.04) as compared to the control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Breast and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> survivors enrolled in a multicenter, telephone-based physical activity intervention increased physical activity and experienced significant improvements in fitness and physical functioning </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Lifestyle intervention research is feasible in a cooperative group setting </plain></SENT>
</text></document>