<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The impact of body mass index (BMI) on laparoscopic surgery for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> in Asian countries is unclear, partly because <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> is less common in Asia than in western countries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to evaluate the association between BMI and short-term outcomes after laparoscopic resection for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> in Japanese patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A cohort of 1194 patients who underwent laparoscopic resection for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> at <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Institute Hospital between July 2005 and February 2010 were enrolled in this prospective study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Outcomes were analyzed according to BMI category: nonobese (BMI&lt;25), <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> I (25 ≤ BMI &lt; 30), and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> II (BMI ≥ 30) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 926 patients (78%) were classified as nonobese, 243 (20%) were <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> I, and 25 (2%) were <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> II </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mean operating time (214 min vs. 244 min vs. 293 min) and mean estimated blood loss (23 mL vs. 42 mL vs. 88 mL) increased significantly with increasing BMI (P&lt;0.0001, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The rate of postoperative complications was significantly higher in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> II patients than in nonobese and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> I patients (24% vs. 9.2% vs. 9.1%, P=0.0428) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis showed that a BMI in the <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> II range was an independent predictive factor for developing anastomotic leakage (odds ratio: 10.27, 95% confidence interval, 1.98-53.44) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Laparoscopic surgery for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> is technically more demanding in Japanese <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> II patients than in nonobese or <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> I patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Special care is required because of the increased risk of developing postoperative complications </plain></SENT>
</text></document>