<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE. : To determine whether racial/ethnic disparities in colonoscopy use vary by physician availability </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>DATA SOURCE. : We used 100 percent Texas Medicare claims data for 2003-2007 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>STUDY DESIGN. : We identified beneficiaries aged 66-79 in 2007, examined racial/ethnic differences in colonoscopy use from 2003 to 2007, and estimated the percentage of white, black, and Hispanic beneficiaries who underwent colonoscopy by level of physician availability and area income </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>PRINCIPAL FINDINGS. : For the 974,879 beneficiaries, colonoscopy use was higher in whites (40.7 percent) compared to blacks (35.0 percent) and Hispanics (28.7 percent, p&lt; .001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>For whites, increasing availability of colonoscopists and primary care physicians (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PCPs</z:e>) was associated with higher colonoscopy use </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>For blacks and Hispanics, colonoscopy use was unchanged or decreased with increases in colonoscopist and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PCP</z:e> availability </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In multilevel models, the odds of colonoscopy were 20 percent lower for blacks (OR 0.80, 95 percent CI 0.79-0.82) and 32 percent lower for Hispanics (OR 0.68, 95 percent CI 0.66-0.69) compared to whites; adjusting for availability of colonoscopists or <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PCPs</z:e> did not attenuate racial/ethnic disparities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>We found greater racial/ethnic disparities in areas with greater colonoscopist and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PCP</z:e> availability </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS. : Greater area availability of colonoscopists and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PCPs</z:e> is associated with increased use of colonoscopy in whites but decreased use in minorities, resulting in larger racial/ethnic disparities </plain></SENT>
</text></document>