<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Motile bacteria can overcome the penetration limitations of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> chemotherapeutics because they can actively migrate into <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0280100" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">solid tumors</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Although several genera of bacteria have been shown to accumulate preferentially in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e>, the spatiotemporal dynamics of <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> colonization and their dependence on <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> motility are not clear </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>For effective <z:mp ids='MP_0010537'>tumor regression</z:mp>, bacteria must penetrate and distribute uniformly throughout <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>To measure these dynamics, we used an in vitro model of continuously perfused <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> tissue to mimic the delivery and systemic clearance of Salmonella typhimurium strains SL1344 and VNP20009, and Escherichia coli strains K12 and DH5α </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Tissues were treated for 1 hour with 10(5) or 10(7) CFU ml(-1) suspensions of each strain and the location and extent of <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> accumulation were observed for 30 hours </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Salmonella had 14.5 times greater average swimming speed than E. coli and colonized tissues at 100 times lower doses than E. coli </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>Bacterial</z:mp> motility strongly correlated (R(2) = 99.3%) with the extent of tissue accumulation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>When inoculated at 10(5) CFU ml(-1), motile Salmonella formed colonies denser than 10(10) CFU/(g-tissue) and less motile E. coli showed no detectable colonization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Based on spatiotemporal profiles and a mathematical model of motility and growth, <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> dispersion was found to be necessary for deep penetration into tissue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>Bacterial</z:mp> colonization caused <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> levels correlated (R(2) = 98.6%) with colonization density </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>These results show that motility is critical for effective distribution of bacteria in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> and is essential for designing <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> therapies that can overcome the barrier of limited <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> penetration </plain></SENT>
</text></document>