<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: There is a controversy about whether lymph node yield can be used as a proxy of quality care for patient with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We aim to use propensity score models to investigate the association between lymph node number and long-term survival for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: Taiwan <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Database was employed to review <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients with newly diagnosed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> from 2003 to 2005 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Exclusion criteria included those patients with stage IV disease or without information of lymph node </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Propensity score models (examined lymph node &gt;12 or &lt;12 as dependent variable) were applied to group of patients with Stage II or Stage III disease and primary end point was 5-year survival (and mortality) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We also report results of Stage I-III for comparison </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: We identified 15,731 newly diagnosed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancers</z:e> during study period, among which a total of 10,517 colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> patients treated at 32 hospitals fulfilled the inclusion criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Pathology reports of about 63 % (6658/10517) patients revealed lymph node retrieval &gt;12 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>After propensity score matching, there were 2888, 1079, 1094 pairs recruited for Stage I-III, Stage II and Stage III, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>According to analysis of these matched pairs, the 5-year risk adjusted overall mortality were lower for lymph node examined ≥12 than &lt;12 among Stage II (24.3% vs. 31.1%, p=0.012) and Stage I-III (20.8% vs. 23.6%, p=0.003), but insignificant for Stage III (40.2% vs. 45.6%, p=0.073) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Similar situation happened with regard to disease-free and disease-specific mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: For patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> undergoing colorectal surgery, the quality metric of lymph node is associated with significantly better 5-year survival except for Stage III disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>