<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Conventional <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> grading systems based on the degree of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> differentiation may not always be optimal because of difficulty in objective assessment and insufficient prognostic value for decision making in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to determine the importance of assessing the number of poorly differentiated clusters as the primary criterion for histologic grading of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Five hundred consecutive patients with curatively resected stage II and III <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRCs</z:e> (2000 to 2005) were pathologically reviewed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> clusters of ≥5 cancer cells and lacking a gland-like structure were counted under a ×20 objective lens in a field containing the highest number of clusters </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Tumors</z:e> with &lt;5, 5 to 9, and ≥10 clusters were classified as grade (G)1, G2, and G3, respectively (n=156, 198, and 146 tumors, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Five-year disease-free survival rates were 96%, 85%, and 59% for G1, G2, and G3, respectively (P&lt;0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Poorly differentiated clusters affected survival outcome independent of T and N stages and could help in more effective stratification of patients by survival outcome compared with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> staging (Akaike information criterion, 1086.7 vs. 1117.0; Harrell concordance index, 0.73 vs. 0.67) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The poorly differentiated cluster-based grading system showed a higher weighted κ coefficient for interobserver variability (5 observers) compared with conventional grading systems (mean, 0.66 vs. 0.52; range, 0.55 to 0.73 vs. 0.39 to 0.68) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Our novel histologic grading system is expected to be less subjective and more informative for prognostic prediction compared with conventional <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> grading systems and TNM staging </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>It could be valuable in determining individualized postoperative <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> treatment </plain></SENT>
</text></document>