<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Few patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> (mCRC) are candidates for resection of their <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0023895" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hepatic disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="2" ids="33331">Yttrium</z:chebi>-90 ((90)Y) radioembolization has promise in the treatment of unresectable mCRC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We conducted a retrospective study to assess the efficacy in patients with refractory mCRC who underwent (90)Y radioembolization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: Patients with unresectable mCRC with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastases</z:e> treated at The Ohio State University were included in this analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Demographic data, carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) values, observed toxicities, and information on prior therapies were collected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Response was assessed by RECIST (Response Evaluation Criteria in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0280100" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Solid Tumors</z:e>) 1.1 criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Overall survival (OS) and progression-free survival (PFS) were estimated by the Kaplan-Meier method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Twenty-four patients (median age, 63 years) were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Of the patients, 54% had extrahepatic disease; 67% had bilobar involvement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The patients had received a median of 3 prior therapies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>No objective responses were observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Five patients had a CEA response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Median PFS and OS were 3.9 months (95% CI, 2.4-4.8 months) and 8.9 months (95% CI, 4.2-16.7 months), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Patients older than 65 years had improved PFS (4.6 vs. 2.4 months) and OS (14 vs. 5.5 months) vs. younger patients, likely due to receipt of (90)Y treatment earlier in their disease course </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>The presence of extrahepatic disease and the absence of CEA response appeared negatively predictive of efficacy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Toxicities were expected and manageable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: (90)Y radioembolization is active in select patients with refractory mCRC and with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastases</z:e>, and is safe and well tolerated in the elderly </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>In patients with extensive extrahepatic disease, (90)Y should be used in combination with chemotherapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>CEA may be a predictor of efficacy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>