<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Phospholipase C-γl (PLC-γl) expression is associated with cellular transformation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Notably, PLC-gamma is up-regulated in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> tissue and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003002'>breast carcinoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Because exotoxins released by Clostridium botulinum have been shown to induce <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> and promote <z:mpath ids='MPATH_73'>growth arrest</z:mpath> in various <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> cell lines, we examined here the potential of Clostridium difficile toxin A to selectively induce <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> in cells transformed by PLC-γl overexpression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We found that PLC-γl-transformed cells, but not vectortransformed (control) cells, were highly sensitive to C. difficile toxin A-induced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> and mitotic inhibition </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Moreover, expression of the proapoptotic Bcl2 family member, <z:chebi fb="3" ids="33173">Bim</z:chebi>, and activation of caspase-3 were significantly up-regulated by toxin A in PLC-γl-transformed cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Toxin A-induced cell rounding and paxillin dephosphorylation were also significantly higher in PLC-γl-transformed cells than in control cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These findings suggest that C. difficile toxin A may have potential as an anticancer agent against <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancers</z:e> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003002'>breast carcinomas</z:hpo> in which PLC-γl is highly up-regulated </plain></SENT>
</text></document>