<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Evidence concerning the role of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005202'>Helicobacter pylori infection</z:hpo> in the development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> remains controversial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The authors assessed the association of H. pylori seroprevalence with risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> in a large population-based case-control study from Germany in 2003-2007 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Serum antibodies to H. pylori in general and the cytotoxin-associated gene A protein (CagA) were measured in 1,712 incident <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> cases and 1,669 controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The association between H. pylori seroprevalence and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> risk was estimated by logistic regression, with adjustment for potential confounders and stratification by age group, sex, anatomic subsites, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> stage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Overall, H. pylori seroprevalence was higher in cases (46.1%) than in controls (40.1%), resulting in an age- and sex-adjusted odds ratio of 1.30 (95% confidence interval (CI): 1.14, 1.50) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Adjustment for established <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> risk factors decreased the odds ratio to 1.26 (95% CI: 1.09, 1.47), with a further reduction to 1.18 (95% CI: 1.01, 1.38) after additional adjustment for previous colorectal endoscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Stratified analyses showed risk elevation to be essentially confined to left-sided <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, with an odds ratio of 1.22 (95% CI: 1.02, 1.45), suggesting that H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> may be associated with a small yet relevant risk increase in the left colorectum </plain></SENT>
</text></document>