<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND AIMS: The effects of polymorphism of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="13392">NAD(P)H</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="36141">quinone</z:chebi> oxidoreductase 1 (NQO1 Pro187Ser, rs1800566) on the risks of colorectal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> have been widely studied and results remain controversial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Therefore, the aim of this meta-analysis was to quantitatively assess the relationships </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Databases of Medline, Embase and Wanfang were retrieved until May 15, 2011 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Pooled odds ratio (OR) and 95% confidence interval (95% CI) as effect sizes were calculated by using fixed- or random-effect model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Cochrane Q-test was used to explore between-study <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo>; p &lt;0.10 indicated statistical significance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 12 case-control studies with 11,700 individuals (including 5528 cases and 6172 controls) were included in this meta-analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Of these studies, four studies conducted in Caucasian populations were for colorectal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath>, and eight studies were for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>NQO1 187Ser allele was significantly associated with increased risk of colorectal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> in co-dominant and dominant comparison models (OR = 1.07, 95% CI = 1.04-1.32 for ProSer vs. ProPro and OR = 1.19, 95% CI = 1.06-1.33 for Ser carries vs. ProPro), without between-study <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Overall, NQO1 Pro187Ser was not associated with risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, without between-study <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Subgroup analyses indicated that Ser allele was significantly associated with increased risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> for Caucasians (OR = 1.14, 95% CI = 1.00-1.30 for ProSer vs. ProPro and OR = 1.16, 95% CI = 1.02-1.31 for Ser carries vs. ProPro) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This meta-analysis suggested that Ser allele of NQO1 Pro187Ser significantly contributed to the increased risks of colorectal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> in Caucasians </plain></SENT>
</text></document>