<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Due to potentially superior short-term outcomes compared with open colorectal surgery, laparoscopic surgery is currently being implemented in clinical practice worldwide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In parallel, enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) programs are shown to improve postoperative recovery in open colorectal surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study reports outcomes in laparoscopic versus open surgery in conjunction with compliance to the ERAS protocol </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The association between surgical approach (laparoscopic or open surgery), compliance to the ERAS protocol, postoperative symptoms, complications, and length of stay after surgery was studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Between January 2007 to December 2010, 114 consecutive patients underwent elective high anterior resection with laparoscopic-assisted (n = 55) or open resection (n = 59) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> clinical data (114 variables) were prospectively recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The overall preoperative ERAS-protocol compliance was 77% for both the laparoscopic and open group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Laparoscopic surgery resulted in shorter total length of stay (median 4 vs. 6 days, p = 0.04), earlier pain control (median 2 vs. 3 days, p = 0.008), shorter need for intravenous infusions, improved mobilization on the first postoperative day (POD1), and lower <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammatory response</z:mp> (CRP (POD1) 54 ± 24 vs. 67 ± 31 mg/l, p = 0.017) compared with open resection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The trends in fewer postoperative complications (9.1 vs. 16.9%; odds ratio (OR) 0.55; 95% confidence interval (CI) 0.17-1.81) and overall postoperative symptoms delaying recovery (20 vs. 30.5%; OR 0.63; 95% CI 0.22-1.34) in laparoscopic surgery were not statistically significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The use of laparoscopy in colorectal surgery within an ERAS protocol results in faster recovery compared with open resection </plain></SENT>
</text></document>