<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The associations between four common genetic polymorphisms of transforming growth factor-β1 (TGF-β1 -509 C &gt; T, +869 T &gt; C, +915 G &gt; C, and -800 G &gt; A) and risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0009404" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal tumor</z:e> (including <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>) have been widely studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To date, no conclusions could be available because of controversial results reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Thus, we conducted a meta-analysis to further assess the associations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We searched the databases of Medline, Embase, and Wangfang to identify eligible studies, and latest update was on January 1, 2012 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Odds ratio (OR) and 95% confidence interval (95%CI) were calculated to present the associations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Our meta-analysis indicated that TGF-β1 -509 C &gt; T, +869 T &gt; C, +915 G &gt; C, and -800 G &gt; A were not associated with risk of colorectal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> (OR = 0.89 for C carriers vs. TT for -509 C &gt; T, 1.03 for C carriers vs. TT for +869 T &gt; C, 1.09 for C carriers vs. GG for +915 G &gt; C, and 1.19 for A carriers vs. GG for 800 G &gt; A) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, C allele of TGF-β1 -509 C &gt; T and A allele of -800 G &gt; A were associated with increased risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>), and OR (95%CI) was 1.23 (0.99-1.52) for CC vs. TT for -509 C &gt; T and 6.64 (3.46-12.72) for A carriers vs. GG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The positive association between -509 C allele and risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> was more obvious when subgroup analyses were conducted for population-based and large sample-sized studies as well as Caucasians </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In contrast, we did not observed any associations between TGF-β1 +869 T &gt; C, +915 G &gt; C, and risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This study indicated that C allele of TGF-β1-509 C &gt; T and A allele of -800 G &gt; A might contribute to the increased risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>, and could be used as two of genetic marks for screening individuals at high risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Because of modest limitation, large sample-sized studies were required to confirm the findings </plain></SENT>
</text></document>