<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Healthy lifestyle might improve outcome among <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) survivors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In this study we investigated the proportion of survivors who meet recommended lifestyle and weight guidelines and compared this to the general population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Factors that predict current behaviour were also assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHOD: A random sample of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> survivors diagnosed between 1998 and 2007 were surveyed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Percentages of current smokers, alcohol consumers, excess weight and clustering of these variables were calculated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Using logistic regression we assessed demographical and clinical factors that predict current lifestyle and excess weight </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: We included 1349 (74% response rate) survivors in this study of whom only 8 and 16% of male and female survivors met the recommended lifestyle and body weight </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Among male survivors up to 10% had at least two unhealthy lifestyle factors and among women, up to 19% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The proportion of smokers and those who had ever consumed alcohol was lower compared to the general population (13 vs. 31%, 82 vs. 86% respectively), but excess weight (BMI at least 25 kg/m(2)) was more prevalent among survivors (69 vs. 53% respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Having received chemotherapy was significantly associated with being overweight (adjusted odd ratio 1.5, 95% confidence interval 1.05-2.3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Younger patients, male gender and survivors of lower socioeconomic status were more likely to show non-compliance to healthy lifestyle recommendations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The observed clustering of unhealthy lifestyle warrants interventions targeting multiple behaviours simultaneously </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Reducing excess weight should be one of the most important targets of interventions, particularly for males, those who had chemotherapy and survivors of lower socioeconomic status </plain></SENT>
</text></document>