<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The benefit of screening for decreasing the risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> from <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) has been shown, yet many patients in primary care are still not undergoing screening according to guidelines </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>There are known variations in delivery of preventive health care services among primary care physicians </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study compared self-reported <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening rates and patient awareness of the need for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening of patients receiving care from family medicine (FPs) vs. internal medicine (internists) physicians </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Nationally representative sample of non-institutionalized beneficiaries who received medical care from FPs or internists in 2006 (using Medicare Current Beneficiary Survey) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The main outcome was the percentage of patients screened in 2007 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We also examined the percentage of patients offered screening </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients of FPs, compared to those of internists, were less likely to have received an FOBT kit or undergone home FOBT, even after accounting for patients' characteristics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Compared to internists, FPs' patients were more likely to have heard of colonoscopy, but were less likely to receive a screening colonoscopy recommendation (18% vs. 27%), or undergo a colonoscopy (43% vs. 46%, adjusted odds ratios [AOR], 95% confidence interval [CI]-- 0.65, 0.51-0.81) or any <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening (52% vs. 60%, AOR, CI--0.80, 0.68-0.94) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Among subgroups examined, higher income beneficiaries receiving care from internists had the highest screening rate (68%), while disabled beneficiaries receiving care from FPs had the lowest screening rate (34%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Patients cared for by FPs had a lower rate of screening compared to those cared for by internists, despite equal or higher levels of awareness; a difference that remained statistically significant after accounting for socioeconomic status and access to healthcare </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Both groups of patients remained below the national goal of 70 percent </plain></SENT>
</text></document>