<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND/AIMS: We aimed to evaluate whether elevated serum synuclein-gamma levels were of clinical significance as a serological marker in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> diagnosis and monitoring </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODOLOGY: Pre-treatment serum synuclein-gamma levels of patients with gastrointestinal and esophageal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002860'>squamous cell carcinomas</z:hpo>, benign disease and healthy controls were analyzed by a specific sandwich ELISA for synuclein-gamma </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Statistically significant differences in serum synuclein-gamma levels between patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="CRC">colo rectal cancer</z:e>, <z:mp ids='MP_0008010'>gastric adenocarcinomas</z:mp>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0546837,C0014859" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">esophageal cancer</z:e> and healthy individuals were observed (p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>When a cut-off value for synuclein-gamma was determined at ≥4 ng/mL by receiver operating characteristic curves, sensitivity and specificity were 16.4% and 97.7% in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, 23.0% and 99.3% in <z:mp ids='MP_0008010'>gastric adenocarcinomas</z:mp>, and 19.5% and 98.7% in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0546837,C0014859" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">esophageal cancer</z:e>, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Compared with carcinoembryonic antigen and carbohydrate antigen 19-9, synuclein-gamma was more sensitive in early detection of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (17.3% vs. 9.6% and 7.5%), <z:mp ids='MP_0008010'>gastric adenocarcinomas</z:mp> (20.6% vs. 0% and 3.2%) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0546837,C0014859" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">esophageal cancer</z:e> (22.2% vs. 3.4% and 0%), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A combined analysis of the above markers yielded incremental positive rates compared with anyone alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These results indicated that serum synuclein-gamma provided a promising diagnostic biomarker for early detection and was a complementary biomarker of carcinoembryonic antigen and/or CA19-9 in gastrointestinal and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0546837,C0014859" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">esophageal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>