<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Laparoscopic liver resection (LLR) is becoming an accepted treatment option for resecting both benign and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignant tumours</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, it is critical that the laparoscopic approach does not compromise the technical quality of the liver resection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of this paper was to review the learning curve of LLR in a specialist HPB unit </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A prospective database was searched to identify patients undergoing LLR over a 4-year period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>To assess the effect of the learning curve on outcome, the series was evaluated during two eras--early versus late </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Fifty-one (27 males, median age 68 years) patients were identified with 37 having LLR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The most common indication was for colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastases</z:e>, and the most common procedure was a non-anatomical metastectomy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Changes in management decisions (n = 14) occurred more frequently during the first era (9 vs. 5; p &gt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>More patients underwent right hepatectomy in the late group (3 vs. 1; p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There did not appear to be any difference in duration of surgery for laparoscopic left lateral resection between the eras (200 vs. 240 min; p &gt; 0.05) which probably reflected trainees performing more operations during the late era </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Left hepatectomy was most commonly performed in the early era compared to more right hepatectomies during the late era </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: LLR is associated with a learning curve, but once this has been overcome it can be safely utilised in the management of malignant liver lesions even for major resections, surgical training and simultaneous resections </plain></SENT>
</text></document>