<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Inflow control prior to transection for right hepatectomy may be achieved either by dissection and ligation of the individual hilar structures outside of the liver (EHD) or by mass stapling of the inflow structures within the hepatic parenchyma </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Our preference is for the anterior intrahepatic approach (AIA) with mass stapling, in order to minimise the risk of inadvertent injury of the left-sided inflow and to preserve as much parenchyma as possible </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In this paper, we present our experience over the last 10 years and compare it with results from the EHD technique </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Data for a 10-year period from 2000 to 2010 were extracted retrospectively from a prospectively collected database </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Results in each group were measured by a combination of technical and oncological outcomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Groups were compared by way of descriptive statistics and differences tested for significance by appropriate statistical means </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 411 right hepatectomies were performed for colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Of these, 242 were by AIA and 169 by EHD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Both groups were well matched in demographic terms and according to disease burden, although more extended resections were performed in the EHD group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Operative duration (433 vs. 350 min), blood loss (420 vs. 348 ml) and incidence of bile leaks (4 vs. 2) were <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> lower in the AIA group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> other technical and oncological outcomes were equivalent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The AIA approach provides equivalent morbidity, mortality and oncological outcome to the EHD dissection technique and may confer the benefits of being safer and providing greater scope to preserve hepatic parenchyma </plain></SENT>
</text></document>