<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> survivors often report comorbid diseases, but there are individual differences in risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Type D personality is a general propensity to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0815107" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">psychological distress</z:e> that is related to poor cardiovascular outcomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In this study, we examined whether type D was also related to comorbidity burden and health care utilization among <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> survivors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Individuals diagnosed with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0476089" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">endometrial cancer</z:e> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> between 1998 and 2007, or with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0006775'>multiple myeloma</z:hpo> between 1999 and 2008 as registered in the Eindhoven <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Registry, received the Self-Administered Comorbidity Questionnaire, questions on health care utilization and the Type D personality scale; 69% (n=3080) responded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Nineteen percent of survivors had a type D personality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Over a 12-month period, type D survivors significantly more often reported <z:hpo ids='HP_0002758'>osteoarthritis</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003418'>back pain</z:hpo>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000716'>depression</z:hpo> than non-type D survivors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Also, type D survivors more often reported to feel bothered by <z:mp ids='MP_0002842'>high blood pressure</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002758'>osteoarthritis</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018799" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">heart disease</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000716'>depression</z:hpo>, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024115" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lung disease</z:e> during daily activities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Type D survivors more often visited their general practitioner than non-type D survivors (P&lt;.001), also in relation to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> (0 visits: 54% vs. 60%; 1-5: 28% vs. 22%; &gt;5: 9% vs. 5%; P&lt;.001), as well as their specialist (0 visits: 6% vs. 7%; 1-5 visits: 59% vs. 64%; &gt;5 visits: 30% vs. 23%; P&lt;.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Type D personality is a vulnerability factor that may help to identify subgroups of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> survivors who are at an increased risk for comorbidity burden and increased health care utilization </plain></SENT>
</text></document>