<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Radiographically small pulmonary nodules (PNs) in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> are troublesome because their discovery raises concern about <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study sought to establish the appropriate timing of radiological follow-up for PNs detected at initial staging evaluation of colorectal <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The medical records of 376 consecutive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> patients who underwent curative surgery and had baseline and follow-up chest X-rays (CXR) and computed tomography (CT) were reviewed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The study included 92 patients who had <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> CXR and chest CT available for review, at least one PN found on baseline imaging, and no synchronous <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasms</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>On baseline chest CT, these 92 patients had 170 PNs altogether and 77 (45.2 %) of them were greater than 5 mm in size </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Baseline CXR detected 13 PNs in 12 patients and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> but 2 were larger than 5 mm </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Nodule size greater than 5 mm and irregular margins were predictors of nodule growth </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The mean doubling time of 24/170 (14.1 %) growing PNs was about 4 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our findings suggest that baseline and follow-up CXR are pointless, and short-interval CT follow-up is warranted when PNs larger than 5 mm with irregular margins are detected on preoperative chest CT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>KEY POINTS: • Pulmonary nodules in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> patients raise concern about <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e>. • Baseline and follow-up chest X-ray in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> can be abandoned. • CT is the best technique for assessing PNs in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>. • Short-interval CT follow-up advisable for PNs larger than 5 mm with irregular margins </plain></SENT>
</text></document>