<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Pathologic response to preoperative chemotherapy for colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastases</z:e> (CLM) is associated with survival after hepatectomy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Histologically, dominant response patterns include <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp>, <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> and/or acellular mucin, but some of these changes can appear without previous chemotherapy and their individual correlation with outcome is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Pathology slides from patients who underwent CLM resection (irrespective of preoperative chemotherapy status) were rereviewed by a blinded pathologist </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Pathologic response was recorded as the summation of percentage <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp>, <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> and acellular mucin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Associations between pathologic response, its components, preoperative chemotherapy, and survival were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Pathology slides were rereviewed in 366 patients undergoing CLM resection from 2003 to 2007 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Preoperative chemotherapy was administered in 249 (68 %) patients, who, when compared to no preoperative chemotherapy patients, had higher rates of overall pathologic response (57 vs. 46 %, P &lt; .01), <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> (21 vs. 12 %, P &lt; .01) and acellular mucin (6 vs. 3 %, P = .05) but similar rates of <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> (30 vs. 31 %, P = .30) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In patients receiving preoperative chemotherapy, overall pathologic response ≥ 75 % (5 year, 83 vs. 47 %, P &lt; .01) and <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp> ≥ 40 % (5 year, 87 vs. 51 %, P &lt; .01) independently correlated with disease-specific survival after hepatectomy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Preoperative hepatic artery infusion chemotherapy (P = .04) and bevacizumab (P = .05) were marginally associated with overall pathologic response and <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>fibrosis</z:mp>, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:mp ids='MP_0003045'>Fibrosis</z:mp> is the predominant chemotherapy-related pathologic alteration driving the association of treatment response with survival after CLM resection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>Necrosis</z:mp> in CLM is not related to chemotherapy or outcome </plain></SENT>
</text></document>