<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Cytoreductive surgery (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRS</z:e>) and intraperitoneal chemotherapy (<z:chebi fb="76" ids="53004">IPC</z:chebi>) treatment of colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1332128" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">peritoneal carcinomatosis</z:e> (PC) is gaining acceptance, but controversy remains </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The primary aims were to analyse the outcome and prognostic variables of colorectal PC patients treated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRS</z:e> and <z:chebi fb="76" ids="53004">IPC</z:chebi>, and to report on the outcome of additional surgical treatments of subsequent recurrences </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Patients referred for treatment of colorectal PC between 1996 and 2010 were included in a cohort </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The following data was collected: clinicopathological parameters, survival, recurrences, perioperative chemotherapy and type of <z:chebi fb="76" ids="53004">IPC</z:chebi> (hyperthermic intraperitoneal chemotherapy, HIPEC; or sequential postoperative intraperitoneal chemotherapy, SPIC) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Multivariable analyses were conducted on potential prognostic factors for overall survival (OS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In the 151-patient cohort, the median OS was 34 months (range: 2-77) for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRS</z:e> and HIPEC with five-year survival predicted at 40% (five-year disease-free survival 32%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRS</z:e> and SPIC, the OS was 25 months (range: 2-188) with five-year survival at 18% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Open-and-close patients survived 6 months (range: 0-14) with no five-year survival (HIPEC vs. SPIC p = 0.047, SPIC vs. open-and-close p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Adjuvant systemic chemotherapy was a noteworthy independent prognostic factor in the multivariable analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>OS for patients undergoing additional surgical treatment of recurrences was 25 months vs. 10 months with best supportive care or palliative chemotherapy (p = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Substantial long-term survival is possible in patients with colorectal PC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>HIPEC was associated with better OS than SPIC and adjuvant systemic chemotherapy may improve the outcome in patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Good OS is achievable in selected patients undergoing additional surgical treatment of isolated liver or peritoneal recurrences after prior complete <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>