<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>C-Jun has been proved as playing an important role in the pathogenesis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e>, as a main component of Activator protein 1 and c-Jun gene polymorphisms are associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, the relationship between the c-Jun gene polymorphism and the susceptibility to <z:hpo ids='HP_0002725'>systemic lupus erythematosus</z:hpo> (SLE) has not been known </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Our purpose is to evaluate whether the c-Jun gene polymorphism (SNP rs3748814) is associated with susceptibility to SLE in a Chinese population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In this study, we enrolled 502 SLE patients and 652 healthy controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The c-Jun polymorphism (rs3748814) was specified from genomic DNA using the TaqMan genotyping assay on a 7300 real-time reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction system </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We found that the frequency of the A/G genotype in SLE patients was lower than in healthy controls, whereas the frequency of the G/G genotype was significantly higher in SLE patients than in healthy controls (A/G vs. G/G p = 8.670e-08, odds ratio [OR] = 0.290, 95% confidence interval [CI] = 0.184-0.456) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In addition, the frequency of allele A in the patients group was significantly lower than in the control group (A vs. G p=5.221e-09, OR = 0.308, 95% CI = 0.212-0.466) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The distribution of genotype and allele frequency in SLE patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024138,C0024141,C0024131,C0409974" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lupus</z:e> <z:hpo ids='HP_0000123'>nephritis</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LN</z:e>) compared with SLE patients without <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LN</z:e> was not statistically significant (A/G vs. G/G p = 0.744, OR = 1.157, 95% CI=0.481-2.785; A vs. G p = 0.748, OR = 1.152, 95% CI = 0.486-2.734; A/A+A/G vs. G/G p = 0.744, OR = 1.157, 95% CI = 0.481-2.785) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, we did not find any significant association between other clinical features and genotypes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Our findings suggest that the c-Jun polymorphism (rs3748814) may be significantly associated with the susceptibility to SLE in a Chinese population </plain></SENT>
</text></document>