<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Neoadjuvant chemotherapy for colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastases</z:e> (CRLM) reduces the accuracy of liver imaging which may understage patients pre-operatively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Retrospective review of a prospective database to determine whether liver-specific magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) prior to pre-operative chemotherapy affects intra-hepatic recurrence and long-term outcome after hepatectomy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: Between 2003 and 2009, 242 patients with CRLM underwent a hepatectomy after ≥3 cycles of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi> or irinotecan-based chemotherapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> had a liver-specific MRI immediately pre-operatively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The outcome of patients who had a liver-specific MRI prior to chemotherapy (PCI group, n= 92) was compared with those who did not (non-PCI group, n= 150) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A liver-specific MRI pre-chemotherapy changed the staging in 56% of patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At a median (range) follow-up of 55 (6-94) months, there was a higher incidence of intra-hepatic recurrence at a new site in the non-PCI group (65% vs. 48% in the PCI group, P= 0.041) and an increased rate of recurrence in patients with the same number of lesions pre- and post-chemotherapy [hazard ratio (HR) 2.02, 1:10-3.37, P= 0.024] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The non-PCI group underwent more repeat hepatectomies than the PCI group (24.7% vs. 13%, P= 0.034), achieving similar long-term survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A liver-specific MRI prior to chemotherapy reduces intra-hepatic recurrence and avoids a repeat hepatectomy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>