<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Clinical observations suggested that a non negligible proportion of patients, ranging from 40% to 70%, does not seem to benefit from the use of anti-EGFR targeted antibodies even in the absence of a mutation of the K- <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> gene </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The EGFR pathway activation via the Ras-Raf-MAP-kinase and the protein-serine/threonine kinase AKT could determine resistance to anti-EGFR treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We tested the interaction between phosphorylated AKT and MAPK expression in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0009404" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal tumours</z:e> and corresponding <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> and global outcome in K-<z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild type</z:mp> patients receiving irinotecan-cetuximab </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Seventy-two patients with histologically proven <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e>, treated with Irinotecan and Cetuximab based chemotherapy, were eligible for our analysis.In <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> pAKT correlated with RR (9% vs. 58%, p = 0.004), PFS (2.3 months vs. 9.2 months p &lt; 0.0001) and OS (6.1 months vs. 26.7 months p &lt; 0.0001) and pMAPK correlated with RR (10% vs. 47%, p = 0.002), PFS (2.3 months vs. 8.6 months p &lt; 0.0001) and OS (7.8 months vs. 26 months p = 0.0004) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At multivariate analysis pAKT and pMAPK in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> were able to independently predict PFS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>pAKT in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> independently correlated with RR as well DISCUSSION: pAKT and pMAPK expression in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> may modulate the activity of EGFR-targeted antibodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We could speculate that in patients with pAKT and pMAPK <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> expression targeting these factors may be crucial </plain></SENT>
</text></document>