<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Synchronous <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastases</z:e> (SLM) occur in 20% of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancers</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Resection of SLM and CLC can be undertaken at different centres (separate management, SM) or at the same centre (global management, GM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Retrospective study of SLM and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> resections carried out during 01/2000 - 12/2006 by SM or GM, using a combined or delayed strategy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Morphologic characteristics and type of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> and SLM resection were similar for the GM (n = 45) or SM (n = 66) groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In patients with delayed liver resection (62 SM, 17 GM), chemotherapy prior to liver surgery was used in 92% and 38% of SM and GM patients (P &lt; 0.0001) and the median delay between procedures was 212 and 182 days, respectively (P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>First step of liver resection was more often performed during colorectal surgery in the GM group (62 vs. 6% for SM, P &lt; 0.0001) and the mean number of procedures (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>+SLM) was lower (1.6 vs. 2.3, P = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Three-month mortality was 3% for GM and 0% for SM (n.s.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Overall survival rates were 67% and 51% for SM and GM at 3 years (n.s.), and 35 and 31% at 5 years (n.s.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Disease-free survival to 5 years was higher in SM patients (14% vs. 11%, P = 0.009) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: GM of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> and SLM was associated with fewer procedures but did not influence overall survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>SM was associated with a longer delay and increased use of chemotherapy between procedures, suggesting that more rigorous selection of SM patients for surgery may explain the higher disease-free survival after SLM resection </plain></SENT>
</text></document>