<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) is the second most common <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> and second most common cause of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>-related <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> in Europe </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening has been proven to reduce disease-specific mortality and several European countries employ national screening programmes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>These almost exclusively rely on stool tests, with endoscopy used as an adjunct in some countries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Computed tomographic colonography (CTC) is a potential screening test, with an estimated sensitivity of 88 % for advanced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo> ≥10 mm </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Recent randomised studies have shown that CTC and colonoscopy have similar yields of advanced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo> per screened invitee, indicating that CTC is potentially viable as a primary screening test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, the evidence is not fully elaborated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>It is unclear whether CTC screening is cost-effective and the impact of extracolonic findings, both medical and economic, remains unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, the effect of CTC screening on <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>-related mortality is unknown, as it is also unknown for colonoscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>It is plausible that both techniques could lead to decreased mortality, as for sigmoidoscopy and gFOBT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Although radiation exposure is a drawback, this disadvantage may be over-emphasised </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, the detection characteristics and acceptability of CTC suggest it is a viable screening investigation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Implementation will depend on detection of extracolonic disease and health-economic impact </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Key Points • Meta-analysis of CT colonographic screening showed high sensitivity for advanced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo> ≥10mm. • CTC, colonoscopy and sigmoidoscopy screening <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> have similar yields for advanced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo>. • Good quality information regarding the cost-effectiveness of CTC screening is lacking. • There is little good quality data regarding the impact of extracolonic findings. • CTC triage is not clinically effective in first round gFOBT/FIT positives </plain></SENT>
</text></document>