<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The aim of our study was to evaluate actual prevalence, uptake and first experiences with a questionnaire developed for early detection of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) in persons with familial/hereditary risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A cross sectional study in an insurance population aged 30-54 years was conducted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Subjects with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>-10 codes C00 to C97 and D37 to D48 were excluded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A standardised questionnaire was sent to 12,139 subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Three months later, subjects with a reported family history were followed by a second questionnaire </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>An additional telephone survey was performed to validate responses </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Nineteen per cent met the inclusion criteria (mean age 45 ± 7 years, 38% men) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Three hundred and seventy-three subjects (16%) were followed by a second questionnaire </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Of these, 248 (66%) returned </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Forty-four per cent were already aware of their increased risk of developing <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Awareness was associated with knowledge of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>One hundred subjects (41%) reported that they had informed their general practitioner (GP) or gastroenterologist </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>A colonoscopy or stool test was recommended to 92 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Subjects who found out about their increased risk for the first time, reported significantly less frequent physician contact (GP: 20% vs. 34%, gastroenterologist: 8% vs. 21%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Results indicate that there is a need for a structured, person at risk-adapted, statutory early detection program </plain></SENT>
</text></document>