<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Colorectal cancer</z:e> is the third most incident <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> and cause of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>-related <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> in the United States </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MicroRNAs, a class of small non-coding <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNAs</z:chebi>, have been implicated in the pathogenesis and prognosis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, although few studies have examined the relationship between germline mutation in the microRNAs with risk and prognosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We therefore investigated the association between a SNP in hsa-mir-608, which lies within the 10q24 locus, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: A cohort consisting of 245 cases and 446 controls was genotyped for rs4919510 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The frequency of the GG genotype was significantly higher in African Americans (15%) compared to Caucasians (3%) controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There was no significant association between rs4919510 and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> risk (African American: OR(GG vs. CC) 0.89 [95% CI, 0.41-1.80]) (Caucasian: OR(GG vs. CC) 1.76, ([95% CI, 0.48-6.39]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, we did observe an association with survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The GG genotype was associated with an increased risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> in Caucasians (HR(GG vs. CC) 3.54 ([95% CI, 1.38-9.12]) and with a reduced risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> in African Americans (HR(GG vs. CC) 0.36 ([95% CI 0.12-1.07) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These results suggest that rs4910510 may be associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> survival in a manner that is dependent on race </plain></SENT>
</text></document>