<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C1167791" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Skin toxicity</z:e> is a frequent adverse event of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) targeting agents </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Occurrence of cetuximab-induced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1167791" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">skin toxicity</z:e> (Cet-ST) correlates with better treatment response and longer survival times </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Molecular markers predicting Cet-ST are still missing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>This investigation analyzed the value of Cet-ST for treatment efficacy in a randomized trial comparing cetuximab plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31348">capecitabine</z:chebi>/irinotecan to cetuximab plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31348">capecitabine</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="31941">oxaliplatin</z:chebi> as first-line treatment of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patient characteristics and molecular parameters (KRAS mutation, EGFR-FISH, EGFR-IHC and EGFR intron-1 polymorphism) of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e> were correlated with response and Cet-ST </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Cet-ST grade 0-1 was observed in 31%, grade 2-3 in 69% of patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Outcome favoured patients with grade 2-3 Cet-ST with regard to overall response rate (62 vs. 41%), PFS (7.8 vs. 5.2 months) and overall survival (OS) (30.3 vs. 18.0 months) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>First-cycle <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0015230" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">rash</z:e> was observed in 66% of patients and corresponded with longer survival (30.7 vs. 20.2 months, p = 0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Patients without Cet-ST had a poor outcome (PFS, 1.9 months; OS, 11 months) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The correlation of Cet-ST with survival was specifically evident in patients with KRAS codon-12-mutated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e> assumed to be cetuximab resistant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In multivariate analysis of patient characteristics, male gender and younger age were significantly correlated with Cet-ST </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Among molecular parameters, no significant correlation with Cet-ST was found </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Cet-ST is an early predictor of treatment efficacy in cetuximab-treated patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>This effect of Cet-ST is independent of the KRAS mutation status, suggesting that Cet-ST rather relates to constitutional factors of the patient than alterations of the EGFR pathway in the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>