<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The purpose of the study was to evaluate the feasibility and efficacy of laparoscopic palliative resection in patients with incurable <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677950" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">stage IV colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We reviewed 100 patients with incurable <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677950" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">stage IV colorectal cancer</z:e> who underwent palliative resection of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e> between 2002 and 2009 at National <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Center Hospital East (NCCHE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Outcomes and postoperative course were compared between patients who underwent open and laparoscopic surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of the 100 patients, 22 were treated with a laparoscopic procedure and 78 underwent an open surgical procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There was no difference in the preoperative characteristics of the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In the laparoscopic group, the mean operation time was significantly longer (177 vs. 148 min, p = 0.007) and the amount of blood loss was significantly lower (166 vs. 361 ml, p = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Postoperative complications occurred in 5 patients (22.7 %) after laparoscopic surgery and in 21 patients (26.9 %) after open surgery, with no significant difference between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Time to flatus, time to start of food intake, and hospital stay were <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> shorter after laparoscopic surgery (3.0 vs. 3.8 days, p = 0.003; 3.6 vs. 5.0 days, p &lt; 0.001; and 12.0 vs. 15.0 days, p = 0.005; respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Significantly more patients in the laparoscopic group had &gt;15 % lymphocytes on postoperative day 7 (p = 0.049) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Overall survival rates were 73.7 and 75.5 % at 1 year after laparoscopic surgery and open surgery, respectively (p = 0.344) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A laparoscopic procedure should be considered for palliative resection of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e> for incurable <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677950" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">stage IV colorectal cancer</z:e>, because the results of this study indicate that the procedure is safe and effective </plain></SENT>
</text></document>