<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: Multidisciplinary teams have become increasingly desirable for managing complex disease but little objective data exist to support this approach </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of our study was to determine the impact of a multidisciplinary clinic on the management of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Data were prospectively collected on <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients with newly diagnosed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> referred to the multidisciplinary clinic at our institution in 2009 and compared to a control group of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients managed outside the clinic from 2008 to 2009 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Comprehensiveness of preoperative evaluation was determined by frequency of abdominal and chest CT, CEA testing, and transrectal ultrasound </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Access to multimodal care was measured by frequency of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>oncology</z:hpo> consultation and treatment, advanced pathology testing, genetics counseling, and trial enrollment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Two hundred eighty-eight patients met inclusion criteria; 88 patients were referred to the clinic (40 preoperative, 48 postoperative) and 200 patients were managed outside </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Complete preoperative evaluation was accomplished three times more frequently in clinic patients (85 vs. 23 %, p &lt; 0.0001) with significant improvements in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> parameters </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Enhanced access to multimodal therapy was demonstrated in clinic patients by increased frequency of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>oncology</z:hpo> consultation (98.9 vs. 61.5 %, p &lt; 0.0001) and treatment (62.5 vs. 41.5 %, p = 0.02), advanced pathology testing (29.6 vs. 10.6 %, p = 0.0001), and genetics counseling (6.8 vs. 1.6 %, p = 0.28) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Clinic patients also received significantly higher rates of neoadjuvant therapy for stage II or greater <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007113" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">rectal cancer</z:e> (82.6 vs. 30.9 %, p = 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Multidisciplinary clinic management of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> is associated with a significantly more complete preoperative evaluation as well as improved access to multimodal therapy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>