<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Over 50% of patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) will progress and/or develop <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Biomarkers capable of predicting progression, risk stratification and therapeutic benefit are needed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> stem cells are thought to be responsible for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0598935" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor initiation</z:e>, dissemination and treatment failure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Therefore, we hypothesized that <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> stem cell markers (CRCSC) will identify a group of patients at high risk for progression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Paraffin-embedded tissue cores of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> (n=8), and histopathologically well-defined primary (n= 30) and metastatic (n=10) <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> were arrayed in duplicate on tissue microarrays (<z:chebi fb="39" ids="18139,53050">TMAs</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Expression profiles of non-CD133 CRCSC (CD29, CD44, ALDH1A1, ALDH1B1, EpCam, and CD166) were detected by immunohistochemistry and the association with clinicopathological data and patient outcomes was determined using standard statistical methodology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>An independent pathologist, blinded to the clinical data scored the samples </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Scoring included percent positive cells (0 to 4, 0 = &lt;10%, 1 = 10 - 24%, 2 = 25 - 49%, 3 = 50 - 74%, 4 = 75 - 100%), and the intensity of positively stained cells (0 to 4; 0 = no staining, 1 = diminutive intensity, 2 = low intensity, 3 = intermediate intensity, 4 = high intensity) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The pathologic score represents the sum of these two values, reported in this paper as a combined IHC staining score (CSS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of 30 patients 7 were AJCC stage IIA, 10 stage IIIB, 7 stage IIIC and 6 stage IV </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Median follow-up was 113 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>DFI was 17 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Median overall survival (OS) was not reached </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Stage-specific OS was: II - not reached; III - not reached; IV - 11 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>In a univariate analysis, poor OS was associated with loss of CD29 expression; median OS, 32 months vs. not reached for CSS 3-7 vs. &gt;7.5, respectively; p=0.052 comparing entire curves, after adjustment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>In a Cox model analysis, loss of CD29 exhibited a trend toward association with survival (p=0.098) after adjusting for the effect of stage (p=0.0076) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Greater expression of ALDH1A1 was associated with increasing stage (p=0.042 over stages 2, 3b, 3c, and 4) while loss of CD29 expression exhibited a trend toward being associated with stages 3 and 4 (p=0.08) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>Compared to <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> colon tissue, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumors</z:e> were associated with increased expression of ALDH1B1 (p=0.008) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>ALD1H1B1 expression level differed according to whether the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> was moderately or poorly differentiated, well differentiated, or mucinous; the highest expression levels were associated with moderately or poorly differentiated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> (p=0.011) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="19" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0686619" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Lymph node metastases</z:e> were associated with a trend toward decreased expression of EpCAM (p = 0.06) when comparing 0 vs. 1 vs. 2+ positive lymph nodes, as was CD29 (p = 0.08) when comparing 0 vs. any positive lymph nodes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="20" pm="."><plain>Compared to <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> colon tissue metastatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancers</z:hpo> from different patients were associated with increased ALDH1B1 expression (p=0.001) whereas CD29 expression was higher in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> colonic tissue (p=0.014) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="21" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: CD29 may be associated with survival as well as clinical stage and number of lymph nodes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="22" pm="."><plain>ALDH1B1 expression was associated with differentiation as well as type of tissue evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="23" pm="."><plain>ALDH1A1 was associated with clinical stage, and decreased EpCAM expression was found in patients with advanced lymph node stage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="24" pm="."><plain>CRCSCs may be useful biomarkers to risk stratify, and estimate outcomes in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="25" pm="."><plain>Larger prospective studies are required to validate the current findings </plain></SENT>
</text></document>