<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To examine public perceptions of and preferences for colonoscopy vs. CT colonography (CTC) as technologies for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) screening </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Six discussion groups were carried out with 30 adults aged 49-60 years (60% female) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Information about different aspects of the tests (e.g. sensitivity, practical issues) was presented sequentially using a semi-structured, step-by-step topic guide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Discussions were recorded and analyzed using framework analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: CTC was favored on the parameters of invasiveness, extra-colonic evaluation and interference with daily life, whereas sensitivity, avoiding false-positives and the capacity to remove <z:mpath ids='MPATH_491'>polyps</z:mpath> immediately were perceived to be important advantages of colonoscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Ultimately, there was no strong preference for either test: with 46% preferring colonoscopy vs. 42% for CTC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: With comprehensive information, colonoscopy and CTC were seen as having different advantages and disadvantages, yielding no clear preferences between the two </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The sensitivity of colonoscopy was a decisive factor for some people, but the lower invasiveness of CTC was seen as an asset in the screening context </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>PRACTICE IMPLICATIONS: CTC may be an acceptable alternative to colonoscopy in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Healthcare professionals working in the screening context should be sensitive to the range of characteristics that can determine preferences for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening tests </plain></SENT>
</text></document>