<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="?"><plain>Study Type - Diagnostic (exploratory cohort) Level of Evidence 3a What's known on the subject? and What does the study add </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Hereditary non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0334108" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">polyposis</z:e> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (HNPCC), also known as <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0009405" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Lynch syndrome</z:e>, is an <z:hpo ids='HP_0000006'>autosomal dominant</z:hpo> multi-organ <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> syndrome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Upper urinary tract urothelial <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinomas</z:mp> belong to HNPCC-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e> and rank third within this group after colorectal and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0476089" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">endometrial cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>However, many urologists are not aware of this association and it is presumed that some <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1333600" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">hereditary cancers</z:e> are misclassified as <z:hpo ids='HP_0003745'>sporadic</z:hpo> and that their incidence is underestimated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Consequently, family members of patients with upper urinary tract urothelial <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinomas</z:mp> secondary to HNPCC may be denied appropriate surveillance and early detection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A significant proportion of patients (21.3%) with newly diagnosed upper urinary tract urothelial <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinomas</z:mp> may have underlying HNPCC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Demographic and epidemiological characteristics suggest different mechanisms of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0596263" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">carcinogenesis</z:e> among this population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Recognition of such potential is essential for appropriate clinical and genetic management of patients and family </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In order to help to identify these patients, we propose a patient-specific checklist </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: •  To identify, based on previously described clinical criteria, hereditary upper urinary tract urothelial <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinomas</z:mp> (UUT-UCs) that are likely to be misclassified as <z:hpo ids='HP_0003745'>sporadic</z:hpo> although they may belong to the spectrum of hereditary non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0334108" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">polyposis</z:e> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (HNPCC) associated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancers</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: •  We identified, using established clinical criteria, suspected hereditary UUT-UC among 1122 patients included in the French national database for UUT-UC. •  Patients were considered at risk for hereditary status in the following situations: age at diagnosis &lt;60 years with no previous history of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0005684" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">bladder cancer</z:e>; previous history of HNPCC-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> regardless of age; one first-degree relative with HNPCC-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> diagnosed before 50 years of age or two first-degree relatives diagnosed regardless of age </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: •  Overall, 239 patients (21.3%) were considered to be at risk of hereditary UUT-UC. •  Compared with <z:hpo ids='HP_0003745'>sporadic</z:hpo> cases, hereditary cases are more likely to be female (P= 0.047) with less exposure to tobacco (P= 0.012) and occupational carcinogens (P= 0.037) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>A greater proportion of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e> were located in the renal pelvis (54.5% vs 48.4%; P= 0.026) and were lower grade (40% vs 30.1%; P= 0.015) in the hereditary cohort. •  The overall, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>-specific and recurrence-free survival rates were similar in both cohorts. •  We propose a patient-specific risk identification tool </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: •  A significant proportion (21.3%) of patients with newly diagnosed UUT-UC may have underlying HNPCC as a cause. •  Recognition of such potential and application of a patient-specific checklist upon diagnosis will allow identification and appropriate clinical and genetic management for patient and family </plain></SENT>
</text></document>