<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Gastrin has been shown to exert carcinogenic effect to the epithelium of the colon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study examines whether hypergastrinemia and H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> -especially <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> by the CagA+ strain- are statistically associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> and examine possible correlations with the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> stage and lymph node <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In this prospective case-control study, fasting serum samples from 93 consecutive patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> treated in a university surgical clinic were preoperatively collected and serum levels of gastrin were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A group of 20 age matched <z:hpo ids='HP_0100790'>hernia</z:hpo> patients were used as controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The pathology report of the specimens was documented and statistical analysis of the data where performed with the spss 17 statistical suite </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: H. pylori IgG antibodies was reported in 66/93 (71%) in the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> group and 13/20 patients in the control group (65%), the difference having non-statistical significance (P = n.s) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of cagA protein expression in the anti- H. pylori IgG+ patients were higher in the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> group (56% positivity), when compared to the control group (38,4% positivity) but the difference was not of statistical significance (P = n.s) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The mean levels of serum gastrin levels in the two groups did not significantly differ (Ca group 51.1 ± 36.6 pg/mL vs Control 49.8 ± 17.6 P = n.s.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Patients with lymph node <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> had higher serum gastrin levels than patients without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> and this difference was statistically significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>(53.6 vs 41.06 pg/mL P = 0.025) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Although the serum gastrin levels were not statistically different between the TNM stages of our patient cohort, our data found that serum gastrin levels were significantly higher in patients with lymph node <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Whether gastrin is implicated in the ability of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> cells to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasize</z:e> to the lymph nodes merits further research </plain></SENT>
</text></document>