<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The aim of this study was to evaluate the feasibility and conferred protection against recurrence of preoperatively administered tegafur suppositories following the intravenous and oral administration of fluoropyrimidine in a multicenter randomized control trial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Patients with clinical T3/4 colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> were randomly assigned to receive the preoperative administration of tegafur suppositories (group A) or no preoperative treatment (group B) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The primary end points were disease-free survival (DFS) and overall survival (OS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The mean follow-up periods were 80.9 ± 31.0 months in group A and 64.5 ± 28.8 months in group B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The 5-year DFS rates were 89.3% in group A and 70.3% in group B (p = 0.045), whereas the 5-year OS rates were 91.4% in group A and 73.2% in group B (p = 0.051) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, a significant difference in the cumulative distant metastatic rate was observed (group A, 7.4% vs. group B, 23.4%; p = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, no significant difference in the cumulative local recurrence rate was seen (group A, 4.6% vs. group B, 8.2%; p = 0.68) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Despite a relatively small sample size, preoperative tegafur suppositories might protect recurrences and improve survival rates, mainly by preventing distant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>These findings suggest the utility of tegafur suppositories as an alternative neoadjuvant treatment in modern chemotherapy for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>