<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="25297">Methylenetetrahydrofolate</z:chebi> reductase (MTHFR) is believed to be involved in <z:chebi fb="3" ids="37445">folate</z:chebi> metabolism which plays a critical role in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0596263" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">carcinogenesis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To date, many case-control studies have investigated the association between MTHFR C677T polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, the results were inconsistent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In order to derive a more precise estimation of the association, we conducted this meta-analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>This meta-analysis recruited 61 published studies which were selected by a search of PubMed up to 31st September 2011, including 16,111 colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> cases and 23,192 controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We used crude odds ratios (ORs) with 95 % confidence intervals (CIs) to assess the association between MTHFR C677T polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> susceptibility </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Our results showed that MTHFR C667T polymorphism contributed to the decreased <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> risk in overall population (for TT vs. CC: OR = 0.89, 95 % CI = 0.82-0.97; for TT vs. CT/CC: OR = 0.88, 95 % CI = 0.83-0.92) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In subgroup analysis by ethnicity, the results also indicated a correlation between the T allele of MTHFR C667T and the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> risk in Asian population (for TT vs. CC: OR = 0.82, 95 % CI = 0.69-0.97; for TT vs. CT/CC: OR = 0.81, 95 % CI = 0.74-0.90) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Additionally, the correlation was also observed in male subgroup in sub-analysis by gender (for TT vs. CC: OR = 0.82, 95 % CI = 0.71-0.93; for TT vs. CT/CC: OR = 0.81, 95 % CI = 0.71-0.92) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In summary, our meta-analysis strongly indicated the MTHFR C667T polymorphism was associated with a reduced risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>