<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Screening colonoscopy effectiveness is hampered by limited adherence by the general population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The present prospective study was performed to evaluate whether adding capsule colonoscopy to the endoscopic screening options increases uptake </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Invitation letters were sent to 2150 persons above the age of 55 insured with a German medical insurance company in the area of Rinteln, Lower Saxony with a baseline spontaneous annual screening colonoscopy uptake of 1 % </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Both capsule or conventional colonoscopy were offered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Interested persons were given information about the two screening options by four local gastroenterologists and examinations were then performed according to screenees' final choice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 154 persons sought further information, and 34 and 90 underwent conventional and capsule colonoscopy, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Colonoscopy uptake was thus increased by the invitation process by 60 % (1.6 % vs. 1 %; p = 0.075), while the option of capsule endoscopy led to a fourfold increase of screening uptake (4.2 % vs. 1 %, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Despite similar age distribution in both sex groups, uptake in men was significantly higher (5.6 % vs. 2.8 %, p = 002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, overall <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> yield was not different in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The present study suggests that offering the option of capsule colonoscopy increases uptake of endoscopic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> screening </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>However, capsule endoscopy sensitivity for <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> detection needs to be improved </plain></SENT>
</text></document>