<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Background/Aims: Using genome-wide case-control association approach, the current study aimed to determine whether genetic polymorphism(s) is/are associated with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> among ethnic Malays from the north-eastern region of Peninsular Malaysia, a region with an exceptionally low prevalence for H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Methodology: Twenty-three Malay subjects positive for H. pylori confirmed with urease test and histology were enrolled as "cases" and 37 subjects negative for H. pylori were "controls" </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Both groups were matched for age and environmental risks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Extracted DNA samples (QIAGEN, Germany) from the venous blood of study subjects were genotyped using the Human Mapping 50k xba1 array (Affymetrix, USA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>High throughput downstream analyses were then used to determine the significant SNP(s) associated with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Results: Out of 20,361 SNPs filtered using the genotype association test, the top 1% (203) significant SNPs were selected for functional enrichment analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Of the 15 "enriched" SNPs, the rs10502974 which was located within the intronic region of Deleted in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Colorectal Cancer</z:e> (<z:chebi fb="8" ids="53090">DCC</z:chebi>) gene was the SNP most significantly associated with H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> (p=0.00549) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: Ethnic Malays is genetically susceptible to H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and is possibly mediated through a genetic variation in the <z:chebi fb="8" ids="53090">DCC</z:chebi> gene </plain></SENT>
</text></document>