<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Probiotics have been shown to have a preventative role in colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0596263" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">carcinogenesis</z:e> but research concerning their prophylactic potential in the later stages of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, specifically <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> is limited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study explored the potential of cell-free supernatants (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CFS</z:e>) from 2 probiotic Lactobacillus sp., Lactobacillus casei and Lactobacillus rhamnosus GG, to inhibit <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> cell invasion by influencing matrix metalloproteinase-9 (MMP-9) activity and levels of the tight junction protein <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019360" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="ZONA">zona</z:e> occludens-1 (ZO-1) in cultured metastatic human colorectal <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>HCT-116 cells were treated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CFS</z:e> from L. casei, L. rhamnosus, or Bacteroides thetaiotaomicron (a gut commensal); or with uninoculated <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> growth media </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Treatment with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CFS</z:e> from both Lactobacillus sp. decreased colorectal cell invasion but treatment with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CFS</z:e> from B. thetaiotaomicron did not </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CFS</z:e> from both Lactobacillus sp. decreased MMP-9 and increased ZO-1 protein levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>L. rhamnosus <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CFS</z:e> also lowered MMP-9 activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>To begin elucidating the secreted <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> factor conveying these responses, Lactobacillus sp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CFS</z:e> were fractionated into defined molecular weight ranges and cell invasion assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Fractionation revealed that the inhibitory activity was contained primarily in the &gt;100 kDa and 50-100 kDa fractions, suggesting the inhibitory compound may be a <z:chebi fb="4" ids="33839">macromolecule</z:chebi> such as a protein, nucleic acid, or a <z:chebi fb="5" ids="18154">polysaccharide</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>