<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND STUDY AIMS: We compared the performance efficiency of a newly developed small-caliber colonoscope (PCF-PQ260 L) with passive bending, high force transmission, and an outer diameter of 9.2 mm with that of a standard colonoscope, in female and male patients, particularly with regard to passage through <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> angulations or into the proximal colon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: A total of 330 patients were randomly allocated to undergo small-caliber (n = 164) or standard (n = 166) colonoscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The patients were assessed for pain using a visual analogue scale (0 = none, 100 = extremely painful), and for cecal intubation, withdrawal time, difficulty of colonoscopy, dosage and level of sedation used, and any complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Median maximum pain and overall pain during colonoscopy were significantly lower in the small-caliber group than in the standard group in women (25 vs. 45, P &lt; 0.001 and 15 vs. 26, P = 0.001, respectively), whereas no significant differences were seen in men (8 vs. 10, P = 0.103 and 16 vs. 20, P = 0.166, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, no significant differences were seen between groups in cecal intubation rate or time to cecum in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients or by sex </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Use of the small-caliber colonoscope reduced pain in female patients, but offered no advantage over standard colonoscopy in male patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The performance of the small-caliber colonoscope was equivalent to that of the standard colonoscope in terms of cecal intubation rate and time to cecum, regardless of the sex of the patient </plain></SENT>
</text></document>