<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Outcome after hepatic resection for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastases</z:e> (CRLM) is <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneous</z:hpo> and accurate predictors of survival are lacking </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study analyzes the prognostic relevance of pathologic details of the primary <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0009404" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal tumor</z:e> in patients undergoing hepatic resection for CRLM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Retrospective review of a prospective database identified patients who underwent resection for CRLM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Clinicopathological variables were investigated and their association with outcome was analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: From 1997-2007, 1,004 patients underwent hepatic resection for CRLM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The median follow-up was 59 months with a 5-year survival of 47% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Univariate analysis identified nine factors associated with poor survival; three of these related to the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e>: lymphovascular invasion (LVI, p&lt;0.0001), perineural invasion (p=0.005), and degree of regional lymph node involvement (N0 vs. N1 vs. N2, p&lt;0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis identified seven factors associated with poor survival, two of which related to the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e>: LVI (hazard ratio (HR) 1.3, 95% confidence interval (CI) 1.06-1.64, p=0.01) and degree of regional lymph node involvement [N1 (HR 1.3, 95% CI 1.04-1.69, p=0.02) vs. N2 (HR 1.7, 95% CI 1.27-2.21, p&lt;0.0005)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A significant decrease in survival along the spectrum of patients ranging from LVI negative/N0 to LVI positive/N2 was present </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Patients who were LVI-positive/N2 had a median survival of 40 months compared with 74 months for patients who were LVI-negative/NO (p&lt;0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Histopathologic details of the primary <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0009404" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal tumor</z:e>, particularly LVI and the detailed assessment of the degree of lymph node involvement, are strong predictors of survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Future biomarker studies should consider exploring factors related to the primary <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0009404" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal tumor</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>