<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To examine the association between Type D personality and illness perceptions among <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> survivors 1-10years post-diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Data from two population-based surveys on <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> survivors was used </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients diagnosed between 1998 and 2009, as registered in the Eindhoven <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Registry, received a questionnaire on Type D personality (DS14) and illness perceptions (B-IPQ); 81% (n=3977) responded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 750 (19%) patients had a Type D personality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>They believe their illness has significantly more serious consequences, will last significantly longer, and experience significantly more symptoms that they attribute to their illness </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Also, they are more concerned about their illness, and their disease more often influences them emotionally </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Differences regarding 'consequences', 'concern' and 'emotional response' were also clinically relevant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The majority of patients stated that the cause of their disease was unknown (23.3%), hereditary (20.3%), lifestyle (15.1%), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0815107" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">psychological distress</z:e> (11.9%) or other (11.6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Significant differences in perceptions on cause of disease between Type Ds and non-Type Ds were found for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0815107" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">psychological distress</z:e> (16.2 vs. 10.9%; p&lt;0.01), randomness (1.7 vs. 5.3%; p&lt;0.01) and unknown (18.8 vs. 24.4%; p&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analyses showed that Type D was negatively associated with 'coherence' and positively with 'consequences', 'timeline', 'identity', 'concern', and 'emotional representation' </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These results elucidate the associations between personality and illness perceptions, demonstrating their close interrelatedness </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Our study may be helpful in further developing theoretical models regarding giving meaning to illness and the illness perceptions that the illness elicits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Future studies should investigate whether interventions can positively impact illness perceptions of Type D <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>