<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: The continued growth in the number of elderly with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> and age-related <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> diseases will cause in Poland an increase in demand for palliative care </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of the study was to identify <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> comorbidities and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> types in palliative home care patients and to compare their incidence with the general Polish population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL AND METHODS: The data was obtained from 543 patients who received palliative home care between 2005-2009 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The occurrence of the most common <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> conditions such as arterial <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0151744" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IHD">ischemic heart disease</z:e>, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024115" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pulmonary diseases</z:e> and central <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system diseases were analysed together with the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> types </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The study group included 259 women (47.7%) and 284 men (52.3%) aged 25-91 years old </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The most common primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasm</z:hpo> locations for men were lung (28.2% vs. 21.4% in general population) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (18.7% vs. 11.4% in general population), and in women breast (19.7% vs. 22.8% in general population) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (17.4% vs. 9.2% in general population) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0151744" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IHD">ischemic heart disease</z:e>, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024115" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pulmonary diseases</z:e> was significantly different in comparison to the general populations (47.0% vs. 11.3%; 20.3% vs. 6.8%; 16.6% vs. 27.5%, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The mean number of concomitant diseases was 1.6 for women and 1.8 for men vs. 1.7 and 1.2 in the general Polish population respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The majority of the patients had concomitant disease, with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular diseases</z:e> being most common </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The most common primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasm</z:hpo> diagnoses in palliative home care patients were lung and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, which corresponds to the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> prevalence in the general population </plain></SENT>
</text></document>