<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) screening is underutilized </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Effective and efficient interventions are needed to increase its utilization in primary care </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We used UNC Internal Medicine electronic medical records to perform 2 effectiveness trials </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Eligible patients had no documentation of recent <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening and were aged 50-75 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The mailed intervention contained a letter documenting the need for screening signed by the attending physician in wave A and the practice director in wave B, a postcard to request a decision aid about <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening options, and information about how to obtain screening </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULT: Three-hundred and forty patients of attending physicians in wave A, 944 patients of resident physicians in wave B, and 214 patients of attending physicians in wave B were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The intervention increased screening compared with controls for attending physicians' patients in wave A (13.1% vs. 4.1%, 95% CI, 3.1%-14.9%) but not for resident physicians' patients in wave B (1.3% vs. 1.9%, 95% CI, -2.2% to 1.0%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A small increase in screening with the intervention was seen in attending physicians' patients in wave B (6.9% vs. 2.4%, 95% CI, -1.4% to 10.5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Requests for decision <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">aids</z:e> were uncommon in both waves (12.5% wave A and 7.8% wave B) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>LIMITATIONS: The group assignments were not individually randomized, and covariate information to explain the differences in effect was limited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The intervention increased <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening in attending physicians' patients who received a letter from their physicians, but not resident physicians' patients who received a letter signed by the practice director </plain></SENT>
</text></document>