<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: We evaluated the association between a KRAS mutational status and various clinicopathologic features including the metastatic pattern in patients with metastatic or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0854750" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">recurrent colorectal cancer</z:e> (MRCRC) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The concordance rates of the KRAS status between <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e> sites and paired metastatic organs were also analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The KRAS mutational status in codons 12, 13, and 61 from formalin-fixed sections of both <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumors</z:e> and related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> was determined by sequencing analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>One hundred forty-three Korean patients with MRCRC with available tissues (resection or biopsy) from both <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumors</z:e> and related metastatic sites were consecutively enrolled </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The KRAS mutation rate was 52.4% (75/143) when considering both the primary and metastatic sites </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>When the relationship between the KRAS status and initial metastatic sites at the time of diagnosis of MRCRC was analyzed, lung <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> was more frequent as the initial metastatic site in patients with the KRAS mutation than in patients without the KRAS mutation (45.3% vs. 22.1%; P = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, liver (37.3% vs. 70.6%; P &lt; 0.001) or distant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0686619" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">lymph node metastases</z:e> (6.7% vs. 19.1%; P = 0.025) were less frequent as the initial metastatic organ in patients with the KRAS mutation than in patients without the KRAS mutation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The discordance rate of KRAS mutational status between primary and paired metastatic sites other than the lung was 12.3% (13/106) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Compared with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e> sites, the KRAS discordance rate was significantly higher in matched <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0153676" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">lung metastases</z:e> [32.4% (12/37)] than in other matched metastatic organs (P = 0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Organs initially involved by distant <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> were different according to the KRAS mutational status in MRCRC patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The concordance rate (87.7%) of the KRAS mutation status at metastatic sites other than the lung was generally high compared with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e> sites; however, lung <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> had a high rate of KRAS discordance (32.4%) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>