<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="?"><plain>UNLABELLED: Study Type--Therapy (case series) Level of Evidence 4 What's known on the subject? and What does the study add </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Radiation Therapy for <z:hpo ids='HP_0012125'>prostate cancer</z:hpo> can increase the risk for the development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0751623" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">second cancers</z:e> after treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study highlights the fact that such <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0751623" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">second cancers</z:e> within the pelvis do occur but are not as common as previously reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In this report we also note that even among patients who develop <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0751623" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">second cancers</z:e>, if detected earlier, the majority are alive 5 years after the diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: • To report on the incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0751623" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">secondary malignancy</z:e> (SM) development after external beam radiotherapy (EBRT) and brachytherapy (BT) for <z:hpo ids='HP_0012125'>prostate cancer</z:hpo> and to compare this with a cohort contemporaneously treated with radical prostatectomy (RP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: • Between 1998 and 2001, 2658 patients with localized <z:hpo ids='HP_0012125'>prostate cancer</z:hpo> were treated with RP (n = 1348), EBRT (n = 897) or BT (n = 413). • Using the RP cohort as a control we compared the incidence of SMs, such as rectal or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0005684" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">bladder cancers</z:e> noted within the pelvis, and the incidence of extrapelvic SMs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: • The 10-year SM-free survival for the RP, BT and EBRT cohorts were 89%, 87%, and 83%, respectively (RP vs EBRT, P = 0.002; RP vs BT, P = 0.37). • The 10-year likelihoods for bladder or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> SM development in the RP, BT and EBRT groups were 3%, 2% and 4%, respectively (P = 0.29). • Multivariate analysis of predictors for development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> SMs showed that older age (P = 0.01) and history of smoking (P &lt; 0.001) were significant predictors for the development of a SM, while treatment intervention was not found to be a significant variable. • Among 243 patients who developed a SM, the 5-year likelihood of SM-related mortality among patients with SMs in the EBRT and BT groups was 43.7% and 15.6%, respectively, compared with 26.3% in the RP cohort; P = 0.052) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: • The incidence of SM after radiotherapy was not significantly different from that after RP when adjusted for patient age and smoking history. • The incidence of bladder and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007113" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">rectal cancers</z:e> was low for both EBRT- and BT-treated patients. • Among patients who developed a SM, the likelihood of mortality related to the SM was not significantly different among the treatment cohorts </plain></SENT>
</text></document>