<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0009405" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Lynch syndrome</z:e> (LS), or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1333990" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">hereditary nonpolyposis colorectal cancer</z:e>, is caused by mutations in mismatch repair (MMR) genes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>An increased risk for upper tract urothelial <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> (UTUC) has been described in this population; however, data regarding the risk for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0005684" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">bladder cancer</z:e> (BCa) are sparse </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To assess the risk of BCa in MMR mutation carriers and suggest screening and management recommendations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> data from 1980 to 2007 were obtained from the Familial <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0685938" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Gastrointestinal Cancer</z:e> Registry in Toronto for 321 persons with known MMR mutations: mutL homolog 1, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo>, nonpolyposis type 2 (E. coli) (MLH1); mutS homolog 2, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo>, nonpolyposis type 1 (E. coli) (MSH2); mutS homolog 6 (E. coli) (MSH6); and PMS2 postmeiotic segregation increased 2 (S. cerevisiae) (PMS2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>OUTCOME MEASUREMENTS AND STATISTICAL ANALYSIS: Standardized incidence ratios from the Ontario <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Registry, using the Surveillance Epidemiology and End Results public database, were used to compare <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> risk in patients with MMR mutations with the Canadian population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Microsatellite instability analysis and immunohistochemistry (IHC) of the MMR proteins were also performed and the results compared with matched <z:hpo ids='HP_0003745'>sporadic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0005695" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">bladder tumors</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS AND LIMITATIONS: Eleven of 177 patients with MSH2 mutations (6.21%, p&lt;0.001 compared with the Canadian population) were found to have BCa, compared with 3 of 129 patients with MLH1 mutations (2.32%, p&gt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Of these 11 tumors, 81.8% lacked expression of MSH2 on IHC, compared with the matched <z:hpo ids='HP_0003745'>sporadic</z:hpo> cases, which <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> displayed <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> expression of MSH2 and MLH1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The incidence of UTUC among MSH2 carriers was 3.95% (p&lt;0.001), and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> were found to be deficient in MSH2 expression on IHC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Mutations in the intron 5 splice site and exon 7 of the MSH2 gene increased the risk of urothelial <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Limitations include possible inflated risk estimates due to ascertainment bias </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: LS patients with MSH2 mutations are at an increased risk for not only UTUC but also BCa and could be offered appropriate screening </plain></SENT>
</text></document>