<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: We compared oncologic outcomes of laparoscopic surgery following self-expandable metallic stent (SEMS) insertion with one-stage emergency surgical treatment of obstructive left-sided colon and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007113" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">rectal cancers</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: From April 1996 to October 2007, 95 consecutive patients with left-sided obstructive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancers</z:e> were included: 25 underwent preoperative stenting and elective laparoscopic surgery (SLAP) and 70 underwent emergency open surgery with intraoperative colon lavage (OLAV) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Long-term oncologic outcomes were analyzed on an intention-to-treat basis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were no significant differences in baseline characteristics of patients between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Perineural invasion of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e> was more frequent with SLAP (76 vs. 51.4 %, p = 0.033) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The median follow-up was 51 months (range, 4-139 months) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were no significant differences between groups in 5-year overall survival rates (SLAP vs. OLAV, 67.2 vs. 61.6 %, p = 0.385) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Five-year disease-free survival rates were also similar between groups (SLAP vs. OLAV, 61.2 vs. 60.0 %, p = 0.932) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Laparoscopic surgery after SEMS was feasible and safe for patients with obstructive left-sided <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, and oncologic outcomes were comparable to emergency open surgery with intraoperative colon lavage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These results support the continued use of SLAP in this setting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Further large-scale study is needed to investigate any clinical impact attached to the higher rates of perineural invasion observed in SLAP </plain></SENT>
</text></document>