<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The occurrence of <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> after ileal pouch-anal anastomosis for <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> (UC) is an infrequent but potentially lethal complication </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Neither histomorphologic nor molecular features of pouch <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> after ileal pouch-anal anastomosis have been fully investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We report the largest series of 12 pouch and peripouch <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinomas</z:mp> and compared them with 58 randomly selected UC-associated <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinomas</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The mean age of patients with pouch/peripouch <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> was 55.2 years (SD 14.8), which was not significantly different from that of controls (P=0.52) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Pouch/peripouch <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> and UC-associated <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> had a comparable frequency of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e>-infiltrating lymphocytes, lack of dirty <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp>, mucin differentiation, signet ring cell differentiation, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo>, and well differentiation (P&gt;0.05 for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Pouch/peripouch <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> was more likely to show Crohn-like reaction compared with UC-associated <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> (P=0.047) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Loss of at least 1 mismatch repair protein was noted in 9% of pouch/peripouch <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinomas</z:mp> and 9.6% of UC-related <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinomas</z:mp> (P=1.0) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference in the frequency of p53 overexpression (36.4% vs. 61.1%, P=0.184) or nuclear immunoreactivity for β-catenin (9% vs. 7.4%, P=0.99) in pouch/peripouch versus UC-associated <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinomas</z:mp>, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Pouch/peripouch and UC-associated <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> had a comparable positive rate for CK7 (54.5% vs. 55.5%, P=0.99), CK20 (100% vs. 98.1%, P=0.99), and CDX2 (72.8% vs. 72.2%, P=0.99) by immunohistochemistry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In summary, pouch and peripouch <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> can occur in patients without colorectal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasia</z:hpo> and in those with idiopathic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021390" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory bowel disease</z:e>, can be potentially lethal, and has histomorphologic and molecular features similar to those of UC-associated <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>