<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Most <z:hpo ids='HP_0003745'>sporadic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (sCRC) <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> are caused by metastatic dissemination of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>New advances in genetic profiling of sCRC suggest that the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumor</z:e> may contain a cell population with metastatic potential </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Here we compare the cytogenetic profile of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumors</z:e> from liver metastatic versus non-metastatic sCRC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODOLOGY/PRINCIPAL FINDINGS: We prospectively analyzed the frequency of numerical/structural abnormalities of chromosomes 1, 7, 8, 13, 14, 17, 18, 20, and 22 by iFISH in 58 sCRC patients: thirty-one non-metastatic (54%) vs. 27 metastatic (46%) disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>From a total of 18 probes, significant differences emerged only for the 17p11.2 and 22q11.2 chromosomal regions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Patients with liver metastatic sCRC showed an increased frequency of del(17p11.2) (10% vs. 67%;p&lt;.001) and del(22q11.2) (0% vs. 22%;p = .02) versusnon-metastatic cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis of prognostic factors for overall survival (OS) showed that the only clinical and cytogenetic parameters that had an independent adverse impact on patient outcome were the presence of del(17p) with a 17p11.2 breakpoint and del(22q11.2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Based on these two cytogenetic variables, patients were classified into three groups: low- (no adverse features), intermediate- (one adverse feature) and high-risk (two adverse features)- with significantly different OS rates at 5-years (p&lt;.001): 92%, 53% and 0%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS/SIGNIFICANCE: Our results unravel the potential implication of del(17p11.2) in sCRC patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastasis</z:e> as this cytogenetic alteration appears to be intrinsically related to an <z:mp ids='MP_0001272'>increased metastatic potential</z:mp> and a poor outcome, providing additional prognostic information to that associated with other cytogenetic alterations such as del(22q11.2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Additional prospective studies in larger series of patients would be required to confirm the clinical utility of the new prognostic markers identified </plain></SENT>
</text></document>