<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The human population at large is exposed to many critical factors (e.g. bad food habits, chemical substances, and stress) leading to the development of serious diseases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Colon or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> is one of the most prevalent types of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> in many countries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Despite being a multi-factorial <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> disease, resulting from the interaction of multiple genetic and environmental factors, the critical factor is mostly a poor diet regimen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Therefore, an accumulation of constant mutations leads to a complex arrangement of events during <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0598935" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor initiation</z:e>, development and propagation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>It is well known that many plants are rich in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26195">polyphenols</z:chebi> with anti-oxidant, anti-atherogenic, anti-diabetic, anti-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>, anti-<z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp>, and anti-inflammatory properties </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>These compounds are <z:chebi fb="1" ids="26619">secondary metabolites</z:chebi> with the ability to donate electrons to free radicals through different mechanisms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In recent years, a large number of studies have attributed a protective effect to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26195">polyphenols</z:chebi> and foods containing these compounds (e.g. plants, vegetables, cereals, tea, coffee or chocolate) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Polyphenolic compounds have been described to inhibit <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> development and propagation, being used as chemopreventive agents </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Some <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26195">polyphenols</z:chebi> reported a preventive action against <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo>, e.g. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="3962">curcumin</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="30778">gallic acid</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="1" ids="4775">ellagic acid</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4806">epigallocatechin-3-gallate</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The present article focuses on the properties of these molecules as chemopreventive agents and the recent advances on their formulation in nanoparticulate systems for targeted therapy and increased bioavailability </plain></SENT>
</text></document>