<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the therapeutic value of self-expanding metallic stent (SEMS) for resectable obstructing left-sided <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007113" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">rectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Clinical data of 73 patients who had <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> obstruction due to left-sided <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007113" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">rectal cancer</z:e> during May 2007 to January 2012 were retrospectively analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The patients were divided into 2 groups: SEMS group (34 cases) underwent surgical resection after insertion of SEMS; emergency surgery group (39 cases) underwent emergency operation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The 2 group patients were compared for the incidence of primary anastomosis, stoma rate, laparoscopic surgery rate, mortality, postoperative morbidity, ICU admission rate, length of ICU stay, hospital stay, and hospitalization costs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The incidence of primary anastomosis in SEMS group was significantly higher than that in emergency surgery group (97.1% vs. 56.4%, χ(2) = 16.256, P &lt; 0.001), and the protective stoma rate and permanent stoma rate in SEMS group were both lower than those in emergency surgery group (33.3% vs. 86.3%, 2.9% vs. 43.6%, χ(2) value were 14.972 and 16.156, both P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Patients in SEMS group underwent significantly more laparoscopic surgery than in emergency surgery group (47.1% vs. 0, χ(2) = 23.505, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were no significant difference in postoperative mortality (2.9% vs. 10.3%, P = 0.364) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The postoperative morbidity in SEMS group was significantly lower than that in emergency surgery group (35.3% vs. 66.7%, P = 0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Incisional <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was the most common complication in both groups, and the incidence of which seemed to be more higher in emergency surgery group (17.6% vs. 38.5%, χ(2) = 3.840, P = 0.050) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There was a lower ICU admission rate in SEMS group (24.2% vs. 53.9%, χ(2) = 6.972, P = 0.008), and the mean length of ICU stay and hospital stay were both shorter in SEMS group ((69.5 ± 7.4) hours vs. (114.3 ± 10.9) hours, t = -20.23, P &lt; 0.001; (19.6 ± 4.8) days vs. (23.4 ± 6.2) days, t = -2.90, P = 0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The cost of hospitalization was less in SEMS group (45 383 ± 15 648 vs. 61 485 ± 20 380, t = -3.74, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: SEMS can effectively relieve the large <z:hpo ids='HP_0005214'>intestinal obstruction</z:hpo> caused by left-sided <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007113" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">rectal cancer</z:e>, and change the traditional emergency surgery into a selective surgery with better outcomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>SEMS appears to be a valuable technique for resectable obstructing left-sided <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>