<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Lactobacillus sp. is the most dominant probiotic strain of bacteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Evidence indicates that the consumption of Lactobacillus sp. reduces the risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> in animal models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The present study was carried out to determine whether administration of Lactobacillus fermentum/ Lactobacillus plantarum alone or in combination with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28445">vincristine</z:chebi> have a synergistic impact on the control of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> in an animal model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Mice with 1,2 dimethylhydrazine (DMH) <z:chebi fb="16" ids="36807">hydrochloride</z:chebi>-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> were fed with L. fermentum and L. plantarum isolated along with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28445">vincristine</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>An increase in body weight, a decrease in ammonia concentration, a decrease in β glucosidase and β glucuronidase enzyme activity and a reduction in the number of crypts in the mice in the pre-carcinogen-induced group was noted when compared to these variables in the post-carcinogen-induced group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The body weight of the mice fed L. fermentum along with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28445">vincristine</z:chebi> was increased (6.5 g), and was found to be 3.5 times higher compared to that of the control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A marked decrease in the ammonia concentration (240 mg), and β glucosidase (0.0023 IU) and β <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37661">glucopyranose</z:chebi> enzyme activity (0.0027 IU) was observed; 22.59% less ammonia concentration, 73.26% less β glucosidase activity and 56.46% less β glucuronidase enzyme activity was noted when compared to the control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A significant reduction in the number of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_557'>aberrant crypt foci</z:mpath> (ACF) (90%) was observed when compared to the control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Maximum protection was observed in the mice fed the probiotics and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28445">vincristine</z:chebi> prior to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0596263" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer induction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Among the different dietary combinations tested in the present study, L. fermentum and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28445">vincristine</z:chebi> showed a more extensive reduction in ammonia concentration, β glucosidase, β glucuronidase activity and the number of ACF </plain></SENT>
</text></document>