<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Management of patients with synchronous colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastases</z:e> (SCRLM) should be individually tailored </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study compares patients managed by hepatobiliary centers from diagnosis with those referred for liver resection (LR) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Between 1998 and 2010, a total of 284 patients with SCRLM underwent resection; 106 resectable patients (1-3 unilobar <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e>, diameter &lt;100 mm, liver-only disease) were divided into two groups: 66 managed from diagnosis (group A) and 40 referred for LR (group B) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Group A contained a greater proportion of multiple <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> (55.0 vs. 34.8%, P = 0.042) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Group B always received colorectal surgery as up-front treatment (vs. 18.2%, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In group B, chemotherapy before LR was more common (72.5 vs. 33.3%, P = 0.0001) and lasted longer (P = 0.010) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>More patients in group B exhibited disease progression before LR (17.5 vs. 3.0%, P = 0.025) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Group A underwent fewer surgical procedures (80.3% simultaneous resection vs. 0%, P &lt; 0.00001), with similar short-term outcomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>After a median follow-up of 42.0 months, group A exhibited higher 5 year disease-free survival (DFS, 64.8 vs. 30.8%, P = 0.005) and fewer extrahepatic recurrences (21.5 vs. 47.5%, P = 0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The late-referral group (&gt;6 months, n = 24) had shorter median overall survival (OS) and DFS than group A (49.1 and 25.3 months vs. not achieved and not achieved, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The early-referral group exhibited OS and DFS similar to group A </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis confirmed late referral as a negative predictive factor of OS and DFS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Monocentric management of SCRLM in hepatobiliary centers is associated with shorter preoperative chemotherapy, better disease control, fewer surgical procedures (simultaneous resection), and, compared with late-referred patients, better survival </plain></SENT>
</text></document>