<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: Recently, a single-stapled technique (SST) was performed instead of the conventional double-stapled technique (<z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi>) in laparoscopic low anterior resection for anastomosis, by placement of intracorporeal purse-string sutures on the distal rectum with transanal specimen extraction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to compare the short-term outcomes between the two anastomotic techniques </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Between July 2007 and April 2010, 60 patients underwent SST by laparoscopic or robotic procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>These patients were matched 1:2 by age, gender, date of surgery, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> stage with 120 patients who underwent conventional <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi> in laparoscopic low anterior resection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The robotic-assisted operative approach was used more frequently in the SST group than in the <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi> group (61.7 % vs. 3.3 %, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The mean operative time was 203.9 (range, 120-400) min for the SST group and 167.6 (range, 90-300) min for the <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi> group (p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For specimen removal, the transanal approach was used in the SST group, while the transabdominal approach was used for the <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The pain score (visual analogue scale) of the SST group was lower (4.5 vs. 5.6, p &lt; 0.001), although postoperative recovery was similar </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Pathological examination revealed that the distal resection margin was significantly longer in the SST group (3.1 vs. 2.5 cm, p = 0.018) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Postoperative morbidity including anastomotic leakage was similar in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: SST yielded equivalent short-term outcomes when compared to conventional <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi> and provided the advantages of minimal access and a longer distal resection margin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Therefore, SST in lower anterior resection may be a useful alternative to conventional <z:chebi fb="14" ids="38291">DST</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>