<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Integument-related toxicities are common during epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)-targeted therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Panitumumab is a fully human monoclonal antibody targeting the EGFR that significantly improves progression-free survival when added to chemotherapy in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> who have <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> (WT) KRAS <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Primary efficacy and tolerability results from a phase II single-arm study of first-line panitumumab plus FOLFIRI in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> have been reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Here we report additional descriptive tolerability and quality of life data from this trial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Integument-related toxicities and quality of life were analysed; toxicities were graded using modified National <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Institute Common Toxicity Criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Kaplan-Meier estimates of time to and duration of first integument-related toxicity were prepared </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Quality of life was measured using EuroQoL EQ-5D and EORTC QLQ-C30 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Best overall response was analysed by <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1167791" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">skin toxicity</z:e> grade and baseline quality of life </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Change in quality of life was analysed by <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1167791" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">skin toxicity</z:e> severity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 154 patients were enrolled (WT KRAS n = 86; mutant KRAS n = 59); most (98%) experienced integument-related toxicities (most commonly <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0015230" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">rash</z:e> [42%], <z:hpo ids='HP_0000958'>dry skin</z:hpo> [40%] and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001061'>acne</z:hpo> [36%]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Median time to first integument-related toxicity was 8 days; median duration was 334 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Overall, proportionally more patients with grade 2+ <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1167791" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">skin toxicity</z:e> responded (56%) compared with those with grade 0/1 (29%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Mean overall EQ-5D health state index scores (0.81 vs. 0.78), health rating scores (72.5 vs. 71.0) and QLQ-C30 global health status scores (65.8 vs. 66.7) were comparable at baseline vs. safety follow-up (8 weeks after completion), respectively and appeared unaffected by <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1167791" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">skin toxicity</z:e> severity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: First-line panitumumab plus FOLFIRI has acceptable tolerability and appears to have little impact on quality of life, despite the high incidence of integument-related toxicity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>TRIAL REGISTRATION: ClinicalTrials.gov NCT00508404 </plain></SENT>
</text></document>