<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>This article examines the relationship between literacy and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) screening knowledge, beliefs, and experiences, with a focus on fecal occult blood tests (FOBTs) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Participants were 975 patients in 8 Louisiana federally qualified health centers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Participants were 50 years of age or older and not up to date with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening; approximately half (52%) had low literacy (less than a 9th-grade level) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Participants with low literacy were less likely than were those with adequate literacy to be aware of advertisements promoting <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening (58.7% vs. 76.3%, p &lt; .0001) or to believe it was very helpful to find <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> early (74.5% vs. 91.9%, p &lt; .0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The majority of participants had positive beliefs about the benefits of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening using FOBTs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Participants with low literacy had more perceived barriers to FOBT completion and were more likely to strongly agree or agree that FOBTs would be confusing, embarrassing, or a lot of trouble; however, none of these remained significant in multivariate analyses controlling for relevant covariates </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Confidence in being able to obtain an FOBT kit was high among those with low and adequate literacy (89.8% vs. 93.1%, respectively, p = .20); yet multivariate analyses revealed a significant difference in regard to literacy (p = .04) with low-literacy participants indicating less confidence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference by literacy in ever receiving a physician recommendation for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening (38.4% low vs. 39.0% adequate, p = .79); however, multivariate analyses revealed significant differences in FOBT completion by literacy (p = .036) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Overall, findings suggest that literacy is a factor in patients' <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> knowledge, beliefs, and confidence in obtaining a FOBT </plain></SENT>
</text></document>