<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Patients with significant comorbidities often are denied laparoscopic colorectal resections, because they are thought to be too "high-risk." This study was designed to examine the feasibility and safety of laparoscopic colorectal resections in high-risk <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> patients and to compare them with a similar cohort of patients undergoing open resections in the same time period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This was a single-center, prospective, cohort study conducted at a high-volume, nonuniversity, tertiary care hospital </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>From a database of 616 patients submitted to elective colorectal surgery for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> within a fast-track protocol (January 2005 to November 2011), 188 patients who met at least one minor (age &gt;80 years and body mass index (BMI) &gt;30 m/kg(2)) and one major (cardiac, pulmonary, renal or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0023895" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">liver disease</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo>) criterion were classified as high-risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Differences in baseline characteristics, intraoperative outcomes, and short-term (30-day) postoperative outcomes, as well as the pathology findings and the readmission and reoperation rates, were compared between the open and laparoscopic cohorts in both high- and low-risk groups and between high- and low-risk groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: During the study period, 68 high-risk patients underwent laparoscopic resections and 120 had open surgeries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A shorter length of postoperative stay (6 vs. 9 days, p &lt; 0.0001) and fewer postoperative nonsurgical complications (4 % vs. 19 %, p = 0.003) were observed among the laparoscopic group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Postoperative major (p = 0.774) and minor complications (p = 0.3) and reoperations (p = 0.196) were similar between the two groups, and a significantly lower rate of mortality (1.5 vs. 7.5 %, p = 0.038) was observed in the laparoscopic group than in the open group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Laparoscopic colorectal resection can be safely performed on "high-risk" surgical patients with better results than a similar group of high-risk patients undergoing open colon resections </plain></SENT>
</text></document>