<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Venous invasion (VI) is an independent prognostic indicator in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> and may prompt consideration for adjuvant chemotherapy in patients with stage II <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Recent evidence suggests that VI is underreported in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> and that detection may be enhanced by an elastin stain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study aimed (1) to determine the impact of an elastin stain on VI detection and on interobserver agreement between gastrointestinal (GI) and non-GI pathologists, and (2) to identify factors associated with increased VI detection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Forty <z:chebi fb="1" ids="51686">hematoxylin</z:chebi> and eosin (H&amp;E)-stained slides were circulated to 6 GI and 6 non-GI pathologists who independently assessed the VI status as positive, negative, or equivocal </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Six weeks later, 40 corresponding Movat-stained slides were recirculated together with the original H&amp;E slides and reassessed for VI status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Detection of VI was &gt;2-fold higher with a Movat stain compared with an H&amp;E stain alone (46.4% vs. 19.6%, P=0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>GI pathologists detected VI more frequently than non-GI pathologists on both H&amp;E (30.0% vs. 9.2%, P=0.029) and Movat (58.3% vs. 34.6%, P=0.018) stains </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was higher interobserver agreement in the case of a Movat stain, particularly for extramural VI (H&amp;E: κ=0.23 vs. Movat: κ=0.41) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A poststudy survey indicated that GI pathologists and non-GI pathologists applied similar diagnostic criteria but that GI pathologists more frequently applied "orphan arteriole" and "<z:hpo ids='HP_0010808'>protruding tongue</z:hpo>" signs as diagnostic clues to VI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This study confirms that VI is underdetected on H&amp;E and highlights the role of elastin staining in improving VI detection and interobserver agreement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Strategies to improve VI detection are warranted </plain></SENT>
</text></document>