<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A systematic meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies on green tea consumption and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> was performed to determine whether green tea has a chemopreventive effect against <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Six eligible cohort studies involving 352,275 participants and 1675 cases of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> were identified </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Combined relative risk (RR) ratios for the highest vs. lowest and increment of 1 cup/day green tea consumption levels were calculated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The combined RR of 0.90 (95% CI: 0.72-1.08) was found comparing highest vs. lowest green tea consumption levels for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>No significant differences by <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>-site were found, but an inverse association between green tea and incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (RR: 0.70; 95% CI: 0.55-0.85) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> (RR: 0.69; 95% CI: 0.48-0.98) was demonstrated in Shanghai population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Singapore men had a higher risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (RR: 1.36; 95% CI: 1.06-1.74) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, an increase in green tea consumption of 1 cup/day was not associated with incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (RR: 0.97; 95% CI: 0.91-1.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Despite the limited evidence from Shanghai studies in support of green tea as potential chemopreventive agents against <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, available data from prospective cohort studies are insufficient to conclude that green tea may protect against <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>