<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Increased life expectancy has led to elevating the mean age of the patients at the time of diagnosis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> and subsequent treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Differences in complication rates and outcome between elderly and younger patients have been investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We retrospectively analysed a database containing the information of patients who underwent surgery for stage I-III <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> from January 2004 to January 2012 at our institution and compared demographic, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>-related, and outcomes data of 235 elderly patients with 211 patients ≤ 65 years old </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Intraoperative complications did not differ between young and old patients whereas some differences have been found in postoperative and late complications: elderly patients suffered more by <z:hpo ids='HP_0002595'>ileus</z:hpo> (P = 0.024), <z:hpo ids='HP_0002586'>peritonitis</z:hpo> or septic shock (P = 0.017), pelvic <z:mpath ids='MPATH_612'>abscess</z:mpath> (P = 0.028), wound <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> (P = 0.031), and incisional/port <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019270" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">herniation</z:e> (P = 0.012) compared with younger patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Moreover, elderly patients suffered by systemic complications such as cardiovascular (4.7% vs. 1.4%, P = 0.049), renal (4.7% vs. 0.5%, P = 0.006), and respiratory (10.6% vs. 5.2%, P = 0.036) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The multivariate analysis assessing the odds of having a complication revealed that older age (Odd Ratio [OR] 2.75, 95% Confidential Interval [CI]: 1.67-4.52) and open surgery (OR 1.63, 95% CI: 1.01-2.62) are significantly and independently associated with having a complication </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In our series, elderly patients have presented a slight higher incidence of comorbidities that may affect the incidence rates of postoperative complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These results have implications in increasing the hospital stay as well as a higher rate of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>