<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To analyze the relationship of K-ras mutation with the development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastasis</z:e> in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> patients and the survival outcomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: From 2003 to 2008, 300 patients who underwent <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> surgery in the Department of General Surgery of Zhongshan Hospital, Fudan University were assigned to different groups, according to the diagnosis and follow-up results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The mutation of exon 2 of K-ras was detected in primary paraffin-embedded lesions by PCR and Pyrosequencing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The association of gene mutation with the development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastasis</z:e> and its prognosis was studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Among 300 cases, the mutations of exon 2 were present in 120 cases(40%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The G13D mutation was more common in metachronous <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> group than that in synchronous group(17.0% vs. 8.0%, P=0.041) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Multivariable regression analysis showed that G13D mutation was an independent risk factor(HR=1.108, 95%CI:1.032-5.062, P=0.048) for metachronous <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients with mutated K-ras had a poorer overall survival compared to those without mutated K-ras for patients without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastasis</z:e>(median overall, 65 vs. 72 months, P=0.039), and for patients who received <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> resection(median disease-free survival 18 vs. 24 months, P=0.048) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Multivariable analysis showed that K-ras mutation was an independent risk factors of overall survival(HR=1.561, 95%CI:1.022-6.422, P=0.045) in patients without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastasis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Conculsion Detection of K-ras mutation may predict the development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0494165" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">liver metastasis</z:e> and prognosis </plain></SENT>
</text></document>