<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>X-ray repair cross-complementing group 1 (XRCC1), a DNA repair enzyme, plays a crucial role in the base excision repair by generating a single nucleotide repair patch </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It has been demonstrated that the XRCC1 Arg399Gln gene polymorphism was associated with variations in XRCC1 enzyme activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to quantitatively summarize the association between the XRCC1 Arg399Gln polymorphism and susceptibility to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A comprehensive search of the PubMed, Embase, and China National Knowledge Infrastructure databases was conducted for studies on the association between the XRCC1 Arg399Gln polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Summary odds ratio (OR) with its corresponding 95 % confidence interval (95 %CI) was estimated, in a fixed-effects model or a random-effects model when appropriate, to assess the association </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Totally, 26 case-control studies with 6,979 cases and 11,470 controls were included into this meta-analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The pooled results of total studies showed that the XRCC1 Arg399Gln polymorphism was significantly associated with increased risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> genetic contrast models (OR(A vs. G) = 1.13, 95 %CI 1.03-1.23, P (OR) = 0.008; OR(Gln/Gln vs. Arg/Arg) = 1.24, 95 %CI 1.04-1.46, P (OR) = 0.015; OR(Gln/Gln vs. Arg/Gln + Arg/Arg) = 1.19, 95 %CI 1.03-1.38, P (OR) = 0.021; OR(Gln/Gln + Arg/Gln vs. Arg/Arg) = 1.14, 95 %CI 1.02-1.28, P (OR) = 0.022), except for the additive contrast model (OR(Arg/Gln vs. Arg/Arg) = 1.11, 95 %CI 0.99-1.25, P (OR) = 0.064) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The statistically significant association between the XRCC1 Arg399Gln polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> risk was observed among studies with high quality and in Asians, but not in Caucasians </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Sensitivity analyses by sequential omission of any individual studies further identified the significant association </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Publication bias was inexistent in this meta-analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The meta-analysis suggests that the XRCC1 Arg399Gln polymorphism is associated with increased risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>