<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: It has been suggested that Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) constitutes a risk for the development of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_490'>adenomatous polyps</z:mpath> and <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp> of the colon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Our aim was to study the association between H. pylori-positive <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> and the occurrence of any colonic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasm</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: From a computerized database of surgical pathology reports, we selected 156,000 subjects who underwent colonoscopy and esophago-gastro-duodenoscopy with biopsy results from both procedures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Compared with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> gastric mucosa, H. pylori <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> occurred more frequently among patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_140'>hyperplastic polyps</z:mpath> (OR=1.24, 95% CI: 1.18-1.30), <z:mpath ids='MPATH_490'>adenomatous polyps</z:mpath> (1.52, 1.46-1.57), advanced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath> (1.80, 1.69-1.92), villous <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath> or <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath> with high-grade <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> (1.97, 1.82-2.14), and <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinomas</z:mp> (2.35, 1.98-2.80) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Similarly, the strength of the association between H. pylori-positive <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> and colonic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasm</z:hpo> increased with size and number of the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The association between H. pylori <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> and the occurrence of colonic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasm</z:hpo> was similar for different locations of the large bowel </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Other gastric conditions etiologically associated with H. pylori, such as <z:mpath ids='MPATH_167'>intestinal metaplasia</z:mpath>, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, and <z:mp ids='MP_0009308'>adenocarcinoma</z:mp>, were also significantly associated with an increased risk of colonic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasm</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Various forms of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo> related to H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> confer an increased risk for colonic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasm</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the past, when H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> was more prevalent, its attributable risk to the occurrence of colorectal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasm</z:hpo> may have been quite substantial </plain></SENT>
</text></document>