<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Fecal occult blood testing (FOBT) and sigmoidoscopy are proven to decrease <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) incidence and mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Sigmoidoscopy's benefit is limited to the distal colon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Observational data are conflicting regarding the degree to which colonoscopy affords protection against proximal <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Our aim was to explore the comparative effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of colonoscopy vs. sigmoidoscopy and alternative <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> screening strategies in light of the latest published data </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We performed a contemporary cost-utility analysis using a Markov model validated against data from randomized controlled trials of FOBT and sigmoidoscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Persons at average <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> risk within the general US population were modeled </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Screening strategies included those recommended by the United States (US) Preventive Services Task Force, including colonoscopy every 10 years (COLO), flexible sigmoidoscopy every 5 years (FS), annual fecal occult blood testing, annual fecal immunochemical testing (FIT), and the combination FS/FIT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The main outcome measures were quality-adjusted life-years (QALYs) and costs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In the base case, FIT dominated other strategies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The advantage of FIT over FS and COLO was contingent on rates of uptake and adherence that are well above current US rates </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Compared with FIT, FS and COLO both cost &lt;$50,000/QALY gained when FIT per-cycle adherence was &lt;50% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>COLO cost $56,800/QALY gained vs. FS in the base case </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>COLO cost &lt;$100,000/QALY gained vs. FS when COLO yielded a relative risk of proximal <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> of &lt;0.5 vs. no screening </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In probabilistic analyses, COLO was cost-effective vs. FS at a willingness-to-pay threshold of $100,000/QALY gained in 84% of iterations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Screening colonoscopy may be cost-effective compared with FIT and sigmoidoscopy, depending on the relative rates of screening uptake and adherence and the protective benefit of colonoscopy in the proximal colon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Colonoscopy's cost-effectiveness compared with sigmoidoscopy is contingent on the ability to deliver ~50% protection against <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> in the proximal colon </plain></SENT>
</text></document>