<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: The results of recent published studies focusing on IL-8 polymorphism in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> susceptibility have often been inconsistent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We therefore carried out a meta-analysis based on independent studies to assess the association </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Nine case-control studies with 7,003 individuals (3,019 cases and 3,984 controls) were included in this meta-analysis through searching the databases of PubMed, Excerpta Medica Database (EMBASE), and Chinese Biomedical Literature Database (CBM; Chinese) (up to Aug 1st, 2012) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The odds ratio (OR) and 95% confidence interval (95%CI) were used to assess the strength of the association </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Meta-analysis was conducted in a fixed/random effect model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: No obvious associations were found for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> genetic models when <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> studies were pooled into the meta-analysis (for A vs. T: OR = 1.084, 95% CI = 0.971- 1.209, P = 0.019; for TA vs. TT: OR = 1.18, 95% CI = 0.943-1.475, P = 0.001; for AA vs. TT: OR = 1.155, 95% CI = 0.916-1.456, P = 0.014; for AA+TA vs. TT: OR = 1.170, 95% CI =0.953-1.437, P = 0.001; for AA vs. TT+TA: OR = 1.044, 95% CI = 0.886-1.230, P = 0.097) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In the subgroup analyses by ethnicity (Caucasian) and source of controls (population based), also no significant associations were found for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> genetic models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Result suggests that the IL-8-251T&gt;A polymorphism is not associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Because of the limitations of this meta-analysis, this finding demands further investigation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>