<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Background/Aims: Low <z:chebi fb="3" ids="37445">folate</z:chebi> intake may increase risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> by altering gene-specific methylation in the colon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We determined whether supplementation with physiological doses of <z:chebi fb="3" ids="37445">folate</z:chebi> could alter methylation in the <z:chebi fb="67" ids="50114">oestrogen</z:chebi> receptor 1 (ESR1) and mutL homolog 1 (MLH1) genes in colonic mucosa of subjects with colorectal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Methods: This was a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Subjects received either 400 µg/day <z:chebi fb="9" ids="27470">folic acid</z:chebi> (n = 15) or placebo (n = 14) for 10 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Blood and colonic tissue samples were collected at baseline and after intervention to determine biomarkers of <z:chebi fb="3" ids="37445">folate</z:chebi> and vitamin B status, MTHFR C677T and MS A2756G genotypes, and ESR1 and MLH1 methylation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Results: Although serum and red cell <z:chebi fb="3" ids="37445">folate</z:chebi> increased (p &lt; 0.001 vs. placebo) and plasma <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">homocysteine</z:chebi> decreased (p = 0018 vs. placebo) in the <z:chebi fb="9" ids="27470">folic acid</z:chebi> group, there were no significant changes in ESR1 (p = 0.649 vs. placebo) or MLH1 (p = 0.211 vs. placebo) methylation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There was a significant effect of gender on ESR1 methylation (p = 0.004) and significant gender and genotype (MTHFR C677T and MS A2756G) interactions (p = 0.04 and p = 0.014, respectively) that were independent of treatment group allocation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: Short-term <z:chebi fb="3" ids="37445">folate</z:chebi> supplementation in physiological doses decreases plasma <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">homocysteine</z:chebi> but has no effect on ESR1 and MLH1 methylation in colonic mucosa of individuals with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Further studies to investigate the interactions between gender, genotype and DNA methylation suggested in this study are warranted </plain></SENT>
</text></document>