<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Colorectal cancer</z:e> is a leading cause of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> mortality with a complex <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0596263" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">carcinogenesis</z:e> that includes reduced cellular senescence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Lamin proteins are decreased in senescing cells, and frequently decreased in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancies</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study identified a new drug candidate for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> that appears to target cell senescence via a lamin protein. β-Asarone (1-propenyl-2,4,5-methoxybenzol) is a compound from the traditional medical herb Acorus calamus Linn </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>This study tested the in vitro and in vivo effects of β-asarone on <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> cells by testing cell viability using human colorectal cell lines HT29 and SW480 in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53233">MTT</z:chebi> assays; <z:mp ids='MP_0002006'>tumorigenesis</z:mp> using xenografts in <z:mp ids='MP_0003815'>nude</z:mp> mice and a mouse model of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>; cell senescence using senescence-associated β-galactosidase activity; and expression of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> and senescence-related proteins, specifically lamins, Oct-1, p53, p21, and p15, by Western blot. β-Asarone appeared to increase expression of lamin B1, p53, p21, but not lamin A/C. β-Asarone regulates p15 expression by regulation of Oct-1 binding </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Collectively, the results suggested that β-asarone inhibits <z:hpo ids='HP_0003003'>colon cancer</z:hpo> formation in vivo and in vitro by inducing senescence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Since β-asarone induced lamin B1 expression, a model is proposed in which β-asarone inhibits <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> by inducing senescence through lamin B1 </plain></SENT>
</text></document>