<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Lesions' detection rate during colonoscopy may be influenced by the endoscopist's experience </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>EPK-i system colonoscopy (i-Scan) can improve mucosal and vascular visualization for detecting lesions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>AIM: To compare mucosal lesions' detection rate and the withdrawal time of the instrument among non-expert and expert endoscopists </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Colonoscopy records of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> consecutive patients undergoing first <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">HD</z:e>+ with i-Scan- or SWL-equipped colonoscopy for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> screening over a twelve-month period were evaluated, in a "post hoc" analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 542 colonoscopies (389 HD+ with i-Scan; 153 SWL): expert and non-expert endoscopists did respectively 272 and 117 HD+ with i-Scan and 83 and 70 SWL colonoscopies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Expert endoscopists did more i-Scan colonoscopies than non-experts (p=0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In the SWL procedures, the experts detected mucosal lesions in more colonoscopies than non-experts (61/22 vs. 23/47, p=0.0001) and found a significantly higher mean number of lesions (1.34 vs. 0.47; p=0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Experts detected more or less the same mean number of lesions with both imaging techniques, while among non-experts detection with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">HD</z:e>+ with i-Scan was significantly better than with SWL imaging (1.39 vs. 0.47; p=0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">HD</z:e>+ with i-Scan imaging enables less skilled endoscopists to achieve results comparable to those of experienced ones in detecting mucosal lesions </plain></SENT>
</text></document>