<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Optimal information provision is important in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> survivorship, but satisfaction with this provision may depend upon individual differences in personality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We examined the effect of the personality traits negative affectivity and social inhibition, and their combined effect (Type D personality) on satisfaction with received information </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Four population-based, cross-sectional surveys were conducted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> individuals diagnosed with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0006775'>multiple myeloma</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0476089" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">endometrial cancer</z:e> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (1998-2008) as registered in the Eindhoven <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> Registry were eligible for participation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In total, 4446 patients received questionnaires including the EORTC QLQ-INFO25 and the Type D personality scale (DS14); 69% responded (n = 3080) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Nineteen percent of patients (n = 572) had a Type D personality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The perceived receipt of disease-specific (mean 46 vs. 51), medical test (56 vs. 63) and treatment information (37 vs. 42) was significantly lower for Type D patients compared with non-Type Ds as assessed with the EORTC QLQ-INFO25 (scales 0-100; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> ps &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> patients with a Type D personality were less satisfied with the received information (49 vs. 58; p &lt; 0.01) and found the received information less useful (55 vs. 61; p &lt; 0.01) compared with non-Type Ds </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Multivariate linear regression analyses showed that Type D personality was independently associated with information about the disease (Beta = -0.09), medical tests (Beta = -0.12) and treatment (Beta = -0.08), and with satisfaction with information received (OR = 0.54; 95%CI = 0.44-0.66;<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> ps &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This study showed that patients with a Type D personality perceived that they received less information and reported less satisfaction with the amount of received information as compared with non-Type D patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Copyright © 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd </plain></SENT>
</text></document>