<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>In our previous study, significantly high expression levels of matrix-remodeling associated 5 (MXRA5) were identified in fresh-cultured <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) tissues compared with their <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> adjacent mucosa by differential secretome analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Whether MXRA5 is a potential serum biomarker of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> has not been evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to investigate the association between MXRA5 expression and clinicopathological characteristics of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The MXRA5 expression levels were determined by quantitative real-time PCR (qRT-PCR) and immunohistochemistry (IHC) in 20 colorectal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> tissues, 156 CRC tissues and their corresponding adjacent <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> mucosa </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Relative quantity (RQ) value and immunoreactive score (IRS) were used for quantitative assessment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The staining for MXRA5 protein was mainly located in the cytoplasm of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> tissues were positively stained, with a higher expression rate (IRS&gt;4) of 67% (105/156), and a lower expression rate (IRS≤4) of 33% (51/156) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Meanwhile, their corresponding <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> tissues exhibited little positive staining; the higher expression rate was 0% (0/156) and the lower expression rate was 25% (16/156) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Additionally, more than half of the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> tissues were positively stained; the higher expression rate was 15% (3/20) and the lower expression rate was 50% (10/20) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The MXRA5 protein positive staining rates were significantly correlated with the lesion sites (colon vs. rectum, 76 vs. 59%), TNM staging (I+II vs. III+IV, 56 vs. 73%) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastasis</z:e> (present vs. absent; 76 vs. 61%) with the most high positive staining rate observable in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0346991" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">omental metastasis</z:e> (82%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>However, MXRA5 <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression levels showed no significant differences between <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> tissues and their corresponding <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> tissues, and no significant correlation between IRS and corresponding RQ value was observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In this study, we present the first evaluation of MXRA5 protein expression in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> tissue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Our results revealed that MXRA5 protein is aberrantly expressed in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> tissues, and has potential value in early detection of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> and prediction of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0346991" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">omental metastasis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>