<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The cannabinoid system has been considered to be a potential target of colorectal <z:mp ids='MP_0002038'>carcinoma</z:mp> therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to address the correlation between cannabinoid type 1 (CB1) receptor expression and disease severity/outcomes in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>CB1 receptor expression was analyzed by immunohistochemistry using tissue microarrays in consecutive patients who underwent surgical resection (n=534) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>CB1 receptor expression was categorized as a high (≥66%) vs. low (&lt;66%) immunopercentage as a median split, and was analyzed in relation to disease severity and overall survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>CB1 receptor expression was observed in 409 patients (76.6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Low CB1 receptor expression was more frequently identified in stage IV than in stage I/II or III <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> (P&lt;0.01 for both) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In stage IV <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>, high vs. low CB1 expression was correlated with a statistically significant poorer overall survival (P=0.033) that was independent of age, R0 resection, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> differentiation and chemotherapy [hazard ratio (HR), 1.805; 95% confidence interval (CI), 1.042-3.094; P=0.035] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, CB1 expression was not observed to be correlated with patient survival following surgery in stage I/II or III <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The high immunoreactivity of the cannabinoid type 1 receptor is a significant prognostic factor following surgery in stage IV <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>