<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: This Japanese multicenter retrospective study evaluated short- and long-term outcomes of palliative laparoscopic procedures for symptomatic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677950" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">stage IV colorectal cancer</z:e> compared with conventional open procedures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Of 968 eligible patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677950" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">stage IV colorectal cancer</z:e> enrolled during January 2006-December 2007 from 41 participating surgical units (Japan Society of Laparoscopic Colorectal Surgery Group), we studied 409 patients who underwent palliative resection of symptomatic primary <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0009404" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal tumor</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Data from patients with laparoscopic resection (n = 98) and open colorectal resection (n = 311) were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Eleven (11.2 %) laparoscopic operations were converted to an open procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Fewer complications were reported for laparoscopic resections than for open procedures (13.3 vs. 26.7 %; p = 0.0042) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Postoperative hospital stay was significantly shorter in the laparoscopic vs. open resection group (median, 14 vs. 17 days; p = 0.0242) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Postoperative chemotherapy treatment was administered to 245 (78.9 %) patients in the open and 78 (79.6 %) patients in the laparoscopic resection group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Time from surgery to start of postoperative chemotherapy was significantly shorter in the laparoscopic vs. open resection group (median, 32 vs. 27 days; p = 0.0487) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Median survival time between the two groups was not significantly different (22.0 vs. 22.2 months; p = 0.948) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Laparoscopic palliative resection results in reduced postoperative complications and earlier recovery with acceptable long-term outcomes comparable with open surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>When performed by experienced surgeons in selected patients, it may be a safe and feasible option </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Because of the potential of significant bias arising from the included studies, further randomized controlled trials should be undertaken to confirm this bias </plain></SENT>
</text></document>