<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: The aim of this study was to determine the clinicopathological characteristics and outcomes of Chinese <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) patients aged 75 years and older undergoing potentially curative surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 2,482 CRC patients at TNM stage I-III undergoing surgical treatment between 1995 and 2005 were evaluated, and patients were divided into a younger (&lt;75 years old) and an elderly (≥75 years) group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were 2,482 CRC patients in this study, of which 2,194 (88.4 %) patients were in the younger group (mean age 57 years) and 288 (11.6 %) were in the elderly group (mean age 79 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Significant differences were observed between the two groups with regard to the American Society of Anesthesiologists' score, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> location, co-morbidities, emergency procedures, use of chemotherapy, proportion admitted to the ICU, length of ICU stay, causes of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, T/N stage and postoperative recurrence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The postoperative mortality increased from 4.8 % in the younger group to 8.3 % in the older group (p = 0.011) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Although significant differences were found in the overall 5-year survival (73 vs. 56 %, p &lt; 0.0001) and disease-free 5-year survival (68 vs. 54 %, p &lt; 0.0001) between the two groups, the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>-specific 5-year survival was similar (88 vs. 85 %, p = 0.089) in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Although elderly <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> patients have unique clinicopathological features, a higher postoperative mortality and a worse overall and disease-free survival compared with younger patients, the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>-specific survival at five years is similar between elderly and younger patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Elderly patients benefit from radical surgery and have a good postoperative oncological outcome, irrespective of their age </plain></SENT>
</text></document>