<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Smoking and high red meat intake have been associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Increased iron exposure may be a common factor, favoring the colonization of certain <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> pathogens that preferentially grow in an iron-rich <z:chebi fb="2" ids="8069">luminal</z:chebi> environment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We analyzed the data from a population-based case-control study of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> and measured antibody levels against flagelin of Salmonella (FliC), one of the irontrophic bacteria, in 2 independent blood collections </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> synergistically increased by combined exposures to <z:chebi fb="4" ids="30413">heme</z:chebi> iron intake and pack-yr (PY) of cigarette smoking (P value for the interaction = 0.039 on the continuous scale) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There was a marginally significant interaction between <z:chebi fb="4" ids="30413">heme</z:chebi> iron intake and PY in increasing FliC antibody in the U.S. control subjects (P = 0.055), although no iron or smoking data were available for Dutch samples </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, FliC antibody levels were significantly higher in patients with colorectal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_491'>polyps</z:mpath> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> than in controls in both Dutch (3.93 vs. 2.23) (P = 0.014) and U.S. samples (6.65 vs. 4.37) (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Potential roles of iron from cigarette smoking and dietary <z:chebi fb="4" ids="30413">heme</z:chebi> in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> through altering irontrophic <z:chebi fb="2" ids="8069">luminal</z:chebi> <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> population may warrant further investigation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>