<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Studies investigating the association between <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4056">cytochrome</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> S-transferase P1 (GSTP1) Ala114Val polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) risk report conflicting results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to quantitatively summarize the evidence for such a relationship </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Two investigators independently searched the Medline, Embase, China National Knowledge Infrastructure, and Chinese Biomedicine databases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Summary odds ratios (ORs) and 95 % confidence intervals (95 % CIs) for GSTP1 polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> were calculated in a fixed effects model (the Mantel-Haenszel method) and a random effects model (the DerSimonian and Laird method) when appropriate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The pooled ORs were performed for co-dominant model (ValVal vs. AlaAla, AlaVal vs. AlaAla), dominant model (ValVal + AlaVal vs. AlaAla), and recessive model (ValVal vs. AlaVal + AlaAla) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This meta-analysis included seven case-control studies, which included 3,173 CRC cases and 3,323 controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Overall, the variant genotypes (ValVal and AlaVal) of the Ala114Val were not associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> risk when compared with the <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> AlaAla homozygote </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Similarly, no associations were found in the dominant and recessive models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>When stratifying for ethnicity, Hardy-Weinberg equilibrium in controls, study sample size, and source of controls, a significantly increased risk was observed among Asians (AlaVal vs. AlaAla, OR = 1.67, 95 % CI = 1.08-2.59; dominant model, OR = 1.74, 95 % CI = 1.14-2.67) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>No <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneity</z:hpo> or publication bias was found in the present study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This meta-analysis suggests that the GSTP1 Ala114Val polymorphism may not be associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> risk, while the observed increase in risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> may be due to small-study bias </plain></SENT>
</text></document>