<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The x-ray repair cross-complementing group 3 (XRCC3), a member of DNA repair genes, plays a critical role in the maintenance of genome stability by homologous recombination repair for DNA double-strand breaks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The polymorphism of XRCC3 Thr241Met has been indicated to be involved in the development of some <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancers</z:e>, but previous individual studies on the association between XRCC3 Thr241Met polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) risk have yielded conflicting and inconclusive results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To shed some light on the contradictory findings and improve our understanding of the pathogenesis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>, we carried out this updated meta-analysis by pooling <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> available publications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Databases including PubMed, Embase, Web of Science and China National Knowledge Infrastructure were searched for relevant publications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The odds ratios (ORs) with the corresponding 95 % confidence intervals (95 % CIs) were calculated to estimate the strength of the association between XRCC3 Thr241Met polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A total of 15 case-control studies involving 4,475 cases and 6,373 controls were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Overall, the pooled ORs for the meta-analysis of total included studies showed no statistically significant association of XRCC3 Thr241Met polymorphism with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> risk in any genetic model (ORMet allele vs. Thr allele = 1.17, 95 % CI 0.97-1.42, P OR = 0.102; ORMetMet vs. ThrThr = 1.32, 95 % CI 0.93-1.87, P OR = 0.121; ORThrMet vs. ThrThr = 1.17, 95 % CI 0.94-1.45, P OR = 0.150; ORMetMet + ThrMet vs. ThrThr = 1.20, 95 % CI 0.96-1.51, P OR = 0.114; ORMetMet vs. ThrThr + ThrMet = 1.37, 95 % CI 0.98-1.93, P OR = 0.065) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, in subgroup analyses stratified by source of controls and ethnicity, the XRCC3 Thr241Met polymorphism was associated with an elevated risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> in the hospital-based case-control studies and the Asian population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Sensitivity analysis indicated that the findings were unlikely due to chance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This meta-analysis suggests that the XRCC3 Thr241Met polymorphism may modify the risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>, particularly in Asians </plain></SENT>
</text></document>