<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Insulin-like growth factor binding protein 3 (IGFBP-3) plays an important role in the development and progress of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancers</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The association between IGFBP-3 polymorphisms and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> remains controversial and ambiguous </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study is to explore the association between IGFBP3 A-202C and Gly32Ala polymorphisms and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> susceptibility using meta-analyisi </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Case-control studies on the association between IGFBP3 A-202C and Gly32Ala polymorphisms and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, which had sufficient data for estimating an odds ratio (OR) with 95% confidence interval (CI), were included in the meta-analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Abstracts, case reports, editorials, and review articles were excluded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Heterozygous and homozygous mutants were compared with the <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild types</z:mp> to estimate combined OR values and 95%CIs with Review Manager 5.0 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Six eligible studies were included, with 3157 patients and 6027 controls for A-202C and 1711 patients and 2995 controls for Gly32Ala </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No significant association was found in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> genetic models (for A-202C, AC vs. AA, OR = 0.99(0.88-1.11), CC vs. AA, OR = 1.06(0.92-1.22), dominant model, OR = 0.98(0.88-1.09), recessive model, OR = 0.94(0.84-1.05); and for Gly32Ala polymorphism, GC vs. GG, OR = 1.10(0.92-1.31), CC vs. GG, OR = 0.93(0.76-1.14), dominant model, OR = 1.05(0.89-1.24), recessive model, OR = 0.90(0.77-1.05)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The results suggest that the IGFBP3 A-202C and Gly32Ala polymorphisms are not associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> susceptibility </plain></SENT>
</text></document>