<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: KRAS is an EGFR effector in the <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp>/RAF/ERK cascade that is mutated in about 40% of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> (mCRC) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Activating mutations in codons 12 and 13 of the KRAS gene are the only established negative predictors of response to anti-EGFR therapy and patients whose <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e> harbor such mutations are not candidates for therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, 40 to 60% of <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> cases do not respond to anti-EGFR therapy, suggesting the involvement of other genes that act downstream of EGFR in the <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp>-RAF-MAPK and PI3K-AKT pathways or activating KRAS mutations at other locations of the gene </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: DNA was obtained from a consecutive series of 201 mCRC cases (FFPE tissue), <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> for KRAS exon 2 (codons 12 and 13) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Mutational analysis of KRAS (exons 3 and 4), BRAF (exons 11 and 15), and PIK3CA (exons 9 and 20) was performed by high resolution melting (HRM) and positive cases were then sequenced </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: One mutation was present in 23.4% (47/201) of the cases and 3.0% additional cases (6/201) had two concomitant mutations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A total of 53 cases showed 59 mutations, with the following distribution: 44.1% (26/59) in KRAS (13 in exon 3 and 13 in exon 4), 18.6% (11/59) in BRAF (two in exon 11 and nine in exon 15) and 37.3% (22/59) in PIK3CA (16 in exon 9 and six in exon 20) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In total, 26.4% (53/201) of the cases had at least one mutation and the remaining 73.6% (148/201) were <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> regions studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Five of the mutations we report, four in KRAS and one in BRAF, have not previously been described in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>BRAF and PIK3CA mutations were more frequent in the colon than in the sigmoid or rectum: 20.8% vs. 1.6% vs. 0.0% (P=0.000) for BRAF and 23.4% vs. 12.1% vs. 5.4% (P=0.011) for PIK3CA mutations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: About one fourth of mCRC cases <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> for KRAS codons 12 and 13 present other mutations either in KRAS, BRAF, or PIK3CA, many of which may explain the lack of response to anti-EGFR therapy observed in a significant proportion of these patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>