<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Background: Detection of circulating <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> cells by reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) has been studied as a prognostic marker in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e>) but so far with conflicting results regarding specificity and prognostic value </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In this study cytokeratin-20 (CK20) was evaluated by real-time RT-PCR as a marker for circulating <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> cell detection and the influence of surgical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> resection on the presence of circulating <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> cells was analyzed. Methods: <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi> was isolated from the mononuclear cell fraction of blood samples taken from 95 CRC patients before and after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> resection and from 23 healthy volunteers and assayed by real-time RT-PCR for CK20 expression. Results: Among 23 healthy volunteers one was positive for CK20 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Among 95 CRC patients, 25 were positive for CK20 before and 23 after surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Sixteen patients positive before surgery became negative after surgery, while 14 patients negative before surgery became positive after surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>An increase in the proportion of CK20-positive samples with increasing stage of disease was observed for preoperative but not postoperative blood samples. Conclusions: Its association with clinical stage indicates that CK20 might have prognostic value as a marker for detection of circulating <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Surgical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> resection can both reduce and induce the presence of circulating <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CRC</z:e> cells </plain></SENT>
</text></document>