<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The proportion of group D streptococcal infective <z:hpo ids='HP_0100584'>endocarditis</z:hpo> (IE) (predominantly due to Streptococcus gallolyticus) and the incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> are higher in France than in most European countries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We assumed that this could be explained by a high group D streptococci (GDS) fecal carriage rate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aims of this study were to re-assess the GDS fecal carriage rate in France and its relationship with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Consecutive adult subjects who were to undergo a complete colonoscopy were invited to participate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>GDS were searched in subjects' stools before their colonoscopy using biomolecular techniques </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Colonoscopic findings were sorted into four subgroups: <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> colonoscopy, non-tumoral lesions, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0086692" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">benign tumors</z:e>, and premalignant/<z:mp ids='MP_0002018'>malignant tumors</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>GDS fecal carriages were calculated overall and in each subgroup and compared </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The data from 259 subjects were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>GDS were identified in the feces of 12 subjects, with the following distribution: S. lutetiensis (n = 9), S. pasteurianus (n = 2), and S. gallolyticus (n = 1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This accounted for an overall GDS fecal carriage rate of 4.6 % </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The GDS fecal carriage rate was 6 % in case of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> colonoscopy, 1.3 % in case of non-tumoral lesions, 3.2 % in case of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0086692" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">benign tumors</z:e>, and 11 % in case of premalignant/<z:mp ids='MP_0002018'>malignant tumors</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>These four percentages were not statistically different </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The GDS fecal carriage rate was lower than expected, which did not confirm our working hypothesis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Most strains belonged to S. bovis biotype II, while S. gallolyticus was found only once </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>These findings suggest that different GDS play different roles in the etiopathogenesis of IE and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>