<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Laparoscopic hepatectomy (LH) for management of hepatic colorectal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027627" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="mets">metastases</z:e> (HCRM) is commonly being performed; however, there are limited reports comparing LH outcomes with those of open hepatectomy <z:chebi fb="2" ids="29191">(OH)</z:chebi> procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of the present study was to compare perioperative outcomes between the LH and OH procedures performed at a single medical center </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: From Jan 2008 to May 2012, 30 patients with pathologically confirmed HCRM underwent LH, and 140 patients underwent OH at our hospital </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients' demographics, perioperative outcomes were retrospectively analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 2 patients (6.7%) in the LH group underwent laparotomies for intraoperative <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The LH group had an increased surgical duration (235 min vs. 365 min, (P&lt;0.001), shorter hospital stay (7.5 days vs. 11.5 days, P&lt;0.001), and fewer complications (26.2% vs. 55%, P&lt;0.001) than the OH group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, in a matched cohort comparison of 30 LH cases and 30 OH cases, no significant variations were observed in the following parameters: surgical duration (235 min vs. 255 min, P = 0.23), positive margin rates (6.7% vs. 0.0%, P = 0.27), or postoperative hematological changes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>LH patients had less estimated blood loss (215 ml vs. 385 ml, P&lt;0.001), less morbidity (26.2% vs. 50%, P = 0.02), shorter hospital stay (7.5 days vs. 11.5 days, P&lt;0.001), and lower <z:chebi fb="29" ids="35480">analgesic</z:chebi> requests than with those in the OH group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: LH for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948380" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">metastatic colorectal cancer</z:e> is a safe and feasible treatment, even in patients who underwent prior laparotomy surgeries and provides significantly less morbidity and shorter hospital stay than OH, without compromising curability or increasing morbidity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>