<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Abstract The aim of the present work was to perform a meta-analysis to evaluate the association between the interleukin 10 (IL-10) -819C/T (rs1800871) polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A total of 73 studies, including 15,942 cancer cases and 22,336 controls, were identified in this meta-analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The odds ratios (ORs) with 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were calculated using the random-effects model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Overall, no significant association was identified between the IL-10 -819C/T polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In the subgroup analyses, the T allele and TT genotype were associated with a moderately reduced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> risk in the Asian population (T allele vs. C allele: OR=0.93, 95%CI: 0.87, 0.99; TT vs. CC: OR=0.86, 95%CI: 0.76, 0.98; TT vs. CT/CC: OR=0.90, 95%CI: 0.82, 0.98) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Individuals who were homozygous for the T allele (TT) were found to be associated with significantly reduced <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> risk in the Asian population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The heterozygous variant (CT) and the dominant model (TT/CT vs. CC) were associated with an increased risk for cervical and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1140680" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">ovarian cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, the IL-10 -819C/T polymorphism was not significantly associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0003002'>breast cancer</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242379" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">lung cancer</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001402'>hepatocellular carcinoma</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0012125'>prostate cancer</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002861'>melanoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The depressed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> risk of the TT genotype occurred in the studies of hospital-based case-control studies and the studies recruited less than 500 subjects, but no statistically significant results were found in the stratified analyses using genotyping method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The results suggest that the IL-10 -819TT genotype may be a protective factor for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> in Asians, especially <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the CT genotype and the dominant model could be risk factors for cervical and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1140680" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">ovarian cancer</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The importance of stratifying by ethnicity, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> type, study design, and sample size needs to be standardized in future studies, together with considering the association between the IL-10 -819C/T polymorphism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, the linkage of -819C/T with other polymorphisms of the IL-10 gene may help explain the variability in findings </plain></SENT>
</text></document>