<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Several prospective cohort studies have examined the association between pre- and / or post-diagnosis physical activity (PA) on <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e> outcomes and reported conflicting results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To quantitatively assess this association, we have conducted a meta-analysis of prospective studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Databases and reference lists of relevant studies were searched using MEDLINE and EMBASE up to January of 2013 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Pooled relative risks (RRs) with 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were calculated using random-effects models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>For this meta-analysis, a total of seven prospective cohort studies were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The analysis included 5,299 patients for pre-diagnosis PA and 6,348 patients for post-diagnosis PA, followed up over a period ranging from 3.8 to 11.9 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The analyses showed that patients who participated in any amount of PA before diagnosis had a RR of 0.75 (95% CI: 0.65-0.87, p&lt;0.001) for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>-specific mortality, compared with patients who did not participate in any PA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Those who participated in high PA before diagnosis (vs. low PA) had a RR of 0.70 (95% CI: 0.56-0.87, p=0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Similarly, patients who participated in any PA after diagnosis had a RR of 0.74 (95% CI: 0.58-0.95, p=0.02) for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>-specific mortality, compared with patients who did not participate in any PA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Those who participated in high PA after diagnosis (vs. low PA) had a RR of 0.65 (95% CI: 0.47-0.92, p=0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Similar inverse associations of pre-diagnosis PA or post-diagnosis PA were found for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, both pre-diagnosis PA and post-diagnosis PA were associated with reduced <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527249,C0009402" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">colorectal cancer</z:e>-specific mortality and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause mortality. © 2013 Wiley Periodicals, Inc </plain></SENT>
</text></document>