<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine if anti-beta2 GPI reactive with surface-bound beta2 GPI can bind C1q, i. e. to determine whether surface-bound beta2 GPI-anti-beta2 GPI immune complexes can initiate the classical pathway of complement activation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Beta2 GPI was bound to chemically-activated microtiter plates which had previously been shown to promote anti-beta2 GPI reactivity with bound beta2 GPI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Wells with surface-bound beta2 GPI (capped with bovine serum albumin) were then reacted with complement-inactivated sera from <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> patients (APS) or with control sera </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Following removal of unbound serum components, the wells were incubated with biotinylated C1q and probed with peroxidase-conjugated avidin D </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Bound C1q was detected at 450 nm using tetramethyl benzidine/peroxidase as a substrate system and expressed as absorbance units (Abs) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The identified 20 APS with elevated anti-beta2 GPI: 4 with IgG only, 4 with IgM only, 1 with IgA only, 1 with IgG and IgA, 6 with IgG and IgM and 4 with IgG, IgA and IgM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>C1q binding from 20 healthy controls was 0.039 +/- 0.029 (SD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Of the APS, 17/20 (85%) had Abs &gt;5 SD above controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The 3 APS with C1q Abs within <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> limits had, respectively, IgM only (1), IgA only (1), and both IgG and IgM (1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Statistical analyses (Kruskal-Wallis followed by Dunn's post test) suggest differences in IgG and IgG + IgM groups compared to con (Kruskal-Wallis: p = 0.0002; Dunn's: con vs. IgG, p &lt; 0.05; con vs. IgG + IgM, p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Anti-beta2 GPI from APS appear to have a variable degree of C1q affinity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Those patients with strong C1q binding responses are likely to have an inflammatory component to their disease processes </plain></SENT>
</text></document>