<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: A considerable diversity in prognosis is seen with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024138,C0024141,C0024131,C0409974" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lupus</z:e> <z:hpo ids='HP_0000099'>glomerulonephritis</z:hpo> (LGN) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Hence, the clinical usefulness of a recent International Society of Nephrology/Renal Pathology Society (ISN/RPS) 2003 classification to judge the long-term outcome of human LGN has been investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We studied retrospectively 60 subjects with LGN (7 males, 53 females, mean age of 33 years old) who underwent renal biopsies and were followed from 1 to 366 months, with a mean of 187 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We diagnosed renal pathology as classes, active and sclerosing lesions, according to the new and WHO1995 classification of LGN, and analyzed the clinicopathologic factors affecting to the prognosis of LGN </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: New classification got much higher consensus in the judgment of classes (98% vs. 83%, P = 0.0084) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The group of Class IV-S (N = 6) or IV-G (N = 17) at initial biopsies showed higher rate of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003774'>end-stage renal failure</z:hpo> (ESRF) compared with that of Class I, II, III or V (40.9% vs. 2.6%, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean 50% renal survival time of Class IV was 189 +/- 29 months, and patients with Class IV-S tended to have a poorer prognosis (95 +/- 22 months for IV-S vs. 214 +/- 35 months for IV-G, P = 0.1495) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Class IV was also selected as the most significant risk factor for ESRF by stepwise model (P = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In subanalysis for ESRF in Class IV (-S or -G), treatment including <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6888">methylprednisolone</z:chebi> pulse therapy was only selected as a significant improving factor for primary outcome (P = 0.034) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In addition, activity index was the significant risk factor of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> and/or ESRF after initial renal biopsies (P = 0.043) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>As for actuarial patient <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> during <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> follow-up periods, complications with anti-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16247">phospholipid</z:chebi> syndrome or <z:hpo ids='HP_0000100'>nephrotic syndrome</z:hpo> were significant risk factors (P = 0.013, P = 0.041, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: New ISN/RPS 2003 classification provided beneficial pathologic information relevant to the long-term renal outcome and the optimal therapy preventing ESRF and/or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> in patients with LGN </plain></SENT>
</text></document>