<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> (APLS) is characterized by <z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>thrombocytopenia</z:hpo>, thromboembolic phenomena, and recurrent fetal loss, associated with anticardiolipin antibodies (ACA) and/or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024138,C0024141,C0024131,C0409974" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lupus</z:e> <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50249">anticoagulant</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The syndrome may be primary or may be associated with other conditions such as <z:hpo ids='HP_0002725'>systemic lupus erythematosus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We have previously shown the ability to induce APLS in naive mice following passive transfer of serum and monoclonal ACAs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Similarly we generated the secondary APLS in BALB/c mice following immunization with a pathogenic anti-DNA antibody </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In the current study we report on the induction of primary APLS following immunization of BALB/c mice with a human monoclonal ACA (H-3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The mice developed high persistent titers of ACA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The APLS was characterized by <z:hpo ids='HP_0003645'>prolonged activated partial thromboplastin time</z:hpo>, low fecundity rate (21% vs. 48% of control immunized mice), high resorption index of fetuses (25% vs. 3%), and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004325'>low weights</z:hpo> of embryos and placentae </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Our study points to the ability of inducing primary APLS in naive mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The induction of various presentations of APLS by different ACA may explain the diversity of clinical manifestations seen in patients with APLS </plain></SENT>
</text></document>