<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> (APS), characterised by <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0000809" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">recurrent miscarriage</z:e> and <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp>, is a significant cause of morbidity and mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Domain I (DI) of human beta 2 glycoprotein I (beta2GPI) is thought to contain crucial antibody binding <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53000">epitopes</z:chebi> for <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid antibodies</z:hpo> (aPL), which are critical to the pathogenesis of APS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Expressing this protein in bacteria could facilitate studies investigating how this molecule interacts with aPL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Using a computer programme called Juniper, sequentially overlapping primers were designed to be used in a recursive polymerase chain reaction (PCR) to produce a synthetic DI gene </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Specifically Juniper incorporates 'major' codons preferred by bacteria altering 41 codons out of 61 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This was cloned into the expression plasmid pET(26b) and expressed in BL21(DE3) Escherichia coli (E. coli) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>By virtue of a pelB leader sequence, periplasmic localisation of DI aided disulphide bond formation and toxicity was addressed by tightly regulating expression through the high stringency T7lac promoter </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Purified, soluble his-tagged DI in yields of 750 microg/L <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> culture was obtained and confirmed on Western blot </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Expression using the native human cDNA sequence of DI in the same construct under identical conditions yielded significantly less DI compared to the recombinant optimised sequence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This constitutes the first description of prokaryotic expression of soluble DI of beta2GPI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Binding to murine monoclonal antibodies that recognise conformationally restricted <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53000">epitopes</z:chebi> on the surface of DI and pathogenic human monoclonal IgG aPL was confirmed by direct and indirect immunoassay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Recombinant DI also bound a series of 21 polyclonal IgG samples derived from patients with APS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: By producing a synthetic gene globally optimised for expression in E. coli, tightly regulating expression and utilising periplasmic product translocation, efficient, soluble E. coli expression of the eukaryotic protein DI of beta2GPI is possible </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>This novel platform of expression utilising pan-gene prokaryote codon optimisation for DI production will aid future antigenic studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Furthermore if DI or <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> derivatives of DI are eventually used in the therapeutic setting either as toleragen or as a competitive inhibitor of pathogenic aPL, then an E. coli production system may aid cost-effective production </plain></SENT>
</text></document>