<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: To determine and characterize the prevalence of cerebral changes on MRI in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> (APLS) within <z:hpo ids='HP_0002725'>systemic lupus erythematosus</z:hpo> (SLE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Seventy-one patients with SLE were prospectively studied with brain MRI: 32 with definite APLS and 39 without </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>Atrophy</z:mpath>, ventricular enlargement, leukoaraiosis, interuncal distance, Evans' index, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath>, and white matter hyperintensities (WMH) were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Demographic data, treatment, and SLE activity were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Groups were similar in age (32.4 vs. 32.8 years old; P= non-significant [NS]), and gender </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Duration of disease was longer in patients with APLS (87.3 vs. 55.4 months; P= .064) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002120'>Cortical atrophy</z:hpo> was common in both groups (68.7% vs. 89.7%; P= NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Leukoaraiosis was present in only 3 patients (9.4%; P= .08), <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> in the APLS group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>WMH were found in more than 40% of the patients from both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>Infarcts</z:mpath> (21.9% vs. 2.6%; P= .019) and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> plus WHM (12.5% vs. 0; P= .037) were more common in patients with APLS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Although a higher prevalence of neurological involvement in SLE has been reported in APLS patients, we found gross brain changes to be similar between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Strokes</z:hpo> and leukoaraiosis were more common in the APLS group, consistent with the idea of an APLS-induced prothrombotic state </plain></SENT>
</text></document>