<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> (APS) represents a serious risk factor in pregnancy resulting in several complications, leading to fetal loss and hemostatic complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In this dedicated report, we describe our experiences in the treatment of pregnancies in patients with APS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The retrospective data from 140 pregnant women were investigated, and the treatment results of 121 patients were recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We studied two groups of patients receiving different treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The first group (N = 78) received the standard therapy with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004325'>low-weight</z:hpo>-molecular <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> (dalteparin 5000 U or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28304">certoparin</z:chebi> 3000 U daily) and aspirin (100 mg daily) and in the second group (N = 43) an additional 0.2 g/kg intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Outcomes were 74.3% and 83.7% live births in the first group and in the second group, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The abortion rate was similar in both groups (11.5% vs. 11.6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The late complication rate was lower in the second group (5.8% vs. 14.1%, P &lt; 0.05) than in the group with standard therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, we found a trend to higher percentage (&gt; 12%) of natural killer (NK) cells in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0032962" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pregnancy complications</z:e> (60% vs. 12%, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Our retrospective data shows an improvement of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0878751" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">late pregnancy</z:e> complications by additional use of IVIG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>It is possible that IVIG influences higher NK cell activity in patients with previous <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0032962" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pregnancy complications</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>