<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Increasing evidence incriminates bacteria, especially Mycoplasma fermentans, as possible arthritogenic agents in humans </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to investigate M. fermentans in the bloodstream of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001370'>rheumatoid arthritis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Two hundred and nineteen blood samples from patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001370'>rheumatoid arthritis</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002725'>systemic lupus erythematosus</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e>, and healthy individuals were screened by <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> culture and direct PCR in order to detect mycoplasmas; IgM and IgG against M. fermentans PG18 were also detected by ELISA and Immunoblotting assays in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001370'>rheumatoid arthritis</z:hpo> and healthy individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Blood samples from patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> and healthy individuals were negative for mycoplasma by culture or direct PCR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In blood samples from patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002725'>systemic lupus erythematosus</z:hpo> were detected by direct PCR M. fermentans in 2/50 (2%), M. hominis in 2/50 (2%) and U. urealyticum in 1/50 (0.5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In patients with RA M. fermentans was detected by culture in 13/87 blood samples and in 13/87 by direct PCR, however, there was only concordance between culture and direct PCR in six samples, so M. fermentans was detected in 20/87(23%) of the blood samples from patients with RA by either culture or PCR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Antibody-specific ELISA assay to M. fermentans PG18 was done, IgM was detected in sera from 40/87 patients with RA and in sera of 7/67 control individuals, IgG was detected in sera from 48/87 RA patients and in sera from 7/67 healthy individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Antibody-specific immunoblotting to M. fermentans PG18 showed IgM in sera from 35/87 patients with RA and in sera from 4/67 healthy individuals, IgG was detected in sera from 34/87 patients and in sera from 5/67 healthy individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our findings show that only M. fermentans produce <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004610" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bacteremia</z:e> in a high percentage of patients with RA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This finding is similar to those reported in the literature </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>IgM and IgG against M. fermentans PG18 were more frequent in patients with RA than healthy individuals </plain></SENT>
</text></document>