<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Ninety-one consecutive <z:hpo ids='HP_0002725'>systemic lupus erythematosus</z:hpo> (SLE) patients (American College of Rheumatology criteria) with a history of cutaneous <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> were compared to 163 SLE controls without this clinical manifestation from July to December 2007 in order to determine the possible clinical and serological association of this manifestation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Data were obtained in an ongoing electronic database protocol and autoantibodies to anti-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="4705">double-stranded DNA</z:chebi>, anti-Sm, anti-RNP, anti-Ro/SS-A, anti-La/SS-B, and anticardiolipin and ribosomal P protein antibody (anti-P) were detected by standard techniques </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Exclusion criteria were the presence of anti-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16247">phospholipid</z:chebi> syndrome or antibodies, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1527336" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Sjögren</z:e> syndrome, and a history of <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The mean age (38.5 ± 11.5 vs. 37.8 ± 11.6 years, p = 0.635), disease duration (12.5 ± 7.8 vs. 11.8 ± 7.9 years, p = 0.501), and frequency of white race (71.4% vs. 70.5%, p = 0.872) and female sex (96.8% vs. 93.7%, p = 0.272) were comparable in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> group had a higher frequency of malar <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0015230" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">rash</z:e> (97.9% vs. 87.4%, p = 0.004), <z:hpo ids='HP_0000992'>photosensitivity</z:hpo> (91.4% vs. 81.6%, p = 0.030), and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0034735" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Raynaud phenomenon</z:e> (RP; 27.7% vs. 7.5%, p &lt; 0.001), whereas <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> other clinical manifestation including renal and central <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system involvements were similar to the control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Laboratorial data revealed that only anti-P (35.1% vs. 12.1%, p &lt; 0.001) was more frequent in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In a multivariate logistic regression model, cutaneous <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> was associated to the presence of RP (OR = 3.70; 95% confidence interval [CI] = 1.73-8.00) and anti-P (OR = 3.42; 95% CI = 1.76-6.66) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In summary, SLE cutaneous <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> characterizes a subgroup of patients with more RP and anti-P antibodies but not accompanied by a higher frequency of renal and central <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system involvements </plain></SENT>
</text></document>