<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Anti-centromere antibodies (ACA) are useful biomarkers in the diagnosis of systemic <z:mp ids='MP_0000612'>sclerosis</z:mp> (SSc) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>ACA are found in 20 to 40% of SSc patients and, albeit with lower prevalence, in patients with other systemic autoimmune <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0035435" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">rheumatic diseases</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Historically, ACA were detected by indirect immunofluorescence (IIF) on HEp-2 cells and confirmed by immunoassays using recombinant CENP-B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to evaluate a novel CENP-A <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> ELISA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Sera collected from SSc patients (n=334) and various other diseases (n=619) and from healthy controls (n=175) were tested for anti-CENP-A antibodies by the novel CENP-A enzyme linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, ACA were determined in the disease cohorts by IIF (ImmunoConcepts, Sacramento, CA, USA), CENP-B ELISA (Dr. Fooke), EliA CENP (Phadia, Freiburg, Germany) and line-immunoassay (LIA, Mikrogen, Neuried, Germany) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Serological and clinical associations of anti-CENP-A with other autoantibodies were conducted in one participating centre </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Inhibition experiments with either the CENP-A <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> or recombinant CENP-B were carried out to analyse the specificity of anti-CENP-A and -B antibodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The CENP-A ELISA results were in good agreement with other ACA detection methods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>According to the kappa method, the qualitative agreements were: 0.73 (vs. IIF), 0.81 (vs. LIA), 0.86 (vs. CENP-B ELISA) and 0.97 (vs. EliA CENP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The quantitative comparison between CENP-A and CENP-B ELISA using 265 samples revealed a correlation value of rho=0.5 (by Spearman equation) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The receiver operating characteristic analysis indicated that the discrimination between SSc patients (n=131) and various controls (n=134) was significantly better using the CENP-A as compared to CENP-B ELISA (P&lt;0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Modified Rodnan skin score was significantly lower in the CENP-A negative group compared to the positive patients (P=0.013) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Inhibition experiments revealed no significant cross reactivity of anti-CENP-A and anti-CENP-B antibodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Statistically relevant differences for gender ratio (P=0.0103), specific joint involvement (<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0152084" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Jaccoud</z:e>) (P=0.0006) and anti-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16247">phospholipid</z:chebi> syndrome (P=0.0157) between ACA positive SLE patients and the entire SLE cohort were observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Anti-CENP-A antibodies as determined by <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> ELISA represent a sensitive, specific and independent marker for the detection of ACA and are useful biomarkers for the diagnosis of SSc </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Our data suggest that anti-CENP-A antibodies are a more specific biomarker for SSc than antibodies to CENP-B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>Furthers studies are required to verify these findings </plain></SENT>
</text></document>