<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to analyze <z:chebi fb="27" ids="27300">vitamin D</z:chebi> levels and their association with bone mineral density and body composition in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0409980" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">primary antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>For this cross-sectional study 23 premenopausal women with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0409980" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">primary antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> (Sapporo criteria) and 23 age- and race-matched healthy controls were enrolled </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Demographic, anthropometric, clinical and laboratorial data were collected using clinical interview and chart review </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels, parathormone, calcium and 24-hour urinary calcium were evaluated in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Bone mineral density and body composition were studied by dual X-ray absorptiometry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The mean age of patients and controls was 33 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Weight (75.61 [20.73] vs. 63.14 [7.34] kg, p = 0.009), body mass index (29.57 [7.17] vs. 25.35 [3.37] kg, p = 0.014) and caloric ingestion (2493 [1005.6] vs. 1990 [384.1] kcal/day, p = 0.03) were higher in PAPS than controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> PAPS were under oral <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50249">anticoagulant</z:chebi> with INR within therapeutic range </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, biochemical bone parameters revealed lower levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D [21.64 (11.26) vs. 28.59 (10.67) mg/dl, p = 0.039], serum calcium [9.04 (0.46) vs. 9.3 (0.46) mg/dl, p = 0.013] and 24-hour urinary calcium [106.55 (83.71) vs. 172.92 (119.05) mg/d, p = 0.027] in patients than in controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Supporting these findings, parathormone levels were higher in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0409980" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">primary antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> than in controls [64.82 (37.83) vs. 44.53 (19.62) pg/ml, p = 0.028] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The analysis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000939'>osteoporosis</z:hpo> risk factors revealed that the two groups were comparable (p &gt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Lumbar spine, femoral neck, total femur and whole body bone mineral density were similar in both groups (p &gt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Higher fat mass [28.51 (12.93) vs. 20.01 (4.68) kg, p = 0.005] and higher percentage of fat [36.08 (7.37) vs. 31.23 (4.64)%, p = 0.010] were observed in PAPS in comparison with controls; although no difference was seen regarding lean mass </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In summary, low <z:chebi fb="27" ids="27300">vitamin D</z:chebi> in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0409980" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">primary antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> could be secondary to higher weight and fat mass herein observed most likely due to adipocyte sequestration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>This <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> may also justify the maintenance of bone mineral density even with altered biochemical bone parameters </plain></SENT>
</text></document>