<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>UNLABELLED: The study of hemostasis often arises in paediatrics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Evidence of activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) prolongation sometime due to the presence of a circulating <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50249">anticoagulant</z:chebi> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> [APS]) may be embarrassing for the physician </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>AIM OF THE STUDY: To evaluate the prevalence of this situation, to identify the leading indicators and assess their impact </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHOD: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> children aged 1 to 18 years old undergoing blood sample whatever was the reason, at the Nice University Hospital with existing isolated aPTT prolongation, were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The assessment was completed by a mixing test, calculation of Rosner's index as well as the study of an APS and the measurement of factor VIII, IX, XI, XII </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Between July 2006 and March 2008, 27 of 1845 children observed (1.5%) were selected for further study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Mean age was 6.17 years old </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>For 16 of the patients, aPTT prolongation was fortuitously discovered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Symptomatic subjects were older (9.8 vs. 5.2 years of age; P = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A significantly higher aPTT was indicative of an APS and predicted a positive Rosner Test outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>A prolongated kaolin clotting time, observed among the younger subjects (3.45 vs. 8.88 years of age; P = 0.0011), was associated with a high aPTT prolongation (57.3 vs. 42.6s; P = 0.0009) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In our study, the discovery of a prolongated aPTT is most often incidental and tends to occur during winter </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The presence of a highly prolongated aPTT, abnormal kaolin clotting time and positive Rosner Test are strong predictors of the existence of an APS, especially in very young children </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>These antibodies are nonpathogenic and transitional </plain></SENT>
</text></document>