<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To perform a global gonadal and sexual functions assessment in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0409980" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">primary antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> (PAPS) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A cross-sectional study was conducted in 12 male PAPS patients and 20 healthy controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>They were assessed by demographic data, clinical features, systematic urological examination, sexual function, testicular ultrasound, seminal parameters according to the World Health Organization (WHO), seminal sperm antibodies, and hormone profile, including follicle stimulating hormone (FSH), luteinizing hormone (LH), morning total <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi>, and thyroid hormones </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The median of current age and age of spermarche were similar in PAPS patients and controls (37.5 vs. 32.4 years, p = 0.270, and 13.1 vs. 12.85 years, p = 0.224, respectively), with a higher frequency of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000802'>erectile dysfunction</z:hpo> in the former group (25% vs. 0%, p = 0.044) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Further analysis of PAPS patients with and without previous <z:hpo ids='HP_0004420'>arterial thrombosis</z:hpo> demonstrated that the median penis circumference was significantly lower in PAPS with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004420'>arterial thrombosis</z:hpo> than in PAPS without this complication (8.1 [6-10] vs. 10.2 [10-11] cm, p = 0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In addition, the median penis circumference was significantly lower in PAPS patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000802'>erectile dysfunction</z:hpo> than in patients without this complication (7.5 [6-9.5] vs. 9.5 [7.5-11] cm, p = 0.039) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Regarding seminal analysis, the median sperm concentration, sperm motility, and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> sperm forms by WHO guidelines were comparable in PAPS patients and controls (141.5 [33-575] vs. 120.06 [34.5-329] × 10(6)/ml, p = 0.65; 61.29 [25-80] vs. 65.42 [43-82]%, p = 0.4; 21.12 [10-42.5] vs. 23.95 [10-45]%, p = 0.45, respectively), and none of them had oligo/<z:hpo ids='HP_0000027'>azoospermia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No differences were observed between PAPS patients and controls regarding the frequency of antisperm antibodies, testicular volume by ultrasound, or hormone profile (FSH, LH, morning total <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi>, and thyroid hormone) (p &gt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>Normal</z:mpath> testicular function has been identified in PAPS patients, in spite of morphofunctional penile abnormalities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Previous <z:hpo ids='HP_0004420'>arterial thrombosis</z:hpo> may underlie penile anthropometry alteration </plain></SENT>
</text></document>