<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Abstract Background: The pathogenesis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmunity</z:hpo> is presumed to be a complex process including genetic predisposition, hormonal balance and environmental factors such as infectious agents </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Helicobacter pylori, a common <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> infectious agent has been associated with a variety of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmune disorders</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, this bacteria is also thought to play a protective role in the development of multiple <z:mp ids='MP_0000612'>sclerosis</z:mp> (MS), <z:hpo ids='HP_0002725'>systemic lupus erythematosus</z:hpo> (SLE) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021390" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory bowel disease</z:e> (IBD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We tested various links between anti-H. pylori (anti-HP) antibodies and a wide profile of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmune diseases</z:hpo> and autoantibodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Methods: A total of 1290 patients diagnosed with 14 different <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmune diseases</z:hpo> from two geographical areas (Europe and Latin America) and two groups of healthy matching controls (n=385) were screened for the presence of H. pylori IgG antibodies by "pylori detect" kit </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In parallel, a large profile belonging to three groups of autoantibodies was tested in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> sera (anti-nuclear antibodies, autoantibodies associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100724'>thrombophilia</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0017178" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">gastrointestinal diseases</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Results: Our data demonstrate associations between anti-HP antibodies and anti-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16247">phospholipid</z:chebi> syndrome, giant cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0012089'>arteritis</z:hpo>, systemic <z:mp ids='MP_0000612'>sclerosis</z:mp> and primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002613'>biliary cirrhosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Our data also support a previously known negative association between the prevalence of anti-HP antibodies and IBD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Additionally, links were made between seropositivity to H. pylori and the presence of anti-nuclear antibodies, dsDNA, anti-Ro and some <z:hpo ids='HP_0100724'>thrombophilia</z:hpo>-associated antibodies, as well as negative associations with gastrointestinal-associated antibodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: Whether these links are epiphenomenal or H. pylori does play a causative role in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmune diseases</z:hpo> remains uncertain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The negative associations could possibly support the notion that in susceptible individuals <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> may protect from the development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmune diseases</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>