<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>To study whether monoclonal anticardiolipin antibodies (aCL), derived from patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> (APS), have similar pathogenic potential, we have employed an experimental model of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Monoclonal aCL were produced by the combined method of EBV transformation and somatic cell hybridization of lymphocytes, derived from patients with APS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The monoclonal aCL were used to immunize mice at the footpads and the mice were followed for serological and clinical manifestations of APS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The monoclonal antibody EY2C9, was found to bind weakly to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28494">cardiolipin</z:chebi> and other <z:chebi fb="1" ids="16247">phospholipids</z:chebi> (i.e. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26025">phosphatidyl</z:chebi>-serine, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26025">phosphatidyl</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16000,23981">ethanolamine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26025">phosphatidyl</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="1" ids="24848">inositol</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The antibody TM1B9, although derived from a patient with SLE and with secondary APS, did not react with <z:chebi fb="1" ids="16247">phospholipids</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Immunization of naive BALB/c mice with EY2C9 was followed by production of sustained high titers of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid antibodies</z:hpo> associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0003645'>prolonged activated partial thromboplastin time</z:hpo> (APTT) (46.8 +/- 5.0 s vs. 22.4 +/- 1.7 s, in the non-immunized mice) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Mice immunized with TM1B9 had a more moderate titer of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid antibodies</z:hpo> and did not show prolonged APTT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The pregnant mice, that were immunized with EY2C9, had increased <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0015951" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">fetal resorption</z:e> rate (the equivalent of fetal loss in the human) of 36.8 +/- 10% (vs. 2 +/- 4% in mice immunized with TM1B9) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Our results confirm that monoclonal aCL, derived from a patient with APS, can have a pathogenic potential, dysregulating the idiotypic network and leading to the development of characteristic signs of APS.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>