<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The immunological type of <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi>-associated <z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>thrombocytopenia</z:hpo> (HAT II) is a severe complication of <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> treatment and is associated with arterial and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Only patients with absolute <z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>thrombocytopenia</z:hpo> have prompted suspicion of HAT in clinical practice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We report on a 44-year-old male who developed thromboembolic episodes after coronary angiography such as reinfarction and thrombotic episodes of A. brachialis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Fibrinolytic therapy combined with i.v. unfractionated <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> treatment was the therapy of choice and was followed by severe further thromboembolic adverse effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Besides an impaired fibrinolytic response and elevated <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid antibodies</z:hpo>, we diagnosed HAT type II in HIPA and ELISA (Stago </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Boehringer-Mannheim) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>This special patient had platelet counts within a <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> range, when developing the thromboembolic episodes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>It appears that the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> platelet count during the thromboembolic episodes reflect a relative <z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>thrombocytopenia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>From a clinical point of view we recommend the use of a lab panel to exclude HAT type II in patients with thromboembolic episodes under therapy with fractionated or unfractionated <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Platelet counts within a <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> range are not absolute exclusion criterion for HAT II </plain></SENT>
</text></document>