<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Recurrent fetal wastage has been attributed to <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid antibody</z:hpo> syndrome (APAS); however, this has not been proven </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Assays of coagulation activation fragments which may provide evidence for a role for <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp>, have not been previously reported in this setting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We therefore investigated whether F1.2 levels are altered in APAS pregnancies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>F1.2 levels were performed on plasmas obtained from fifty-four <z:chebi fb="21" ids="53713">APA</z:chebi> patients with a history of persistent elevation of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid antibodies</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0000809" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">recurrent abortion</z:e> who were studied during eighty-three consecutive visits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Results from these patients were compared to a control group of thirty-two healthy pregnant females </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>F1.2 levels were significantly higher in APAS patients than controls in the second trimester (6.5 nM +/- 4.3 nM vs. 1.2 nM +/- 0.9 nM, p &lt; 0.0001), and in the third trimester of pregnancy (8.6 nM +/- 2.5 nM vs. 3.7 nM +/- 2.0 nM, p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The F1.2 levels in the <z:chebi fb="21" ids="53713">APA</z:chebi> group returned to baseline soon after delivery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No correlation was observed between F1.2 and <z:chebi fb="21" ids="53713">APA</z:chebi> values </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This study shows that pregnant patients with a history of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0000809" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">recurrent abortions</z:e> and <z:chebi fb="21" ids="53713">APA</z:chebi> have significantly increased activation of prothrombin compared to healthy pregnant females </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These data indicate that the potential value of activations <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> assays such as F1.2 in this setting should be tested in prospective clinical trials </plain></SENT>
</text></document>