<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The mechanisms of vascular <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> and pregnancy loss in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid-antibody</z:hpo> syndrome are unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Levels of annexin V, a <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16247">phospholipid</z:chebi>-binding protein with potent <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50249">anticoagulant</z:chebi> activity, are markedly reduced on placental villi from women with this syndrome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0100724'>Hypercoagulability</z:hpo> in such women may therefore be due to the reduction of surface-bound annexin V by <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid antibodies</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>To test this idea, we studied how <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid antibodies</z:hpo> affect levels of annexin V on cultured trophoblasts and human umbilical-vein endothelial cells and how they affect the procoagulant activity of these cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We isolated IgG fractions from three patients with the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid-antibody</z:hpo> syndrome and from <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>These antibodies were incubated with cultured BeWo cells (a placental-trophoblast cell line), primary cultured trophoblasts, and human umbilical-vein endothelial cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Annexin V on the cell surfaces was measured by an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The coagulation times of plasma overlaid on the cells were also determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Trophoblasts and endothelial cells exposed to <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid-antibody</z:hpo> IgG as compared with control IgG had reduced levels of annexin V (trophoblasts, 0.37 +/- 0.02 vs. 0.85 +/- 0.12 ng per well, P=0.02; endothelial cells, 1.6 +/- 0.04 vs. 2.1 +/- 0.05 ng per well, P=0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Also, trophoblasts and endothelial cells exposed to <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid-antibody</z:hpo> IgG had faster mean (+/- SE) plasma coagulation times than cells exposed to control IgG (trophoblasts, 8.7 +/- 2.0 vs. 21.3 +/- 2.9 minutes, P=0.02; endothelial cells, 9.8 +/- 0.8 vs. 14.2 +/- 1.2 minutes, P=0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>Antiphospholipid antibodies</z:hpo> reduce the levels of annexin V and accelerate the coagulation of plasma on cultured trophoblasts and endothelial cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The reduction of annexin V levels on vascular cells may be an important mechanism of <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> and pregnancy loss in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid-antibody</z:hpo> syndrome </plain></SENT>
</text></document>