<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085278" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">antiphospholipid syndrome</z:e> (APS) is characterised by both arterial and <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo>, recurrent pregnancy loss and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0040034" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">thrombocytopaenia</z:e> in association with <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid antibodies</z:hpo> (aPL) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To explore further the pathogenesis of <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> in APS, we evaluated the behaviour of tissue factor (TF) pathway in patients with APS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Plasma antigen levels of soluble TF and tissue factor pathway inhibitor (TFPI), a physiological regulator of TF dependent coagulation activation, were measured in 57 APS patients (36 primary and 21 secondary to <z:hpo ids='HP_0002725'>systemic lupus erythematosus</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Significantly elevated levels of both TF and TFPI were found in APS patients compared with 25 healthy controls (279 +/- 15 vs. 217 +/- 17 pg/ml, p = 0.01; 56.24 +/- 2.00 vs. 47.92 +/- 2.22 ng/ml, p = 0.01, respectively), suggesting in vivo upregulation of TF pathway in patients with APS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>By flow-cytometry, monocytes from a healthy donor displayed higher TF antigen expression when incubated in the presence of APS plasmas than in control plasmas (24.23 +/- 3.11 vs. 12.78 +/- 1.57%, p = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) also expressed more procoagulant activity (<z:chebi fb="20" ids="36751">PCA</z:chebi>) when incubated in the presence of APS plasmas than in control plasmas (1.80 +/- 0.12 vs. 1.35 +/- 0.054, p = 0.001) implying that TF up-regulation in APS was reproducible in vitro </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Human monoclonal anticardiolipin antibodies induced <z:chebi fb="20" ids="36751">PCA</z:chebi> on PBMC and also TF <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> on both PBMC and human umbilical vein endothelial cells shown by reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These data strongly suggest that the TF pathway is implicated in the pathogenesis of aPL related <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>