<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024408" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MJD|SCA3">Machado-Joseph disease</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MJD</z:e>), an <z:hpo ids='HP_0000006'>autosomal dominant</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002503'>spinocerebellar degeneration</z:hpo> caused by an expanded CAG repeat on chromosome 14q32.1, is a disorder with wide range of neurological findings and brain regions involved </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Studies evaluating neurophysiological parameters related to sensory gating in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MJD</z:e> are lacking </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This study intends to investigate P50 suppression, an auditory mid-latency evoked potential in a test-conditioning paradigm, considered as an index of sensory gating function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Twelve patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MJD</z:e>, 24 <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> subjects and 12 schizophrenic patients were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MJD</z:e> subjects had higher P50 ratios as compared to <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> subjects (76.2 vs. 42.1%, P = 0.001), but similar to the group of schizophrenic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The difference from controls was due to greater test amplitudes (3.4 vs. 2.0 microV, P = 0.002), rather than to conditioning amplitudes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Latencies were higher for the <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MJD</z:e> subjects than for controls (60.4 vs. 56.1 ms, P = 0.016) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MJD</z:e> may present sensory gating dysfunction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, the pattern of this dysfunction seems to slightly differ from that classically found in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100753'>schizophrenia</z:hpo>, were both test and conditioning amplitudes seem to be implicated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>SIGNIFICANCE: These results point out the P50 paradigm as a potential tool for further neurophysiological surveying in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MJD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>