<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024408" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="MJD|SCA3">Machado-Joseph disease</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MJD</z:e>) is the most common dominant spinocerebellar <z:hpo ids='HP_0001251'>ataxia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MJD</z:e> is caused by a CAG trinucleotide expansion in the ATXN3 gene, which encodes a protein named ataxin-3 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Ataxin-3 has been proposed to act as a deubiquitinating enzyme in the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway and to be involved in transcriptional repression; nevertheless, its precise biological function(s) remains unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>To gain further insight into the function of ataxin-3, we have identified the Caenorhabditis elegans orthologue of the ATXN3 gene and characterized its pattern of expression, developmental regulation, and subcellular localization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We demonstrate that, analogous to its human orthologue, C. elegans ataxin-3 has deubiquitinating activity in vitro against polyubiquitin chains with four or more ubiquitins, the minimum ubiquitin length for proteasomal targeting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>To further evaluate C. elegans ataxin-3, we characterized the first known knockout animal models both phenotypically and biochemically, and found that the two C. elegans strains were viable and displayed no gross phenotype </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>To identify a molecular phenotype, we performed a large-scale microarray analysis of gene expression in both knockout strains </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The data revealed a significant deregulation of core sets of genes involved in the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway, structure/motility, and signal transduction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This gene identification provides important clues that can help elucidate the specific biological role of ataxin-3 and unveil some of the physiological effects caused by its absence or diminished function </plain></SENT>
</text></document>