<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Spinocerebellar <z:hpo ids='HP_0001251'>ataxia</z:hpo> (SCA) types 1, 2, 3, 6, 7, and 17 as well as <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020179" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="HD">Huntington's disease</z:e> are a group of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0524851" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neurodegenerative disorders</z:e> caused by expanded CAG repeats encoding a long polyglutamine (polyQ) tract in the respective proteins </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Evidence has shown that the accumulation of intranuclear and cytoplasmic misfolded polyQ proteins leads to <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> and cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Thus suppression of aggregate formation is expected to inhibit a wide range of downstream pathogenic events in polyQ diseases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In this study, we established a high-throughput aggregation screening system using 293 ATXN3/Q75-GFP cells and applied this system to test the aqueous extract of Paeonia lactiflora (P. lactiflora) and its constituents </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We found that the aggregation can be significantly prohibited by P. lactiflora and its active compound paeoniflorin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Meanwhile, P. lactiflora and paeoniflorin upregulated HSF1 and HSP70 chaperones in the same cell models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Both of them further reduced the aggregation in neuronal differentiated SH-SY5Y ATXN3/Q75-GFP cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Our results demonstrate how P. lactiflora and paeoniflorin are likely to work on polyQ-aggregation reduction and provide insight into the possible working mechanism of P. lactiflora in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SCA3</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We anticipate our paper to be a starting point for screening more potential herbs for the treatment of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SCA3</z:e> and other polyQ diseases </plain></SENT>
</text></document>