<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We compared the rates of recanalization cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> and <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp> between intra-arterial (i.a.) reteplase and intravenous (i.v.) alteplase thrombolysis in a canine model of basilar artery <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>Thrombosis</z:mp> was induced by injecting a clot in the basilar artery of 13 anesthetized dogs via superselective catheterization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The animals were randomized in a blinded fashion, 2 h after clot injection and verification of <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>arterial occlusion</z:mp>, to receive i.v. alteplase 0.9 mg/kg over 60 min and i.a. placebo, or i.a. reteplase 0.09 units/kg over 20 min, equivalent to one-half the alteplase dose, and i.v. placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Recanalization was studied for 6 h after treatment with serial angiography; the images were later graded in a blinded fashion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Blinded interpretation of postmortem MRI was performed to assess the presence of brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> and/or <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>At 3 h after initiation of treatment, partial or complete recanalization was observed in one of six dogs in the i.v. alteplase group and in five of seven in the i.a. reteplase group (P = 0.08) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At 6 h, no significant difference in partial or complete recanalization was observed between the groups (two of six vs. five of seven; P = 0.20) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Postmortem MRI revealed <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> in four of six animals treated with i.v. alteplase and three of seven treated with i.a. reteplase (P = 0.4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001342'>Intracerebral hemorrhage</z:hpo> was more common in the i.v. alteplase group (four of six vs. none of seven; P = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This study thus suggests that i.a. thrombolysis affords a recanalization rate similar to that of i.v. thrombolysis, but with a lower rate of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001342'>intracerebral hemorrhage</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>