<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Provide evidence whether there is a difference in the presence of inflammatory parameters in patients with cerebrovascular attacks (<z:chebi fb="4" ids="46274">CVA</z:chebi>) with a thrombotic etiology as compared with a <z:chebi fb="4" ids="46274">CVA</z:chebi> with an embolic etiology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: In 45 patients with an <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:chebi fb="4" ids="46274">CVA</z:chebi> the level of C reactive protein (CRP) was assessed, interleukin 6 (IL-6), interleukin 8 (IL-8) and the value of the D-dimer </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients with clinical signs of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> were eliminated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>21 patients had a sinus rhythm (SR) and 24 patients <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo> (AF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Between the group of patients with SR and AF there was no difference in age or sex distribution </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The CRP concentration was in the SR group, as compared with the AF group, increased (4.67 mg/l vs. 3.65 mg/l, p = 0.043), similarly as the concentration of IL-8 (12.53 ng/l vs. 8.1 ng/l, p = 0.039) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The IL-6 concentrations in the two groups did not differ (5.45 ng/l vs. 5.014 n.s.), similarly as the number of patients with elevated D-dimer values (29% vs. 35% n.s.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The assembled findings of elevated inflammatory parameters in patients with <z:chebi fb="4" ids="46274">CVA</z:chebi> of a thrombotic etiology as compared with patients with <z:chebi fb="4" ids="46274">CVA</z:chebi> with embolic etiology indicate similarly as in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> coronary syndrome - the possible role of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> in the etiopathogenesis of thrombotic <z:chebi fb="4" ids="46274">CVA</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The results suggest the possible use of inflammatory markers for the differentiation of the etiology of ischaemic <z:chebi fb="4" ids="46274">CVA</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>