<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: This paper reports the complications of transsphenoidal surgery for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002893'>pituitary adenomas</z:hpo> in a series of 1240 consecutive patients operated at our Institute between 1990 and 2004 (first operations) and indicate the clinical characteristics of patients which affected surgical morbidity and mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: According to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e> type, there were 420 (33.9%) non-functioning <z:hpo ids='HP_0002893'>pituitary adenomas</z:hpo> (NFPA), 349 (28.1%) GH-secreting, 288 (23.2%) ACTH-secreting, 155 (12.5%) prolactin (PRL)-secreting, and 28 (2.3%) TSH-secreting <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The mean age of patients was 43.7 +/- 0.4 yr and 122 patients (9.9%) were 65 yr or older; the female/male ratio was 1.5/1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>There were 370 (29.8%) microadenomas and 870 (70.2%) macroadenomas of which 54 (4.4%) were giant <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The series mortality was 0.2%, the medical morbidity 1.9%, and the surgical morbidity 3.5% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Medical complications were significantly more frequent in patients older than 65 yr (4.9 vs. 1.4%; p = 0.009) and in patients with giant <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath> (5.6 vs. 1.6%; p = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis showed that both variables were independently associated with a higher morbidity rate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The surgical morbidity was increased in giant <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath> (15 vs. 3%; p = 0.0001), in NFPA (6.2 vs. 2.1% in secreting <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenomas</z:mpath>; p = 0.0002) and in patients older than 65 yr (6.6 vs. 3.1%; p = 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis showed that only giant size was independently associated with an increased surgical morbidity rate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In our experience, the size of the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_270'>adenoma</z:mpath> was a risk factor for medical and surgery related complications and age over 65 yr for medical complications alone </plain></SENT>
</text></document>