<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0005305'>Cerebral venous thrombosis</z:hpo> (CVT) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002625'>deep vein thrombosis</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002204'>pulmonary embolism</z:hpo> (DVT/PE) are associated with many risk factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It is unclear why CVT occurs less often than DVT/PE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Age dependent risk factors may play a role </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The aim of our study was to compare risk factors in a uniform age group of CVT and DVT/PE patients aged between 15 and 50 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Thrombophilic markers and clinical risk factors of 79 CVT patients and 173 DVT/PE patients aged 15-50 years were compared </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Multivariable logistic regression analysis was performed to investigate if risk factors were independently associated with CVT or DVT/PE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0005305'>Cerebral venous thrombosis</z:hpo> patients were younger (median age 30 years vs. 42 years; p&lt;0.001) and more often female (82% vs. 52%; p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There were no differences in thrombophilic markers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0005305'>Cerebral venous thrombosis</z:hpo> was less often associated with trauma, immobilisation or surgery than DVT/PE (6% vs. 21%; adjusted OR 0.29; 95%CI 0.10-0.82) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In women, CVT was more frequently associated with oral contraceptive use, pregnancy or puerperium (82% vs. 53%; adjusted OR 2.34; 95%CI 1.03-5.32) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This study demonstrated no differences in thrombophilic markers between CVT patients and DVT/PE patients aged between 15 and 50 years, while the frequency of some transient risk factors was different </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0005305'>Cerebral venous thrombosis</z:hpo> was relatively more common in women and hormonal factors may predispose to CVT compared to DVT/PE, while trauma, immobilisation and surgery may be less important in the pathophysiology of CVT </plain></SENT>
</text></document>