<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We assessed blood-brain barrier (<z:chebi fb="2" ids="33602">BBB</z:chebi>) disruption in early stage of photothrombotic focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> in the rat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We specifically looked for contralateral changes in <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33602">BBB</z:chebi> permeability and tested the influence of two <z:chebi fb="37" ids="38867">anesthetics</z:chebi> on the results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Adult Wistar rats were randomly anesthetized with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="7983">pentobarbital</z:chebi> (PB) or ketamine-xylazine (KX) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Rats received intravenously (i.v.) <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52261">Rose Bengal</z:chebi> followed by Evans Blue (EB) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Stereotactically defined spots on denuded skull were irradiated by laser (532 nm) for 18 min </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Twenty four hours later, rats were killed, brains perfused, fixated, sectioned and slices analyzed by fluorescence microscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Volume of <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> and volume of EB-albumin extravasation were calculated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Evidence of <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33602">BBB</z:chebi> breakdown in remote brain areas was sought and compared to sham handled controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="2" ids="33602">BBB</z:chebi> disruption was consistently present, frequently with EB-albumin accumulating cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Total lesion volume did not significantly differ among groups (TLVPB=9.4±1.3 mm³ vs. TLVKX=8.3±2.1 mm³); same was true for the volume of <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> (NVPB=5.1±0.7 mm³ vs. NVKX=6.3±1.9 mm³) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>However, volume of EB-albumin extravasation area was significantly smaller in KX group (EBEVPB=4.3±0.8 mm³ vs. EBEVKX=2.0±0.5 mm³; p=0.0293) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Median background EB-fluorescence signal density was higher in PB group (p&lt;0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, regional increase in EB-fluorescence was found in two animals in PB group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Our study shows that anesthesia with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">NMDA</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi> ketamine and α2-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="37886">adrenergic agonist</z:chebi> xylazine may reduce <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33602">BBB</z:chebi> breakdown in photothrombosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="7983">Pentobarbital</z:chebi> anesthesia lead to increased <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33602">BBB</z:chebi> permeability in the contralateral hemisphere </plain></SENT>
</text></document>