<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Morphological and functional changes in the enteric <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system (ENS) have been reported in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021390" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory bowel disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We examined the effects of <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> on the expression of <z:chebi fb="3" ids="15354">choline</z:chebi> acetyltransferase (ChAT) and nNOS in the muscularis externae of two models of colonic <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="48110">trinitrobenzene</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29214">sulfonic acid</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="53063,53506">TNBS</z:chebi>)-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo>, which models <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo>-like <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, and DSS-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo>, which models <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative Colitis</z:hpo>-like <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53063,53506">TNBS</z:chebi> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo>, we observed significant decline in ChAT, nNOS, and protein gene product (PGP) 9.5 protein and <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In DSS <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo>, ChAT and PGP9.5 were significantly upregulated while nNOS levels did not change </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The nNOS dimer-to-monomer ratio decreased significantly in DSS- but not in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53063,53506">TNBS</z:chebi>-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>No differences were observed in the percentage of either ChAT (31 vs. 33%)- or nNOS (37 vs. 41%)-immunopositive neurons per ganglia or the mean number of neurons per ganglia (55 ± 5 vs. 59 ± 5, P &gt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Incubation of the distal colon muscularis externae in vitro with different types of <z:mp ids='MP_0002501'>inflammatory mediators</z:mp> showed that cytokines decreased ChAT and nNOS expression, whereas H₂O₂, a component of <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp>, increased their expression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>NF-κB inhibitor MG-132 did not prevent the IL-1β-induced decline in either ChAT or nNOS expression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>These findings showed that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53063,53506">TNBS</z:chebi>- and DSS-induced <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> differentially regulates the expression of two critical proteins expressed in the colonic myenteric neurons </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These differences are likely due to the exposure of the myenteric plexus neurons to different combinations of Th1-type <z:mp ids='MP_0002501'>inflammatory mediators</z:mp> and H₂O₂ in each model </plain></SENT>
</text></document>