<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: We propose that higher airway occlusion pressure (P0.1) responses to hypercapnic challenge (HC) indicate less severe injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The study aim was to determine whether P0.1 responses to HC were associated with successful weaning after prolonged mechanical ventilation (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PMV</z:e>) in patients with brainstem lesions and to determine a reference value for clinical use </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>DESIGN AND SETTING: Forty-two patients with brainstem lesions on <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PMV</z:e> were recruited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Breathing parameters and P0.1 were measured before HC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Three-minute HC challenges with increasing <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16526">CO(2)</z:chebi> concentrations were initiated and P0.1, respiratory rate, minute ventilation (V (e)), tidal volume (V (t)) and end tidal <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16526">CO(2)</z:chebi> were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>MEASUREMENTS AND RESULTS: Patients were classified into high (group I) and low (group II) response groups on the basis of P0.1 responses to HC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Increases in V (e) and V (t) after HC were significantly greater in group I patients (12.22 +/- 8.22 vs. 3.08 +/- 4.84 L/min, P &lt; 0.001 and 399.11 +/- 278.18 vs. 110.54 +/- 18.275 ml, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>P0.1 levels were significantly higher in group I compared to group II before HC (2.69 +/- 1.81 vs. 1.28 +/- 1.04 cmH(2)O, P = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The increase in P0.1 following HC was significantly greater in group I compared to group II patients (11.05 +/- 4.06 vs. 2.90 +/- 2.53 cmH(2)O, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Weaning success was significantly higher in group I compared to group II patients (72.2% vs. 33.3%, P = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>A P0.1 increase of &gt;6 cmH(2)O following HC was significantly associated with successful weaning </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Assessing the P.01 response to serial increases in the level of HC may be a safe means to ascertain whether patients with brainstem lesions are ready for ventilator weaning </plain></SENT>
</text></document>