<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A case of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1611178" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cheiro-oral syndrome</z:e> presumably due to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0521542" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain stem infarction</z:e> was reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A 41-year-old man suddenly experienced the numbness of the palm and the lips on the left side at 2 p. m </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>March 30, 1982 and was admitted to our clinic at 5 p.m. on that day </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Neurological examination on admission revealed hypesthesia of the palm and the lips on the left side, but pain and temperature sensibilities were preserved </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Neither <z:hpo ids='HP_0010527'>astereognosia</z:hpo> nor extinction phenomenon was there </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CT scan showed no abnormal findings </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At 9 p.m. his speaking became somewhat obscure and he became unable to swallow fluid </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>And after ten hours or so, he became quadriplegic, anarthric and lost almost <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> voluntary movement below the eye, while his consciousness was preserved ("Locked-in" syndrome) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CT scan taken on the 9th hospital day revealed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0521542" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain stem infarction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>He expired on the 58 th hospital day because of the exacerbation of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002090'>pneumonia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>At autopsy both vertebral arteries and basilar artery were markedly sclerotic </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The rostral two-thirds of the basilar artery was occluded by organized <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The serial microscopic sections through the midbrain and the medulla oblongata showed extensive infarction of the basis pontis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The tegmentum pontis remained free, except that a small offshoot of the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> reached into the medial part of the medial lemniscus.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>