<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A case of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0038505" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="PKWS">Sturge-Weber syndrome</z:e> with marked abnormalities in the cerebral venous system was reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The patient was a 2-year old boy who was admitted to the Department of Neurosurgery with the chief complaints of left <z:hpo ids='HP_0001269'>hemiparesis</z:hpo> and left <z:hpo ids='HP_0007359'>focal seizures</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>He had vascular <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027960" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">nevi</z:e> on the forehead and upper lip of his face, scalp, right forearm and thigh (Fig. 1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Neurological examination of admission revealed left <z:hpo ids='HP_0001269'>hemiparesis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Plain skull films indicated no <z:hpo ids='HP_0002514'>intracranial calcification</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>EEG showed paroxysmal focus in the right parieto-temporal area </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Plain CT scan showed calcium deposits in the right parietooccipital area and contrast enhancement occurred around the areas of calcification (Fig. 2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Venous phases of bilateral CAGs showed abnormalities of the cortical veins and sinuses and abnormal drainage from the cerebral cortex to the deep veins </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>It also demonstrated persistence of the primitive straight sinus (Fig. 3, 4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>From the neurological and neuroradiological findings, this case was diagnosed as the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0038505" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="PKWS">Sturge-Weber syndrome</z:e> with marked abnormalities in the cerebral venous system </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>These abnormal findings of veins and sinuses seemed to be brought about by development abnormalities of veins and sinuses which continuously occurred following Streeter's primordial plexus, which has been considered to be a cause of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0038505" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="PKWS">Sturge-Weber syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>