<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To investigate the correlation between ASCA and presence of mucosal S. cerevisiae DNA in a population of CD, <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> (UC) patients and controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: S. cerevisiae-specific primers and a <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39442">fluorescent probe</z:chebi> were designed for a 5' exonuclease real time PCR (TaqMan) assay, which is a homogenous system using a fluorescent-labelled probe for the detection of PCR product in real time </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We analyzed the relation of the PCR results with the ASCA findings in a group of 76 inflammatory <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021831" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bowel disease</z:e> (IBD) patients (31 CD, 45 UC) and 22 healthy controls (HC) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: ASCA (IgA or IgG) were positive in 19 (61%) patients with CD, 12 (27%) with UC and none of the HC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>PCR amplification was inhibited and excluded from the final results in 10 (22%) UC patients, 7 (22%) CD patients, and 6 (30%) HC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In only 15 of the mucosal samples, S. cerevisiae DNA was detected by real time PCR, including 7 (29%) in CD, 7 (19%) in UC, 1 (6%) in HC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In 4 CD and in 4 UC patients, ASCA and mucosal S. cerevisiae were positive </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Mucosal S. cerevisiae was present in combination with negative ASCA IgA and IgG in 3 UC, and 3 CD patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: We conclude that since the presence of S. cerevisiae in colonic mucosal biopsy specimens is very rare, ASCA is unlikely to be explained by continuous exposure to S. cerevisiae in the mucosa </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Therefore, ASCA formation must occur earlier in life and levels remain relatively stable thereafter in immunological susceptible persons </plain></SENT>
</text></document>