<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: In order to maintain the mucosal barrier against <z:chebi fb="2" ids="8069">luminal</z:chebi> microorganisms the intestinal epithelial cells synthesise various broad-spectrum antimicrobial <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptides</z:chebi> including defensins and cathelicidins </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Recent studies indicate that both may be deficient in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To elucidate the possible functional consequences of this deficiency antimicrobial activity in colonic mucosa from patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021390" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory bowel disease</z:e> and healthy controls was investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A flow cytometric assay was established to quantitate <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> killing and test the antibacterial activity of cationic <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> extracts from colonic biopsies taken from patients with active or inactive ileocolonic or colonic <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> (n = 22), <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> (n = 29) and controls (n = 13) against clinical isolates of Bacteroides vulgatus and Enterococcus faecalis or the reference strains Escherichia coli American Type Culture Collection (ATCC) 25922 and Staphylococcus aureus ATCC 25923 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Compared with controls and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> there was a reduced antimicrobial effect in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> extracts that was most evident against B. vulgatus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The antimicrobial effect against E. coli and E. faecalis was significantly lower in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> compared with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Activity against S. aureus disclosed a similar pattern, but was less pronounced </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The differences were independent of the <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> status or concurrent steroid treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Bacteria incubated with biopsy extracts from <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> patients frequently showed a characteristic change in cell size and granularity, compatible with more extensive membrane disintegration, compared with bacteria incubated with extracts from controls or <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> of the colon is characterized by a diminished functional antimicrobial activity that is consistent with the reported low antibacterial <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> expression </plain></SENT>
</text></document>