<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To evaluate the therapeutic effects of a probiotic supplement (Clostridium butyricum, CGMCC0313) in a chemically-induced rat model of experimental <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: An experimental <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> model was established by rectal injection of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53076">oxazolone</z:chebi> into the colon of 40 Wistar rats randomly divided into four groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The positive control group was sacrificed 3 d after <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The remaining groups were fed daily with either 2 mL of C. butyricum (2.3 x 10(11) CFU/L), 2 mL of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6775">mesalamine</z:chebi> (100 g/L), or 1 mL of <z:chebi fb="199" ids="26708">sodium</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17968">butyrate</z:chebi> (50 mmol/L) for 21 d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The animals' body weight, behavior, and bowel movements were recorded weekly </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After sacrifice, visual and microscopic observations of pathological changes of colon tissue were made, body weight and wet colon mass index were measured and recorded, and serum levels of interleukin-23 (IL-23) and TNF-alpha were measured using ELISA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Expression of calcitonin gene-related <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> in colon tissue was measured by RT-PCR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Finally, changes in rat intestinal microflora status were measured in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: We found that treatment with C. butyricum lowered the serum levels of both IL-23 and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> factor-alpha (TNF-alpha) with similar or even better efficiency than that of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6775">mesalamine</z:chebi> or <z:chebi fb="199" ids="26708">sodium</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17968">butyrate</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The rat intestinal flora appeared to recover more quickly in the group treated with C. butyricum than in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6775">mesalamine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="199" ids="26708">sodium</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17968">butyrate</z:chebi> groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Finally, we found that the expression level of calcitonin gene related <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> was elevated in colon tissue in the <z:chebi fb="199" ids="26708">sodium</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17968">butyrate</z:chebi> treated group but not in the C. butyricum or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6775">mesalamine</z:chebi> treated groups, indicating a sensitization of colon following <z:chebi fb="199" ids="26708">sodium</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17968">butyrate</z:chebi> treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In our experimental <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> model, treatment with C. butyricum CGMCC0313, a probiotic supplement, is at least as efficient as treatment with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6775">mesalamine</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>