<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021390" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</z:e> (IBD) remain significant health problems in the US and worldwide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>IBD is most often associated with eastern European ancestry, and is less frequently reported in other populations of African origin e.g. African Americans ('AAs') </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Whether AAs represent an important population with IBD in the US remains unclear since few studies have investigated IBD in communities with a majority representation of AA patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center in Shreveport (LSUHSC-S) is a tertiary care medical center, with a patient base composed of 58% AA and 39% Caucasian (W), ideal for evaluating racial (AA vs. W) as well and gender (M vs. F) influences on IBD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In this retrospective study, we evaluated 951 visits to LSUHSC-S for IBD (between 2000 to 2008) using non-identified patient information based on <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ICD</z:e>-9 medical record coding (<z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> 'CD'-555.0- 555.9 and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> 'UC'-556.0-556.9) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Overall, there were more cases of CD seen than UC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>UC and CD affected similar ratios of AA and Caucasian males (M) and females (F) with a rank order of WF &gt; WM &gt; AAF &gt; AAM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, in CD, we found that annual visits per person was the highest in AA M (10.7 ± 1.7); significantly higher (* -p &lt; 0.05) than in WM (6.3 ± 1.0) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Further, in CD, the female to male (F: M) ratio in AA was significantly higher (*- p &lt; 0.05) (1.9 ± 0.2) than in Caucasians (F:M = 1.3 ± 0.1) suggesting a female dominance in AACD; no differences were seen in UC F: M ratios </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Although Caucasians still represent the greatest fraction of IBD (~64%), AAs with IBD made up &gt;1/3 (36.4%) of annual IBD cases from 2000-2008 at LSUHSC-S </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Further studies on genetic and environments risks for IBD risk in AAs are needed to understand differences in presentation and progression in AAs and other 'non-traditional' populations </plain></SENT>
</text></document>