<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Blastocystosis is a frequent <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021831" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bowel disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We planned to to evaluate the prevalence of Blastocystis spp. in patients who applied to the same internal medicine-gastroenterology clinic with or without gastrointestinal complaints to reveal the association of this parasite with diagnosed <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IBS</z:e> and IBD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 2334 patients with gastrointestinal symptoms composed the study group, which included 335 patients with diagnosed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021390" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory bowel disease</z:e> and 877 with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022104" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IBS">irritable bowel syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients without any gastrointestinal symptoms or disease (n = 192) composed the control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Parasite presence was investigated by applying native-Lugol and formol <z:chebi fb="0" ids="27750">ethyl acetate</z:chebi> concentration to stool specimens, and trichrome staining method in suspicious cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Blastocystis spp. was detected in 134 patients (5.74%) in the study group and 6 (3.12%) in the control group (p = 0.128) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In the study group, Blastocystis spp. was detected at frequencies of 8.7% in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> (24/276), 6.78% in <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> (4/59), 5.82% in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022104" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IBS">irritable bowel syndrome</z:e> (51/877), and 4.9% in the remaining patients with gastrointestinal symptoms (55/1122) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Blastocystis spp. was detected at a statistically significant ratio in the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021390" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory bowel disease</z:e> (odds ratio [OR] = 2.824; 95% confidence interval [CI]: 1.149-6.944; p = 0.019) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> (OR = 2.952; 95% CI: 1.183-7.367; p = 0.016) patients within this group compared to controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There were no statistically significant differences between the control group and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022104" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IBS">irritable bowel syndrome</z:e> patients in terms Blastocystis spp. frequency (p = 0.251, p = 0.133) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Blastocystosis was more frequent in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021390" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory bowel disease</z:e>, especially those with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Although symptomatic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022104" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IBS">irritable bowel syndrome</z:e> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0100280'>Crohn's disease</z:hpo> patients had higher rates of Blastocystis spp. <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>, the differences were not significant when compared to controls </plain></SENT>
</text></document>