<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To investigate the effect of moxibustion on intestinal flora and release of interleukin-12 (IL-12) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> factor-α (TNF-α) from the colon in rat with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> (UC) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A rat model of UC was established by local stimulation of the intestine with supernatant from colonic contents harvested from human UC patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A total of 40 male Sprague-Dawley rats were randomly divided into the following groups: <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> (sham), model (UC), herb-partition moxibustion (HPM-treated), and positive control <z:chebi fb="3" ids="9334">sulfasalazine</z:chebi> (SA-treated) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Rats treated with HPM received HPM at acupuncture points ST25 and RN6, once a day for 15 min, for a total of 8 d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Rats in the SA group were perfused with SA twice a day for 8 d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The colonic histopathology was observed by <z:chebi fb="1" ids="51686">hematoxylin</z:chebi>-eosin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The levels of intestinal flora, including Bifidobacterium, Lactobacillus, Escherichia coli (E. coli), and Bacteroides fragilis (B. fragilis), were tested by real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction to detect <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> <z:chebi fb="4" ids="26833">16S</z:chebi> rRNA/DNA in order to determine DNA copy numbers of each specific species </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Immunohistochemical assays were used to observe the expression of TNF-α and IL-12 in the rat colons </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: HPM treatment inhibited <z:mpath ids='MPATH_188'>immunopathology</z:mpath> in colonic tissues of UC rats; the general morphological score and the immunopathological score were significantly decreased in the HPM and SA groups compared with the model group [3.5 (2.0-4.0), 3.0 (1.5-3.5) vs 6.0 (5.5-7.0), P &lt; 0.05 for the general morphological score, and 3.00 (2.00-3.50), 3.00 (2.50-3.50) vs 5.00 (4.50-5.50), P &lt; 0.01 for the immunopathological score] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>As measured by DNA copy number, we found that Bifidobacterium and Lactobacillus, which are associated with a healthy colon, were significantly higher in the HPM and SA groups than in the model group (1.395 ± 1.339, 1.461 ± 1.152 vs 0.045 ± 0.036, P &lt; 0.01 for Bifidobacterium, and 0.395 ± 0.325, 0.851 ± 0.651 vs 0.0015 ± 0.0014, P &lt; 0.01 for Lactobacillus) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>On the other hand, E. coli and B. fragilis, which are associated with an inflamed colon, were significantly lower in the HPM and SA groups than in the model group (0.244 ± 0.107, 0.628 ± 0.257 vs 1.691 ± 0.683, P &lt; 0.01 for E. coli, and 0.351 ± 0.181, 0.416 ± 0.329 vs 1.285 ± 1.039, P &lt; 0.01 for B. fragilis) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The expression of TNF-α and IL-12 was decreased after HPM and SA treatment as compared to UC model alone (4970.81 ± 959.78, 6635.45 ± 1135.16 vs 12333.81 ± 680.79, P &lt; 0.01 for TNF-α, and 5528.75 ± 1245.72, 7477.38 ± 1259.16 vs 12550.29 ± 1973.30, P &lt; 0.01 for IL-12) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: HPM treatment can regulate intestinal flora and inhibit the expression of TNF-α and IL-12 in the colon tissues of UC rats, indicating that HPM can improve colonic immune response </plain></SENT>
</text></document>