<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Visualisation of mucosa at ileocolonoscopy (IC) remains the gold standard in the assessment of mucosal healing (MH) in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021390" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory bowel disease</z:e> (IBD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MH is evolving as a key endpoint in assessing response to therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This will invariably mean an increased endoscopic burden on these patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We aimed to investigate IBD patients' perspectives on this, as well as their tolerance of IC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Consecutive patients attending IBD clinic between September and December 2013 were questioned on their experience of IC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Data on sex, age, disease type (Crohn's (CD) or <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> (UC)), duration of illness, and no. of IC was obtained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>They were asked to grade various components of the IC experience (concerns about complications, bowel preparation, disruption to life, procedure discomfort, travel to hospital) on a standardised tolerance scale from 1-5 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>They were also asked to qualitatively rate their overall experience of IC (not unpleasant/neither unpleasant nor pleasant/bearable/unpleasant/very unpleasant) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Finally, they were asked how often they would be prepared to undertake IC in the future </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 98 patients responded (46% male) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Mean age was 43.2 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>33 had UC, 50 had CD, and 11 were unsure of diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Mean no. IC was 3.7 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>62% had a disease duration &gt;5 years, with only 4% diagnosed in the previous year </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Mean tolerance scores for the group were: concerns about complications 2.6, bowel preparation 3.0, disruption to life 2.4, discomfort during procedure 3.0, travel to/from hospital 1.7 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Comparisons between patient subgroups CD versus UC, age ≥55 years versus age &lt;55 years, ≥4 IC versus &lt;4 IC, and diagnosis ≥5 years versus diagnosis &lt;5 years, revealed no significant differences in scores </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>However, comparison between sexes showed females were more worried about the procedure than males (3.0 vs. 2.1, p = 0.02), were less tolerant of bowel preparation (3.5 vs. 2.3, p &lt; 0.001), experienced more disruption to their lives (2.9 vs. 1.9, p &lt; 0.001) and were more troubled by travel concerns (2.0 vs. 1.4, p = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>The majority of the patients felt IC was bearable (53%) with only 13% describing it as very unpleasant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>55% would have the procedure as frequently as required if their physician felt it appropriate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="19" pm="."><plain>7% would only have IC every 5 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="20" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Bowel preparation and procedural discomfort are the most bothersome aspects of IC amongst IBD patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="21" pm="."><plain>There are clear differences in tolerance between female and male patients, and these results should prompt endoscopy units to find ways of improving patient acceptability </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="22" pm="."><plain>This could be provided in the form of a pre-test telephone consultation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="23" pm="."><plain>A minority of patients were reluctant to increase their frequency of IC, which may be relevant in the monitoring of MH in their future management </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="24" pm="."><plain>DISCLOSURE OF INTEREST: None Declared </plain></SENT>
</text></document>