<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Strains of E. coli from the faeces of patients with active <z:hpo ids='HP_0100279'>ulcerative colitis</z:hpo> and with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> in remission were examined for haemolysin and necrotoxin production </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Cultures from 63 patients with active <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> grew haemolytic E. coli in 23 (37%) as compared with 24 (21%) from 115 patients whose disease was in remission (p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The corresponding proportions for necrotoxin-producing strains were 22% and 12% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Of 35 patients investigated both in relapse and remission of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo>, 14 changed their carriage of haemolytic E. coli </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Thirteen of these carried haemolytic organisms in relapse but not in remission, and one carried haemolytic organisms in remission but not in relapse (p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Strains of E. coli were also examined from specimens of faeces obtained at weekly intervals for 28 weeks from 19 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The acquisition of haemolytic or necrotoxic E. coli strains tended to follow rather than precede the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of the attack in the four patients who developed a relapse of the disease during this period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Among these 19 patients haemolytic and necrotoxic strains were found most commonly when blood was regularly present in the faeces </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>These facts suggest that conditions in the bowel during a relapse of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> tend to favour the presence of haemolysin- and necrotoxin-producing organisms, rather than that these organisms cause the relapse </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Of 50 strains of E. coli from patients treated with sulphasalazine tested for sensitivity to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="132842">sulphapyridine</z:chebi> 49 were resistant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>There was no clear relation between the activity of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0002583'>colitis</z:hpo> and the presence of any of the 27 serotypes of E. coli examined </plain></SENT>
</text></document>