<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: To examine the microvascular changes in the retrobulbar optic nerve in idiopathic intracranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (PTC) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Both optic nerves from a 29-year-old man with a two year history of PTC were examined histologically and morphometrically </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A semi-automated image analysis system and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="51403">paraphenylenediamine</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="48" ids="51403,53543">PPD</z:chebi>) stain were employed to resolve sufficiently the microvascular images for counts and measurement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were 150 vessels distributed in the optic nerves which revealed the following: The average lumen of the vessels in outer sectors were larger than those of the inner sector vessels (168.17 microns 2 vs. 46.99 microns 2; p = 0.0338; OD; and 251.96 microns 2 vs. 130.02 microns 2; p = 0.029; OS) while in the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> control optic nerve the outer and inner area lumens were reversed in size-differential, but this did not show a statistical difference </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The thickness of the PTC optic nerve vessel walls in the outer sectors was also greater than that of the walls in the inner sectors (4.95 microns vs. 2.67 microns; p = 0.013; OD and 5.25 microns vs. 3.34 microns; p = 0.019; OS); the same measurements in the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> optic nerve showed a reversed ratio, which was opposite that of the experimental group and but not statistically different </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: This pattern of microvascular changes is consistent with the selective <z:hpo ids='HP_0003447'>axonal loss</z:hpo> in the peripheral area of each optic nerve as much more severe than that in the inner sectors </plain></SENT>
</text></document>