<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Bolus injections of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6456">lidocaine</z:chebi> are commonly used during neuroanesthesia to prevent or treat ICP elevations caused by tracheal or painful stimuli </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="6456">Lidocaine</z:chebi> can also be employed in case of hard intracranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>, when the usual therapy fails </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>With continuous perfusion, at high doses, of this agent, a state of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6456">lidocaine</z:chebi> anesthesia can be induced which is more readily reversible than <z:chebi fb="8" ids="29745">barbiturate</z:chebi> anesthesia </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A simultaneous <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35623">anticonvulsant</z:chebi> therapy is mandatory because of the well-known epileptogenicity of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6456">lidocaine</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Closed cardiovascular monitoring is also needed to detect early signs of cardiotoxicity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Experimental works point to the effectiveness of i.v. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6456">lidocaine</z:chebi> to prevent ischemic lesions secondary to a cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>This protective effect may result from some properties exhibited by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6456">lidocaine</z:chebi> and not by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="102166">thiopental</z:chebi>: stabilisation of transmembrane ionic fluxes, inhibition of leucocytes intravascular sticking and tissular migration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>So, i.v. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6456">lidocaine</z:chebi> seems help to preserve or improve cerebral perfusion pressure and in cases when the latter decrease below the critical threshold, to protect against <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>