<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To compare French and American white patients with idiopathic intracranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (IIH), and to determine prognostic factors associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000572'>visual loss</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Medical records of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> consecutive white patients with definite IIH seen between 2001 and 2006 in three French tertiary care medical centers and one American tertiary medical center were reviewed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Demographics, associated clinical features, and visual function at presentation and follow-up were collected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>French white patients were compared to American white patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: One hundred and thirty-four patients (66 French, 68 American) were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>American patients were 8.7 times more likely than French patients to have visual acuity 20/60 or worse or <z:hpo ids='HP_0001133'>visual field constriction</z:hpo> (95% CI: 2.1-36.1, p=0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>American patients were treated more aggressively than French patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>French patients were older (31 vs. 28 years, p=0.02) and more likely to have <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anemia</z:hpo> (20 vs. 2%, p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>American patients had a longer duration of symptoms prior to diagnosis (12 vs. 4 weeks, p=0.01) and longer follow-up than French patients (26 vs. 11 months, p=0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Multivariable analysis found that nationality was an independent risk factor for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000572'>visual loss</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>French and American patients did not differ regarding gender proportion, frequency of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0010535'>sleep apnea</z:hpo>, <z:chebi fb="32" ids="24621">endocrine</z:chebi> diseases, or <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>systemic hypertension</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) opening pressures were similar in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: American patients with IIH had worse visual outcomes than French patients despite more aggressive treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>These differences are not explained by differences in previously known risk factors </plain></SENT>
</text></document>