<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Complications of idiopathic intracranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (IIH) are usually caused by <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0151740" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">elevated intracranial pressure</z:e> (ICP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In a similar way as in the optic nerve, elevated ICP could also compromise the olfactory nerve system </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>On the other side, there is growing evidence that an extensive lymphatic network system around the olfactory nerves could be disturbed in cerebrospinal fluid disorders like IIH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The hypothesis that patients with IIH suffer from <z:hpo ids='HP_0004409'>hyposmia</z:hpo> has been suggested in the past </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>However, this has not been proven in clinical studies yet </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This pilot study investigates whether structural changes of the olfactory nerve system can be detected in patients with IIH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>METHODOLOGY/PRINCIPAL FINDINGS: Twenty-three patients with IIH and 23 matched controls were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Olfactory bulb volume (OBV) and sulcus olfactorius (OS) depth were calculated by magnetic resonance techniques </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>While mean values of total OBV (128.7±38.4 vs. 130.0±32.6 mm(3), p=0.90) and mean OS depth (8.5±1.2 vs. 8.6±1.1 mm, p=0.91) were similar in both groups, Pearson correlation showed that patients with a shorter medical history IIH revealed a smaller OBV (r=0.53, p&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In untreated symptomatic patients (n=7), the effect was greater (r=0.76, p&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Patients who suffered from IIH for less than one year (n=8), total OBV was significantly smaller than in matched controls (116.6±24.3 vs. 149.3±22.2 mm(3), p=0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>IIH patients with visual disturbances (n=21) revealed a lower OS depth than patients without (8.3±0.9 vs. 10.8±1.0 mm, p&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS/SIGNIFICANCE: The results suggest that morphological changes of the olfactory nerve system could be present in IIH patients at an early stage of disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>