<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Idiopathic intracranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (IIH) is a clinical disorder of unknown etiology manifesting with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002516'>increased intracranial pressure</z:hpo> in the absence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000238'>hydrocephalus</z:hpo>, an underlying mass lesion, and demonstrating <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> cerebrospinal fluid composition </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>IIH may exhibit several non-specific imaging findings including: an empty sella, posterior globe flattening, tortuosity of the optic nerve, and optic nerve sheath distention </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: To introduce widening of the foramen ovale as a new imaging marker for IIH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL AND METHODS: IIH is a syndrome which may exhibit several previously described non-specific imaging findings including: an empty sella, posterior globe flattening, tortuosity of the optic nerve, and optic nerve sheath distention </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We hypothesize that chronically elevated cerebrospinal fluid pressure can lead to osseous <z:mpath ids='MPATH_580'>erosions</z:mpath> and we propose widening of the foramen ovale as a new imaging marker for IIH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Average foramen ovale sizes were increased in patients with IIH compared to controls (30.03 ± 7.00 mm(2) vs. 24.21 ± 5.97 mm(2), P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For a cut-off value of 30 mm(2), the sensitivity of FO area to detect IIH was 50%, with 81% specificity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Classic findings were significantly more common in patients with IIH compared to controls including: empty sella (65.9% vs. 0%), posterior globe flattening (65.9% vs. 4.5%), vertical tortuosity of the optic nerve (54.5% vs. 9.1%), and optic nerve sheath distention (52.3% vs. 11.4%, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P values &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our study confirms the association of several classic imaging findings with IIH and supports widening of the foramen ovale as an additional imaging marker which may be incorporated into the evaluation of patients suspected to have this condition </plain></SENT>
</text></document>