<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Invasive management of patients ≥80 years of age with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100546'>carotid stenosis</z:hpo> may be questionable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The higher likelihood of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> needs to be balanced with the increased perioperative risk and the reduced life expectancy of this ageing population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to evaluate the clinical relevance of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100546'>carotid stenosis</z:hpo> revascularisation in octogenarians </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients ≥80 years of age who received carotid revascularisation in 2001-2010 were reviewed for perioperative and 5-year outcomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The experience was comprehensive of carotid endarterectomy (CEA) and carotid stenting (CAS) performed during the training frame when age was not a contraindication for this procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mortality rates were compared to those of octogenarians of the same geographical territory according to <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>-related mortality national statistics datasets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 348 procedures performed in ≥80-year-old patients (272 males) were reviewed: 162 (46.6%) were by CAS and 169 (48.6%) were for symptomatic disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Perioperative <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>/<z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> rate was 5.5% and was non-significantly higher for symptomatic disease (7.1% vs. 3.9% asymptomatic; p = 0.24), after CAS (6.2% vs. 4.8% CEA; p = 0.64) and in females (6.6% vs. 5.1% males; p = 0.57) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>At median follow-up of 36.18 months, 95 <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> and 21 new ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>strokes</z:hpo> (12 fatal) occurred with 5-year Kaplan-Meier freedom from <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> of 84.8% (78.7%, symptomatic vs. 90.3% asymptomatic; p = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>According to national datasets, in 80-85-year-old resident population 5-year mortality was 29.9% (23.4% females, 40.6% males) and ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>-related mortality was 14.9% (16.8% females, 13.0% males) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Corresponding figures from treated population showed a 5-year mortality of 49.4%, higher in males (39.5% females, 52.5% males) and ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>-related mortality of 20.2%, higher in females (40.0% females, 15.6% males) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Comparing data from the study population with residents' figures, ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>-related mortality hazard was significantly higher in the study females: odds ratio (OR) 3.2, 95% confidence interval (CI) 1.16-9.17; p = 0.029 (for males: OR 0.97, 95%CI 0.89-1.10; p = 0.99) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Despite perioperative <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>/<z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> risks being lower compared with CAS, the benefit of surgical carotid revascularisation in old patients remains controversial due to limited life expectancy and high fatality of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> in this ageing population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Invasive treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100546'>carotid stenosis</z:hpo> may not be warranted in most patients ≥80 years of age with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100546'>carotid stenosis</z:hpo>, especially when female and asymptomatic </plain></SENT>
</text></document>