<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To evaluate health-related quality of life (HRQoL) in patients with symptomatic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0741975" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid disease</z:e> (<z:hpo ids='HP_0100576'>amaurosis fugax</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007787" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="tia|TIA|T.I.A.">transient ischaemic attack</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>); to compare it with that of the general population; to explore whether HRQoL depends on the severity of the disease and to investigate the possible association between some demographic and clinical characteristics of patients and HRQoL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This cross-sectional study involved 175 patients with symptomatic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0577631" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid atherosclerotic disease</z:e> who were referred for endarterectomy between January 2011 and December 2011 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>HRQoL was measured using Medical Outcome Survey Short Form 36 (SF-36) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In comparison to both referent populations, patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0741975" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid disease</z:e> had significantly lower mean SF-36 scores for role-physical (41.6 vs. 61.5 and 67.8), social functioning (65.4 vs. 73.8 and 80.0), role-emotional (48.2 vs. 68.6 and 80.5) and mental health (51.5 vs. 61.9 and 66.0) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The SF-36 scores were significantly lower in female patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0741975" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid disease</z:e> than in men (for role-physical 32.3 vs. 46.5; for bodily pain 57.0 vs. 73.0; for general health 55.6 vs. 61.5; for vitality 55.4 vs. 60.1; for social functioning 57.1 vs. 69.8 and for role-emotional 37.2 vs. 54.1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Significantly lower SF-36 scores were also found in patient with comorbidity (for physical functioning 68.1 vs. 77.7; for role-physical 35.1 vs. 52.3; for bodily pain 62.6 vs. 75.4; for general health 56.8 vs. 63.8; for social functioning 61.9 vs. 71.0, for role-emotional 41.6 vs. 59.1and for mental health 52.5 vs 49.8) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In a multivariable analysis, education, occupation, body mass index, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> and severity of the disease had a weak influence on patients' HRQoL, while age, marital status, smoking, alcohol consumption, physical activity and the degree of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100546'>carotid stenosis</z:hpo> had no effect on patients' HRQoL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The SF-36 scores did not substantially change after adjustment for confounding variables </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Patients with symptomatic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0741975" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid disease</z:e> had poorer HRQoL, especially its mental components, than the general population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The severity of the disease was significantly associated only with the SF-36 role-physical subscale </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>HRQoL in patients with symptomatic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0741975" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid disease</z:e> was poorer in women than in men, and was not affected by age and other demographic and clinical characteristics of patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>