<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Intracranial large artery disease (ICLAD), such as stenosis and calcification, is common in Chinese patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, little is known about ICLAD and its association with large arterial stiffness in hypertensive patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We recruited 270 (mean age 61.0 years, 45.6% male) untreated hypertensive patients without <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> from a community in Shanghai, China </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>ICLAD was detected by computerized tomographic angiography (CTA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Carotid-femoral pulse wave velocity (cf-PWV), office, and 24-h ambulatory pulse pressure (PP) as well as ambulatory arterial stiffness index (AASI) were determined as the measures of arterial stiffness </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Among <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> participants, 26 (9.6%) had concurrent intracranial <z:hpo ids='HP_0100545'>arterial stenosis</z:hpo> and calcification, 11 (4.1%) stenosis only, and 71 (26.3%) calcifications only </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>After adjustment for age, mean arterial pressure, and other covariables, there was significant difference in cf-PWV (13.1 vs. 13.7 vs. 15.0 m/s; P = 0.0015) and 24-h PP (46.7 vs. 48.8 vs. 55.7 mm Hg; P = 0.0007) between patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> vessels (n = 162), with stenosis or calcification (n = 82), and with both lesions (n = 26) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Multiple ordinal logistic regression analyses showed that both cf-PWV and 24-h PP were independently associated with ICLAD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Odds ratios (95% confidence interval (CI)) of ICLAD after multivariable and mutually adjustment were 1.51 (1.09-2.10) and 1.46 (1.06-2.01) for 1-s.d. increase in cf-PWV and 24-h PP, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>No significant association (P ≥ 0.10) with AASI or office PP was observed in multivariable analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Increased arterial stiffness was independently associated with ICLAD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>cf-PWV and 24-h PP might be useful in identifying those more likely to have ICLAD among hypertensive patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>