<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002145'>Frontotemporal dementia</z:hpo> (FTD) is a clinical syndrome characterized by progressive decline in social conduct and a focal pattern of frontal and temporal lobe damage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Its biological basis is still poorly understood but the focality of the brain degeneration provides a powerful model to study the cognitive and anatomical basis of social cognition </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Here, we present Dr. A, a patient with a rare hereditary <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0005940" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bone disease</z:e> (hereditary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002762'>multiple exostoses</z:hpo>) and FTD (pathologically characterized as <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0236642" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Pick's disease</z:e>), who presented with a profound behavioral disturbance characterized by acquired <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0233523" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">sociopathy</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We conducted a detailed genetic, pathological, neuroimaging and cognitive study, including a battery of tests designed to investigate Dr. A's abilities to understand emotional cues and to infer mental states and intentions to others (theory of mind) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Dr. A's genetic profile suggests the possibility that a mutation causing hereditary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002762'>multiple exostoses</z:hpo>, Ext2, may play a role in the pattern of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002180'>neurodegeneration</z:hpo> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002145'>frontotemporal dementia</z:hpo> since knockout mice deficient in the Ext gene family member, Ext1, show severe <z:chebi fb="7" ids="29425,29426,29441,29447">CNS</z:chebi> defects including loss of olfactory bulbs and abnormally <z:hpo ids='HP_0002472'>small cerebral cortex</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Dr. A showed significant impairment in emotion comprehension, second order theory of mind, attribution of intentions, and empathy despite preserved general cognitive abilities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Voxel-based morphometry on structural MRI images showed significant <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> in the medial and right orbital frontal and anterior temporal regions with sparing of dorsolateral frontal cortex </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>This case demonstrates that social and emotional dysfunction in FTD can be dissociated from preserved performance on classic executive functioning tasks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The specific pattern of anatomical damage shown by VBM emphasizes the importance of the network including the superior medial frontal gyrus as well as temporal polar areas, in regulation of social cognition and theory of mind </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This case provides new evidence regarding the neural basis of social cognition and suggests a possible genetic link between <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0005940" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">bone disease</z:e> and FTD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>