<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to determine the effects of removal of amniotic fluid in cases of symptomatic severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001561'>polyhydramnios</z:hpo> on Doppler waveform indices of the uterine and umbilical arteries and flow velocities of the uterine arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Nine women underwent therapeutic amniocentesis during ten pregnancies for symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001561'>polyhydramnios</z:hpo> due to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004903" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Congenital Abnormality" abbrv="">Beckwith-Wiedemann Syndrome</z:e> (n = 1), <z:hpo ids='HP_0002032'>esophageal atresia</z:hpo> (n = 2), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677608" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">chorioangioma</z:e> (n = 1), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0015958" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">twin-twin transfusion syndrome</z:e> (n = 3), a presumed <z:hpo ids='HP_0000007'>autosomal recessive</z:hpo> syndrome (n = 2), and an unbalanced double translocation (n = 1; partial dup 3q and partial del <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0795830" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">9p syndrome</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>An average of 2.78 +/- 0.9 (range 1-4) 1 of fluid were removed at each procedure between the gestational ages of 18 and 34 weeks (mean of 28 weeks) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The systolic/diastolic (S/D) ratio, pulsitility index (PI), and resistance index (RI) of the uterine and umbilical arteries were obtained before and after the procedure using color and pulsed Doppler </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After angle correction, the peak systolic velocity (PSV) and mean velocity (MV) in centimeters/second (cm/s) of the uterine arteries were also determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The presence or absence of a uterine artery waveform notch was determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Dominant uterine arteries were defined as those with lower impedance indices or higher flow velocities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Statistical analysis was performed with the Wilcoxon signed-rank test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Significance was set at P &lt; 0.05 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There was a significant increase in the median value of the uterine artery MV (43.8 vs. 81.1 cm/s, P = 0.005) and PSV (74.2 vs. 125.5 cm/s, P = 0.007) after amniocentesis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The uterine S/D (3.0 vs. 1.84, P = 0.007), PI (1.12 vs. 0.68, P = 0.008), and RI (0.60 vs. 0.45, P = 0.005) impedance indices significantly decreased following amniocentesis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>When uterine arteries were categorized as dominant vs. nondominant, there were greater improvements in impedance indices and flow velocities in the nondominant uterine arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>There were three cases of unilateral and one case of bilateral early diastolic notches of the uterine artery waveforms which either resolved (n = 4) or improved (n = 1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>There was no effect on the umbilical artery impedance indices </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Therapeutic amniocentesis significantly improved uterine artery impedance indices and resulted in improved flow velocities, while there was no effect on umbilical artery waveform indices </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>The procedure resulted in the disappearance or improvement of the uterine waveform notch </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Our findings suggest that in cases of severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001561'>polyhydramnios</z:hpo> abnormal uterine artery velocimetry may not be due to lack of trophoblastic invasion of the spiral arteries but to increased intrauterine pressure secondary to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001561'>polyhydramnios</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>