<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The t(14;18) is present in 85-90% of follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It results in overexpression of the Bcl-2 protein, which inhibits <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> and plays a role in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0598766" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">lymphomagenesis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Bcl-2 antisense oligonucleotides (ODNs) down-regulate Bcl-2 expression and inhibit growth of the follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> cell line WSU-FSCCL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In this study, we have established a human <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1520166" disease_type="Experimental Model of Disease" abbrv="">xenograft model</z:e> in severe combined immunodeficient (<z:mp ids='MP_0002536'>SCID</z:mp>) mice using the WSU-FSCCL cell line. s.c., i.v., or i.p. injection of WSU-FSCCL cells into <z:mp ids='MP_0002536'>SCID</z:mp> mice results in the development of disseminated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumors</z:e>, with the liver, spleen, bone marrow, and lymph nodes as major sites of disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Tumors</z:e> were fatal in 7-14 weeks, depending on cell inoculum and route of administration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Immunohistochemistry, flow cytometry, and cytogenetic analysis confirmed the human B-cell origin of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> cells in the xenograft </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Phosphorothioate ODNs against the translation initiation site of bcl-2 mRNA in the antisense and mismatched antisense sequences were administered i.v. or i.p. to the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1520166" disease_type="Experimental Model of Disease" abbrv="">xenograft models</z:e> three times a week for 2 weeks, starting on day 7 after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> injections </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Antisense-treated animals had significantly longer survival (mean, 11.6 weeks) compared with 7.6 weeks for the control group and 7.5 weeks for the mismatched antisense-treated animals (P = 0.002 and 0.004, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>More significantly, a pathological examination showed no <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> in the liver, spleen, or bone marrow of the antisense group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, subsequent experiments showed that the central <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system was involved, causing mice to die although other sites were disease free </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>We conclude that bcl-2 antisense ODN therapy is effective against systemic FSCCL disease in <z:mp ids='MP_0002536'>SCID</z:mp> mice xenografts; however, it does not prevent disease dissemination into the central <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system causing animal <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>