<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The chromosomal rearrangement t(14;18)(q32;21) involves the major (MBR) or minor (mcr) breakpoint cluster regions and the immunoglobulin heavy chain joining regions (JH) in most follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>As a first step towards determining the clinical significance of circulating cells with t(14;18), we detected and quantitated circulating cells in samples obtained from volunteer blood donors and follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The t(14;18) was co-amplified with beta-actin with real-time quantitative PCR (QRT-PCR) in reactions containing 1 microg of DNA from peripheral blood or bone marrow aspirates </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The cell number was quantitated using linear regression and an external standard of serially diluted DNA from cell lines with MBR/JH or mcr/JH rearrangements </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At dilutions of 10(5) and 106, sensitivity was 100 and 55% for MBR/JH, and 100 and 10% for mcr/JH rearrangements </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Among 102 volunteer blood donors MBR/JH vs. mcr/JH amplicons were detected in 22 vs. 4% with duplicate 1 microg DNA reactions, and in 41 vs. 6% with a total 10 microg DNA analyzed in multiple reactions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Among volunteer blood donors the mean number of circulating cells with MBR/JH vs. mcr/JH rearrangements were 0.8 vs. 0.1/microg DNA, and exceeded the upper <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> limit (defined as the mean of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> volunteer samples plus two standard deviations) in 3% vs. 2%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Analysis for MBR/JH rearrangements revealed that follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> patients vs. volunteer blood donors were positive in 76% vs. 22% (p = 0.008 by Fisher's exact test); that the mean number of MBR/JH cells per microg of DNA was 91 vs. 0.8 (p = 0.0002 by Mann-Whitney test); and the number of the MBR/JH cells exceeded the upper <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> limit in 32% vs. 3% of subjects (p = 0.0001 by Fisher's exact test) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Circulating cells with mcr/JH were not detected among any of these 25 <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We conclude that patients with follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> are more frequently positive, have higher numbers of circulating cells with t(14;18), which exceed upper <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> limit more frequently than in volunteer blood donors </plain></SENT>
</text></document>