<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We have treated 38 transplant-eligible patients with relapsed/refractory non-Hodgkin's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019829" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="hd">Hodgkin's disease</z:e> using an outpatient-based regimen of ifosfamide, <z:chebi fb="2" ids="31355">carboplatin</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4911">etoposide</z:chebi> (ICE) for both salvage and peripheral blood stem cell mobilisation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Patients included relapsed or refractory diffuse large B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (n = 17), follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (n = II), T-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (n = 2), mantle cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (n = 2) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019829" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="hd">Hodgkin's disease</z:e> (n = 6) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Seven patients with diffuse large B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and three patients with follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (26%) were considered chemorefractory </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Cycles of ICE therapy were administered every 21 days as an outpatient and consisted of ifosfamide 5000 mg/m2 intravenously (i.v.) fractionated into three equally divided doses over 3 days, <z:chebi fb="2" ids="31355">carboplatin</z:chebi> [mg dose = 5 x area under the curve (AUC)] i.v. on day 1 and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4911">etoposide</z:chebi> 100 mg/m2- i.v. daily for 3 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Subsequently. granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF)5 microg/kg subcutaneously (s.c.) was administered daily from day +5 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Of the I I follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> patients, 10 also received rituximab with ICE therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Median age of patients was 52 years (range 30-65) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients received a mean of 2.6 cycles (range 1-4) of ICE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There were no toxic <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> and no significant non-haematological toxicities secondary to ICE therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Grade IV <z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>thrombocytopenia</z:hpo> and grade IV <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> with at least one cycle of ICE were seen in 47% and 53% of patients, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Median time to peripheral blood stem cell (PBSC) harvest was 14 days (range 10-20). while the median CD34+ cell yield was 5.2 x 10(6) cells/kg(range 2.3 x 10(6)-27.2 x 10(6)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Only one of the ICE-responders failed to mobilise PBSCs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The overall response rate to ICE was 87%. comprising 14 patients (37%) who achieved a complete response (CR) and 19 (50%) who achieved a partial response (PR) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>A total of 30 patients have undergone autologous stem cell transplantation(SCT) while two follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> patients have received a non-myeloablative allogeneic SCT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Follow-up is short: however, the Kaplan-Meier estimate of the proportion of patients alive and event-free at a median follow-up of 11 months is 80% and 59%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Event-free survival for patients who achieved a CR after ICE and transplantation is 88% versus 45% for those who achieved a PR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>These data confirm the efficacy and tolerability of fractionated ICE chemotherapy as both a salvage and mobilisation regimen that can be readily delivered in an outpatient setting </plain></SENT>
</text></document>