<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: In patients with advanced-stage follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (FL) and mantle cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MCL</z:e>), conventional chemotherapy remains a noncurative approach, and no major improvement in overall survival has been achieved in recent decades </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The German Low-Grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>Lymphoma</z:hpo> Study Group performed a randomized trial comparing combined <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4027">cyclophosphamide</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28445">vincristine</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28748">doxorubicin</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8382">prednisone</z:chebi> (CHOP) chemotherapy with combined <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50729">mitoxantrone</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28830">chlorambucil</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8382">prednisone</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="17" ids="50099">MCP</z:chebi>) chemotherapy as first-line therapy for patients with advanced-stage FL or <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MCL</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Three hundred sixty-three patients with advanced-stage FL (n = 277 patients) or <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MCL</z:e> (n = 86 patients) entered the trial and were evaluable fully </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>CHOP resulted in a significantly higher overall response rate in patients with FL (91% vs. 82%; P = .026) and a similar tendency in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MCL</z:e> (87% vs. 73%; P = .080) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>However, no significant differences were observed in the time to treatment failure or in overall survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CHOP produced significantly more nonhematologic toxicities, whereas <z:chebi fb="17" ids="50099">MCP</z:chebi> was associated with more severe hematologic side effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The proportion of patients who successfully underwent peripheral blood stem cell collection was significantly lower after <z:chebi fb="17" ids="50099">MCP</z:chebi> (44% vs. 93% after CHOP; P = .0003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Taking into account that, currently, chemotherapy regularly is combined with rituximab as first-line therapy for FL and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MCL</z:e>, the data from this study may have an impact on the type of chemotherapy to be applied in such combinations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Particularly in younger, high-risk patients who are candidates for autologous stem cell transplantation, CHOP should be preferred over <z:chebi fb="17" ids="50099">MCP</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>