<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: To investigate the relationship between Bcl-2 protein expression and cell proliferation at single-cell level in B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> using double-labelling techniques </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: The relationship between Bcl-2 protein expression and cell proliferation was explored in 124 cases of B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> using double immunofluorescence labelling for Bcl-2 and Ki67 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, marginal zone <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and a subset of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> lymphocytic <z:mpath ids='MPATH_336'>leukaemia</z:mpath>/small lymphocytic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="C1302547" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">CLL/SLL</z:e>), neoplastic cells tended to lose Bcl-2 when they are in cell cycle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>This pattern is usually maintained in both follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1302547" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">CLL/SLL</z:e> when they undergo high-grade transformation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In mantle cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, diffuse large B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and a subset of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1302547" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">CLL/SLL</z:e>, the inverse relationship (between Bcl-2 and Ki67) was not observed, i.e. the proliferating cells tended to show co-expression of Bcl-2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In low-grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo>, including those that are transformed, Bcl-2 expression is lost when cell proliferate </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, in more aggressive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e> (i.e. mantle cell and de novo diffuse large B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo>) the inverse Bcl-2/Ki67 relationship was not observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>It would be of interest to explore the clinical implications in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> of the presence and absence of the inverse Bcl-2/Ki67 pattern </plain></SENT>
</text></document>