<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>Lymphomas</z:hpo> of the gall bladder and extrahepatic bile ducts are exceedingly rare </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We present the clinicopathological features of 19 cases from our files; 14 patients had primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (13 involving gall bladder and 1 involving common hepatic duct), while 5 had systemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> on further work-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Most patients presented with symptoms mimicking <z:hpo ids='HP_0001082'>cholecystitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The most common primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> types were diffuse large B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, extranodal marginal zone <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, B-lymphoblastic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, and follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Two cases had features of lymphomatous <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0334108" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">polyposis</z:e>, one a case of follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and the second a case of mantle cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, with disease limited to the mantle zones, so-called in situ mantle cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Other rare <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> subtypes not described earlier in this site included the extracavitary variant of primary effusion <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and plasmablastic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients with diffuse large B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> and extranodal marginal zone <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> were older (mean age 75.8 y) than those with other subtypes (mean age 47 y) and more likely to have <z:hpo ids='HP_0001081'>gallstones</z:hpo> (60% vs. 12.5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A comprehensive literature review revealed 36 primary gall bladder and 16 primary extrahepatic bile duct <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>When compared with primary gall bladder <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo>, those involving the extrahepatic bile ducts present at a younger age (47 y vs. 63 y) usually with obstructive <z:hpo ids='HP_0000952'>jaundice</z:hpo>, and are less often associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001081'>gallstones</z:hpo> (17% vs. 50%) or regional lymph node involvement (6% vs. 31%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> of the gall bladder and extrahepatic bile ducts show a broad spectrum of disease types, but in many respects mirror the spectrum of primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> of the gastrointestinal tract </plain></SENT>
</text></document>