<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>This study was conducted to evaluate the efficacy and safety of Rituximab, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="175901">Gemcitabine</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="2" ids="27899">Cisplatin</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="41879">Dexamethasone</z:chebi> (R-GDP) in relapsed or refractory aggressive B-Cell Non-Hodgkin's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>Lymphoma</z:hpo> (NHL) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Treatments consisted of rituximab 375 mg/m2, i.v. on day 1; <z:chebi fb="0" ids="175901">gemcitabine</z:chebi> 1,000 mg/m2, i.v. on days 1 and 8, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="41879">dexamethasone</z:chebi> 40 mg i.v. on days 1-4, and <z:chebi fb="2" ids="27899">cisplatin</z:chebi> 25 mg/m2 i.v. on days 1-3, every 21 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The primary end-points were the overall survival (OS) and progression-free survival (PFS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Secondary endpoints included response rate (ORR; CR) and toxicities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Eligible patients could then proceed to high-dose chemotherapy (HDC) and autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT) or receive up to six treatment cycles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>From January 2005 to December 2010, 50 successive patients at Tianjin <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> hospital <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> department were enrolled in this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients were recurrent or refractory aggressive B-cell NHL, including diffuse large B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (n=30) and follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> grade 3b (n=20) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The median follow-up time was 42 months (range, 12-70) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>After two cycles, the overall response rate was 72.0%, with a CR/CRu rate of 56% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The 2-year OS and PFS of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients were 70.0 and 48.0%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Grade III-IV <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>thrombocytopenia</z:hpo> occurred in 34 and 40% of patients, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Twenty-one patients (42%) proceeded to ASCT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Higher International Prognostic Index and refractory disease were independently associated with worse survival and progression-free survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>R-GDP chemotherapy in patients with refractory or relapsed aggressive B-Cell NHL was effective as a salvage therapy and helpful for HDC/ASCT </plain></SENT>
</text></document>