<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PCR product sizing on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4883">ethidium bromide</z:chebi>-stained gels, coupled with Southern transfer and hybridization with nonisotopic probes, is an effective way of detecting t(14;18)(q32;q21) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We evaluated an alternative ELISA-based test for detecting amplified t(14;18) products </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="42098">Digoxigenin</z:chebi> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">DIG</z:e>)-labeled <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17625">dUTP</z:chebi> is incorporated in a standard PCR method for amplification of bcl-2 major breakpoint region (mbr) rearrangements </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The product is hybridized to a specific biotinylated DNA probe internal to the mbr primer, placed in streptavidin-coated wells of a microtiter plate, and detected with a alkaline phosphatase-conjugated anti-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">DIG</z:e> antibody and enzyme substrate (pNpp) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The colorimetric product is quantitated by an automated optical density (O.D.) reader </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We evaluated 13 mbr-positive follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> (FL), five mbr-negative B-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002664'>neoplasms</z:hpo> (BCN), 16 reactive <z:mp ids='MP_0000688'>lymphoid hyperplasias</z:mp> (RLH), 14 cases of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019829" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="hd">Hodgkin's disease</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">HD</z:e>), and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> peripheral blood samples from 20 healthy volunteers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> samples were evaluated in duplicate on separate plates </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Positive [t(14;18)-containing cell line] and negative [cell line without t(14;18); master mix only] controls, and a standard curve were included with each run </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Numerical O.D. readings from the specific hybridization assays revealed differences between FL and the other categories </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> FL had an O.D. reading at &gt; 2.0 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The vast majority of RLH, <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">HD</z:e>, BCN, and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> peripheral blood samples showed O.D. readings well below 2.0 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Specifically, 13/16 RLH and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">HD</z:e>, BCN, and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> peripheral blood samples had an O.D. of &lt; or = 0.6 in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> runs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The three outliers, which were <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> &lt; 2.0, may represent the low level detection of t(14;18)-containing cells in RLH similar to previous reports </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Moreover, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> but four RLH had O.D. readings above the background negative controls, suggesting that rare t(14;18)-containing cells may have been present in these samples, as well </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Dilution studies estimate that this assay is capable of detecting 1 t(14;18)-containing cell in approximately 10(5) cells, a greater level of sensitivity than can be obtained with gel visualization alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>We conclude that this semi-automated, potentially quantifiable ELISA-based system is a useful, objective and reproducible alternative hybridization procedure for verifying PCR product specificity in this setting </plain></SENT>
</text></document>