<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>Lymphoma</z:hpo> of the nasal cavity and paranasal sinuses is a rare presentation of extranodal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> with a natural history that is not well characterized in this era of combination chemotherapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The goals of this retrospective study were 1) to define the natural history of sinonasal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo>; 2) to compare the results of radiation therapy (XRT) alone with those of combined modality therapy (CMT) in the treatment of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> of the nasal cavity and paranasal sinuses; and 3) to define prognostic factors for each treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Between 1947 and 1993, 70 patients with newly diagnosed <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> of the nasal cavity and paranasal sinuses were treated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The Ann Arbor stages were: Stage IE: 42 patients; Stage IIE: 14 patients; Stage IIIE: 2 patients; and Stage IV: 12 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The distribution of T classifications of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0677930" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">primary tumors</z:e> was as follows: T1: 2 patients; T2: 16; T3: 18; and T4: 34 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Greater than 90% of the patients had intermediate grade <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> (Working Formulation), and none had follicular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Twenty-eight patients received XRT alone, and 42 received CMT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The actuarial 5-year freedom from progression (FFP) and overall survival (OS) rates for the entire group were 57% and 52%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>For patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0277565" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">localized disease</z:e> (Stages IE and IIE) receiving CMT, the actuarial 5-year FFP and OS were 83% and 67%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In multivariate analysis, treatment with CMT (P = 0.0005) and stage (IE vs. IIIE-IV) (P = 0.0001) were associated with improved FFP </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In the group of patients receiving XRT, extent of disease (Stage IE, T1-3 vs. Stage IE, T4 vs. Stage IIE-IV) (P = 0.0001) was the only clinical characteristic associated with improved FFP in multivariate analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>For patients receiving CMT, International Index (0 vs. 1-3 vs. 4, 5) (P = 0.0001) was the only significant factor predictive of improved FFP in multivariate analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>One patient failed in the central <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system (<z:chebi fb="7" ids="29425,29426,29441,29447">CNS</z:chebi>) after initial therapy as a result of a radiation therapy marginal miss </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In a Western population, patients with localized <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> of the nasal cavity and paranasal sinuses have a favorable prognosis when treated with CMT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>FFP is significantly improved by treatment with CMT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>For patients treated with XRT, extent of disease is the strongest predictor of outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>International Index is the most significant prognostic factor for patients receiving CMT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>Failure in the <z:chebi fb="7" ids="29425,29426,29441,29447">CNS</z:chebi> is rare after initial therapy and is associated with local failure </plain></SENT>
</text></document>