<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The gerbil Psammomys obesus develops nutrition-dependent <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We studied the interaction between diet and diabetic predisposition for beta-cell function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A 4-day high-energy (HE) diet induced a 3-, 4-, and 1.5-fold increase in serum <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi>, respectively, in <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-prone (DP) but not <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-resistant (DR) P. obesus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>Hyperglycemia</z:hpo> and concurrent 90% <z:mpath ids='MPATH_63'>depletion</z:mpath> of islet immunoreactive insulin stores were partially corrected by an 18-h fast </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In vitro early insulin response to <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> was blunted in both DR and DP perifused islets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The HE diet augmented early and late insulin response in DR islets, whereas in DP islets, secretion progressively declined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Dose-response studies showed a species-related increase in islet <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> sensitivity, further augmented in DP P. obesus by a HE diet, concomitant with a decreased threshold for <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and a 55% reduction in maximal response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These changes were associated with a fourfold increase in <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> phosphorylation capacity in DP islets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There were no differences in islet glucokinase (GK) and hexokinase (HK) Km; however, GK Vmax was 3.7- to 4.6-fold higher in DP islets, and HK Vmax was augmented 3.7-fold by the HE diet in DP islets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We conclude that the insulin-resistant P. obesus has an inherent deficiency in insulin release </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In the genetically predisposed P. obesus (DP), augmented islet <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> phosphorylation ability and diet-induced reduction of the <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> threshold for secretion may lead to inadequate insulin secretion and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_63'>depletion</z:mpath> of insulin stores in the presence of caloric abundance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Thus, genetic predisposition and beta-cell maladaptation to nutritional load seem to determine together the progression to overt <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in this species </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>It is hypothesized that similar events may occur in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>