<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is a <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneous</z:hpo> disease in which both <z:hpo ids='HP_0006279'>beta-cell dysfunction</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> are pathogenetic factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Disproportionate hyperproinsulinemia (elevated proinsulin/insulin) is another abnormality in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> whose mechanism is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Increased demand due to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> and/or <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> may result in secretion of immature beta-cell granules with a higher content of intact proinsulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We investigated the impact of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> on beta-cell secretion in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> subjects and in type 2 diabetic patients by measuring intact proinsulin, total proinsulin immunoreactivity (PIM), intact insulin, and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> (by radioimmunoassay) by specific enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays in the fasting state and during a 120-min glucagon (1 mg i.v.) stimulation test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Lean (BMI 23.5 +/- 0.3 kg/m2) (LD) and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> (30.1 +/- 0.4 kg/m2) (OD) type 2 diabetic patients matched for fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (10.2 +/- 0.6 vs. 10.3 +/- 0.4 mmol/l) were compared with age- and BMI-matched lean (22.4 +/- 0.6 kg/m2) (LC) and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> (30.8 +/- 0.9 kg/m2) (OC) <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Diabetic patients (LD vs. LC and OD vs. OC) had elevated fasting levels of intact proinsulin 6.6 +/- 1.0 vs. 1.6 +/- 0.3 pmol/l and 7.7 +/- 2.0 vs. 1.2 +/- 0.2 pmol/l; PIM: 19.9 +/- 2.5 vs. 5.4 +/- 1.0 pmol/l and 29.6 +/- 6.1 vs. 6.1 +/- 0.9 pmol/l; and total PIM/intact insulin: 39 +/- 4 vs. 15 +/- 2% and 35 +/- 5 vs. 13 +/- 2%, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P &lt; 0.01 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>After glucagon stimulation, PIM levels were disproportionately elevated (PIM/intact insulin based on area under the curve analysis) in diabetic patients (LD vs. LC and OD vs. OC): 32.6 +/- 6.7 vs. 9.2 +/- 1.1% and 22.7 +/- 5.2 vs. 9.1 +/- 1.1%, both P &lt; 0.05 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Intact insulin and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> net responses were significantly reduced in type 2 diabetic patients, most pronounced in the lean group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The ratio of intact proinsulin to PIM was higher in diabetic patients after stimulation in both LD versus LC: 32 +/- 3 vs. 23 +/- 2%, and OD versus OC: 28 +/- 4 vs. 16 +/- 2%, both P &lt; 0.01 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> subjects, intact proinsulin/PIM was lower both in the fasting state and after glucagon stimulation: OC versus LC: 22 +/- 3 vs. 33 +/- 3% (fasting) and 16 +/- 2 vs. 23 +/- 2% (stimulated), both P &lt; 0.05 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Increased secretory demand from <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>-associated <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> cannot explain elevated intact proinsulin and disproportionate hyperproinsulinemia in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>This abnormality may be an integrated part of pancreatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0006279'>beta-cell dysfunction</z:hpo> in this disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>