<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: We conducted this study to assess the metabolic alterations in middle-aged and elderly <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Healthy control subjects (9 middle-aged, aged 42 +/- 2 years, BMI 33 +/- 1 kg/m2; 10 elderly, aged 71 +/- 1 years, BMI 29 +/- 1 kg/m2) and patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (11 middle-aged, aged 43 +/- 2 years, BMI 34 +/- 2 kg/m2; 23 elderly, aged 73 +/- 1 years; BMI 30 +/- 1 kg/m2) underwent a 3-h oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test (OGTT), a 2-h hyperglycemic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> clamp, and a 3-h euglycemic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> clamp study with tritiated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> methodology to measure hepatic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> production and peripheral disposal rates </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Middle-aged and elderly control subjects and patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were similar in percentage of body fat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Waist-to-hip ratio was greater in elderly patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> than in elderly control subjects (P &lt; 0.01), but was similar in both middle-aged groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>VO2max was less in control subjects than in both middle-aged and elderly patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Insulin responses during the OGTT were similar in elderly control subjects and patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, but were less in middle-aged patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> than in control subjects (305 +/- 49 vs. 690 +/- 136 pmol/l, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> had absent first-phase insulin responses during the hyperglycemic clamp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Second-phase (80-120 min) insulin values were similar in elderly patients and control subjects, but were reduced in middle-aged patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> compared with control subjects (285 +/- 35 vs. 894 +/- 143 pmol/l, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>During the euglycemic clamp, basal and steady-state (150-180 min) hepatic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> output values were less in middle-aged control subjects than in patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (basal, 3.03 +/- 0.10 vs. 3.69 +/- 0.09 mg.kg-1 lean body mass.min-1, P &lt; 0.0001; steady-state, 0.72 +/- 0.10 vs. 1.84 +/- 0.20 mg.kg-1 lean body mass.min-1, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Basal and steady-state hepatic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> output values were similar in elderly patients and control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Finally, steady-state (150-180 min) <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal rates were higher in control subjects than in patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in both the middle-aged (7.51 +/- 0.85 vs. 4.62 +/- 0.24 mg.kg-1 lean body mass.min-1, P &lt; 0.01) and elderly (9.91 +/- 0.61 vs. 6.78 +/- 0.60 mg.kg-1 lean body mass.min-1, P &lt; 0.01) groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: We conclude that type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> middle-aged subjects is characterized by impaired <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-induced insulin release, altered regulation of hepatic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> output, and resistance to insulin-mediated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the primary defect in elderly <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is resistance to insulin-mediated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Our findings may have important therapeutic implications for these patient populations </plain></SENT>
</text></document>