<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: In lean diabetic patients, the presentation of the disease does not allow one to easily distinguish between type 1 and type 2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Aims of this study were to describe clinical, immunological, and genetic features of lean newly diagnosed diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A population-based cohort of 130 lean (BMI &lt; 25 kg/m2) newly diagnosed patients, aged 30-54 years, was identified among residents of the province of Turin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Islet cell antibodies (ICAs), anti-GAD, fasting and glucagon-stimulated C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> values, and HLA DQA1-DQB1 susceptibility genotypes were assessed within 2 months of the diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 45 (34.6%) and 29 (22.3%) patients were, respectively, ICA+ and anti-GAD+, with 15 (11.5%) having both antibodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In 59 patients, ICAs and/or anti-GAD antibodies were detected, giving a high prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmunity</z:hpo> (45.4%, 95% Cl 36.8-54.0); relative to patients without markers (n = 71), they were younger (40.8 +/- 7.5 vs. 45.0 +/- 6.5 years, P &lt; 0.001) and showed lower values of fasting C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> (0.56 +/- 0.33 vs. 0.79 +/- 0.41 nmol/l, P &lt; 0.001) and stimulated C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> (1.03 +/- 0.56 vs. 1.42 +/- 0.69 nmol/l, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The lowest stimulated C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> values were found in patients with both ICA and anti-GAD antibodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Frequencies of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003581'>adult-onset</z:hpo> type 1 and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were, respectively, 49.2 and 50.8% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Clinical and genetic features were not useful in the classification of patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Almost 50% of lean young and middle-aged patients were ICA+ and/or anti-GAD+, suggesting a high prevalence of a slowly evolving form of type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The evaluation at diagnosis of both beta-cell secretory capacity and markers of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmunity</z:hpo> is recommended to provide a pathogenetic classification of the disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>