<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>To elucidate potential mechanisms for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> occurring early in the development of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, we studied 10 young healthy individuals, each with two first-degree relatives with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, and 10 control subjects without known type 2 diabetic relatives </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>They were pairwise matched for age (35 +/- 1 vs. 35 +/- 1 years), BMI (23.6 +/- 0.6 vs. 23.1 +/- 0.4 kg/m2), and sex (four men, six women) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi> turnover was assessed during a euglycemic clamp at two insulin levels (low approximately 20 mU/l; high approximately 90 mU/l), and abdominal subcutaneous adipose tissue (SAT) lipolysis and blood flow were concomitantly studied with microdialysis and 133Xe clearance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>HbA1c was higher in patients with type 2 diabetic relatives than in control subjects (4.8 +/- 0.1 vs. 4.5 +/- 0.1%, P &lt; 0.02), but fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> levels were similar </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>During the clamp, the insulin sensitivity index for <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal was lower (P &lt; 0.03) in relatives than in control subjects (low 12.0 +/- 1.6 vs. 18.1 +/- 1.4; high 9.4 +/- 0.8 vs. 12.9 +/- 0.6 [100 x mg x l x kg(-1) x mU(-1) x min(-1)]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This difference was partially attributed to slightly higher clamp insulin levels in the relatives (P &lt; 0.03), suggesting an impaired rate for insulin clearance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>SAT lipolysis measured as in situ <z:chebi fb="3" ids="17754">glycerol</z:chebi> release did not differ under basal conditions (2.0 +/- 0.2 vs. 2.1 +/- 0.2 micromol x kg(-1) x min(-1)), but the suppression during the insulin infusion was less marked in relatives than in control subjects (<z:chebi fb="3" ids="17754">glycerol</z:chebi> release: low 0.92 +/- 0.09 vs. 0.68 +/- 0.16; high 0.71 +/- 0.10 vs. 0.34 +/- 0.10 micromol x kg(-1) x min(-1); P &lt; 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Plasma nonesterified fatty acids also tended to be higher in relatives than in control subjects during the insulin infusion (NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In contrast, in vitro experiments with isolated subcutaneous adipocytes displayed similar effects of insulin in relatives and control subjects with respect to both <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> uptake and antilipolysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, insulin action in vivo on both lipolysis and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> uptake is impaired early in the development of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Since this impairment was not found in isolated adipocytes, it may be suggested that neural or hormonal perturbations precede cellular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>