<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To examine the effects of hormone replacement therapy (HRT) on <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> metabolism, glycemic control, total body and central abdominal fat, blood pressure (BP), and arterial pulse wave velocity (APWV) in overweight postmenopausal females with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This was a 12-month prospective study of 14 subjects (mean +/- SD age 57.5+/-5.6 years, BMI 29.5+/-4.8 kg/m2) randomized to 6 months of observation or HRT before crossover </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>HRT consisted of 2 months of conjugated equine <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50114">estrogen</z:chebi> (CEE) 0.625 mg daily, followed by 4 months CEE and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6715">medroxyprogesterone</z:chebi> 5 mg daily </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Measures included anthropometry, fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, HbA1c, total and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> B, <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> particle size, nonesterified fatty acids (NEFA), <z:chebi fb="25" ids="50112">sex hormone</z:chebi>-binding globulin, resting energy expenditure (REE), total and central abdominal fat (by dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry), resting BP, APWV (by applanation tonometry), physical activity, well-being, and sexual function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Six months of HRT resulted in significant reductions in waist-to-hip ratio (-0.03+/-0.01 vs. 0.01+/-0.009, P = 0.007), HbA1c (-0.34+/-0.24 vs. 0.6+/-0.4%, P = 0.04), total cholesterol (-0.6+/-0.1 vs. 0.2+/-0.2 mmol/l, P = 0.001), central abdominal fat (-175+/-51 vs. -24+/-56 g, P = 0.05), and improved physical functioning (P = 0.05), compared with observation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There was a minor increase in REE with HRT (33+/-23 vs. -38+/-23 kJ/day, P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Total fat mass, fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> B, NEFA, resting BP, APWV, and physical activity were unchanged </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Postmenopausal HRT in these overweight women with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was associated with a reduction in central <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> and improvement in <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> metabolism and glycemic control without deterioration in weight status or cardiovascular parameters measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Whether HRT-induced improvements in these <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0850624" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiovascular risk factors</z:e> result in lower long-term <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1301700" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiovascular morbidity</z:e> and mortality, as observed in nondiabetic women, awaits further study </plain></SENT>
</text></document>