<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="15693">Aldose</z:chebi> reductase (AR) protein was measured in peripheral mononuclear cells (PMCs) from 55 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> by a two-site ELISA using anti-human AR monoclonal antibody </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>AR levels did not correlate with age, duration of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, and HbAlc </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, no significant differences were found in AR levels between the patients and healthy subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Thirty seven patients had at least one of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0025945" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">diabetic microangiopathy</z:e>; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e>, or <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>AR levels were significantly higher in the patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0155765" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">microangiopathy</z:e> than in those without it (52.3 +/- 15.7 vs. 43.0 +/- 15.2 ng/10(6) cells, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e> had significantly higher AR levels than those without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e> (53.7 +/- 15.8 vs. 42.7 +/- 14.3 ng/l0(6) cells, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The same result applied to the patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> (54.5 + 15.4 vs. 44.6 +/- 15.3 ng/10(6) cells, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The AR levels in the patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> tended to give a higher value than those without it </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, there were no significant differences between the two (53.9 +/- 3.6 vs. 46.4 +/- 2.6 ng/10(6) cells, NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These results indicate that AR levels in PMCs from type 2 diabetic patients are associated with the presence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0155765" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">microangiopathy</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The measurement of AR proteins in PMCs with this ELISA system is a useful tool for the clinical study of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0271672" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">diabetic complications</z:e>, and would increase our understanding of the pathogenesis of the disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>