<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Metabolically <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp>, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath>-weight (MONW) individuals are a hypothesized subgroup of the general population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>These <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath>-weight individuals potentially display a cluster of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>-related features, although this has not been systematically tested in young women </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that MONW young women would display higher levels of total and visceral fat and lower levels of physical activity than <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> women </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In a cohort of 71 healthy nonobese women (21-35 years old), we identified MONW women based on cut points for insulin sensitivity (<z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> = <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal &gt;8 mg x min(-1) x kg(-1) of fat-free mass [FFM], n = 58; impaired = <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal &lt;8 ml x min(-1) x kg(-1) of FFM, n = 13) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Thereafter, we measured body composition (dual energy X-ray absorptiometry) and body fat distribution (computed tomography), cardiorespiratory fitness (VO2max on a treadmill), physical activity energy expenditure (doubly labeled water and indirect calorimetry), <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance (oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test), serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile, and dietary intake </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We found a higher body fat percentage (32 +/- 6 vs. 27 +/- 6%, P = 0.01) and higher subcutaneous (213 +/- 61 vs. 160 +/- 78 cm2, P = 0.03) and visceral (44 +/- 16 vs. 35 +/- 14 cm2, P &lt; 0.05) abdominal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> in the MONW group versus the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The MONW group showed a lower physical activity energy expenditure (2.66 +/- 0.92 vs. 4.39 +/- 1.50 MJ/day, P = 0.01), but no difference in cardiorespiratory fitness was noted between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, despite a <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> body weight, a subset of young, apparently healthy women displayed a cluster of risky phenotypic characteristics that, if left untreated, may eventually predispose them to type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>