<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">Troglitazone</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> lower <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels in diabetic patients without increasing plasma insulin levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We compared the insulin sparing actions of these two agents and their effects on insulin sensitivity and insulin secretion in 20 type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To avoid the confounding effect of improved glycemic control on insulin action and secretion, patients were first rendered euglycemic with 4 weeks of continuous subcutaneous insulin infusion (CSII) before randomization to CSII plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">troglitazone</z:chebi> (n = 10) or CSII plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (n = 10); euglycemia was maintained for another 6-7 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Insulin sensitivity was assessed by a hyperinsulinemic-euglycemic clamp 1) at baseline, 2) after 4 weeks of CSII, and 3) after CSII plus either <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">troglitazone</z:chebi> or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The 24-h <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> profiles were performed on the day before the second and third <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> clamps </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Good glycemic control was achieved with CSII alone and was maintained with CSII plus an oral agent (mean 24-h <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">troglitazone</z:chebi>, 6.2+/-0.6 mmol/l; <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, 6.2 +/-0.3 mmol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Insulin requirements decreased 53% with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">troglitazone</z:chebi> compared with CSII alone (48+/-4 vs. 102+/-13 U/day, P &lt; 0.001), but only 31% with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (76+/-13 vs. 110+/-18 U/day, P &lt; 0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The 24-h C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> profiles were similar </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>Normal</z:mpath> fasting hepatic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> output was maintained with both agents despite lower insulin levels than on CSII alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Insulin sensitivity did not change significantly with CSII alone or with CSII plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, but improved 29% with CSII plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">troglitazone</z:chebi> (P &lt; 0.005 vs. CSII alone) and was then 45% higher than in the CSII plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> patients (P &lt; 0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> has no effect on insulin-stimulated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal independent of glycemic control in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">Troglitazone</z:chebi> (600 mg/day) has greater <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0877012" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">insulin-sparing effects</z:e> than <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (1,700 mg/day) in CSII-treated euglycemic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>This is probably explained by the peripheral tissue insulin-sensitizing effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">troglitazone</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>