<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Variation at the variable number tandem repeat (VNTR) minisatellite 5' of the insulin gene (INS) is associated with several phenotypes, including type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000147'>polycystic ovary</z:hpo> syndrome, and birth weight </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Case-control studies have suggested that class III VNTR alleles are also associated with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, but results have been inconsistent and may reflect population stratification </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To explore further the role of the INS-VNTR in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> susceptibility, we used family-based association methods in 155 parent-offspring trios from the British Diabetic Association-Warren Trios repository, each ascertained via a Europid proband with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Overall, there was no significant association between <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and the INS-VNTR genotype, with 65 of 119 heterozygous parents (55%) transmitting class III and 54 class I (P = 0.16, one-sided) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>However, whereas maternal transmissions followed Mendelian expectation, there was a marked excess of class III transmission from the 49 heterozygous fathers (34 [69%] vs. 15, P = 0.003 vs. 50% expectation, P = 0.003 vs. maternal transmission) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>These results confirm that variation within the TH-INS-IGF2 locus, most plausibly at the VNTR itself, influences type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> susceptibility </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>By demonstrating that this effect is mediated exclusively by the paternally derived allele, these findings implicate imprinted genes in the pathogenesis of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>