<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The concentration of some of the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26395">purine nucleotides</z:chebi> and their metabolites together with that of malondialdehyde (<z:chebi fb="14" ids="32506">MDA</z:chebi>) have been measured in resting and stimulated platelets of type 1 and type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>While control platelets show a net decrease of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15996">guanosine triphosphate</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="11" ids="15996">GTP</z:chebi>) (3.1 vs. 2.3 nmol per 10(9) platelets) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16750">guanosine</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="2" ids="18361">diphosphate</z:chebi> (GDP) (3.0 vs. 2.0 nmol per 10(9) platelets) and a significant increase of <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> (0.04 vs. 0.55 nmol per 10(9) platelets) with platelet stimulation, platelets of type 1 and type 2 diabetic patients have a lesser change of these metabolites (<z:chebi fb="11" ids="15996">GTP</z:chebi>, 2.6 vs. 2.4; GDP, 2.3 vs. 2.4; <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi>, 0.04 vs. 0.30 (P &lt; 0.05 vs. control) nmol per 10(9) platelets in type 1 diabetics; <z:chebi fb="11" ids="15996">GTP</z:chebi>, 2.4 vs. 2.7; GDP, 2.4 vs. 2.1; <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi>, 0.08 vs. 0.32 (P &lt; 0.05 vs. control) nmol per 10(9) platelets in type 2 diabetics) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>These results indicate that the change (stimulated minus resting) of <z:chebi fb="11" ids="15996">GTP</z:chebi>, GDP and <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> in diabetic platelets is significantly different from that of controls (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Moreover, the amount of <z:chebi fb="14" ids="32506">MDA</z:chebi> produced during platelet activation seems to be lower than controls only in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (1.81 vs. 2.86 nmol per 10(9) platelets, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>These results seem to indicate that a difference in the pattern of platelet <z:chebi fb="9" ids="36976">nucleotides</z:chebi> could be an important feature even in well-controlled <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, while <z:chebi fb="14" ids="32506">MDA</z:chebi> is probably modified only in association with the late vascular complications of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>