<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Repaglinide is a new oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">hypoglycemic agent</z:chebi> that acts as a prandial <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> regulator proposed for the treatment of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> by stimulating insulin secretion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to explore actions of repaglinide on the rapid pulsatile insulin release by high-frequency insulin sampling and analysis of insulin-concentration time series </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We examined 8 healthy lean male subjects in a single-dose double-blind placebo-controlled crossover design </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>After the subjects underwent an overnight fast, blood sampling was initiated and continued every minute for 120 min </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After 40 min, a single dose (0.5 mg) of repaglinide or placebo was given </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Serum insulin-concentration time series were assessed by deconvolution analyses and the regularity statistic by approximate entropy (ApEn) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Average insulin concentration was increased after repaglinide administration (basal vs. stimulated period, P values are placebo vs. repaglinide) (25.1 +/- 3.6 vs. 33.5 +/- 4.1 pmol/l, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Insulin secretory burst mass (15.8 +/- 2.2 vs. 19.6 +/- 2.8 pmol x l(-1) x pulse(-1), P = 0.02) and amplitude (6.1 +/- 0.9 vs. 7.7 +/- 1.2 pmol x l(-1) x min(-1), P = 0.008) were augmented after repaglinide administration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A concomitant trend toward an increase in basal insulin secretion was observed (2.5 +/- 0.3 vs. 3.2 +/- 0.4 pmol x l(-1) x min(-1), p = 0.06), while the interpulse interval was unaltered (6.8 +/- 1.0 vs. 5.4 +/- 0.4 min/pulse, P = 0.38) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>ApEn increased significantly after repaglinide administration (0.623 +/- 0.045 vs. 0.670 +/- 0.034, P = 0.04), suggesting less orderly oscillatory patterns of insulin release </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In conclusion, a single dose of repaglinide amplifies insulin secretory burst mass (and basal secretion) with no change in burst frequency </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The possible importance of these mechanisms in the treatment of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> characterized by disrupted pulsatile insulin secretion remains to be clarified </plain></SENT>
</text></document>