<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Elevated <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> and its principal carrier protein <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> a1 [apo(a1)] are associated with reduced risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010068" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary heart disease</z:e> (CHD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>No studies are available on the impact of the -75-bp and/or +83-bp polymorphisms of the apo(a1) gene on <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> and apo(a1) levels in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We determined the prevalence of the: -75-bp and +83-bp polymorphisms of the apo(a1) gene by restriction fragment length polymorphism analysis among 308 unrelated nondiabetic subjects with CHD and among 251 unrelated patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with CHD and in randomly selected 82 healthy men (CHD-) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The rare M1- and M2- allele frequencies of the apo(a1) gene were 23 and 1.8%, respectively, among control subjects; 20 and 1.5%, respectively, among nondiabetic subjects with CHD; and 22 and 2.6%, respectively, among patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and CHD (NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Nonsmoking nondiabetic subjects with CHD having the M2+- genotype had higher <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> (1.48 +/- 0.19 vs. 1.23 +/- 0.02 mmol/l, P &lt; 0.01) and apo(a1) (1.43 +/- 0.10 vs. 1.36 +/- 0.02 g/l, P &lt; 0.05) levels than subjects with the M2++ genotype, even after adjustment for confounding factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This association was not found among patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and CHD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: We conclude that the +83-bp polymorphism of the apo(a1) gene is associated with elevated <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> and apo(a1) levels in Finnish nondiabetic subjects but not in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>