<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Despite the effects of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000842'>hyperinsulinemia</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo>, 2 factors known to inhibit endogenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> production (EGP) in nondiabetic subjects, increased EGP is a consistent feature of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Recent studies have suggested that increased <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-6-phosphatase (G6Pase) and/or decreased glucokinase (GK) may explain the increase in EGP </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>However, no studies to date have clearly established this relationship in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The present studies were designed to determine rates of EGP and the activities of G6Pase and GK in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients scheduled for gastric bypass surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The study group consisted of 14 <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> nondiabetic subjects and 13 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (BMI 53.7 +/- 2.4 vs. 50.1 +/- 1.6 kg/m2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Rates of EGP were determined after an overnight fast with a 4-h infusion of [6,6]-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="4167">D-glucose</z:chebi>, and they were significantly higher in the type 2 diabetic patients (85.9 +/- 10.0 vs. 137.8 +/- 14.4 mg x m(-2) x min(-1), P &lt; 0.001) despite greater plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (5.1 +/- 0.1 vs. 12.0 +/- 1.1 mmol/l) and similar insulin concentrations (130.8 +/- 19.8 vs. 112.8 +/- 16.2 pmol/l, NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Moreover, resistance to insulin-induced suppression of EGP was observed in the patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> when insulin concentrations were increased from approximately 120 to 180 pmol/l </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Hepatic G6Pase activity determined from freshly isolated microsomes was significantly increased in the type 2 diabetic patients compared with the <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> control subjects (0.16 +/- 0.02 vs. 0.09 +/- 0.01 micromol x min(-1) x mg(-1) protein, P &lt; 0.02), whereas levels of GK were decreased (1.20 +/- 0.16 vs. 2.01 +/- 0.01 micromol x min(-1) x mg(-1) protein, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Net flux through G6Pase was significantly increased in type 2 diabetic patients (P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We conclude that increased EGP is mediated in part by increased G6Pase flux in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>