<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Although it is well established that glucagon-like <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> 1(7-36) <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29337,32988">amide</z:chebi> (GLP-1) is a potent stimulator of insulin secretion, its effects on insulin action and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> effectiveness are less clear </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To determine whether GLP-1 increases insulin action and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> effectiveness, subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were studied on two occasions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Insulin was infused during the night on both occasions to ensure that baseline <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentrations were comparable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>On the morning of study, either GLP-1 (1.2 pmol x kg(-1) x min(-1)) or saline were infused along with somatostatin and replacement amounts of glucagon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi> also was infused in a pattern mimicking that typically observed after a carbohydrate meal </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Insulin concentrations were either kept constant at basal levels (n = 6) or varied so as to create a prandial insulin profile (n = 6) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The increase in <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentration was virtually identical on the GLP-1 and saline study days during both the basal (1.21 +/- 0.15 vs. 1.32 +/- 0.19 mol/l per 6 h) and prandial (0.56 +/- 0.14 vs. 0.56 +/- 0.10 mol/l per 6 h) insulin infusions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>During both the basal and prandial insulin infusions, <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disappearance promptly increased after initiation of the <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> infusion to rates that did not differ on the GLP-1 and saline study days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Suppression of endogenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> production also was comparable on the GLP-1 and saline study days during both the basal (-2.7 +/- 0.3 vs. -3.1 +/- 0.2 micromol/kg) and prandial (-3.1 +/- 0.4 vs. -3.0 +/- 0.6 pmol/kg) insulin infusions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We conclude that when insulin and glucagon concentrations are matched, GLP-1 has negligible effects on either insulin action or <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> effectiveness in people with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>These data strongly support the concept that GLP-1 improves glycemic control in people with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> by increasing insulin secretion, by inhibiting glucagon secretion, and by delaying gastric emptying rather than by altering extrapancreatic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> metabolism </plain></SENT>
</text></document>