<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We studied whether there is an association between the single nucleotide polymorphism c.533A&gt;C (K121Q) in the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="17089">glycoprotein</z:chebi> PC-1 gene and features of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> in case-control and intrafamily association studies in 922 subjects from Finland and Sweden </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>No difference was observed in the Q allele frequency between control subjects and type 2 diabetic subjects (12.9 vs. 15.1%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The QK genotype was associated with higher fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) concentrations than the KK genotype in type 2 diabetic patients (P &lt;0.001) and their relatives (P &lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A permutation test of siblings discordant for the QK and KK genotypes also showed that the nondiabetic siblings with the QK genotype had higher FPG (6.1 +/- 2.0 vs. 5.4 +/- 0.6 mmo/l, P &lt;0.001) and fasting insulin (7.0 +/- 3.6 vs. 4.8 +/- 2.6 mU/l, P &lt;0.05) concentrations than the carriers of the KK genotype </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In addition, diabetic siblings with the QK genotype had higher systolic blood pressure (147.0 +/- 18.0 vs. 140.0 +/- 18.7 mmHg, P &lt;0.05) and higher fasting (9.9 +/- 3.0 vs. 8.8 +/- 2.8 mmol/l, P &lt;0.05) and 2-h plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (17.3 +/- 8.5 vs. 12.9 +/- 4.2 mmol/l, P &lt; 0.05) concentrations than the diabetic carriers of the KK genotype </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The present study shows that, although the Q allele of the human <z:chebi fb="2" ids="17089">glycoprotein</z:chebi> PC-1 gene is associated with surrogate measures of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, it may not be enough to increase the susceptibility to type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>