<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the usefulness of the homeostasis model assessment as an index of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> (HOMA-IR) for evaluating the clinical course of patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: The usefulness of HOMA-IR and its relationship with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> assessed by the hyperinsulinemic-euglycemic clamp study (clamp IR) were evaluated in 55 Japanese patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> before and after treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The patients were subjected to diet (approximately 1,440-1,720 kcal/day) and exercise therapy (walking 10,000 steps daily) for 6 weeks during their hospitalization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Univariate regression analysis disclosed a significant correlation between log-transformed HOMA-IR and log-transformed clamp IR before (r = -0.613, P &lt; 0.0001) and after ( = -0.734, P &lt; 0.0001) treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Neither the slopes (-0.71 +/- 0.12 vs. -0.79 +/- 0.09, F = 0.25, P = 0.61) nor the intercepts (y-intercept = 1.67 vs. 1.70, x-intercept = 2.36 vs. 2.15, F = 0.02, P = 0.88) of the regression lines between HOMA-IR and clamp IR were significantly different before and after treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There was a significant correlation between the decrease in log-transformed HOMA-IR and the increase in clamp IR during treatment (r = -0.617, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: HOMA-IR may constitute a useful method not only for diagnosing <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, but also for follow-up during the treatment of patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>