<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine the efficacy of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> compared with placebo in reducing <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: After a 4-week placebo run-in period, 959 patients were randomized to placebo or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> (total daily dose 4 or 8 mg) for 26 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The primary measure of efficacy was change in the HbA1c concentration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">Rosiglitazone</z:chebi> produced dosage-dependent reductions in HbA1c of 0.8, 0.9, 1.1, and 1.5% in the 4 mg o.d., 2 mg b.i.d., 8 mg o.d., and 4 mg b.i.d. groups, respectively, compared with placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Clinically significant decreases from baseline in HbA1c were observed in drug-naive patients at <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> doses and in patients previously treated with oral monotherapy at <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> 8 mg o.d. and 4 mg b.i.d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Clinically significant decreases from baseline in HbA1c were also observed with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> 4 mg b.i.d. in patients previously treated with combination oral therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Approximately 33% of drug-naive patients treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> achieved HbA1c &lt; or =7% at study end </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The proportions of patients with at least one adverse event were comparable among the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> and placebo groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was no evidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0235378,C0348754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Injury or Poisoning" abbrv="">hepatotoxicity</z:e> in any treatment group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There were statistically significant increases in weight and serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> treatment groups compared with placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>For <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi>, the observed increase appeared to be dose related </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">Rosiglitazone</z:chebi> at total daily doses of 4 and 8 mg significantly improved glycemic control in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and was well tolerated </plain></SENT>
</text></document>