<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: Non-<z:hpo ids='HP_0100651'>insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>) not responding to dietary treatment alone in patients with non-alcoholic liver <z:hpo ids='HP_0001394'>cirrhosis</z:hpo> is characterized by high postprandial <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020456" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hyperglycaemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The control of postprandial <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020456" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hyperglycaemia</z:e> in such patients, is generally achieved by the means of progressively higher doses of insulin, with an increasing risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> in the late postprandial period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to evaluate the use of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> for the control of postprandial <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020456" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hyperglycaemia</z:e> in 100 patients with well-compensated liver <z:hpo ids='HP_0001394'>cirrhosis</z:hpo> and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> treated with insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The study was double blind with randomization of treatments into <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> (52 patients) vs. placebo (48 patients) with parallel branches over a period of 28 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients tolerated the treatments well and no significant variations in liver function tests were observed (&lt; 5% vs. pretreatment) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A significant reduction of several parameters was observed only after <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> treatment: fasting glycaemia (173 +/- 28 vs. 146 +/- 19 mg/dl; p &lt; 0.01), postprandial glycaemia (230 +/- 24 vs. 148 +/- 20 mg/dl; p &lt; 0.01), mean glycaemia (206 +/- 20 vs. 136 +/- 13 mg/dl; p &lt; 0.01), mean variation (180 +/- 14 vs. 51 +/- 10 mg/dl; p &lt; 0.01), HbA1c (8.9 +/- 0.8 vs. 7.2 +/- 0.5; p &lt; 0.05), C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> 2 h after a standard meal (4.5 +/- 1.9 vs. 2.8 +/- 1.7 ng/ml; p &lt; 0.05), whereas the parameters did not change significantly after the placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>After <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> treatment a significant increase of intestinal voiding/week (+116% vs. +10%; p &lt; 0.01) and a parallel reduction of blood ammonia levels (-52 +/- 9% vs. -9 +/- 5%; P &lt; 0.01) were observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The results clearly document the good tolerability and the absence of toxic effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> on liver, due to the lack of both intestinal absorption and hepatic metabolism of the drug at doses in the therapeutic range </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In fact, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> increases the peristalsis movements of the gut, stimulates the proliferation of the saccarolytic bacteria and simultaneously reduces the proliferation of proteolytic bacteria, thus resulting active in the reduction of blood ammonia levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> may be advantageously exploited in the treatment of type 2 diabetic patients with well-compensated non-alcholic liver <z:hpo ids='HP_0001394'>cirrhosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>