<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate the efficacy of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> in the treatment of secondary failures to sulphonylurea-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> therapy, its comparison against bedtime <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin, and to measure the changes in postprandial metabolism resulting from both treatments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: One hundred type 2 diabetic patients in a secondary failure were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The study begun with a run-in diet period of 6 weeks, in which an isocaloric diet was prescribed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Only subjects who continued hyperglycaemic were randomly assigned to placebo and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> (n = 17) or bedtime <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin (n = 12) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">Acarbose</z:chebi> (300 mg/day) or placebo were administered using a randomized, double blind, crossover design </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Treatment periods of 3 months were separated by a 3-week washout period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Insulin was administered during 3 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At the beginning and the end of each treatment period, an i.v. <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test and a meal test were performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Safety tests were done every 4 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">Acarbose</z:chebi> resulted in a small but significant improvement in fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (13.5 +/- 2.4 vs. 11.3 +/- 3.9 mmol/l, p = 0.05), HbA1c (11.1 +/- 3.4 vs. 10.3 +/- 2.5%, P = 0.3) and in a decreased plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> during the meal test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Bedtime insulin significantly decreased fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (13.1 +/- 2.9 vs. 8.2 +/- 2.3 mmol/l, p &lt; 0.01), HbA1c (11.7 +/- 2.9 vs. 9.4 +/- 2.7%, p &lt; 0.01) and plasma cholesterol </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>No change in insulin secretion resulted from insulin and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">Acarbose</z:chebi> decreases blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> in secondary failure to sulphonylurea-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> therapy; however, the decrease is not enough to reach the desired metabolic control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Bedtime <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin is, by far, a more effective alternative </plain></SENT>
</text></document>