<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To assess the effect of oral antihyperglycaemic therapy on fasting proinsulin and the relation between proinsulin levels and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0850624" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiovascular risk factors</z:e> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: One hundred and sixty-five patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, fasting blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentration (FBG) &gt; or = 6.7 mmol/l, were recruited from five <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> outpatient clinics in primary health care </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Diet and antihyperglycaemic medication, aiming at FBG &lt; 6.7 mmol/l, was maintained for 6 months after completed dose titration in a randomized, double-blind, double-dummy trial with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (M), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> (G) and primary combination of both drugs (MG) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The study compared M, G and MG in low dose (MGL) and also different high-dose regimens, i.e. G added to M (M/G), M added to G (G/M) and primary combination (MGH) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Outcome measures were fasting proinsulin, glycaemia, body mass index, blood pressure, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi>, insulin and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Lower proinsulin levels were found when therapy was initiated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (M vs. G, p = 0.013 and M/G vs. G/M, p = 0.033) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>M and G were equally effective on <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In the group as a whole FBG decreased from (mean +/- s.d.) 10.2 +/- 2.7 to 7.0 +/- 1.2 mmol/l with no change in proinsulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Proinsulin was associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0850624" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiovascular risk factors</z:e>, linking high proinsulin to an atherogenic risk marker profile </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Mean proinsulin change from baseline was inconsistently associated with markers of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Meal-stimulated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (net AUC) decreased after treatment only in those with low baseline proinsulin levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: It may be advantageous to initiate oral antihyperglycaemic therapy with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> rather than with sulphonylurea </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>High proinsulin levels are associated with an atherogenic-risk marker profile and an impaired therapeutic postprandial <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> response after treatment in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Proinsulin change after therapy is inconsistently associated with markers of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> and unrelated to fasting blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> reduction </plain></SENT>
</text></document>