<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To assess the efficacy and tolerability of sibutramine 15 mg once daily as a weight reduction agent in overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients (body mass index (b.m.i.) &gt; 26 kg/m2) with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> when given with a customised, reduced-calorie diet, and to evaluate the influence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> on diabetic control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Randomised, placebo-controlled, double-blind, parallel-group, 12-week study conducted at two hospital-based <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>/<z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> clinics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients were men and women aged 30-65 years, with b.m.i. &gt; 26 kg/m2 and &lt; or = 35 kg/m2 and treated or untreated type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> diagnosed &gt; or = 6 months previously </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Each patient was given sibutramine 15 mg or placebo once daily and advised to follow a customised diet of 500 kcal/day less than the individual's energy needs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The principal measure of efficacy was change in body weight (b.w.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Additional efficacy measurements were changes in b.m.i., body composition as measured by dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry, and change in waist and hip measurements </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Changes in diabetic control were assessed by blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels fasting and after a standard test meal, fasting insulin level, and glycosylated <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> level </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Adverse events (AEs) were monitored at each visit, and routine laboratory safety tests were done at 4-week intervals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Ninety-one patients were randomised into the study, 44 to placebo and 47 to sibutramine 15 mg once daily </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Eighty-three patients (91%) completed the study, 40 (91%) on placebo and 43 (91%) on sibutramine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Mean weight reduction from baseline was statistically significantly greater with sibutramine than with placebo at every measurement and at the end of the study (2.4 vs. 0.1 kg at week 12; p &lt; 0.001; intent-to-treat) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The proportion of patients who lost &gt; 5% of their baseline b.w. was 19% in the sibutramine group and 0% in the placebo group (p &lt; 0.001; 95% confidence interval: 9, 30) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Patients receiving sibutramine lost significantly more fat mass compared with those receiving placebo, as a percentage (1.0% vs. 0.1%; p &lt; 0.05) and in absolute terms (1.8 vs. 0.2 kg, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Loss of lean mass was not significantly different between the groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Mean peak blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentration after a standard test meal decreased by 1.1 mmol/l in the sibutramine treatment group but increased by 0.5 mmol/l in the placebo group (p = 0.04; difference in means, 1.6, 95% confidence interval: -3.3, -0.1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Mean fasting blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> decreased by 0.3 mmol/l with sibutramine and increased by 1.4 mmol/l with placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Mean glycosylated <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> levels decreased by 0.3% units with sibutramine treatment, and were unchanged with placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>However, more sibutramine-treated patients (33%) than placebo-treated patients (5%) achieved decreases in glycosylated <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> of 1% unit or more (p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>Sibutramine 15 mg was safe and well tolerated, and AEs were mostly mild or moderate in severity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="19" pm="."><plain>No significant differences were found between treatment groups in blood pressure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="20" pm="."><plain>No clinically significant conduction or rhythm abnormalities were observed on ECG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="21" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Sibutramine 15 mg once daily with a customised, reduced-calorie diet significantly <z:mp ids='MP_0001262'>reduced weight</z:mp> compared with placebo in overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients (b.m.i. &gt; 26 kg/m2) with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="22" pm="."><plain>Sibutramine was well tolerated, and significant improvement in diabetic control was seen in conjunction with weight reduction on sibutramine treatment </plain></SENT>
</text></document>