<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Psammomys obesus is a model of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> that displays resistance to insulin and deranged beta-cell response to <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We examined the major signaling pathways for insulin release in P. obesus islets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Islets from hyperglycemic animals utilized twice as much <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> as islets from normoglycemic <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-prone or <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-resistant controls but exhibited similar rates of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> oxidation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Fractional oxidation of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> was constant in control islets over a range of concentrations, whereas islets from hyperglycemic P. obesus showed a decline at high <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> substrates <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17865">alpha-ketoisocaproate</z:chebi> and monomethyl succinate had no effect on insulin secretion in P. obesus islets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Basal insulin release in islets from <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-resistant P. obesus was unaffected by glucagon-like <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> 1 (GLP-1) or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="42471">forskolin</z:chebi>, whereas that of islets of the diabetic line was augmented by the drugs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>GLP-1 and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="42471">forskolin</z:chebi> potentiated the insulin response to maximal (11.1 mmol/l) <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> in islets from <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37532">phorbol ester</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8116">phorbol</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28875">myristic acid</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="1" ids="53780">PMA</z:chebi>) potentiated basal insulin release in islets from <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0362046" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">prediabetic</z:e> animals, but not those from hyperglycemic or <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-resistant P. obesus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>At the maximal stimulatory <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentration, <z:chebi fb="1" ids="53780">PMA</z:chebi> potentiated insulin response in islets from normoglycemic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0362046" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">prediabetic</z:e> and <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-resistant P. obesus but had no effect on islets from hyperglycemic P. obesus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Maintenance of islets from hyperglycemic P. obesus for 18 h in low (3.3 mmol/l) <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> in the presence of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4495">diazoxide</z:chebi> (375 pmol/l) dramatically improved the insulin response to <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and restored the responsiveness to <z:chebi fb="1" ids="53780">PMA</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Immunohistochemical analysis indicated that <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> was associated with reduced expression of alpha-protein kinase C (PKC) and diminished translocation of lambda-PKC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In summary, we found that 1) P. obesus islets have low oxidative capacity, probably resulting in limited ability to generate ATP to initiate and drive the insulin secretion; 2) insulin response potentiated by cyclic <z:chebi fb="47" ids="16027,28971">AMP</z:chebi>-dependent protein kinase is intact in P. obesus islets, and increased sensitivity to GLP-1 or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="42471">forskolin</z:chebi> in the diabetic line may be secondary to increased sensitivity to <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>; and 3) islets of hyperglycemic P. obesus display reduced expression of alpha-PKC and diminished translocation of lambda-PKC associated with impaired response to <z:chebi fb="1" ids="53780">PMA</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>We conclude that low beta-cell oxidative capacity coupled with impaired PKC-dependent signaling may contribute to the animals' poor adaptation to a high-energy diet </plain></SENT>
</text></document>