<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Deficient insulin secretion and relative hyperproinsulinemia are characteristic features of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The gerbil Psammomys obesus appears to be an ideal natural model of the human disease because it shows increased tendency to develop diet-induced <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, which is associated with moderate <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The disease is characterized by initial <z:hpo ids='HP_0000842'>hyperinsulinemia</z:hpo>, progressing to <z:mp ids='MP_0002727'>hypoinsulinemia</z:mp> associated with depleted pancreatic insulin stores and an increased proportion of insulin precursor molecules in the blood and islets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Although the proinsulin translational efficacy was found to be increased in hyperglycemic animals, insulin <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> levels were not augmented and exhibited a gradual decrease with disease progression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> was associated with a transient increase in beta-cell proliferative activity, as opposed to a prolonged increase in the rate of beta-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, culminating in disruption of islet architecture </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The hypothesis that glucotoxicity is responsible in part for these in vivo changes was investigated in vitro in primary islet cultures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Islets from <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-prone P. obesus cultured at high <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentrations displayed changes in beta-cell function that mimic those observed in diabetic animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These changes include deficient insulin secretion, depleted insulin content, an increased proportion of insulin precursor molecules, a progressive increase of DNA fragmentation, and a transient proliferative response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, insulin <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> was not increased by short-term exposure of P. obesus islets to elevated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> in vitro </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>It is proposed that beta-cell glucotoxicity in P. obesus results from the inability of proinsulin biosynthesis to keep pace with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> insulin hypersecretion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The resulting <z:mpath ids='MPATH_63'>depletion</z:mpath> of the insulin stores may be related to deficient <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-regulated insulin gene transcription, possibly due to defective PDX-1 (pancreatic duodenal homeobox factor-1) expression in the adult P. obesus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>An additional glucotoxic effect involves the loss of beta-cell mass in hyperglycemic P. obesus as a result of progressive beta-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> without an adequate increase in the rate of beta-cell proliferation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>