<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate health care access and utilization and health status and outcomes for type 2 diabetic patients according to race and ethnicity and to determine whether health status is influenced by health care access and utilization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: National samples of Caucasians, African-Americans, and Mexican-Americans were studied in the third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Information on medical history and treatment of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, health care access and utilization, and health status and outcomes was obtained by structured questionnaires and by clinical and laboratory assessments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Almost <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients in each race and ethnic group had one primary source of ambulatory medical care (92-97%), saw one physician at this source (83-92%), and had at least semiannual physician visits (83-90%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Almost <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients &gt; or = 65 years of age had health insurance (99-100%), and for those patients &lt; 65 years of age, Caucasians (91%) and African-Americans (89%) had higher rates of coverage than Mexican-Americans (66%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Rates of treatment with insulin or oral agents (71-78%), eye examination in the previous year (61-70%), blood pressure check in the previous 6 months (83-89%), and the proportion of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> that was diagnosed (84-91%) were similar for each race and ethnic group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Lower proportions of African-Americans and Mexican-Americans self-monitored their blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (insulin-treated, 27 vs. 44% of Caucasians), had their cholesterol checked (62-68 vs. 81%), and had their <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e> diagnosed (45 vs. 58%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>African-American and Mexican-American patients had a somewhat higher proportion than Caucasian patients, with HbA1c &gt; or = 7% (58-66 vs. 55%), blood pressure &gt; or = 140/90 mmHg among those with diagnosed <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (60-65 vs. 55%), and clinical <z:hpo ids='HP_0000093'>proteinuria</z:hpo> (11-14 vs. 5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In contrast, they had better levels of total cholesterol (&gt; or = 240 mg/dl) (28 -30 vs. 34%) and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> (&gt; or = 45 mg/dl) (46 -59 vs. 38%), and African-American and Mexican-American men were less overweight than Caucasian men (BMI &gt; or = 30) (34-37 vs. 44%), although the opposite was true for women </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="1" ids="47774">LDL cholesterol</z:chebi> levels and the proportion of patients who smoked cigarettes or were hospitalized in the past year were similar among <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> three groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In logistic regression analysis, there was little evidence that levels of blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, blood pressure, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi>, or <z:mp ids='MP_0002871'>albuminuria</z:mp> were associated with access to or utilization of health care or with socioeconomic status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: There are some differences by race and ethnicity in health care access and utilization and in health status and outcomes for adults with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>However, the magnitude of these differences pale in comparison with the suboptimal health status of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> three race and ethnic groups relative to established treatment goals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Health status does not appear to be influenced by access to health care </plain></SENT>
</text></document>