<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The Gly972Arg polymorphism in the insulin receptor substrate (IRS)-1 was found in some studies to have a higher prevalence in type 2 diabetic subjects than in control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Previously, transfection of IRS-1 with this polymorphism into insulin-secreting cells resulted in a marked reduction of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-stimulated insulin secretion compared with the <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> transfected cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In the present study, we compared insulin secretion in well-matched <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-tolerant subjects with and without this polymorphism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Several validated indexes of beta-cell function from the oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test were significantly lower in X/Arg (n = 31) compared with Gly/Gly (n = 181) (P between 0.002 and 0.05), whereas insulin sensitivity (measured with a euglycemic clamp) was not different </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>During a modified hyperglycemic clamp, insulin secretion rates were significantly lower in Gly/Arg (n = 8) compared with Gly/Gly (n = 36) during the first phase (1,711+/-142 vs. 3,014+/-328 pmol/min, P = 0.05) and after maximal stimulation with arginine (5,340+/-639 vs. 9,075+/-722 pmol/min, P = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In summary, our results suggest that the Gly972Arg polymorphism in IRS-1 is associated with <z:mp ids='MP_0003059'>decreased insulin secretion</z:mp> in response to <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> but not with insulin sensitivity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>It is possible that this polymorphism causes <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> at the level of the beta-cell and contributes to the polygenic etiology of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>