<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Available insulin sensitivity (IS) methods based on the oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test (OGTT) are empirical </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We used a <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-insulin model to derive an OGTT-based IS (oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> insulin sensitivity [OGIS]) index, which predicts <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> clearance in a <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> clamp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We validated OGIS against clamp data </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: OGIS requires <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and insulin concentrations from a 75-g OGTT at 0, 2, and 3 h (3-h OGTT) or at 0, 1.5, and 2 h (2-h OGTT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The formula includes six constants optimized to match the clamp results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>For this purpose, 15 lean nondiabetic subjects (BMI &lt; 25 kg/m2), 38 <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> nondiabetic subjects (BMI &gt; 25 kg/m2), and 38 subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> randomly underwent an OGTT and a 120 mU x min(-1) x m(-2) insulin infusion euglycemic clamp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi> clearance (Cl CLAMP), calculated as the ratio of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> infusion to concentration during the last hour of the clamp, was compared with OGIS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>OGIS was also tested on an independent group of 13 subjects with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo> (IGT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: OGIS and Cl CLAMP were correlated in the whole group (R = 0.77, P &lt; 0.0001), in the subgroups (lean: R = 0.59; <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp>: R = 0.73; type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>: R = 0.49; P &lt; 0.02), and in the independent IGT group (R = 0.65, P &lt; 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Reproducibility of OGIS and Cl CLAMP were similar (coefficients of variation: OGIS 7.1%, Cl CLAMP 6.4%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>OGIS was as effective as Cl CLAMP in discriminating between groups (for OGIS, lean vs. <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp>: 440 +/- 16 vs. 362 +/- 11 ml x min(-1) x m(-2), p &lt; 0.001; lean vs. type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>: 440 +/- 16 vs. 239 +/- 7, P &lt; 0.0001; <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> vs. type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>: 362 +/- 11 vs. 239 +/- 7, P &lt; 0.0001; results were similar for Cl CLAMP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The relationships between IS and BMI, fasting plasma insulin, and insulin secretion (calculated from the OGTT insulin concentration) were examined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>OGIS yielded results similar to Cl CLAMP and fully consistent with established physiological principles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The performance of the index for the 3-h and 2-h OGTT was similar </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: OGIS is an index of IS in good agreement with the clamp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Because of its simplicity (only three blood samples required), this method has potential use for clinical investigation including large-scale epidemiological studies </plain></SENT>
</text></document>