<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Activation of <z:chebi fb="47" ids="16027,28971">AMP</z:chebi>-activated protein kinase (AMPK) with 5-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="22512">aminoimidazole</z:chebi>-4-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="23004,37622">carboxamide</z:chebi>-1-beta-D-ribofurano-side (AICAR) increases <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> transport in skeletal muscle via an insulin-independent pathway </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To examine the effects of AMPK activation on skeletal muscle <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> transport activity and whole-body carbohydrate and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> metabolism in an insulin-resistant rat model, awake <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> Zuckerfa/fa rats (n = 26) and their lean (n = 23) littermates were infused for 90 min with AICAR, insulin, or saline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The insulin infusion rate (4 mU.kg(-1).min(-1)) was selected to match the <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> requirements during AICAR (bolus, 100 mg/kg; constant, 10 mg.kg(-1).min(-1)) isoglycemic clamps in the lean rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The effects of these identical AICAR and insulin infusion rates were then examined in the <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16646">Zucker</z:chebi> rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>AICAR infusion increased muscle AMPK activity more than fivefold (P &lt; 0.01 vs. control and insulin) in both lean and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Plasma <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi>, fatty acid concentrations, and <z:chebi fb="3" ids="17754">glycerol</z:chebi> turnover, as assessed by [2-13C]<z:chebi fb="3" ids="17754">glycerol</z:chebi>, were <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> decreased in both lean and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> rats infused with AICAR (P &lt; 0.05 vs. basal), whereas insulin had no effect on these parameters in the <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Endogenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> production rates, measured by [U-13C]<z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, were suppressed by &gt;50% during AICAR and insulin infusions in both lean and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> rats (P &lt; 0.05 vs. basal) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In lean rats, rates of whole-body <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal increased by more than two-fold (P &lt; 0.05 vs. basal) during both AICAR and insulin infusion; [3H]<z:chebi fb="0" ids="15866">2-deoxy-D-glucose</z:chebi> transport activity increased to a similar extent, by &gt;2.2-fold (both P &lt; 0.05 vs. control), in both soleus and red gastrocnemius muscles of lean rats infused with either AICAR or insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16646">Zucker</z:chebi> rats, neither AICAR nor insulin stimulated whole-body <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal or soleus muscle <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> transport activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, AICAR increased <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> transport activity by approximately 2.4-fold (P &lt; 0.05 vs. control) in the red gastrocnemius from <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> rats, whereas insulin had no effect </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In summary, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> infusion of AICAR in an insulin-resistant rat model activates skeletal muscle AMPK and increases <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> transport activity in red gastrocnemius muscle while suppressing endogenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> production and lipolysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Because type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is characterized by diminished rates of insulin-stimulated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> uptake as well as increased basal rates of endogenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> production and lipolysis, these results suggest that AICAR-related compounds may represent a new class of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> agents </plain></SENT>
</text></document>