<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: This study compared the effects of nateglinide, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi>, and placebo on postmeal <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> excursions and insulin secretion in previously diet-treated patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled multicenter study was conducted in 152 patients who received either nateglinide (120 mg before three meals daily, n = 51), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> (5 mg q.d. titrated to 10 mg q.d. after 2 weeks, n = 50), or placebo (n = 51) for 8 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> profiles during liquid meal challenges were measured at weeks 0 and 8 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>At weeks -1 and 7, 19-point daytime <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and insulin profiles, comprising three solid meals, were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: During the liquid-meal challenge, nateglinide reduced the incremental <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> area under the curve (AUC) more effectively than <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> ( = -4.94 vs. -2.71 mmol. h/l, P &lt; 0.05), whereas <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> reduced fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> more effectively than nateglinide ( = -2.9 vs. -1.0 mmol/l, respectively, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In contrast, C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> induced by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> was greater than that induced by nateglinide ( = +1.83 vs. +0.95 nmol. h/l, P &lt; 0.01), and only <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> increased fasting insulin levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>During the solid meal challenges, nateglinide and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> elicited similar overall <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control ( 12-h incremental AUC = -13.2 vs. -15.3 mmol. h/l), but the insulin AUC induced by nateglinide was significantly less than that induced by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> ( 12-h AUC = +866 vs. +1,702 pmol. h/l, P = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This study demonstrated that nateglinide selectively enhanced early insulin release and provided better mealtime <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control with less total insulin exposure than <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>