<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Physical activity and insulin sensitivity are related in epidemiological studies, but the consistency of this finding among populations that greatly differ in body size is uncertain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The present multiethnic epidemiological study examined whether physical activity was related to insulin concentrations in two populations at high risk for <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> that greatly differ by location, ethnic group, and BMI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: The study populations consisted of 2,321 nondiabetic Pima Indian men and women aged 15-59 years from Arizona and 2,716 nondiabetic men and women aged 35-54 years from Mauritius </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Insulin sensitivity was estimated by mean insulin concentration (average of the fasting and postload insulin), and total (i.e., leisure and occupational) physical activity was assessed by questionnaire </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Pima men and women who were more active had significantly (P &lt; 0.05) lower mean insulin concentrations than those less active (BMI and age-adjusted means were 179 vs. 200 and 237 vs. 268 pmol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Similar findings were noted in Mauritian men and women (94 vs. 122 and 127 vs. 148 pmol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In both populations, activity remained significantly associated with mean insulin concentration controlled for age, BMI, waist-to-thigh or waist-to-hip ratio, and mean <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentrations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Physical activity was negatively associated with insulin concentrations both in the Pima Indians, who tend to be overweight, and in Mauritians, who are leaner </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>These findings suggest a beneficial role of activity on insulin sensitivity that is separate from any influence of activity on body composition </plain></SENT>
</text></document>