<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The homeodomain transcription factor IPF1/PDX1 is required in beta-cells for efficient expression of insulin, <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> transporter 2, and prohormone convertases 1/3 and 2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Psammomys obesus, a model of diet-responsive type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, shows markedly depleted insulin stores when given a high-energy (HE) diet </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Despite <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo>, insulin <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> levels initially remained unchanged and then decreased gradually to 15% of the basal level by 3 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Moreover, insulin gene expression was not increased when isolated P. obesus islets were exposed to elevated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentrations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Consistent with these observations, no functional Ipf1/Pdx1 gene product was detected in islets of newborn or adult P. obesus using immunostaining, Western blot, DNA binding, and reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction analyses </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Other beta-cell transcription factors (e.g., ISL-1, Nkx2.2, and Nkx6.1) were expressed in P. obesus islets, and the DNA binding activity of the insulin transcription factors RIPE3b1-Act and IEF1 was intact </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Ipf1/Pdx1 gene transfer to isolated P. obesus islets normalized the defect in <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-stimulated insulin gene expression and prevented the rapid <z:mpath ids='MPATH_63'>depletion</z:mpath> of insulin content after exposure to high <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Taken together, these results suggest that the inability of P. obesus islets to adapt to dietary overload, with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_63'>depletion</z:mpath> of insulin content as a consequence, results from IPF1/PDX1 deficiency </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, because not <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> animals become hyperglycemic on HE diet, additional factors may be important for the development of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in this animal model </plain></SENT>
</text></document>