<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To compare prescribing, dosage and blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in two communities with differences in anti-hyperglycaemic drug utilization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A retrospective longitudinal (1984-1994) population-based study in two neighbour towns in southern Sweden </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The mean prescribed daily dose was expressed as a fraction of the Defined Daily Dose (<z:chebi fb="12" ids="27841">DDD</z:chebi>) for each drug </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In town A, prescribing of oral agents and insulin was predominantly made by one specialized <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> clinician, while in town B it was spread among several different general practitioners and one specialist </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Altogether 44 636 medical visits by 2348 patients were identified </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In each town, about 40% of the patients were treated without anti-hyperglycaemic drugs, about 40% with oral agents and about 20% with insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, there were pronounced between-town differences in dosage and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The mean prescribed daily dose of sulphonylurea monotherapy decreased gradually from approximately 0.7 to approximately 0.5 DDD in town B but remained approximately 0.8 DDD in town A </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The proportion of patients on both sulphonylurea and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> increased substantially in town A but not in town B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In these patients, the mean prescribed daily dose of sulphonylurea exceeded 1.0 DDD in both towns, although it decreased with time in town B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The mean prescribed daily dose of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020459" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">insulin increased</z:e> from 1.05 to 1.2 DDD in town A but remained virtually unchanged at 0.95 DDD in town B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The mean fasting blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> was lower in town A than in town B both overall (7.7 vs. 8.8 mmol/l), in those treated without any anti-hyperglycaemic drugs (7.2 vs. 8.1 mmol/l), in those on sulphonylurea monotherapy (8.3 vs. 9.7 mmol/l) and in those treated with insulin (8.1 vs. 10.2 mmol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi> control in routine care was better when most patients were treated by a <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> specialist and were exposed to more intense pharmacotherapy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>