<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine whether adults diagnosed with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> at 18-44 years of age (early type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>) have different metabolic profiles at diagnosis than adults diagnosed at &gt; or =45 years of age (usual type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Within a health maintenance organization, we studied characteristics among 2,437 adults newly diagnosed with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> between 1996 and 1998 who had measured weight, HbA(1c), blood pressure, and cholesterol within 3 months of diagnosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We abstracted clinical data from electronic medical records </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We compared mean and proportional differences with parametric t tests and chi(2) analyses, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We used multiple logistic regression to identify the factors independently associated with the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> group (early vs. usual type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There was an inverse linear relationship between BMI and age at diagnosis of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>On univariate analysis, adults with early type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were more <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> (BMI 39 vs. 33 kg/m(2), P &lt; 0.001), were more likely to be female (P = 0.04), had slightly worse glycemic control (HbA(1c) 7.7 vs. 7.5%, P = 0.03), had a higher prevalence of diastolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (37 vs. 26%, P &lt; 0.001), despite a lower prevalence of systolic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (34 vs. 55%, P &lt; 0.001), and had an equally high rate of abnormal <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> (82 vs. 78%, P = 0.13) than adults with usual type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>BMI, female gender, cholesterol, and diastolic and systolic blood pressure remained independently associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> group at multivariate analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Although both <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> groups were on average <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp>, the inverse linear relationship of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> and age of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> that we observed suggests that <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> is a continuous risk rather than a threshold risk for <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Both <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> groups had a high prevalence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> risk factors </plain></SENT>
</text></document>