<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To study the prevalence of <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> (MA) in African-American women with a history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0009800'>gestational diabetes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GDM</z:e>) who are at high risk for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000082'>renal dysfunction</z:hpo> and to study MA's relation to <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: MA was assessed using 24-h, timed, and/or random urine samples in a cross-sectional sample (n = 289) from a cohort of African-American women with a history of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GDM</z:e> and followed for a median of 11 years (range 3.0-18.4) since their diabetic pregnancy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Subjects with a urine albumin excretion rate of 30-300 g/24 h or 30-300 microg/mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> in a random sample were classified as having MA if two of three samples over a 3- to 6-month period were positive </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>These women were evaluated for family history of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, smoking and alcohol use, BMI, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>, and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> abnormalities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Insulin sensitivity was determined using the homeostasis model assessment (HOMA) estimates, which used fasting insulin and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> measurements obtained at the same time as the MA urine sample </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: At MA assessment, the women ranged in age from 22 to 57 years, with a median of 39 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The overall prevalence of MA was 20%; 36% in those with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Those women with MA had higher rates of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (63.8 vs. 28.6%, odds ratio [OR] = 4.4, P &lt; 0.05), <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (82.8 vs. 42.9%, OR = 6.4, P &lt; 0.05), and family history of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (85.7 vs. 61.7%, OR = 3.7, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The proportion of subjects with MA with a family history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> was nonsignificantly increased (92.9 vs. 82.4%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Subjects with MA were more <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> (BMI 37.2 +/- 8.9 vs. 34.4 +/- 8.6 kg/m(2)) and had higher levels of HbA(1c) (8.8 +/- 3.3 vs. 6.6 +/- 1.8%, P &lt; 0.001) and systolic (144.3 +/- 25.9 vs. 122.8 +/- 17.2 mmHg, P &lt; 0.0001) and diastolic (95.1 +/- 15.4 vs. 82.5 +/- 11.9 mmHg, P &lt; 0.0001) blood pressures </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">Lipid</z:chebi> fractions were similar in those with and without MA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Although fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> was much higher in subjects with MA (10.3 +/- 5.8 vs. 7.1 +/- 4.2 mmol/l, P = 0.0002), insulin levels were not significantly higher in subjects with MA (17.4 +/- 21.2 vs. 15.2 +/- 12.4 pmol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Insulin sensitivity, as measured using log HOMA, was similar (1.5 +/- 0.6 vs. 1.6 +/- 0.6) in women with and without MA, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Multivariable logistic regression analyses indicated that HbA(1c), OR = 1.16 (1.07, 1.27), and systolic blood pressure, OR = 1.27 (1.14, 1.41), were independent risk factors for MA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>In those with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the subjects with MA had higher rates of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>-83.8 vs. 56.1%, OR = 4.1 (1.5, 11.10)-which was reflected by their higher systolic and diastolic blood pressures, 146.1 mmHg (P = 0.001) and 94.8 mmHg (P = 0.002), respectively, and lower levels of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="39027">VLDL</z:chebi> (0.45 +/- 0.22 vs. 0.61 +/- 0.33 mmol/l, P = 0.021) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>In the multivariable analyses of those with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the two independent risk factors for MA were similar: HbA(1c), OR = 1.13 (1.01, 1.28), and systolic blood pressure, OR = 1.21 (1.04, 1.41) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: African-American women with a history of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GDM</z:e> have one of the highest rates for MA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>Presence of MA was not associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> but was significantly independently associated with HbA(1c) levels and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>These results, taken in context of the literature, suggest that <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>glucose intolerance</z:hpo>, in part, influence MA through different mechanisms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="19" pm="."><plain>Because of the high prevalence of MA in this population and MA's relation to <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-cause and cardiovascular mortality, screening for MA should be considered </plain></SENT>
</text></document>