<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Although it is accepted that elevated plasma <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">homocysteine</z:chebi> (tHcy) levels occur in <z:hpo ids='HP_0003774'>end-stage renal disease</z:hpo> and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the changes with milder <z:hpo ids='HP_0000082'>renal dysfunction</z:hpo> (e.g., <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp>) are less clearly established </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study explores the relationship among tHcy, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> clearance (Ccr), and albumin excretion rate (AER) in a population with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A total of 260 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were screened in our outpatient clinic during 10 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Fasting blood samples were collected, and AER was calculated from an overnight timed urine sample </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Ccr was calculated using the Cockroft-Gault formula </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 198 subjects (76%) had normoalbuminuria (&lt;20 microg/min), 50 subjects (19%) had <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> (20-200 microg/min), and 12 subjects (5%) had macroalbuminuria (&gt;or=200 microg/min) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Those with <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> had higher levels of tHcy than those with normoalbuminuria (13.2 +/- 7.8 vs. 11.3 +/- 4.6 micromol/l, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients were then subdivided based on low Ccr (&lt;80 ml x min(-1) x 1.73 m(-2)) and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> Ccr (&gt;or=80 x min(-1) x 1.73 m(-2)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>None of the patients with macroalbuminuria had <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> Ccr </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In those with normoalbuminuria, tHcy levels were higher than in those with low Ccr than in those with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> Ccr (12.0 +/- 4.6 vs. 10.0 +/- 4.4 micromol/l, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The same was found for those with <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> (low Ccr versus <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> Ccr: 14.6 +/- 9.0 vs. 10.2 +/- 2.8 micromol/l, P &lt; 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>For <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> Ccr, tHcy was similar irrespective of AER (normoalbuminuria versus <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp>: 10.0 +/- 4.4 vs. 10.2 +/- 2.8 micromol/l, NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>For low Ccr, tHcy was higher in those with <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> versus normoalbuminuria (14.6 +/- 9.0 vs. 12.0 +/- 4.6 micromol/l, P = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Using multivariate regression, Ccr, but neither AER nor the presence of <z:mp ids='MP_0002871'>albuminuria</z:mp>, was an independent predictor of tHcy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These data strongly suggest that in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the relationship between plasma tHcy and AER is largely due to associated changes in renal function, as defined by Ccr </plain></SENT>
</text></document>