<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>To examine whether and how intramyocellular <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> (IMCL) content contributes to interindividual variation in insulin action, we studied 20 healthy men with no family history of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>IMCL was measured as the resonance of intramyocellular CH(2) protons in <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi>/resonance of CH(3) protons of total <z:chebi fb="2" ids="16919">creatine</z:chebi> (IMCL/Cr(T)), using proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy in vastus lateralis muscle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Whole-body insulin sensitivity was measured using a 120-min euglycemic-hyperinsulinemic (insulin infusion rate 40 mU/m(2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>min) clamp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Muscle biopsies of the vastus lateralis muscle were taken before and 30 min after initiation of the insulin infusion to assess insulin signaling </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The subjects were divided into groups with high IMCL (HiIMCL; 9.5 +/- 0.9 IMCL/Cr(T), n = 10) and low IMCL (LoIMCL; 3.0 +/- 0.5 IMCL/Cr(T), n = 10), the cut point being median IMCL (6.1 IMCL/Cr(T)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The groups were comparable with respect to age (43 +/- 3 vs. 40 +/- 3 years, NS, HiIMCL versus LoIMCL), BMI (26 +/- 1 vs. 26 +/- 1 kg/m(2), NS), and maximal oxygen consumption (33 +/- 2 vs. 36 +/- 3 ml </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>kg(-1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>min(-1), NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Whole-body insulin-stimulated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> uptake was lower in the HiIMCL group (3.0 +/- 0.4 mg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>kg(-1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>min(-1)) than the LoIMCL group (5.1 +/- 0.5 mg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>kg(-1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>min(-1), P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Serum free fatty acid concentrations were comparable basally, but during <z:hpo ids='HP_0000842'>hyperinsulinemia</z:hpo>, they were 35% higher in the HiIMCL group than the LoIMCL group (P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Study of insulin signaling indicated that insulin-induced tyrosine phosphorylation of the insulin receptor (IR) was blunted in HiIMCL compared with LoIMCL (57 vs. 142% above basal, P &lt; 0.05), while protein expression of the IR was unaltered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>IR substrate-1-associated phosphatidylinositol (PI) 3-kinase activation by insulin was also lower in the HiIMCL group than in the LoIMCL group (49 +/- 23 vs. 84 +/- 27% above basal, P &lt; 0.05 between HiIMCL and LoIMCL) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, IMCL accumulation is associated with whole-body <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> and with defective insulin signaling in skeletal muscle independent of body weight and physical fitness </plain></SENT>
</text></document>