<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to investigate to what extent disturbances in fatty acid metabolism found in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> are already present in subjects at high risk for developing <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (i.e., <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo> [IGT]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Components of fatty acid metabolism were measured in male subjects with IGT during postabsorptive conditions and during 60 min of exercise (50% VO(2max)) with the use of the stable isotope tracer [U-(13)C]<z:chebi fb="2" ids="29889">palmitate</z:chebi> in combination with indirect calorimetry, and those values were compared with previously published findings in male type 2 diabetic and male <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>No differences were found between groups in energy expenditure and in total fat and carbohydrate oxidation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Rate of appearance and rate of disappearance of plasma free fatty acid (FFA) were lower in subjects with IGT and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> compared with <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Plasma FFA oxidation was lower in subjects with IGT and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> compared with <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects at rest and tended to be lower during exercise (rest: 3.7 +/- 0.3, 4.4 +/- 0.6, and 6.9 +/- 1.0 micromol. kg fat-free mass [FFM](-1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>min(-1), P &lt; 0.01; exercise: 15.0 +/- 1.7, 14.1 +/- 1.9, and 19.6 +/- 1.5 micromol. kg FFM(-1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>min(-1) for IGT, type 2 diabetic, and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects, respectively, P = 0.07) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">Triglyceride</z:chebi>-derived fatty acid oxidation, however, was elevated in subjects with IGT and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> during exercise (3.6 +/- 1.4, 1.4 +/- 1.4, and -4.0 +/- 2.0 micromol. kg FFM(-1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>min(-1) for IGT, type 2 diabetic, and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects, respectively; P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These data demonstrate that male subjects with a <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0362046" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">prediabetic</z:e> condition (IGT) have the same defects in fatty acid utilization as subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, suggesting that these disturbances may play an important role in the progression from IGT to type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>