<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Current incidence trends in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> portend a significant public health burden and have largely been attributed to similar trends in overweight and physical inactivity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Medical surveillance of the U.S. military indicates that the incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> types of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is similar to that in the civilian population (1.9 vs. 1.6 cases per 1,000 person-years) despite weight and fitness standards </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Differences in the common determinants of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> have not been studied in the military population, which may provide novel clues to the increasing incidence of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in the U.S </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A case-control study, 4-to-1 matched for age, sex, entry date, time in service, and service component (e.g., Army, Navy), was used to describe the association of race/ethnicity, socioeconomic status, and BMI and blood pressure at entry into military service with the subsequent development of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:mp ids='MP_0006087'>Increased BMI</z:mp> (adjusted odds ratio, 3.0 for the &gt; or =30 kg/m(2) vs. &lt; or =20 kg/m(2) categories and 2.0 for the 25.0-29.9 kg/m(2) category, compared with the reference category), African-American (adjusted odds ratio, 2.0) and Hispanic origin (adjusted odds ratio, 1.6) compared with white race and rank (adjusted odds ratio for junior enlisted versus officers, 4.1) were <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> associated with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Individuals with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in the U.S. military have risk factors similar to the general U.S. population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Because <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is a preventable disease, it is of concern that it is occurring in this population of younger and presumably more fit individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>This has significant implications for the prevention of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in both military and civilian populations </plain></SENT>
</text></document>