<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Seven hundred and sixteen randomly selected, unrelated patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were screened for mutations using a PCR-RFLP technique to assess the prevalence of the A-G mutation at position 3243 of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> (mt) tRNAleu(UUR) gene in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in the Chinese population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Three individuals with this mutation were identified, representing approximately 0.4% of the type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> patients screened </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Further screening of the first-degree relatives of these three patients identified another four affected carriers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In comparison with type 2 diabetic patients without the mutation, these seven carriers of the mt 3243 mutation had; (1) had an earlier <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (38.0+/-10.1 vs. 53.4+/-10.0 year, P&lt;0.001); (2) a lower body mass index (BMI) (19.5+/-2.0 vs. 24.9+/-10.9, P&lt;0.0001); and (3) and lower post-challenge insulin levels (area under the curve of insulin levels during the OGTT, 2946+/-1647.2 vs. 7469+/-6647.7, P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In addition, the same 716 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, as well as 181 controls with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance, were screened for a newly described mt 3316 G-A mutation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This mutation was found in 16 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (2.2%) and five controls (2.7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Therefore, the frequency of the mutation was not significantly different in the patients and controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Moreover, the clinical characteristics such as the age of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the BMI, and insulin levels were not significantly different between the diabetic patients with the mt 3316 G-A mutation and those without </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This shows that the mt 3316 G-A mutation is a polymorphism unrelated to <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>