<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to understand by which intrahepatic mechanism <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (Met) may inhibit basal hepatic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> production (HGP) in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We studied rats that were fed for 6 weeks a high-fat (HF) diet, supplemented (HF-Met) or not (HF) with Met (50 mg x kg(-1) x day(-1)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Basal HGP, assessed by 3-[(3)H]<z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tracer dilution, was lower by 20% in HF-Met rats compared with HF-rats: 41.6 +/- 0.7 vs. 52 +/- 1.5 micromol x kg(-1) x min(-1) (means +/- SE, n = 5; P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi>-6 phosphatase (Glc6Pase) activity, assayed in a liver lobe freeze-clamped in situ, was lower by 25% in HF-Met rats compared with HF-rats (7.9 +/- 0.4 vs. 10.3 +/- 0.9 micromol x min(-1) x g(-1) wet liver; P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi>-6 phosphate and <z:chebi fb="15" ids="28087">glycogen</z:chebi> contents, e.g., 42 +/- 5 nmol/g and 3.9 +/- 2.4 mg/g, respectively, in HF-rats were dramatically increased by three to five times in HF-Met rats, e.g., 118 +/- 12 nmol/g and 19.6 +/- 4.6 mg/g (P &lt; 0.05 and P &lt; 0.01, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi>-6 phosphate dehydrogenase activity was increased in HF-Met compared with HF rats (1.51 +/- 0.1 vs. 1.06 +/- 0.08 micromol x min(-1) x g(-1); P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Intrahepatic <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> concentration tended to be lower in the Met-group (-30%; NS), whereas plasma <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> concentration was higher in HF-Met rats (1.59 +/- 0.15 mmol/l) than in HF rats (1.06 +/- 0.06 mmol/l; P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>We concluded that Met decreases HGP in insulin-resistant HF-fed rats mainly by an inhibition of hepatic Glc6Pase activity, promoting <z:chebi fb="15" ids="28087">glycogen</z:chebi> sparing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Additional mechanisms might involve the diversion of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-6 phosphate into the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25901">pentose</z:chebi> phosphate pathway and an inhibition of hepatic <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> uptake </plain></SENT>
</text></document>