<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">Metformin</z:chebi> is the most commonly prescribed oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> agent in the U.S. for adults with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The incidence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in children has increased dramatically over the past 10 years, and yet, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> has never been formally studied in children with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This study evaluated the safety and efficacy of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> at doses up to 1,000 mg twice daily in 82 subjects aged 10-16 years for up to 16 weeks in a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial from September 1998 to November 1999 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were enrolled if they had a fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) levels &gt; or =7.0 and &lt; or =13.3 mmol/l (&gt; or =126 and &lt; or =240 mg/dl), HbA(1c) &gt; or =7.0%, stimulated C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> &gt; or =0.5 nmol/l (&gt; or =1.5 ng/ml), and a BMI &gt; 50th percentile for age </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">Metformin</z:chebi> significantly improved glycemic control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>At the last double-blind visit, the adjusted mean change from baseline in FPG was -2.4 mmol/l (-42.9 mg/dl) for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> compared with +1.2 mmol/l (+21.4 mg/dl) for placebo (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Mean HbA(1c) values, adjusted for baseline levels, were also significantly lower for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> compared with placebo (7.5 vs. 8.6%, respectively; P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Improvement in FPG was seen in both sexes and in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> race subgroups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">Metformin</z:chebi> did not have a negative impact on body weight or <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Adverse events were similar to those reported in adults treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">Metformin</z:chebi> was shown to be safe and effective for treatment of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in pediatric patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>