<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine whether first-degree relatives of individuals with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, who are at high risk of subsequently developing <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo>, manifest alterations in beta-cell function including an alteration in the co-release of insulin and amylin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In 30 first-degree relatives and 24 matched subjects with no family history of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, beta-cell function was measured as the intravenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> insulin response (AIR(g)) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> amylin response (AAR(g)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The insulin sensitivity index (S(I)) was quantified and used to account for the role of insulin sensitivity to modulate beta-cell function (S(I) x beta-cell function) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (5.3 +/- 0.1 vs. 5.1 +/- 0.1 mmol/l; means +/- <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SEM</z:e>), immunoreactive insulin (IRI) (68 +/- 7 vs. 57 +/- 6 pmol/l) and amylin-like immunoreactivity (ALI) (5.5 +/- 0.6 vs. 4.7 +/- 0.7 pmol/l) were similar in relatives and control subjects, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Relatives were insulin resistant compared with control subjects (S(I): 4.86 +/- 0.63 vs. 7.20 +/- 0.78 x 10(-5) min(-1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>pmol(-1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>l(-1), P = 0.01), but their AIR(g) (392 +/- 59 vs. 386 +/- 50 pmol/l) and AAR(g) (5.9 +/- 0.9 vs. 6.1 +/- 0.8 pmol/l) did not differ </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>When beta-cell function was determined relative to insulin sensitivity, in the first-degree relatives, both AIR(g) (S(I) x AIR(g): 1.60 +/- 0.23 vs. 2.44 +/- 0.31 x 10(-2) min(-1), P &lt; 0.05) and AAR(g) (S(I) x AAR(g): 2.39 +/- 0.35 vs. 4.06 +/- 0.56 x 10(-4) min(-1), P &lt; 0.05) were reduced </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The molar proportion of ALI to IRI was not altered in high-risk subjects (1.75 +/- 0.16 vs. 1.71 +/- 0.15%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: First-degree relatives of subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> have diminished beta-cell function at a time when they are not hyperglycemic, and this reduction affects insulin and amylin responses proportionally </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Thus, an altered amylin-to-insulin ratio is not likely to identify individuals at high risk of developing type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>