<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We developed a mathematical model of the <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control of insulin secretion capable of quantifying beta-cell function from a physiological meal test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The model includes a static control, i.e., a secretion component that is a function of plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentration (the dose-response function), and a dynamic control, i.e., a secretion component that is proportional to the positive values of the <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentration derivative </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, the dose-response function is assumed to be modulated by a time-varying potentiation factor </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>To test the model, nine nondiabetic control subjects and nine type 2 diabetic patients received three standardized mixed meals over a period of 14-15 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Blood samples were drawn for the measurement of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> concentration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The dose-response function, the parameter of the dynamic control, and the potentiation factor were determined by fitting the model to <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> concentrations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In diabetic patients, the dose-response function was shifted to the right (<z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentration at a reference insulin secretion of 300 pmol.min(-1).m(-2) was 11.7 +/- 1.1 vs. 7.2 +/- 0.7 mmol/l; P &lt; 0.05), and decreased in slope (53 +/- 15 vs. 148 +/- 38 pmol.min(-1).m(-2).mmol(-1).l; P &lt; 0.05) and the parameter of the dynamic control was decreased (220 +/- 67 vs. 908 +/- 276 pmol.m(-2).mmol(-1).l; P &lt; 0.05) compared with the nondiabetic control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, potentiation was markedly blunted and delayed: maximum potentiation was observed at the first meal in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> subjects and at the second meal (about 4 h later) in diabetic subjects; the mean time for the potentiation factor was higher (7.1 +/- 0.2 vs. 5.9 +/- 0.2 h; P &lt; 0.01), and the size of potentiation was reduced (2.6 +/- 0.5 vs. 7.2 +/- 1.5 fold increase; P &lt; 0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, our model of insulin secretion extracts multiple indexes of beta-cell function from a physiological meal test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Use of the model in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> retrieves known defects in insulin secretion but also uncovers new facets of <z:hpo ids='HP_0006279'>beta-cell dysfunction</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>