<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To compare the prevalence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and features of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> among Filipina and Caucasian women in San Diego County, California </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Data on several <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> diseases were collected between 1992 and 1999 from community-dwelling Filipina (n=294) and Caucasian (n=379) women aged 50-69 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Filipina and Caucasian women did not differ in mean age (59.7 vs. 60 years, respectively), BMI (25.6 vs. 25.4 kg/m(2)), percentage of body fat (33.5 vs. 34.2%), or waist-to-hip ratio (0.84 vs. 0.83), although Filipinas had larger waist circumferences and higher percentages of truncal fat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Compared with Caucasians, Filipinas were less likely to be <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> (BMI &gt; or = 30 kg/m(2), 8.8 vs. 14%, P=0.04) and less likely to smoke, consume alcohol, or take postmenopausal <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50114">estrogen</z:chebi>; Filipinas also had lower levels of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Compared with Caucasians, Filipinas had higher prevalence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> by oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test criteria (36 vs. 9%) and the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> (34 vs. 13%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>These differences persisted after adjusting for age, body size, fat distribution, percentage of body fat, smoking, alcohol consumption, exercise, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50114">estrogen</z:chebi> therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A total of 10% of Filipinas with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp>, compared with one third of Caucasians with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The finding of a high prevalence of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in an unstudied nonobese ethnic group reinforces the importance of expanding the study of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> to diverse populations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The high prevalence of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in populations who are not of Northern European ancestry may be missed when they are not <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> by Western standards </plain></SENT>
</text></document>