<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To examine the effects of improved glycaemic control over 20 weeks on the type and distribution of weight change in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who at baseline have poor glycaemic control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Forty-three patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and HbA1c &gt; 8.9% were randomised to either intensive glycaemic control (IC) n = 21 or usual glycaemic control (UC) n = 22 for 20 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Dual energy X-ray absorptiometry was used to assess the type and distribution of weight change during the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: After 20 weeks HbA1c was significantly lower in patients randomised to IC than UC (HbA1c IC 8.02 +/- 0.25% vs. UC 10.23 +/- 0.23%, p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In the IC group weight increased by 3.2 +/- 0.8 kg after 20 weeks (fat-free mass increased by 1.8 +/- 0.3 kg) compared to 0.02 +/- 0.70 kg in UC (p = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The gain in total body fat mass comprised trunk fat mass (IC 0.94 +/- 0.5 kg vs. UC 0.04 +/- 0.4 kg, p = 0.18) and peripheral fat mass (total body fat - trunk fat) (IC 0.71 +/- 0.32 kg vs. UC -0.21 +/- 0.28 kg, p = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Blood pressure and serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> concentrations did not change over time in either group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Intensive glycaemic control was associated with <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> which was distributed in similar proportions between the central and peripheral regions and consisted of similar proportions of fat and fat-free mass </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Blood pressure and serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> concentrations were not adversely affected </plain></SENT>
</text></document>