<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Elevated serum levels of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo>-phase proteins, indicating <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> subclinical <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, have been associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> as well as the <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> syndrome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>Chronic</z:hpo> <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> may also be a risk factor for developing type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We studied the concentrations of C-reactive protein (CRP), fibrinogen, and plasminogen activator inhibitor-1 (PAI-1) in 1,047 nondiabetic subjects in relation to incident <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> within 5 years in the <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>Insulin Resistance</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>Atherosclerosis</z:hpo> Study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Subjects with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> at follow-up (n = 144) had higher baseline levels of fibrinogen (mean +/- SD; 287.8 +/- 58.8 vs. 275.1 +/- 56.0 mg/dl; P = 0.013) as well as of CRP (median [interquartile range]; 2.40 [1.29, 5.87] vs. 1.67 mg/l [0.75, 3.41]; P = 0.0001) and PAI-1 (24 [15, 37.5] vs. 16 ng/ml [9, 27]; P = 0.0001) than nonconverters </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The odds ratio (OR) of converting to <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was significantly increased with increasing baseline concentrations of the inflammatory markers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In contrast to PAI-1, the association of CRP and fibrinogen with incident <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was significantly attenuated after adjustment for body fat (BMI or waist circumference) or insulin sensitivity (S(I)), as assessed by a frequently sampled intravenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In a logistic regression model that included age, sex, ethnicity, clinical center, smoking, BMI, S(I), physical activity, and family history of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, PAI-1 still remained significantly related to incident type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (OR [95% CI] for 1 SD increase: 1.61 [1.20-2.16]; P = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>Chronic</z:hpo> <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> emerges as a new risk factor for the development of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>; PAI-1 predicts type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> independent of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> and other known risk factors for <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>