<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>Oxidative stress</z:mp> has been ascribed a role in the pathogenesis of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and its complications, and stress proteins have been shown to protect organisms in vitro and in vivo against <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To study the putative role of one of the most abundant cytoprotective stress proteins, inducible cytoplasmic 72-kDa-mass heat shock protein (Hsp-72), in the pathogenesis of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, we measured its <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> concentration in muscle biopsies from six type 2 diabetic patients and six healthy control subjects (protocol 1) as well as in 12 twin pairs discordant for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and 12 control subjects undergoing a euglycemic-hyperinsulinemic clamp in combination with indirect calorimetry (protocol 2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The amount of Hsp-72 mRNA in muscle was significantly lower in type 2 diabetic patients than in healthy control subjects (in protocol 1: 5.2 +/- 2.2 vs. 53 +/- 32 million copies of Hsp-72 mRNA/microg total <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi>, n = 6, P = 0.0039; in protocol 2: 3.2 +/- 3.3 vs. 43 +/- 31 million copies of Hsp-72 mRNA/microg total <z:chebi fb="40" ids="33697">RNA</z:chebi>, n = 12, P = 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Hsp-72 mRNA levels were also markedly reduced in the nondiabetic co-twins compared with healthy control subjects (5.8 +/- 5.0 vs. 43 +/- 31, n = 12, P = 0.0001), but they were also statistically significantly different from their diabetic co-twins when the difference between the pairs was compared (P = 0.0280) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Heat shock protein <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> content in muscle of examined patients correlated with the rate of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> uptake and other measures of insulin-stimulated carbohydrate and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> metabolism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, the finding of decreased levels of Hsp-72 mRNA in skeletal muscle of patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and its relationship with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> raises the question of whether heat shock proteins are involved in the pathogenesis of skeletal muscle <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>