<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Combination therapy of oral hypoglycaemic agents and insulin is a therapeutic option for those who have deterioration in glycaemic control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We examined the contribution of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> by withdrawing it from Type 2 diabetic patients who had been stabilised on combination therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Fifty-one subjects with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and secondary oral hypoglycaemic agent failure were studied in a randomised, open and parallel study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the first phase of 36 weeks, subjects were stabilised on combined therapy of sulphonylureas and nocturnal insulin, with or without <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>During the second phase, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> was withdrawn </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The primary variables for efficacy were HbA(1c), fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and 3-point capillary blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> profiles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>After stabilisation with combination therapy, those subjects on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> used less insulin to maintain glycaemic control (13.7+/-6.8 vs. 23.0+/-9.4 U/day, P=0.001) and had lower HbA(1c) values (8.13+/-0.89 vs. 9.05+/-1.30%, P=0.003) compared with those not given <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Withdrawal of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> therapy caused deterioration in HbA(1c) (P=0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This study confirms that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> plays an important role in the success of the combination therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The rational use of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> and sulphonylurea together with insulin will help to improve metabolic control in Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> patients who have secondary drug failure </plain></SENT>
</text></document>