<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We investigated whether the effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">troglitazone</z:chebi> on <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal is associated with altered insulin signaling </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Nondiabetic first-degree relatives of type 2 diabetic patients (age 30 +/- 2 years, BMI 30 +/- 1 kg/m(2); n = 20) were randomized in a double-blind manner to 3 months of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">troglitazone</z:chebi> (200 mg/day) or placebo treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Before and after treatment, 3-h euglycemic-hyperinsulinemic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> clamps (40 mU </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>m(-2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>min(-1)) were performed, and muscle biopsies were obtained immediately before and after the clamps </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In the biopsies, insulin receptor kinase (IRK) activity, insulin receptor substrate (IRS)-1-associated phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase (PI3K) activity, Ser(473) and Thr(308) phosphorylation of protein kinase B (PKB), and protein expression of IRS-1, IRS-2, phosphoinositol-dependent kinase-1 (PDK-1), PKB, and GLUT-4 were determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>After <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">troglitazone</z:chebi> treatment, insulin-stimulated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal was increased compared with pretreatment and placebo (279 +/- 37 vs. 211 +/- 26 and 200 +/- 25 mg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>m(-2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>min(-1); both P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>IRK and PI3K activities were not altered by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">troglitazone</z:chebi>, but PKB Ser(473) phosphorylation was enhanced compared with pretreatment and placebo at the clamp insulin level (138 +/- 36 vs. 77 +/- 16 and 55 +/- 13 internal standard units; both P &lt; 0.05) and with pretreatment at the basal level (31 +/- 9 vs. 14 +/- 4 internal standard units; P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>PKB Thr(308) phosphorylation also tended to be higher, but this was not statistically significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9753">Troglitazone</z:chebi> did not alter insulin receptor number or IRS-1, IRS-2, PKB, PDK-1, or GLUT-4 protein expression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>We conclude that increased PKB phosphorylation may contribute to the insulin-sensitizing effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50864">thiazolidinediones</z:chebi> in human skeletal muscle </plain></SENT>
</text></document>