<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To examine the effect of high-intensity progressive resistance training combined with moderate <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> on glycemic control and body composition in older patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Sedentary, overweight men and women with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, aged 60-80 years (n = 36), were randomized to high-intensity progressive resistance training plus moderate <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> (RT &amp; WL group) or moderate <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> plus a control program (WL group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Clinical and laboratory measurements were assessed at 0, 3, and 6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: HbA(1c) fell significantly more in RT &amp; WL than WL at 3 months (0.6 +/- 0.7 vs. 0.07 +/- 0.8%, P &lt; 0.05) and 6 months (1.2 +/- 1.0 vs. 0.4 +/- 0.8%, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Similar reductions in body weight (RT &amp; WL 2.5 +/- 2.9 vs. WL 3.1 +/- 2.1 kg) and fat mass (RT &amp; WL 2.4 +/- 2.7 vs. WL 2.7 +/- 2.5 kg) were observed after 6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In contrast, lean body mass (LBM) increased in the RT &amp; WL group (0.5 +/- 1.1 kg) and decreased in the WL group (0.4 +/- 1.0) after 6 months (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were no between-group differences for fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="2" ids="6495">lipoproteins</z:chebi>, or resting blood pressure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: High-intensity progressive resistance training, in combination with moderate <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo>, was effective in improving glycemic control in older patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Additional benefits of improved muscular strength and LBM identify high-intensity resistance training as a feasible and effective component in the management program for older patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>