<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the metabolic effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, as compared with placebo, in type 2 diabetic patients intensively treated with insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">Metformin</z:chebi> improves glycemic control in poorly controlled type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Its effect in type 2 diabetic patients who are intensively treated with insulin has not been studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A total of 390 patients whose type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was controlled with insulin therapy completed a randomized controlled double-blind trial with a planned interim analysis after 16 weeks of treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The subjects were selected from three outpatient clinics in regional hospitals and were randomly assigned to either the placebo or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> group, in addition to insulin therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Intensive <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> monitoring with immediate insulin adjustments according to strict guidelines was conducted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Indexes of glycemic control, insulin requirements, body weight, blood pressure, plasma <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi>, hypoglycemic events, and other adverse events were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of the 390 subjects, 37 dropped out (12 in the placebo and 25 in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Of those who completed 16 weeks of treatment, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> use, as compared with placebo, was associated with improved glycemic control (mean daily <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> at 16 weeks 7.8 vs. 8.8 mmol/l, P = 0.006; mean GHb 6.9 vs. 7.6%, P &lt; 0.0001); reduced insulin requirements (63.8 vs. 71.3 IU, P &lt; 0.0001); <z:mp ids='MP_0001262'>reduced weight</z:mp> gain (-0.4 vs. +1.2 kg, P &lt; 0.01); and decreased plasma <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47774">LDL cholesterol</z:chebi> (-0.21 vs. -0.02 mmol/l, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> was similar in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS-In type 2 diabetic patients who are intensively treated with insulin, the combination of insulin and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> results in superior glycemic control compared with insulin therapy alone, while insulin requirements and <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> are less </plain></SENT>
</text></document>