<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: This study was designed to compare the efficacy of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> premeal administration of glipizide versus nateglinide in controlling <z:hpo ids='HP_0011998'>postprandial hyperglycemia</z:hpo> in subjects with non-insulin-requiring type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A total of 20 subjects (10 female, 10 male) with non-insulin-requiring type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were admitted overnight to the General Clinical Research Center on four occasions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In random order, 10 mg glipizide (30 min premeal), 120 mg nateglinide (15 min premeal), 10 mg glipizide plus nateglinide (30 and 15 min premeal, respectively), or placebo pills (30 and 15 min premeal) were administered in a double-blind fashion before a standardized breakfast </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Blood was drawn for analysis of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> at -0.05, 0, 0.5, 1, 2, 3, and 4 h relative to the meal </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The subjects were aged 56 +/- 2 years and were moderately <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> (BMI 31 +/- 1 kg/m(2)), with a mean HbA(1c) of 7.4 +/- 0.4% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The peak postprandial <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> excursion above baseline was higher with placebo (6.1 +/- 0.5 mmol/l) than glipizide (4.3 +/- 0.6 mmol/l, P = 0.002), nateglinide (4.2 +/- 0.4 mmol/l, P = 0.001), or glipizide plus nateglinide (4.1 +/- 0.5 mmol/l, P = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The area under the curve for the <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> excursion above baseline was also higher with placebo (14.1 +/- 1.8 mmol/h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>l) compared with glipizide (6.9 +/- 2.4 mmol/h. l, P = 0.002), nateglinide (9.7 +/- 2 mmol/h. l, P = 0.004), or glipizide plus nateglinide (5.6 +/- 2.2 mmol/h. l, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Peak and integrated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> excursions did not differ significantly between glipizide and nateglinide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, by 4 h postmeal, plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels were significantly higher with nateglinide (9 +/- 0.9 mmol/l) compared with the premeal baseline (7.8 +/- 0.6 mmol/l, P = 0.04) and compared with the 4-h postprandial <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> level after administration of glipizide (7.6 +/- 0.6 mmol/l, P = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Integrated postprandial insulin levels were higher with glipizide (1,556 +/- 349 pmol/h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>l) than nateglinide (1,364 +/- 231 pmol/h. l; P = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Early insulin secretion, as measured by insulin levels at 30 min postmeal, did not differ between glipizide and nateglinide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> premeal administration of nateglinide or glipizide has equal efficacy in controlling postbreakfast <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> when each drug is administered at the optimum time before the meal </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Glipizide causes a more pronounced and sustained postmeal insulin secretory response compared with nateglinide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Glipizide facilitates the return to near-fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels at 4 h postmeal, but with the possible risk of increased frequency of postmeal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> in drug-naive patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>The clinical decision to use glipizide versus nateglinide should be based on factors other than the control of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011998'>postprandial hyperglycemia</z:hpo> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>