<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0339471" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Diabetic maculopathy</z:e> (DMa) is the most prevalent sight-threatening type of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and a leading cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000572'>visual loss</z:hpo> in the western world </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The disease is characterized by hyperpermeability of <z:chebi fb="46" ids="15035">retinal</z:chebi> blood vessels and subsequent formation of hard exudates and macular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo>, the degree of which can be estimated by measurement of <z:chebi fb="46" ids="15035">retinal</z:chebi> thickness </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We examined associations between <z:chebi fb="46" ids="15035">retinal</z:chebi> thickness as evaluated by optical coherence tomography scanning (OCT), glomerular leakage as evaluated by urinary albumin excretion rate (UAE), and general vascular leakage as evaluated by the transcapillary escape rate of albumin (TER(alb)) in type 2 diabetic patients with and without DMa </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In 20 type 2 diabetic patients with DMa and 20 type 2 diabetic patients without <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> matched for age, sex, and duration of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, we performed OCT, fundus photography, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31624">fluorescein</z:chebi> angiography, and 24-h ambulatory blood pressure measurement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>UAE was determined by radioimmunoassay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>TER(alb) was determined as the initial disappearance of intravenously injected (125)I-labeled human serum albumin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0339471" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">diabetic maculopathy</z:e> had higher HbA(1c) (8.5 +/- 1.5 vs. 7.4 +/- 1.2%, P &lt; 0.05) and higher total cholesterol (5.8 +/- 0.7 vs. 5.2 +/- 0.9 mmol/l, P &lt; 0.05) than patients without <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>UAE was higher in the DMa group than in the group with no <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> (9.3 x// 3.1 vs. 3.9 x// 1.9 micro g/min, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was no difference in TER(alb) between the two groups (6.0 +/- 1.6 vs. 6.6 +/- 1.5%, NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In the group with DMa, OCT, TER(alb), and UAE correlated significantly (OCT versus TER(alb): r = 0.55, P &lt; 0.05; OCT versus UAE: r = 0.58, P &lt; 0.01; UAE versus TER(alb): r = 0.81, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Conversely, there were no correlations between these three parameters in the group without <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Macular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo> seems to reflect a generalized vascular leakage in type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>