<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine the efficacy of high-intensity progressive resistance training (PRT) on glycemic control in older adults with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We performed a 16-week randomized controlled trial in 62 Latino older adults (40 women and 22 men; mean +/- SE age 66 +/- 8 years) with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> randomly assigned to supervised PRT or a control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Glycemic control, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> abnormalities, body composition, and muscle <z:chebi fb="15" ids="28087">glycogen</z:chebi> stores were determined before and after the intervention </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Sixteen weeks of PRT (three times per week) resulted in reduced plasma glycosylated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> levels (from 8.7 +/- 0.3 to 7.6 +/- 0.2%), increased muscle <z:chebi fb="15" ids="28087">glycogen</z:chebi> stores (from 60.3 +/- 3.9 to 79.1 +/- 5.0 mmol <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>/kg muscle), and reduced the dose of prescribed <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> medication in 72% of exercisers compared with the control group, P = 0.004-0.05 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Control subjects showed no change in glycosylated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi>, a reduction in muscle <z:chebi fb="15" ids="28087">glycogen</z:chebi> (from 61.4 +/- 7.7 to 47.2 +/- 6.7 mmol <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>/kg muscle), and a 42% increase in <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> medications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>PRT subjects versus control subjects also increased lean mass (+1.2 +/- 0.2 vs. -0.1 +/- 0.1 kg), <z:mp ids='MP_0006264'>reduced systolic blood pressure</z:mp> (-9.7 +/- 1.6 vs. +7.7 +/- 1.9 mmHg), and decreased trunk fat mass (-0.7 +/- 0.1 vs. +0.8 +/- 0.1 kg; P = 0.01-0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: PRT as an adjunct to standard of care is feasible and effective in improving glycemic control and some of the abnormalities associated with the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> among high-risk older adults with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>