<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate the association between the C242T polymorphism of the p22 phox gene, an essential component of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="13392">NAD(P)H</z:chebi> oxidase in the vasculature, with intima-media thickness (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e>) of the carotid artery and risk factors for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> in type 2 diabetic subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: C242T polymorphism of the p22 phox gene was detected by polymerase chain reaction-restriction fragment-length polymorphism in 200 Japanese type 2 diabetic subjects and 215 nondiabetic subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We examined the association with this mutation and carotid <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> as well as the patients' clinical characteristics and the level of 8-hydroxy-2'deoxyguanosine (8-OHdG) as an index of oxidative DNA damage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The diabetic subjects with the TC+TT genotypes displayed a significantly lower average <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e> (1.13 +/- 0.31 vs. 1.31 +/- 0.34 mm; P = 0.0099) and a not significantly lower serum 8-OHdG level than those with the CC genotype, despite no difference in the risk factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Stepwise multiple regression analysis showed that the risk factors for increased <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e> in the diabetic subjects were systolic blood pressure (P = 0.0042) and p22 phox CC genotype (P = 0.0151) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In nondiabetic subjects, the average <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e> of the TC+TT group was not different from that of the CC group (0.85 +/- 0.14 vs. 0.94 +/- 0.30 mm, P = 0.417) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Fasting plasma insulin concentration (41.4 +/- 15.6 vs. 64.2 +/- 59.4 pmol/l, P = 0.0098) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> index of homeostasis model assessment (HOMA-R) (1.58 +/- 0.66 vs. 2.60 +/- 2.56, P = 0.0066) were significantly lower in the TC+TT group than in the CC group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These results show that the C242T mutation in the p22 phox gene is associated with progression of asymptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> in the subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and is also associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in nondiabetic subjects </plain></SENT>
</text></document>