<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To assess whether the insulin analog lispro may antagonize the renal effects of IGF-1, a mediator of glomerular hyperfiltration involved in the progression of diabetic and nondiabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathies</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In a randomized crossover study, we compared the renal and metabolic responses to regular or lispro insulin (0.1 units/kg body wt) administered after a euglycemic clamp and 5 and 30 min before a standard meal to 11 type 2 diabetic patients with macroalbuminuria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Two- and four-hour postprandial changes (vs. preprandial euglycemia) in glomerular filtration rate (GFR) followed a significantly different trend (5.8 +/- 5.0 vs. -6.3 +/- 4.7, P &lt; 0.05; and 11.0 +/- 6.8 vs. 0.7 +/- 5.1%, P &lt; 0.05) after regular insulin and lispro injection, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>After lispro, postprandial GFR changes were negatively correlated (r = -0.48, P = 0.0001) with plasma insulin concentration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After regular insulin, renal plasma flow increased in parallel with a decrease in renal vascular resistances </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Both changes were fully prevented by lispro </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Postprandial blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> maximum concentration (278 +/- 16 vs. 240 +/- 16 mg/dl, P &lt; 0.01) and area under the curve (79,381 +/- 19,237 vs. 72,810 +/- 16,211 mg/dl per min, P &lt; 0,05) were significantly lower after insulin lispro than after regular insulin injection, respectively, despite comparable postprandial insulin profiles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Changes in total and gluconeogenic amino acids followed a similar trend </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Changes in blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and plasma amino acids did not correlate with concomitant changes in GFR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In overt <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, lispro prevents glomerular hyperfiltration and offsets the renal effects of meal or meal-associated <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> by mechanisms possibly related to IGF-1 antagonism </plain></SENT>
</text></document>