<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: The aim of our double-blind, placebo-controlled study was to compare the effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> on the insulin sensitivity in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We investigated 77 patients (mean age 58.7 years, mean BMI 27.3 kg/m2), treated by diet alone for at least 4 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The subjects were randomized into three treatment groups for 16 weeks: 100 mg t.i.d. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> (n = 25) or 1 mg t.i.d. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> (n = 27) or one t.i.d. placebo (n = 25) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Before and after therapy, the levels of fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, glycosylated <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi>, fasting insulin, plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and insulin 1 h after a standardized breakfast were measured and insulin sensitivity determined by euglycaemic hyperinsulinaemic clamp test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: After the treatment period, BMI in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> and placebo group decreased significantly, whereas in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> group a significant increase was observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> was only significant reduced under <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The postprandial <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> decreased significantly after <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> (13.8 vs. 11.4 mmol/l, p &lt; 0.05) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> treatment (14.6 vs. 11.4 mmol/l, p &lt; 0.05) and was unchanged under placebo (13.8 vs. 13.7 mmol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The fasting insulin levels remained unchanged in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> three groups, whereas postprandial insulin values increased significantly under <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Neither <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> nor <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> significantly changed insulin sensitivity [<z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi>: <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal rate before treatment 2.3 mg/kg body weight/min/insulin, after treatment 3.2; <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> 2.2 vs. 2.1; placebo 2.6 vs. 3.0] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our results show a more substantial improvement of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control under <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> than under <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> which, however, was not associated with an increase of insulin sensitivity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>