<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The purpose of this study was to determine whether an extended infusion of the incretin hormone glucagon-like <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> 1 (GLP-1) has a greater effect to promote insulin secretion in type 2 diabetic subjects than <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> administration of the <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Nine diabetic subjects and nine nondiabetic volunteers of similar age and weight were studied in identical protocols </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>First-phase insulin release (FPIR; the incremental insulin response in the first 10 min after the intravenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> bolus) and second-phase insulin release (SPIR; the incremental insulin response from 10-60 min after intravenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>) were measured during three separate intravenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance tests (IVGTTs): 1). without GLP-1 (control); 2). with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> administration of GLP-1 as a square wave starting just before <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> administration; and 3). with an extended infusion of GLP-1 for 3 h before and during the IVGTT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In the subjects with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, FPIR was severely impaired-a defect that was only modestly improved by <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> administration of GLP-1 (197 +/- 97 vs. 539 +/- 218 pmol/l. min, P &lt; 0.05), while SPIR was substantially increased (1952 +/- 512 vs. 8072 +/- 1664 pmol/l. min, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the 3-h preinfusion of GLP-1 normalized fasting <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> (7.9 +/- 0.5 vs. 5.2 +/- 0.6, P &lt; 0.05), increased FPIR by 5- to 6-fold (197 +/- 97 vs. 1141 +/- 409 pmol/l. min, P &lt; 0.05), and augmented SPIR significantly (1952 +/- 512 vs. 4026 +/- 851 pmol/l. min, P &lt; 0.05), but to a lesser degree than the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> administration of GLP-1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In addition, only the 3-h GLP-1 preinfusion significantly improved intravenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance (K(g) control 0.61 +/- 0.04, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> infusion 0.71 +/- 0.04, P = NS; 3-h infusion 0.92 +/- 0.08%/min, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These findings were also noted in the nondiabetic subjects in whom <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> administration of GLP-1 significantly increased SPIR relative to the control IVGTT (9439 +/- 2885 vs. 31553 +/- 11660 pmol/l. min, P &lt; 0.001) with less effect on FPIR (3221 +/- 918 vs. 4917 +/- 1614 pmol/l. min, P = 0.075), while the 3-h preinfusion of GLP-1 significantly increased both FPIR (3221 +/- 918 vs. 7948 +/- 2647 pmol/l. min, P &lt; 0.01) and SPIR (9439 +/- 2885 vs. 21997 +/- 9849 pmol/l. min, P &lt; 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Extended administration of GLP-1 not only augments <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-stimulated insulin secretion, but also shifts the dynamics of the insulin response to earlier release in both diabetic and nondiabetic humans </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The restitution of some FPIR in subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is associated with significantly <z:mp ids='MP_0005292'>improved glucose tolerance</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These findings demonstrate the benefits of a 3-h infusion of GLP-1 on beta-cell function beyond those of an <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> insulin secretagogue, and support the development of strategies using continuous or prolonged GLP-1 receptor agonism for treating diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>