<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The cholesteryl <z:chebi fb="21" ids="35701">ester</z:chebi> transfer protein (CETP) plays a key role in the remodeling of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> (TG)-rich and <z:chebi fb="17" ids="39025">HDL</z:chebi> particles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Sequence variations in the CETP gene may interfere with the effect of <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi>-lowering treatment in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We performed a 30-week randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> 10 mg (A10) and 80 mg (A80) in 217 unrelated patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: CETP TaqIB and A-629C polymorphisms were tightly concordant (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At baseline, B1B1 carriers had lower plasma <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> (0.99 +/- 0.2 vs. 1.11 +/- 0.2 mmol/l, P &lt; 0.05), higher CETP mass (2.62 +/- 0.8 vs. 2.05 +/- 0.4 mg/l, P &lt; 0.001), and slightly increased, though not significant, plasma TGs (2.7 +/- 1.05 vs. 2.47 +/- 0.86, P = 0.34) compared with B2B2 carriers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">Atorvastatin</z:chebi> treatment significantly reduced CETP mass dose-dependently by 18% (A10) and 29% (A80; both vs. placebo P &lt; 0.001, A10-A80 P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CETP mass and activity were strongly correlated (r = 0.854, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CETP TaqIB polymorphism appeared to modify the effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> on <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> elevation (B1B1 7.2%, B1B2 6.1%, B2B2 0.5%; P &lt; 0.05), TG reduction (B1B1 39.7%, B1B2 38.4%, B2B2 18.4%; P = 0.08), and CETP mass reduction (B1B1 32.1%, B1B2 29.6%, B2B2 21.9%; P = 0.27, NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Similar results were obtained for the A-629C polymorphism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In conclusion, the B1B1/CC carriers of the CETP polymorphisms have a more atherogenic <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile, including low <z:chebi fb="17" ids="39025">HDL</z:chebi>, and they respond better to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statin</z:chebi> therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>These results favor the hypothesis that CETP polymorphisms modify the effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statin</z:chebi> treatment and may help to identify patients who will benefit most from <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statin</z:chebi> therapy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>