<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>Hypertension</z:hpo> is known to accompany type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in middle age, but it is unknown how early in life blood pressure (BP) begins to rise among individuals who later develop <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to evaluate elevated BP as a long-term predictor of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We conducted a prospective cohort study of 1,152 white male medical students in The Johns Hopkins Precursors Study to longitudinally assess systolic BP (SBP) and diastolic BP (<z:chebi fb="4" ids="35861">DBP</z:chebi>) from young adulthood through middle age in men who went on to develop <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Incident <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was identified by self-report through mailed questionnaires verified by medical record review </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: During a median follow-up of 38 years, 77 cases of incident <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> occurred </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The mean age of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> diagnosis was 58 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>As early as age 30 years, mean SBP and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="35861">DBP</z:chebi> were significantly higher in men who developed <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> during follow-up than in those who remained nondiabetic (SBP 122 vs. 119 mmHg, P = 0.009; <z:chebi fb="4" ids="35861">DBP</z:chebi> 78 vs. 75 mmHg, P = 0.0005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The rate of increase in SBP and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="35861">DBP</z:chebi> over time in men who developed <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was greater than the rate of increase in men who did not develop <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (SBP 0.49 vs. 0.27 mmHg/year, P &lt; 0.00003; <z:chebi fb="4" ids="35861">DBP</z:chebi> 0.24 vs. 0.17 mmHg/year; P = 0.09) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>After adjustment for BMI and other risk factors for <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, SBP and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="35861">DBP</z:chebi> at age 30 years remained significantly higher in individuals who developed <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> than in their nondiabetic counterparts; however, the difference in the rate of increase in SBP was no longer significant following multivariate adjustment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: BP elevations precede the development of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in middle age by 20-25 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Higher BP in the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0362046" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">prediabetic state</z:e> might contribute to the presence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> at the time of diagnosis of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>