<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The orphan receptor small heterodimer partner (SHP, NR0B2) modulates the transcription activity of the MODY1 gene HNF4a </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Mutations in SHP were found in 7% of Japanese <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> young-<z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> type 2 diabetic patients and were associated with moderate <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> and <z:mp ids='MP_0009673'>increased birth weight</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We investigated SHP in 1927 U.K. subjects, examining relationships with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, and birth weight </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Sequencing of the coding region of SHP in 122 <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp>, young-<z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> type 2 diabetic patients detected the polymorphism G171A </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The polymorphism was not associated with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in case control or familial association studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The A allele (frequency 0.07) was not associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> in type 2 diabetic subjects (n = 348), their parents (n = 272), or young nondiabetic adults (n = 925) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, the rare (&lt;1%) AA homozygotes had a raised BMI in each cohort; this was significant when <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cohorts were combined (Z score = 0.67 AA vs. -0.05 G/x, P = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was no association with corrected birth weight in 382 <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> babies, but the only AA baby was 4,069 g </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Our study suggests that genetic variation in SHP is unlikely to be common in the predisposition to <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, or <z:mp ids='MP_0009673'>increased birth weight</z:mp> in U.K </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Caucasians </plain></SENT>
</text></document>