<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: Familial partial <z:hpo ids='HP_0009125'>lipodystrophy</z:hpo>, Dunnigan variety (FPLD), is an <z:hpo ids='HP_0000006'>autosomal dominant</z:hpo> disorder due to missense mutations in the lamin A/C (LMNA) gene encoding nuclear lamina proteins </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It is characterized by loss of subcutaneous fat from the extremities and trunk and accumulation of fat in the head and neck region beginning at puberty </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients with FPLD are predisposed to metabolic complications of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> such as <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We sought to identify risk factors for <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in patients with FPLD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A cross-sectional study comparing clinical, biochemical, and anthropometric variables and LMNA genotypes in FPLD patients with and without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: We studied 52 women and 24 men with FPLD from 18 different families </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Twenty-eight women (54%) but only four men (17%) had <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (P &lt; 0.001); therefore further comparisons were mostly limited to women </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Compared with women without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, those with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> had higher BMI (median values 23 vs. 24 kg/m(2), respectively; P = 0.03), increased chin skinfold thickness (10 vs. 20 mm; P = 0.001), lower rates of nulliparity (60% vs. 28%; P = 0.04), and higher levels of fasting serum <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi> (2.4 vs. 3.5 mmol/l; P &lt; 0.001) but similar serum leptin levels (3.4 vs. 3.6 ng/ml; P = 0.9) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was not related to age, menopausal status, family history of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in unaffected relatives, or LMNA genotype </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: We conclude that <z:mp ids='MP_0010024'>increased adiposity</z:mp> as reflected by excess subcutaneous fat accumulation in the chin region and parity may predispose women with FPLD to develop <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>