<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Glucagon-like <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> 1 (GLP-1) stimulates insulin secretion in a <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-dependent manner, but its short half-life limits its therapeutic potential </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We tested NN2211, a long-acting GLP-1 derivative, in 10 subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (means +/- SD: age 63 +/- 8 years, BMI 30.1 +/- 4.2 kg/m(2), HbA(1c) 6.5 +/- 0.8%) in a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A single injection (7.5 micro g/kg) of NN2211 or placebo was administered 9 h before the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>beta-cell sensitivity was assessed by a graded <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> infusion protocol, with <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels matched over the 5-12 mmol/l range </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Insulin secretion rates (ISRs) were estimated by deconvolution of C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Findings were compared with those in 10 nondiabetic volunteers during the same <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> infusion protocol </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In type 2 diabetic subjects, NN2211, in comparison with placebo, increased insulin and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> levels, the ISR area under the curve (AUC) (1,130 +/- 150 vs. 668 +/- 106 pmol/kg; P &lt; 0.001), and the slope of ISR versus plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (1.26 +/- 0.36 vs. 0.54 +/- 0.18 pmol x l[min(-1) x mmol(-1) x kg(-1)]; P &lt; 0.014), with values similar to those of nondiabetic control subjects (ISR AUC 1,206 +/- 99; slope of ISR versus plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, 1.44 +/- 0.18) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The long-acting GLP-1 derivative, NN2211, restored beta-cell responsiveness to physiological <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> in type 2 diabetic subjects </plain></SENT>
</text></document>