<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: An open-label, parallel-group, randomized, multicenter trial was conducted to compare efficacy and safety of repaglinide versus nateglinide, when used in a combination regimen with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> for treatment of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Enrolled patients (n = 192) had HbA(1c) &gt;7% and &lt; or =12% during previous treatment with a <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, or low-dose Glucovance (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> &lt; or =2.5 mg, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> &lt; or =500 mg) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>After a 4-week <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> run-in therapy period (doses escalated to 1,000 mg b.i.d.), patients were randomized to addition of repaglinide (n = 96) (1 mg/meal, maximum 4 mg/meal) or nateglinide (n = 96) (120 mg/meal, reduced to 60 mg if needed) to the regimen for 16 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, and glucagon were assessed after a liquid test meal at baseline and week 16 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Final HbA(1c) values were lower for repaglinide/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> treatment than for nateglinide/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (7.1 vs. 7.5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Repaglinide/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> therapy showed significantly greater mean reductions of HbA(1c) (-1.28 vs. -0.67%; P &lt; 0.001) and of fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) (-39 vs. -21 mg/dl; P = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Self-monitoring of blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> profiles were significantly lower for repaglinide/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> before breakfast, before lunch, and at 2:00 A.M </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Changes in the area under the curve of postprandial <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, or glucagon peaks after a test meal were not significantly different for the two treatment groups during this study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Median final doses were 5.0 mg/day for repaglinide and 360 mg/day for nateglinide </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Safety assessments were comparable for the two regimens </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The addition of repaglinide to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> therapy resulted in reductions of HbA(1c) and FPG values that were significantly greater than the reductions observed for addition of nateglinide </plain></SENT>
</text></document>