<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Endothelial dysfunction</z:e> has been reported in type 2 diabetic patients and in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> syndrome (IRS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study evaluates the effects of weight reduction and exercise on vascular reactivity of the macro- and the microcirculation in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects with IRS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS; We studied 24 <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects (9 men and 15 women, age 49.3 +/- 1.9 years, BMI 36.7 +/- 0.94 kg/m(2), mean +/- <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SEM</z:e>) with IRS at baseline and after 6 months of weight reduction and exercise </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Brachial artery flow-mediated dilation (FMD) and response to sublingual glyceryltrinitrate (GTN) were assessed by high-resolution ultrasound </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Microvascular reactivity was evaluated by the laser-Doppler perfusion imaging after iontophoresis of <z:chebi fb="9" ids="15355">acetylcholine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29321">sodium nitroprusside</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We also measured plasma levels of soluble intercellular <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0001511" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">adhesion</z:e> molecule (sICAM), vascular <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0001511" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">adhesion</z:e> molecule, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042974" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">von Willebrand</z:e> factor, plasminogen activator inhibitor-1 (PAI-1) antigen, and tissue plasminogen activator antigen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: This intervention resulted in 6.6 +/- 1% reduction in body weight (P &lt; 0.001) and significant improvement of insulin sensitivity index (2.9 +/- 0.36 vs. 1.9 +/- 0.33 [10(-4) x min(-1) x ( microU ml(-1))], P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>FMD significantly improved (12.9 +/- 1.2% vs. 7.9 +/- 1.0%, P &lt; 0.001), whereas response to GTN and microvascular reactivity did not change </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Similar observations were seen when the subjects were subclassified according to their <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance to <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo>, and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>sICAM and PAI-1 significantly decreased (251.3 +/- 7.7 vs. 265.6 +/- 9.3 ng/ml, P = 0.018 and 36.2 +/- 3.6 vs. 48.6 +/- 3.9 ng/ml, P = 0.001, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The relationship between percentage weight reduction and improved FMD was linear (R(2) = 0.47, P = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: We conclude that 6 months of weight reduction and exercise improve macrovascular endothelial function and reduces selective markers of endothelial activation and coagulation in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects with IRS regardless of the degree of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance </plain></SENT>
</text></document>