<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine the age- and sex-specific prevalence of impaired fasting glycemia, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo>, screen-detected <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, and known <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in a Danish population aged 30-60 years and to examine the phenotype and the cardiovascular risk profile in individuals with impaired <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> regulation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In the Inter99 study, 13,016 inhabitants living in Copenhagen County were invited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> participants underwent anthropometric measurements, blood samples, and a 75-g standardized oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The age-specific prevalences in men were as follows: impaired fasting glycemia: 1.4-16.3%; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo>: 6.9-17.8%; screen-detected <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>: 0.7-9.7%; and known <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>: 0-5.8% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The corresponding figures in women were 0-5.1, 10.5-17.3, 0.6-6.3, and 0.5-9% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of impaired <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> regulation increased with age </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Among individuals with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, 65.6% were previously undiagnosed; this proportion was highest in the youngest age-group (82% among 45-year-old men vs. 63% among 60-year-old men, and 70% among 45-year-old women vs. 52% among 60-year-old women) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Mean BMI, waist, HbA(1c), systolic blood pressure, diastolic blood pressure, and total cholesterol were significantly higher (P &lt; 0.0001) in the individuals with impaired <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> regulation compared with individuals with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This study revealed that the prevalence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is high and that still two out of three individuals are undiagnosed, indicating a need for more attention to the disease in society </plain></SENT>
</text></document>