<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: We investigated the phenotypic features of diabetic microvascular complications and their association with a (CA)(n) microsatellite and a C/T polymorphism at the 5' region of the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15693">aldose</z:chebi> reductase gene (ALR2) in a consecutive cohort of 738 Chinese type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Of the entire patient cohort, 392 were free of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> complications, or uncomplicated, 159 had diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo>, 66 had diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo>, and 121 had both diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>Nephropathy</z:hpo> was defined as urinary albumin excretion rate (AER) &gt;or=20 micro g/min and albumin-to-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> ratio &gt;or=3.5 mg/mmol in two urine collections </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>Retinopathy</z:hpo> was defined by the presence of <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhages</z:mp>, exudates, laser marks, and fibrous proliferation or by a history of vitrectomy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>(CA)(n) and C/T polymorphisms were examined by PCR followed by capillary electrophoresis and digestion with BfaI, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In the whole cohort, patients with diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> (n = 187) had higher blood pressure and lower BMI, while those with diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> (n = 280) had higher blood pressure, waist-to-hip ratio, and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile than those without the respective complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The z+6 carriers of the (CA)(n) polymorphism were less common in patients with diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> than those without diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> (n = 551) (4.3 vs. 9.3%, P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The CT/TT carriers had a higher AER than the CC carriers (30.2 x/divided by 7.2 vs. 21.9 x/divided by 6.9 micro g/min, P = 0.03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Further subgroup analysis was performed after excluding uncomplicated patients with &lt;5 years disease duration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The group with both diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> had higher frequencies of the z-2 allele (25.7 vs. 16.9%, P = 0.03) and T allele (26.4 vs. 18.5%, P = 0.04) and a lower frequency of the z+6 allele (1.7 vs. 5.5%, P = 0.054) than the uncomplicated group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Multiple logistic regression analysis confirmed that z-2 carrying (odds ratio 2.6, 95% CI 1.20-5.83, P = 0.02) and CT/TT genotypes (OR 2.5, 95% CI 1.19-5.19, P = 0.02) were independent predictors for both diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Chinese type 2 diabetic patients exhibited phenotypic differences in terms of risk factors for both diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> and diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Both the z-2 allele of (CA)(n) polymorphism and T allele of ALR2 were independently associated with severe diabetic microvascular complications </plain></SENT>
</text></document>