<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> elevations in free fatty acids (FFAs) stimulate insulin secretion, but prolonged <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> exposure impairs beta-cell function in both in vitro studies and in vivo animal studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In humans data are limited to short-term (&lt; or =48 h) <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> infusion studies and have led to conflicting results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We examined insulin secretion and action during a 4-day <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> infusion in healthy <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerant subjects with (FH+ group, n = 13) and without (control subjects, n = 8) a family history of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Volunteers were admitted twice to the clinical research center and received, in random order, a <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> or saline infusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>On days 1 and 2, insulin and C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> concentration were measured as part of a metabolic profile after standardized mixed meals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Insulin secretion in response to <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> was assessed with a +125 mg/dl hyperglycemic clamp on day 3 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>On day 4, <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> turnover was measured with a euglycemic insulin clamp with [3-3H]<z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Day-long plasma FFA concentrations with <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> infusion were increased within the physiological range, to levels seen in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (approximately 500-800 micromol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">Lipid</z:chebi> infusion had strikingly opposite effects on insulin secretion in the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>After mixed meals, day-long plasma C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> levels increased with <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> infusion in control subjects but decreased in the FH+ group (+28 vs. -30%, respectively, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>During the hyperglycemic clamp, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> infusion enhanced the insulin secretion rate (ISR) in control subjects but decreased it in the FH+ group (first phase: +75 vs. -60%, P &lt; 0.001; second phase: +25 vs. -35%, P &lt; 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>When the ISR was adjusted for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> (ISRRd = ISR / [1/Rd], where Rd is the rate of insulin-stimulated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal), the inadequate beta-cell response in the FH+ group was even more evident </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Although ISRRd was not different between the two groups before <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> infusion, in the FH+ group, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> infusion reduced first- and second-phase ISR(Rd) to 25 and 42% of that in control subjects, respectively (both P &lt; 0.001 vs. control subjects) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">Lipid</z:chebi> infusion in the FH+ group (but not in control subjects) also caused severe hepatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> with an increase in basal endogenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> production (EGP), despite an elevation in fasting insulin levels, and impaired suppression of EGP to insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>In summary, in individuals who are genetically predisposed to type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, a sustained physiological increase in plasma FFA impairs insulin secretion in response to mixed meals and to intravenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, suggesting that in subjects at high risk of developing type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, beta-cell lipotoxicity may play an important role in the progression from <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance to overt <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>