<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To compare the abilities and associated <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> risks of insulin glargine and human <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin added to oral therapy of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> to achieve 7% HbA(1c) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In a randomized, open-label, parallel, 24-week multicenter trial, 756 overweight men and women with inadequate glycemic control (HbA(1c) &gt;7.5%) on one or two oral agents continued prestudy oral agents and received bedtime glargine or <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> once daily, titrated using a simple algorithm seeking a target fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) &lt;or=100 mg/dl (5.5 mmol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Outcome measures were FPG, HbA(1c), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo>, and percentage of patients reaching HbA(1c) &lt;or=7% without documented nocturnal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Mean FPG at end point was similar with glargine and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> (117 vs. 120 mg/dl [6.5 vs. 6.7 mmol/l]), as was HbA(1c) (6.96 vs. 6.97%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A majority of patients ( approximately 60%) attained HbA(1c) &lt;or=7% with each insulin type </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, nearly 25% more patients attained this without documented nocturnal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> (&lt;or=72 mg/dl [4.0 mmol/l]) with glargine (33.2 vs. 26.7%, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Moreover, rates of other categories of symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> were 21-48% lower with glargine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Systematically titrating bedtime basal insulin added to oral therapy can safely achieve 7% HbA(1c) in a majority of overweight patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with HbA(1c) between 7.5 and 10.0% on oral agents alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In doing this, glargine causes significantly less nocturnal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> than <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e>, thus reducing a leading barrier to initiating insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This simple regimen may facilitate earlier and effective insulin use in routine medical practice, improving achievement of recommended standards of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> care </plain></SENT>
</text></document>