<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: A cohort of patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, prescribed <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> tablets, experienced significantly greater improvements in glycaemic control compared to patients receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> co-administered with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>AIM: To compare the change in A1C for type 2 diabetic patients new to combination therapy with fixed-dose <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> tablets vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> co-administered with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> in a usual-care setting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This retrospective cohort study analysed medication usage via an administrative pharmacy claims database and the patients' corresponding laboratory results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients were new to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> combination therapy with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> tablets or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> co-administered with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> between August 2000 and July 2001 and had A1C measurements at baseline and within 76-194 days of initiating combination therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The change from baseline in A1C was analysed using statistical regression to adjust for significant covariates (baseline A1C and dosage) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Adherence with therapy was also compared </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The cohort consisted of 950 patients who received <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> tablets and 471 taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> co-administered with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">Glyburide</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> patients were younger (mean age = 56 vs. 60 years, p &lt; 0.0001) and received lower doses of each drug than patients taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> co-administered with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> mean final dose = 6 vs. 10 mg/day, p &lt; 0.0001; <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> = 893 vs. 1297 mg/day, p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The mean decrease from baseline A1C, adjusted for baseline A1C and dosage, of 2.02% for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> tablets was significantly (p &lt; 0.0001) greater than the decrease of 1.49% for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> co-administered with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">Glyburide</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> patients with baseline A1C &gt;/= 8 experienced a significantly (p &lt; 0.0001) greater decrease in A1C of 2.93% compared to 1.92% for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> co-administered with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>For patients with baseline A1C &lt; 8%, the difference between the A1C responses remained significant, even though the reductions in A1C were smaller for both <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> tablets and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> co-administered with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (0.54% and 0.23%, p = 0.0017) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Patients were more adherent with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> tablets (84% vs. 76%, p &lt; 0.0001), though regression analysis indicated that adherence was not a significant predictor of change in A1C </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The lower medication doses delivered by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> tablets provided a significantly greater reduction in A1C than did <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> co-administered with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, especially when baseline A1C &gt;/= 8% </plain></SENT>
</text></document>