<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma2 (PPARgamma2) Pro12Ala polymorphism has been associated with a decreased risk of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and a lower albumin excretion rate (AER) in patients with established <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We performed a case-control study aiming to evaluate the association between the Pro12Ala polymorphism and diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Genomic DNA was obtained from 104 type 2 diabetic patients (case subjects) with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0000083'>renal insufficiency</z:hpo> (78 on dialysis and 26 with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000093'>proteinuria</z:hpo> [AER &gt;or=200 microg/min] and serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> &gt;or=2.0 mg/dl) and 212 normoalbuminuric patients (AER &lt;20 microg/min) with known <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> duration &gt;or=10 years (control subjects) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The genotypic distribution of the PPARgamma2 Pro12Ala polymorphism in these diabetic patients was in Hardy-Weinberg equilibrium, and the Ala allele frequency was 9% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The frequency of Ala carriers (Ala/Ala or Ala/Pro) was 20.3% in control subjects and 10.6% in case subjects (P = 0.031) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The odds ratio of having diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> for Ala carriers was 0.465 (95% CI 0.229-0.945; P = 0.034) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Carriers of the Ala allele were not different from noncarriers (Pro/Pro) regarding sex (38.9 vs. 44.1% males) or ethnicity (77.4 vs. 71.7% white) distribution, age (61 +/- 10 vs. 61 +/- 10 years), known <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> duration (17 +/- 7 vs. 16 +/- 7 years), BMI (27 +/- 4 vs. 28 +/- 5 kg/m(2)), fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (184 +/- 81 vs. 176 +/- 72 mg/dl), HbA(1c) (6.7 +/- 2.3 vs. 6.9 +/- 2.4%; high-performance liquid chromatography reference range: 2.7-4.3%), and systolic (145 +/- 27 vs. 0.144 +/- 24 mmHg) or diastolic (87 +/- 14 vs. 85 +/- 14 mmHg) blood pressure, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, the presence of the Ala allele may confer protection from diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>