<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: Based on the known effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (MET) in improving insulin sensitivity in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, with the scope to focus the effects on glycaemic and free fatty acids (FFA) levels, we studied the effects of a short-term treatment with this drug in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> or family history of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (FHD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We used a method to allow us to evaluate the possible difference of insulin sensibility with regard to the insulin action on glycaemia and blood FFA, both in the basal state and during oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test (OGTT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Insulin sensitivity was investigated before and after MET treatment (850 mg bid for 10 days) in seven <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance and without FHD and 13 <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (n=7) or FHD (n=6) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>By using specifically designed formulae, we calculated four insulin-sensitivity indices (ISI) from basal level (b) and area values (a) (during OGTT) of insulinaemia, glycaemia (gly) or FFA (ffa), namely: ISI (gly)-b, ISI (gly)-a, ISI (ffa)-b and ISI (ffa)-a </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> or FHD, MET improved ISI (gly)-b (0.79 +/- 0.06 vs. 0.59 +/- 0.07, p&lt;0.001) and ISI (gly)-a (0.69 +/- 0.09 vs. 0.51 +/- 0.07, p&lt;0.05), whereas only minor changes occurred for ISI (ffa)-b and ISI (ffa)-a </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In contrast, in simple <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects, MET induced further deterioration of both ISI (gly)-a (0.47 +/- 0.07 vs. 0.64 +/- 0.10, p&lt;0.01) and ISI (ffa)-a (0.43 +/- 0.07 vs. 0.55 +/- 0.08, p&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Fasting level and total area of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> were high in the <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients and were not affected by MET </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A statistically significant increase (p&lt;0.01), however, was observed for the 'decremental' area of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> or FHD, which might probably contribute to the reduction of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> induced by the drug in these patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Although the low number of subjects studied precludes absolute conclusions, data would suggest that MET improved ISI towards <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> but not towards FFA, in the diabetic and '<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0362046" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">prediabetic</z:e>' <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients, whereas worsened it in the <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects without FHD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Therefore, the effects of MET would not be secondary to changes of FFA but rather to a primary action of MET on <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> metabolism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Thus, utilization of MET to treat the <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> is indicated only in the presence of alterations of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> metabolism or FHD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>