<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> low-grade <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, but the underlying mechanism(s) is not well understood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Because in vitro studies have shown that advanced glycation end products (AGEs) can trigger <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammatory responses</z:mp>, the present study has investigated whether serum concentration of AGEs is an important determinant of circulating levels of inflammatory markers, like C-reactive protein (CRP), in type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Diabetic patients (n = 210) and healthy control subjects (n = 110) of similar BMI were recruited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Serum AGEs were assayed by competitive enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay using a polyclonal rabbit anti-sera raised against AGE-RNase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Plasma high-sensitivity CRP was measured by an immunoturbidimetric assay and interleukin (IL)-6 by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Serum AGEs were increased in diabetic patients compared with control subjects (4.24 +/- 0.88 vs. 3.15 +/- 0.81 unit/ml, respectively, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Both plasma CRP (1.55 [0.81-2.95] vs. 0.88 mg/dl [0.51-1.89], respectively, P &lt; 0.01; median [interquartile range]) and IL-6 (0.80 [0.68-0.97] vs. 0.69 pg/ml [0.48-0.84], respectively, P &lt; 0.01) were also higher in diabetic patients than in control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In the diabetic patients, log(CRP) correlated with AGEs (r = 0.22, P = 0.002) and with log(IL-6) (r = 0.29, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Forward stepwise linear regression analysis showed that BMI, log(IL-6), and AGEs were significant independent determinants of log(CRP) in the diabetic patients, accounting for 17, 12, and 10% of the variation in log(CRP), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Serum concentration of AGEs is increased in patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and is an independent determinant of plasma CRP levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Subclinical <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> in these patients may therefore be partly due to activation of the <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammatory response</z:mp> by AGEs </plain></SENT>
</text></document>