<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>To investigate the possible relevance of free radicals and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26347">prostanoids</z:chebi> to the mode of initiation and/or evolution of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0155765" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">microangiopathy</z:e> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo>, we measured serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="39" ids="44785">peroxides</z:chebi> (LPO), an accepted index of intravascular free radicals, and plasma <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28667">11-dehydrothromboxane B2</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="28667">11-dehydro-TXB2</z:chebi>), a stable metabolite of vasoactive <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15627">thromboxane A2</z:chebi> released from platelets, in 95 patients with normolipidemic type 2 (non-insulin-dependent) <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> at different stages of the disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In general, either LPO or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28667">11-dehydro-TXB2</z:chebi> was significantly greater in the patients, as a group, than in the matched controls (3.82 vs. 2.65 nmol/ml, P &lt; 0.01 for LPO; and 17.3 vs. 5.8 pg/ml, P &lt; 0.01 for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28667">11-dehydro-TXB2</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In patients, both LPO and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28667">11-dehydro-TXB2</z:chebi> increased according to the severity of their diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A highly significant positive correlation existed between the LPO values and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28667">11-dehydro-TXB2</z:chebi> in the patients (r = 0.64, P &lt; 0.0001), while there was no such relationship in the controls (r = 0.18, P = NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>No difference in serum levels of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoproteins</z:chebi> A-I, A-II, B, C-II, C-III, or E was observed between the patients and controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Short-term glycemic control (25 cal/kg of standardized body weight/day, for 8 weeks) resulted in a small but significant reduction in LPO (4.2 vs. 4.6 nmol/ml, control; P &lt; 0.05) without alteration in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28667">11-dehydro-TXB2</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There was a tendency towards deterioration in LPO according to the improvement in glycemic control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These results appear consistent with the view that, in addition to LPO, the release of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15627">TXA2</z:chebi> from activated platelet in the human circulation could be an important factor for the initiation and/or evolution of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0155765" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">microangiopathy</z:e> in diabetic patients even when they are not apparently hyperlipidemic </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Further, the results of the present study emphasize the notion that more tight control of serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> is worthy of serious consideration in preventing the advance of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0025945" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">diabetic microangiopathy</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>