<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The aim of this study was to determine patient satisfaction in patients with type 1 or type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> receiving an inhaled insulin or subcutaneous insulin regimen, as assessed by pooled analysis of two 12-week parent studies and 1-year extension studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In the 12-week parent studies, patients with type 1 (n = 70) or type 2 (n = 51) <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were randomized to an inhaled insulin or subcutaneous insulin regimen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In the 1-year extension studies, patients were allowed to select either treatment regimen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patient satisfaction was assessed at baseline, week 12, and 1 year using the Patient Satisfaction with Insulin Therapy questionnaire </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of the 60 patients who received inhaled insulin during the parent studies, 85.0% (n = 51) chose to continue treatment, 13.3% (n = 8) switched to subcutaneous insulin, and 1.7% (n = 1) did not continue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Of the 61 patients who received subcutaneous insulin, 21.3% (n = 13) chose to continue treatment, 75.4% (n = 46) switched to inhaled insulin, and 3.3% (n = 2) did not continue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>From baseline (parent studies) to 1 year (extension studies), HbA(1c) reductions of 0.8% were sustained, and greater improvements were observed in the inhaled insulin group compared with the subcutaneous insulin group in terms of overall satisfaction (37.9 vs. 3.1%; P &lt; 0.01) and ease of use (43.2 vs. -0.9%; P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Inhaled insulin was preferred over subcutaneous insulin, which resulted in greater patient satisfaction up to 1 year in patients with type 1 or type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with durable effects on HbA(1c) levels </plain></SENT>
</text></document>