<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The aims of this study were to determine: (1). endothelial function in type 2 diabetic subjects with and without diabetic microvascular complications using flow mediated <z:mpath ids='MPATH_66'>dilatation</z:mpath> method (FMD); (2). influence of other variables on FMD; and (3). the correlation between FMD and carotid intimal media thickness (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH, DESIGN AND METHODS: In this cross-sectional study, flow mediated <z:mpath ids='MPATH_66'>dilatation</z:mpath> (FMD) and intimal media thickness (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e>) were determined using high resolution ultrasonography in 20 non-diabetic subjects, in 23 type 2 diabetic subjects without any complications and in 23 type 2 diabetic patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Age-adjusted mean (S.D.) FMD value in diabetic subjects (8.9 +/- 5%) was lower (P &lt; 0.0001) when compared with the group of control subjects (18.8 +/- 7.5 % </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>However, there was no difference in the age-adjusted FMD values between diabetic subjects with and without complications (7.3 +/- 3.3 % versus 10.5 +/- 5.9 %) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>FMD levels did not vary significantly between sexes in both non-diabetic and diabetic groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>FMD correlated negatively with carotid <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e> (r = -0.23, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In multiple linear regression analysis, age adjusted FMD was associated only with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with complications (P = 0.012) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The variance explained was 21.9% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Abnormal FMD and increased carotid <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IMT</z:e> were present in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Both these parameters negatively correlated with each other supporting an association between impaired FMD and atherogenesis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>As these abnormalities existed even in diabetic subjects with no microvascular complications, it is likely that they preceded the development of these complications </plain></SENT>
</text></document>