<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Both <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> increase hepatic insulin sensitivity, but their mechanism of action has not been compared in humans </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to compare the effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> treatment on liver fat content, hepatic insulin sensitivity, insulin clearance, and gene expression in adipose tissue and serum adiponectin concentrations in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A total of 20 drug-naive patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (age 48 +/- 3 years, fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> 152 +/- 9 mg/dl, BMI 30.6 +/- 0.8 kg/m2) were treated in a double-blind randomized fashion with either 8 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> or 2 g <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> for 16 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Both drugs similarly decreased HbA1c, insulin, and free fatty acid concentrations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Body weight decreased in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (84 +/- 4 vs. 82 +/- 4 kg, P &lt; 0.05) but not the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Liver fat (proton spectroscopy) was decreased with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> by 51% (15 +/- 3 vs. 7 +/- 1%, 0 vs. 16 weeks, P = 0.003) but not by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (13 +/- 3 to 14 +/- 3%, NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">Rosiglitazone</z:chebi> (16 +/- 2 vs. 20 +/- 1 ml.kg(-1).min(-1), P = 0.02) but not <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> increased insulin clearance by 20% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Hepatic insulin sensitivity in the basal state increased similarly in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Insulin-stimulated <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> uptake increased significantly with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> but not with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Serum adiponectin concentrations increased by 123% with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> but remained unchanged during <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The decrease of serum adiponectin concentrations correlated with the decrease in liver fat (r = -0.74, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">Rosiglitazone</z:chebi> but not <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> significantly increased expression of peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-gamma, adiponectin, and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="6495">lipoprotein</z:chebi> lipase in adipose tissue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> but not <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> decreases liver fat and increases insulin clearance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The decrease in liver fat by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> is associated with an increase in serum adiponectin concentrations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Both agents increase hepatic insulin sensitivity, but only <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> increases peripheral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> uptake </plain></SENT>
</text></document>