<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The aim of this study was to prospectively assess the relation between red meat intake and incidence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Over an average of 8.8 years, we evaluated 37,309 participants in the Women's Health Study aged &gt;/=45 years who were free of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e>, and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and completed validated semiquantitative food frequency questionnaires in 1993 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: During 326,876 person-years of follow-up, we documented 1,558 incident cases of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>After adjusting for age, BMI, total energy intake, exercise, alcohol intake, cigarette smoking, and family history of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, we found positive associations between intakes of red meat and processed meat and risk of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Comparing women in the highest quintile with those in the lowest quintile, the multivariate-adjusted relative risks (RRs) of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were 1.28 for red meat (95% CI 1.07-1.53, P &lt; 0.001 for trend) and 1.23 for processed meat intake (1.05-1.45, P = 0.001 for trend) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, the significantly increased <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> risk appeared to be most pronounced for frequent consumption of total processed meat (RR 1.43, 95% CI 1.17-1.75 for &gt;/=5/week vs. &lt;1/month, P &lt; 0.001 for trend) and two major subtypes, which were bacon (1.21, 1.06-1.39 for &gt;/=2/week vs. &lt;1/week, P = 0.004 for trend) and hot dogs (1.28, 1.09-1.50 for &gt;/=2/week vs. &lt;1/week, P = 0.003 for trend) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These results remained significant after further adjustment for intakes of dietary fiber, <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi>, glycemic load, and total fat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Intakes of total cholesterol, animal protein, and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="30413">heme</z:chebi> iron were also significantly associated with a higher risk of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our data indicate that higher consumption of total red meat, especially various processed meats, may increase risk of developing type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in women </plain></SENT>
</text></document>