<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Insulin glulisine is a novel analog of human insulin designed for use as a rapid-acting insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study compared the safety and efficacy of glulisine with regular human insulin (RHI) in combination with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In total, 876 relatively well-controlled patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (mean HbA1c 7.55%) were randomized and treated with glulisine/<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> (n = 435) or RHI/<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> (n = 441) for up to 26 weeks in this randomized, multicenter, multinational, open-label, parallel-group study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Subjects were allowed to continue the same dose of prestudy regimens of oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> agent (OAD) therapy (unless <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> necessitated a dose change) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A slightly greater reduction from baseline to end point of HbA1c was seen in the glulisine group versus RHI (-0.46 vs. -0.30% with RHI; P = 0.0029) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Also, at end point, lower postbreakfast (156 vs. 162 mg/dl [8.66 vs. 9.02 mmol/l]; P &lt; 0.05) and postdinner (154 vs. 163 mg/dl [8.54 vs. 9.05 mmol/l]; P &lt; 0.05) blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels were noted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> (overall, nocturnal, and severe) and <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> were comparable between the two treatment groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There were no between-group differences in baseline-to-end point changes in insulin dose </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Twice-daily glulisine associated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> can provide small improvements in glycemic control compared with RHI in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who are already relatively well controlled on insulin alone or insulin plus OADs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The clinical relevance of such a difference remains to be established </plain></SENT>
</text></document>