<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To compare the efficacy and safety of adding once-daily basal insulin versus switching to twice-daily premixed insulin in type 2 diabetic patients insufficiently controlled by oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> agents (OADs) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In a 24-week, multinational, multicenter, open, parallel group clinical trial, 371 insulin-naive patients with poor glycemic control (fasting blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> [FBG] &gt;/=120 mg/dl, HbA(1c) 7.5-10.5%) on OADs (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>) were randomized to once-daily morning insulin glargine plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (glargine plus OAD) or to 30% regular/70% human <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin (70/30) twice daily without OADs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Insulin dosage was titrated to target FBG &lt;/=100 mg/dl (both insulins) and predinner blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> &lt;/=100 mg/dl (70/30 only) using a weekly forced-titration algorithm </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Mean HbA(1c) decrease from baseline was significantly more pronounced (-1.64 vs. -1.31%, P = 0.0003), and more patients reached HbA(1c) &lt;/=7.0% without confirmed nocturnal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> (45.5 vs. 28.6%, P = 0.0013) with glargine plus OAD than with 70/30 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Similarly, FBG decrease was greater with glargine plus OAD (adjusted mean difference -17 mg/dl [-0.9 mmol/l], P &lt; 0.0001), and more patients reached target FBG &lt;/=100 mg/dl with glargine plus OAD than with 70/30 (31.6 vs. 15.0%, P = 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Glargine plus OAD patients had fewer confirmed <z:hpo ids='HP_0001988'>hypoglycemic episodes</z:hpo> than 70/30 patients (mean 4.07 vs. 9.87/patient-year, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Initiating insulin treatment by adding basal insulin glargine once daily to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> treatment was safer and more effective than beginning twice-daily injections of 70/30 and discontinuing OADs in type 2 diabetic patients inadequately controlled with OADs </plain></SENT>
</text></document>