<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: This study evaluates insulin sensitivity, pancreatic beta-cell function (BCF), and the balance between the two in youth with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and assesses the relationship of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> duration and HbA(1c) to insulin sensitivity and BCF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: The subjects were 14 adolescents with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and 20 <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> control subjects of comparable age, BMI, body composition, and puberty </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Insulin sensitivity was evaluated with a 3-h hyperinsulinemic (80 mU  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>m(-2)  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>min(-1)) euglycemic clamp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>First-phase insulin secretion (FPIS) and second-phase insulin secretion (SPIS) were evaluated with a 2-h hyperglycemic (12.5 mmol/l) clamp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> rate of appearance was determined with the use of [6,6-(2)H(2)]<z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> rate of appearance was higher in type 2 diabetic patients than in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> control subjects (16.5 +/- 1.1 vs. 12.3 +/- 0.5 micromol  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>kg(-1)  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>min(-1); P = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Insulin sensitivity was lower in type 2 diabetic patients than in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> control subjects (1.0 +/- 0.1 vs. 2.0 +/- 0.2 micromol  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>kg(-1)  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>min(-1) per pmol/l; P = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Fasting insulin was higher in type 2 diabetic patients than in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> control subjects (289.8 +/- 24.6 vs. 220.2 +/- 18.0 pmol/l; P = 0.007), and FPIS and SPIS were lower (FPIS: 357.6 +/- 42.0 vs. 1,365.0 +/- 111.0 pmol/l; SPIS: 652.2 +/- 88.8 vs. 1,376.4 +/- 88.8 pmol/l; P &lt; 0.001 for both) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposition index (GDI = insulin sensitivity x FPIS) was approximately 86% lower in type 2 diabetic patients than in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>HbA(1c) correlated with FPIS (r = -0.61, P = 0.025) with no relationship to insulin sensitivity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Despite the impairment in both insulin sensitivity and BCF in youth with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the magnitude of the derangement is greater in BCF than insulin sensitivity when compared with that in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>The inverse relationship between BCF and HbA(1c) may either reflect the impact of deteriorating BCF on glycemic control or be a manifestation of a glucotoxic phenomenon on BCF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>Future studies in youth type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> should target the natural course of beta-cell failure and means of retarding and/or preventing it </plain></SENT>
</text></document>