<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Islet <z:mpath ids='MPATH_34'>amyloid deposition</z:mpath> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is associated with reduced beta-cell mass </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Therefore, interventions aimed at reducing islet amyloid formation may help preserve beta-cell mass in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">Rosiglitazone</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> act by different mechanisms to improve insulin sensitivity and thereby reduce beta-cell secretory demand, resulting in decreased release of insulin and islet amyloid <z:chebi fb="1" ids="15841">polypeptide</z:chebi> (IAPP), the unique constituent of islet amyloid deposits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that this reduced beta-cell secretory demand would lead to reduced islet amyloid formation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Human IAPP (hIAPP) transgenic mice, a model of islet amyloid, were treated for 12 months with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> (1.5 mg.kg(-1).day(-1), n = 19), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (1 g.kg(-1).day(-1), n = 18), or control (n = 17) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>At the end of the study, islet amyloid prevalence (percent islets containing amyloid) and severity (percent islet area occupied by amyloid), islet mass, beta-cell mass, and insulin release were determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Islet amyloid prevalence (44 +/- 8, 13 +/- 4, and 11 +/- 3% for control, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>-, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi>-treated mice, respectively) and severity (9.2 +/- 3.0, 0.22 +/- 0.11, and 0.10 +/- 0.05% for control, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>-, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi>-treated mice, respectively) were markedly reduced with both <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> (P &lt; 0.001 for both measures) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> treatment (P &lt; 0.001 for both measures) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Both treatments were associated with reduced insulin release assessed as the <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> insulin response to intravenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (2,189 +/- 857, 621 +/- 256, and 14 +/- 158 pmol/l for control, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>-, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi>-treated mice, respectively; P &lt; 0.05 for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> vs. control and P &lt; 0.005 for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> vs. control), consistent with reduced secretory demand </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Similarly, islet mass (33.4 +/- 7.0, 16.6 +/- 3.6, and 12.2 +/- 2.1 mg for control, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>-, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi>-treated mice, respectively) was not different with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> treatment (P = 0.06 vs. control) but was significantly lower with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> treatment (P &lt; 0.05 vs. control) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>When the decreased islet mass was accounted for, the islet amyloid-related decrease in beta-cell mass (percent beta-cell mass/islet mass) was ameliorated in both <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi>- and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>-treated animals (57.9 +/- 3.1, 64.7 +/- 1.4, and 66.1 +/- 1.6% for control, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>-, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi>-treated mice, respectively; P &lt; 0.05 for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> vs. control) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In summary, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> protect beta-cells from the deleterious effects of islet amyloid, and this effect may contribute to the ability of these treatments to alleviate the progressive loss of beta-cell mass and function in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>