<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Effective type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> management requires prompt intervention if glycemic control is not achieved by nonpharmacological means </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study investigates whether inhaled insulin (INH; Exubera) can achieve target glycemic control in patients failing on diet and exercise </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Patients with suboptimal control on diet and exercise (HbA(1c) [A1C] 8-11%) were randomized to 3 months' treatment with either INH before meals (n = 76) or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> 4 mg twice a day (n = 69), in conjunction with a diet and exercise regimen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The primary end point was percentage of patients achieving A1C &lt;8.0% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The INH and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> groups had comparable baseline A1C values (9.5 vs. 9.4%, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Significantly more patients achieved A1C &lt;8.0% (83 vs. 58%, adjusted odds ratio 7.14 [95% CI 2.48-20.58], P = 0.0003), A1C &lt;7.0% (44 vs. 18%, 4.43 [1.94-10.12]), and A1C &lt; or = 6.5% (28 vs. 7.5% 5.34 [1.83-15.57]) with INH </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A1C decrease was greater with INH (-2.3% vs. -1.4%, adjusted treatment group difference: -0.89% [95% CI -1.23 to -0.55]) with final mean A1C values of 7.2 and 8.0% for INH and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi>, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>Hypoglycemia</z:hpo> (episodes per subject-month) was higher with INH (0.7 vs. 0.05, risk ratio 14.72 [95% CI 7.51-28.83]), with no severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001988'>hypoglycemic episodes</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Pulmonary function changes were small and comparable between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: INH could be an effective therapy for people with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> early in the course of their disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>