<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>Insulin resistance</z:hpo> plays a major role in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e>, and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>TRB3, a mammalian tribbles homolog, whose chromosomal region 20p13-p12 has been linked to human type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, impairs insulin signaling through the inhibition of Akt phosphorylation and is overexpressed in murine models of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We here report that the prevalent TRB3 missense Q84R polymorphism is significantly (P &lt; 0.05) associated with several <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>-related abnormalities in two independent cohorts (n = 178 and n = 605) of nondiabetic individuals and with the presence of a cluster of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0850624" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiovascular risk factors</z:e> in 716 type 2 diabetic patients (OR 3.1 [95% CI 1.2-8.2], P = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In 100 additional type 2 diabetic patients who suffered from <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0151744" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IHD">myocardial ischemia</z:e>, age at <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0151744" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IHD">myocardial ischemia</z:e> was progressively and significantly (P = 0.03) reduced from Q84Q to Q84R to R84R individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>To test the functional role of TRB3 variants, either Q84 or R84 TRB3 full-length cDNAs were transfected in human HepG2 <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019204" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">hepatoma</z:e> cell lines </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>As compared with control HepG2 cells, insulin-induced Ser473-Akt phosphorylation was reduced by 22% in Q84- (P &lt; 0.05 vs. control cells) and by 45% in R84-transfected cells (P &lt; 0.05 vs. Q84 transfected and P &lt; 0.01 vs. control cells) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These data provide the first evidence that TRB3 gene plays a role in human <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> and related clinical outcomes </plain></SENT>
</text></document>