<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A graded relationship has been reported between fasting and postprandial plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels and the subsequent risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1301700" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiovascular morbidity</z:e> and mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that the GCK -30G&gt;A promoter polymorphism is associated with elevated glycemia in the middle-aged general population of whites, as well as with features of the World Health Organization (WHO)-defined <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The GCK -30G&gt;A polymorphism was genotyped in the population-based Inter99 study cohort (5,965 subjects) and in 332 nondiabetic subjects and 1,063 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the Inter99 cohort, the GCK -30A allele was associated with increased fasting (P &lt; 0.001) and post-oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test (OGTT) plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels (P &lt; 0.001), and in the same cohort, the GCK -30A allele was more frequent among 1,325 subjects with the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> than among 1,679 subjects without any components of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> (P = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Moreover, the GCK -30A allele frequency was higher among 2,587 subjects with impaired <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> regulation (IGR) than among 4,773 glucose-tolerant subjects (17.3% [95% CI 16.2-18.3] vs. 15.0% [14.3-15.7], P &lt; 0.001, odds ratio GG vs. GA 1.21 [1.08-1.36], GG vs. AA 1.62 [1.17-2.24]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, the GCK -30G&gt;A polymorphism associates with elevated fasting and post-OGTT glycemia in the middle-aged general population of whites, as well as with IGR and other features of the WHO-defined <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>