<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Early <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> is generally considered to predict long-term weight outcome in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients, and this is reflected in prescribing guidelines for antiobesity drugs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>For example, the current prescribing guidelines for the antiobesity drug, sibutramine, indicate that if patients have not lost 2 kg (or 4 lb) in the first 4 weeks of treatment with sibutramine 10 mg, the physician should re-evaluate the therapy, which may result in increasing the dose to 15 mg or discontinuation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This regimen may deny treatment to a large group of patients who might otherwise benefit, particularly patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who often find it more difficult to lose weight than non-diabetic <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS: We have re-analysed pooled data from seven randomized, controlled studies of sibutramine-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> and maintenance in which patients (n = 928; 75% female) had taken sibutramine 10 or 15 mg continuously for 12 months, in order to determine the predictors of success in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> (defined as loss of at least 5% of initial body weight at Month 12) in both diabetic and non-diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Sensitivity and specificity analyses were used to calculate optimal predictive values </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In both diabetic and non-diabetic patients, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> of 4 kg at 3 months was identified as the optimal predictor for achieving at least 5% <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> at 12 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>This target was associated with the best average values for sensitivity, specificity and accuracy, as well as high positive (78% vs. 84% for non-diabetics and 76% vs. 85% for diabetics, compared to existing guidelines target of 2 kg after 1 month treatment) and negative predictive values (63% vs. 71% for non-diabetics; 52% vs. 70% for diabetics) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Sibutramine, in conjunction with diet and exercise, should be continued for at least 3 months (providing there are no adverse effects) to determine whether or not patients are likely to achieve a clinically valid outcome at 1 year </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This highlights the need to ensure that regulatory restrictions reflect the needs of clinical practice </plain></SENT>
</text></document>