<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: Serum proinsulin (PI) levels were investigated in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> children to determine whether PI is a sensitive indicator of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, as previously shown in adults with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (DM), and to evaluate their relationship with insulin-like growth factor-binding protein-1 (IGFBP-1) known as a predictor of the development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> in diabetic adults </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>SUBJECTS AND METHODS: Forty-two <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> children without DM (age, 12.1 +/- 1.5 year) and 42 age-matched control children were included in the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The serum levels of PI, immunoreactive insulin (IRI), IGFBP-1 and free insulin-like growth factor-1 (IGF-1) were measured in the fasting state </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The fasting levels of serum PI and IRI were significantly higher in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> children than in controls (PI, 10.5 +/- 6.8 vs. 5.6 +/- 2.0 pmol/l, p &lt; 0.001; IRI, 72.0 +/- 41.8 vs. 32.7 +/- 19.5 pmol/l, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Serum IGFBP-1 levels were significantly lower in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> children than in controls (37.7 +/- 24.6 vs. 76.3 +/- 26.5 microg/l, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The ratio of PI to IRI (calculated as molar ratios) did not differ significantly between <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> and control subjects (0.16 +/- 0.08 vs. 0.19 +/- 0.11, p = 0.08) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For the whole group, serum PI levels correlated positively with IRI and inversely with IGFBP-1 (IRI, r = 0.67, p &lt; 0.001; IGFBP-1, r = -0.49, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Serum IGFBP-1 levels correlated inversely with both BMI and IRI (BMI, r = -0.73, p &lt; 0.001; IRI, r = -0.60, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Multiple regression analysis revealed that the best predictive parameters for IGFBP-1 were BMI and PI (R2 = 0.57, p &lt; 0.001 and p &lt; 0.05, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: These findings suggest that fasting serum PI levels may be a better predictor than fasting insulin levels for the future development of type 2 DM and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> children, and PI, in addition to insulin, contributes to the suppression of hepatic IGFBP-1 production </plain></SENT>
</text></document>