<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The purpose of this study was to determine the effect of 24 weeks of treatment with 45 mg/day <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> on peripheral skin blood flow (SkBF) and skin nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> (NO) production in vivo in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This was a randomized, parallel, cross-over, double-blind, within- and between-subject study designed to compare vascular responses before and after treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We studied 12 subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (average age 58.6 +/- 30.8 years, HbA(1c) 7.9 +/- 00.4%, BMI 31.3 +/- 1.2 kg/m(2)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>SkBF was measured using laser Doppler techniques in response to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> reperfusion and local skin warming, and NO production was assessed in vivo using an amperometric NO meter inserted directly into the skin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>These measurements were performed before treatment and at 6 and 24 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The SkBF response was not significantly improved after 24 weeks in either of the groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>NO production was significantly decreased in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi>-treated group in the basal condition (area under the curve 6.4 +/- 1.0 vs. 2.8 +/- 0.8, P &lt; 0.01), after local heat stimulation at 40 degrees C (12.9 +/- 2.2 vs. 5.7 +/- 1.7, P &lt; 0.01), and after nociceptor stimulated flow with local heating at 44 degrees C (36.4 +/- 6.3 vs. 16.6 +/- 3.4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Differences were not significant in the placebo-treated group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Treatment of patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> for 24 weeks reduced skin NO production, thus probably reducing nitrosative stress without a demonstrable effect on SkBF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Because nitrosative stress is considered to be a factor in the pathogenesis of neurovascular dysfunction, these findings warrant further investigation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>