<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>Microalbuminuria</z:mp> is a risk factor for renal and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A role for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in the pathogenesis of <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> has been suggested but is still unproven </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In this case-control, cross-sectional study, we compared <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal rate (GDR), measured by hyperinsulinemic-euglycemic clamp, in 50 pairs of matched type 2 diabetic patients with micro- or normoalbuminuria (main study) and in 29 matched pairs of diabetic patients with macro- or <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> (substudy) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the main study, GDR was approximately 25% lower in micro- than in normoalbuminuric patients (5.20 +/- 1.91 vs. 6.86 +/- 2.88 mg  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>kg(-1)  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>min(-1), P &lt; 0.05) and was independently associated with <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> (P = 0.002), with each 1 mg  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>kg(-1)  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>min(-1) decrease predicting approximately 40% increased prevalence (odds ratio 1.37 [95% CI 1.14-1.70]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>Microalbuminuria</z:mp> was threefold more frequent in patients with GDR &lt; or =7.50 +/- 2.56 mg  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>kg(-1)  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>min(-1) than in those with higher GDR (60% vs. 20%, P &lt; 0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In the substudy, GDR in macro- and microalbuminuric patients was comparable (5.52 +/- 2.56 vs. 5.16 +/- 1.61 mg  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>kg(-1)  </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>min(-1)) and independent of macroalbuminuria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>GDR was significantly correlated with urinary albumin excretion rate in the main study (P = 0.004) but not in the substudy (P = 0.60) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>In type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, more severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> is independently associated with <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>Longitudinal studies are needed to clarify the role of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in the pathogenesis of <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> and related complications </plain></SENT>
</text></document>