<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: We sought to evaluate the effects of muraglitazar, a dual (alpha/gamma) peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor (PPAR) activator within the new glitazar class, on <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> abnormalities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A double-blind, randomized, controlled trial was performed in 1,159 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> inadequately controlled with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients received once-daily doses of either 5 mg muraglitazar or 30 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> for a total of 24 weeks in addition to open-label <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients were continued in a double-blind fashion for an additional 26 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Analyses were conducted at week 24 for HbA1c (A1C) and at week 12 for <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> parameters </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mean A1C at baseline was 8.12 and 8.13% in muraglitazar and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> groups, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At week 24, muraglitazar reduced mean A1C to 6.98% (-1.14% from baseline), and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> reduced mean A1C to 7.28% (-0.85% from baseline; P &lt; 0.0001, muraglitazar vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At week 12, muraglitazar and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> reduced mean plasma <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> (-28 vs. -14%), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> B (-12 vs. -6%), and non-<z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> (-6 vs. -1%) and increased <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> (19 vs. 14%), respectively (P &lt; 0.0001 vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> comparisons) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>At week 24, <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> (1.4 and 0.6 kg, respectively) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo> (9.2 and 7.2%, respectively) were observed in the muraglitazar and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> groups; at week 50, <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo> were 2.5 and 1.5 kg, respectively, and 11.8 and 8.9%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>At week 50, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>heart failure</z:hpo> was reported in seven patients (five with muraglitazar and two with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi>), and seven <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> occurred: three from <z:hpo ids='HP_0001699'>sudden death</z:hpo>, two from <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>cerebrovascular accident</z:hpo>, and one from <z:hpo ids='HP_0002894'>pancreatic cancer</z:hpo> in the muraglitazar group and one from perforated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002588'>duodenal ulcer</z:hpo> in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: We found that 5 mg muraglitazar resulted in greater improvements in A1C and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> parameters than a submaximal dose of 30 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> when added to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>Weight gain</z:mp> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo> were more common when muraglitazar was compared with a submaximal dose of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>