<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: About one of five patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001677'>coronary artery disease</z:hpo> (CAD) suffers from previously unknown, predominantly postprandial type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In the process of atherogenesis and the subsequent increased cardiovascular mortality of diabetic patients, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">endothelial dysfunction</z:e> is suspected to play an important role, and it is observed in diabetic as well as insulin-resistant states </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Thus, the aim of our study was to investigate the effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> on <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">endothelial dysfunction</z:e>, insulin sensitivity, and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control in newly detected type 2 diabetic patients with CAD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We investigated 42 patients (39 men and 3 women, age 60.25 +/- 7.5 years, HbA1c 6.1 +/- 0.5%) with manifest CAD and newly detected type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel study with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> (30 mg/day for 12 weeks) was performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>At study entry and end, we performed an oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test and measurements of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">endothelial dysfunction</z:e> by photoplethysmographic pulse wave analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Endothelial dysfunction</z:e> was severely impaired at baseline in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>After 12 weeks, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">endothelial dysfunction</z:e> was significantly better in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> group (change of reflection index 6.5 +/- 5.1 vs. 1.6 +/- 2.9%, P = 0.002) compared with placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Insulin sensitivity, as assessed by homeostasis model assessment (2.20 +/- 1.62 vs. 3.61 +/- 1.87, P = 0.01), or the change of insulin sensitivity index from baseline to study end (0.021 +/- 0.023 vs. -0.003 +/- 0.012 micromol x kg(-1) x min(-1) per pmol/l, P = 0.0001) and beta-cell function (57.42 +/- 49.86 vs. 21.78 +/- 18.54 mU/l per mmol/l, P = 0.0014) significantly improved in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> group, with no change observed after placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">Pioglitazone</z:chebi> improves <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">endothelial dysfunction</z:e> independently from the observed benefits on insulin sensitivity and beta-cell function in patients with newly diagnosed type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and CAD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>