<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>Obesity</z:hpo> is often associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> and the components of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, wide variations in insulin sensitivity are noted in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> youth </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>It is not clear if greater <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> confers a higher risk of cardiovascular comorbidities and risk for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We investigated physical and metabolic features of 54 <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> adolescents </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Subsequently, we pair matched 17 moderately insulin-resistant (MIR group) to 17 severely insulin-resistant (SIR group) youth based on cut points for insulin sensitivity (MIR group insulin sensitivity within 2 SDs and SIR group &lt;2 SDs of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath>-weight adolescent values) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We evaluated differences in body composition (dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry), abdominal fat (computed tomography scan), cardiorespiratory fitness (CRF) (Vo(2max) on a treadmill), insulin sensitivity and secretion (hyperinsulinemic-euglycemic and hyperglycemic clamps), substrate utilization (indirect calorimetry), and fasting adiponectin and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: SIR youth had higher visceral <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> (78.3 +/- 6.9 vs. 60.3 +/- 6.9 cm(2), P = 0.017) and waist-to-hip ratio (0.91 +/- 0.01 vs. 0.86 +/- 0.02, P = 0.026) and lower <z:chebi fb="17" ids="39025">HDL</z:chebi> (1.0 +/- 0.03 vs. 1.16 +/- 0.06 mmol/l, P = 0.015) than pair-matched MIR subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was a tendency for adiponectin (6.1 +/- 0.5 vs. 8.6 +/- 1.1 microg/ml, P = 0.079) and CRF (49.9 +/- 3.2 vs. 55.2 +/- 3.5 ml x min(-1) x kg(-1) fat-free mass, P = 0.09) to be lower in SIR subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>SIR youth also had an <z:mp ids='MP_0001525'>impaired balance</z:mp> between insulin sensitivity and beta-cell compensation with a lower <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposition index </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Despite similar BMI, the degree of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> impacts the risk for <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>-related metabolic comorbidities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The SIR youth are at greater risk for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>