<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50369">Chromium picolinate</z:chebi> (CrPic) supplementation has been suggested to improve glycemia, but there are conflicting reports on efficacy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We sought to determine the effect of CrPic on insulin sensitivity, glycemic control, and body composition in subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Thirty-seven subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>After baseline, subjects were placed on a <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> (glipizide gastrointestinal therapeutic system 5 mg/day) with placebo for 3 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Subjects were then randomized in a double-blind fashion to receive either the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> plus placebo (n = 12) or the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> plus 1,000 microg Cr as CrPic (n = 17) for 6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Body composition, insulin sensitivity, and glycemic control were determined at baseline, end of the 3-month single-blind placebo phase, and end of study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Subjects randomized to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi>/placebo, as opposed to those randomized to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi>/CrPic, had a significant increase in body weight (2.2 kg, P &lt; 0.001 vs. 0.9 kg, P = 0.11), percent body fat (1.17%, P &lt; 0.001 vs. 0.12%, P = 0.7), and total abdominal fat (32.5 cm(2), P &lt; 0.05 vs. 12.2 cm(2), P &lt; 0.10) from baseline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Subjects randomized to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi>/CrPic had significant improvements in insulin sensitivity corrected for fat-free mass (28.8, P &lt; 0.05 vs. 15.9, P = 0.4), GHb (-1.16%, P &lt; 0.005 vs. -0.4%, P = 0.3), and free fatty acids (-0.2 mmol/l, P &lt; 0.001 vs. -0.12 mmol/l, P &lt; 0.03) as opposed to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi>/placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This study demonstrates that CrPic supplementation in subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who are taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> agents significantly improves insulin sensitivity and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Further, CrPic supplementation significantly attenuated body <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> and visceral fat accumulation compared with the placebo group </plain></SENT>
</text></document>