<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: This controlled proof-of-concept study investigated inhaled insulin (INH) as adjunctive therapy to existing oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> agents in subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Twenty-four subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> [19 men and 5 women, 56.1 +/- 6.6 years, body mass index 32.7 +/- 4.2 kg/m(2), glycosylated <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> (HbA1c) 8.4 +/- 0.8% (mean +/- s.d.)] inadequately controlled by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> and/or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylureas</z:chebi> were randomized to receive additional therapy with either INH administered preprandially using a metered-dose inhaler (<z:chebi fb="5" ids="53218">MDI</z:chebi>), or insulin glargine (GLA) injected subcutaneously at bedtime for 4 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Both inhaled and injected insulin doses were titrated to predefined blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (BG) targets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: INH and GLA improved metabolic control to a similar extent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Mean daily BG decreased by 2.8 mmol/l in the INH group (p &lt; 0.001) and by 2.4 mmol/l in the GLA group (p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Accordingly, fasting BG (-2.7 vs. -3.6 mmol/l for INH vs. GLA), preprandial- and 2-h postprandial BG, HbA1c (-1.23 vs. -1.05%), body weight (-1.9 vs. -2.3 kg) and serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="24103">fructosamine</z:chebi> were similarly and significantly reduced in both groups (p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">Triglycerides</z:chebi> decreased significantly with INH (-1.15 micromol/l; p &lt; 0.001) but not with GLA [-0.52 micromol/l; not significant (NS)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Incidence rates of adverse events did not differ significantly, and there were no indications of respiratory tract irritation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> inadequately controlled by oral agents, preprandial administration of INH delivered by a <z:chebi fb="5" ids="53218">MDI</z:chebi> provided a comparable metabolic control to bedtime GLA and did not show any safety concerns during a 4-week treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These results warrant a more extensive investigation of preprandial treatment with INH in longer term studies </plain></SENT>
</text></document>