<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Young adults with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (T2Dm) present the clinician with the problem of when to start therapies for the primary prevention of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> and how to identify those at most vascular risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We examine whether the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> (MetS) can be a useful clinical tool to stratify vascular risk in this context </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Data were collected from 5928 subjects with T2Dm, and subjects were categorized as having MetS by World Health Organization criteria (body mass index criteria modified for Asians using &gt;23 kg/m2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of macrovascular disease was examined by MetS status and age </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The overall MetS prevalence was 72.3% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>MetS was associated with an increased prevalence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0151744" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="IHD">ischaemic heart disease</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IHD</z:e>) (17.2% MetS vs. 11.6% no MetS, p &lt; 0.0001), coronary artery bypass graft (7.6 vs. 4.7%, p &lt; 0.0003), <z:hpo ids='HP_0004950'>peripheral vascular disease</z:hpo> (PVD) (4.7 vs. 3.7%, p = 0.08) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> (6 vs. 3.9%, p = 0.002) across <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> age groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>MetS subjects had an <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IHD</z:e> prevalence equivalent to that seen in subjects who were one decade older without MetS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The most significant impact of MetS was for the age group of 40-49 years with much lesser impact seen with progressively increasing age [odds ratio (OR) = 2.1 for <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IHD</z:e> in MetS compared with no MetS at age 40-50 years, p &lt; 0.05; falling progressively to OR = 1.5 at age &gt;70 years, p &gt; 0.05] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Similar trends were seen for coronary artery by-pass graft (CABG) and PVD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There was a strong relationship between the number of MetS risk factors and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">IHD</z:e> prevalence (r = 0.99, p = 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These data suggest that MetS is particularly useful in stratifying vascular risk in younger T2Dm patients and in those with a high number of MetS components </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>For patients with MetS, especially those with a full house of MetS risk factors, commencing risk-lowering interventions 10 years earlier than their MetS-free counterparts could be considered </plain></SENT>
</text></document>