<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: We sought to examine the distribution of insulin and homeostasis model assessment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> (HOMA-IR) and associations of HOMA-IR with sex, race/ethnicity, age, and weight status, as measured by BMI, among U.S. adolescents </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Of 4,902 adolescents aged 12-19 years who participated in the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 1999-2002, analysis was performed for a nationally representative subsample of 1,802 adolescents without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who had fasting laboratory measurements </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The main outcome measure was HOMA-IR, calculated from fasting insulin and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and log transformed for multiple linear regression analyses </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In adjusted regression models that included age and weight status, girls had higher HOMA-IR than boys and Mexican-American children had higher HOMA-IR levels than white children </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There were no significant differences in adjusted HOMA-IR between black and white children </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>Obese</z:mp> children (BMI &gt;/=95th percentile) had significantly higher levels of HOMA-IR compared with children of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> weight (BMI &lt;85th percentile) in adjusted comparisons (mean HOMA-IR 4.93 [95% CI 4.56-5.35] vs. 2.30 [2.21-2.39], respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Weight status was by far the most important determinant of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, accounting for 29.1% of the variance in HOMA-IR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> adolescents was 52.1% (95% CI 44.5-59.8) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>Obesity</z:hpo> in U.S. adolescents represents the most important risk factor for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, independent of sex, age, or race/ethnicity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> children foreshadows a worrisome trend for the burden of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in the U.S </plain></SENT>
</text></document>