<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To project the long-term clinical and economic outcomes of treatment with biphasic insulin aspart 30 (BIAsp 70/30, 30% soluble and 70% protaminated insulin aspart) vs. insulin glargine in insulin-naïve type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> patients failing to achieve glycemic control with oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> agents alone (OADs) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Baseline patient characteristics and treatment effect data from the recent 'INITIATE' clinical trial served as input to a peer-reviewed, validated Markov/Monte-Carlo simulation model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>INITIATE demonstrated improvements in HbA1c favouring BIAsp 70/30 vs. glargine (-0.43%; p &lt; 0.005) and greater efficacy in reaching glycaemic targets among patients poorly controlled on OAD therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Effects on life expectancy (LE), quality-adjusted life expectancy (QALE), cumulative incidence of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-related complications and direct medical costs (2004 USD) were projected over 35 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Clinical outcomes and costs were discounted at a rate of 3.0% per annum </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Sensitivity analyses were performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Improvements in glycaemic control were projected to lead to gains in LE (0.19 +/- 0.24 years) and QALE (0.19 +/- 0.17 years) favouring BIAsp 70/30 vs. glargine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Treatment with BIAsp 70/30 was also associated with reductions in the cumulative incidences of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-related complications, notably in renal and <z:chebi fb="46" ids="15035">retinal</z:chebi> conditions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The incremental cost-effectiveness ratio was $46 533 per quality-adjusted life year gained with BIAsp 70/30 vs. glargine (for patients with baseline HbA1c &gt;/= 8.5%, it was $34 916) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Total lifetime costs were compared to efficacy rates in both arms as a ratio, which revealed that the lifetime cost per patient treated successfully to target HbA1c levels of &lt;7.0% and &lt;/= 6.5% were $80 523 and $93 242 lower with BIAsp 70/30 than with glargine, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Long-term treatment with BIAsp 70/30 was projected to be cost-effective for patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> insufficiently controlled on OADs alone compared to glargine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Treatment with BIAsp 70/30 was estimated to represent an appropriate investment of healthcare dollars in the management of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>