<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Japanese American is an ethnic group with a high risk for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, which is linked to the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Central <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> is considered to play a key role in the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Not known are the optimal cut point values for central and visceral <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> to identify Japanese Americans at risk for the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Study subjects included 639 Japanese Americans </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The nonadipose variables of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> were defined using modified International <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Federation criteria, and the accuracy of identifying at least two of these by intra-abdominal fat area (IAFA) as measured by computed tomography and waist circumference was cross-sectionally assessed using area under receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The values for IAFA and waist circumference that resulted in maximizing the Youden index were defined as "optimal." RESULTS: The area under the ROC curve for IAFA exceeded that for waist circumference (men 0.787 vs. 0.686; women 0.792 vs. 0.721) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For women, the optimal cut points for IAFA and waist circumference were 51.5 cm(2) and 80.8 cm (age &lt; or = 56 years) and 86.3 cm(2) and 89.0 cm (age &gt; 56 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>For men, the optimal cut points for IAFA and waist circumference were 88.6 cm(2) and 90.0 cm (age &lt; or = 57 years) and 96.1 cm(2) and 87.1 cm (age &gt; 57 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These results argue that current Japanese waist circumference cut points for the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> need to be revised </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Moreover, the waist circumference and IAFA cut points should be age specific, especially in women </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Appropriate waist circumference cut points are from 80 to 90 cm in women and from 87 to 90 cm in men </plain></SENT>
</text></document>