<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the efficacy of orlistat on the maintenance of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> over 3 years following a major <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> induced by very-low-energy diet (VLED) in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with metabolic risk factors such as <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e>, impaired fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, and diet-treated type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Initially, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> was induced by an 8-week VLED (600-800 kcal/day) in 383 patients with a mean BMI of 37.5 kg/m(2) (range 30.0-45.2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Those who lost &gt; or = 5% of their body weight (309 of 383 patients) were then randomized to receive lifestyle counseling for 3 years together with either orlistat 120 mg t.i.d. or matching placebo capsules </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Primary end points were the maintenance of &gt; or = 5% <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> after 3 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Additionally, differences in the development of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> between orlistat and placebo were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The VLED induced a mean <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> of 14.4 +/- 2.0 kg among the subsequently randomized patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> after 3 years was lower with orlistat than with placebo (4.6 +/- 8.6 vs. 7.0 +/- 7.1 kg; P &lt; 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The number of participants who achieved &gt; or =5% <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> also favored orlistat (67 vs. 56%; P = 0.037) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Waist circumference was significantly more reduced in the orlistat group (P &lt; 0.05), but no other differences in the risk factors were observed between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The incidences of new cases of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were significantly reduced in the orlistat group (8 cases out of 153 subjects) versus placebo (17 cases out of 156 subjects) (P = 0.041) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The addition of orlistat to lifestyle intervention was associated with maintenance of an extra 2.4 kg <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> after VLED for up to 3 years in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The combination of orlistat and lifestyle intervention was associated with a reduced occurrence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>