<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Metabolic syndrome</z:e> is a cluster of risk factors for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Definitions exist to identify those "at risk." Treatment of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019693" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">HIV infection</z:e> with highly active antiretroviral therapy can induce severe metabolic complications including <z:hpo ids='HP_0009125'>lipodystrophy</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to report the prevalence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> in HIV-infected patients and compare <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> and total body, limb, and visceral fat and adipokines in those with and without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This was an international cross-sectional study of a well-characterized cohort of 788 HIV-infected adults recruited at 32 centers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Metabolic syndrome</z:e> prevalence was examined using International <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Federation (IDF) and U.S </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>National Cholesterol Education Program Adult Treatment Panel III (ATPIII) criteria, relative to body composition (whole-body dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry and abdominal computed tomography), <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi>, glycemic parameters, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, leptin, adiponectin, and C-reactive protein (CRP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The prevalence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> was 14% (n = 114; 83 men) by IDF criteria and 18% (n = 139; 118 men) by ATPIII criteria; the concordance was significant but only moderate (kappa = 0.46, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Many patients (49%) had at least two features of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> but were not classified as having <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> as their waist circumferences or waist-to-hip ratios were in the non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> range </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Metabolic syndrome</z:e> was more common in those currently receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37670">protease inhibitors</z:chebi> (P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> prevalence was five- to ninefold higher in those with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>With IDF criteria, subjects with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> showed disturbances in <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> and adipokines: they had higher CRP (5.5 +/- 7.0 vs. 3.9 +/- 6.0 mg/l, P &lt; 0.003) and leptin (9 +/- 9 vs. 4 +/- 6 ng/ml, P &lt; 0.0001) and lower adiponectin (12 +/- 8 vs. 15 +/- 10 microg/ml, P &lt; 0.0001) levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>By ATPIII criteria, those with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> had higher leptin (6 +/- 8 ng/ml, P = 0.006) and lower adiponectin (15 +/- 10 vs. 18 +/- 8 microg/ml, P &lt; 0.0001) levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Metabolic syndrome</z:e> prevalence in HIV-positive adults was lower than that reported for the general population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Metabolic syndrome</z:e> was associated with a substantially increased prevalence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in this specific cohort </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Many subjects without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> had at least two <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> components (particularly elevated <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> levels) but did not meet waist circumference or waist-to-hip ratio cutoff <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> criteria in this group with high rates of body fat partitioning disturbances </plain></SENT>
</text></document>