<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS/HYPOTHESIS: We investigated glucagon responses during OGTT and isoglycaemic i.v. <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> infusion, respectively, to further elucidate the mechanisms behind the <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>glucose intolerance</z:hpo> in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: Ten patients (eight men) with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (age: 64 [51-80] years; BMI: 23 [21-26] kg/m(2); HbA(1c): 6.9 [6.2-8.7]%, values mean [range]) and ten control subjects matched for sex, age and BMI were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Blood was sampled on two separate days following a 4-h 50-g OGTT and an isoglycaemic i.v. <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> infusion, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Isoglycaemia during the 2 days was obtained in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In the control subjects no difference in glucagon suppression during the first 45 min of OGTT and isoglycaemic i.v. <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> infusion (-36 +/- 12 vs -64 +/- 23 mmol/l x 45 min; p = NS) was observed, whereas in the group of patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> significant glucagon suppression only occurred following isoglycaemic i.v. <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> infusion (-63 +/- 21 vs 10 +/- 16 mmol/l x 45 min; p = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The incretin effect was significantly reduced in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> compared with control subjects, but no significant differences in the secretion of glucagon-like <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi>-1 or <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-dependent insulinotropic <z:chebi fb="1" ids="15841">polypeptide</z:chebi> between the two groups during OGTT or isoglycaemic i.v. <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> infusion, respectively, could explain this </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS/INTERPRETATION: Attenuated and delayed glucagon suppression in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> occurs after oral ingestion of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, while isoglycaemic i.v. administration of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> results in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> suppression of glucagon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>We suggest that this phenomenon contributes both to the <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>glucose intolerance</z:hpo> and to the reduced incretin effect observed in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>