<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The aim of the study was to determine whether the loss of fasting and postprandial glycemic control occurs in parallel or sequentially in the evolution of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In 130 type 2 diabetic patients, 24-h <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> profiles were obtained using a continuous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> monitoring system </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The individuals with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were divided into five groups according to A1C levels: 1 (&lt;6.5%, n = 30), 2 (6.5-6.9%, n = 17), 3 (7-7.9%, n = 32), 4 (8-8.9%, n = 25), and 5 (&gt; or =9%, n = 26) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> profiles between the groups were compared </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The overall <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentrations for the diurnal, nocturnal, and morning periods, which represent the postprandial, fasting, and the dawn phenomenon states, respectively, were also compared </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi> concentrations increased steadily from group 1 to 5 in a stepwise manner </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The initial differences in mean <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentrations reaching statistical significance occurred 1) between groups 1 and 2 (6.4 vs. 7.7 mmol/l, P = 0.0004) for daytime postprandial periods, followed by differences; 2) between groups 2 and 3 (7.5 vs. 9.3 mmol/l, P = 0.0003) for the morning periods (dawn phenomenon); and finally 3) between groups 3 and 4 (6.3 vs. 8.4 mmol/l, P &lt; 0.0001) for nocturnal fasting periods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The deterioration of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> homeostasis in individuals with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> progressed from postprandial to fasting <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> following a three-step process </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The first step related to the three diurnal postmeal periods considered as a whole, the second step occurred during the morning period, and the third and final step corresponded to sustained <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> over the nocturnal fasting periods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Such a description of the key stages in the evolution of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> may be of interest for implementing antidiabetes treatment </plain></SENT>
</text></document>