<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Cardiovascular events are high in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, whereas their risk stratification is more difficult </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The higher risk may be related to differences in coronary plaque burden and composition </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to evaluate whether differences in the extent and composition of coronary plaques in patients with and without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> can be observed using multislice computed tomography (MSCT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: MSCT was performed in 215 patients (86 [40%] with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The number of diseased coronary segments was determined per patient; each diseased segment was classified as showing obstructive (&gt; or = 50% <z:chebi fb="2" ids="8069">luminal</z:chebi> narrowing) disease or not </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In addition, plaque type (noncalcified, mixed, and calcified) was determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Plaque characteristics were compared in patients with and without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Regression analysis was performed to assess the correlation between plaque characteristics and <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> showed significantly more diseased coronary segments than nondiabetic patients (4.9 +/- 3.5 vs. 3.9 +/- 3.2, P = 0.03) with more nonobstructive (3.7 +/- 3.0 vs. 2.7 +/- 2.4, P = 0.008) plaques </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Relatively more noncalcified (28 vs. 19%) and calcified (49 vs. 43%) and less mixed (23 vs. 38%) plaques were observed in patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> correlated with the number of diseased segments and nonobstructive, noncalcified, and calcified plaques </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Differences in coronary plaque characteristics on MSCT were observed between patients with and without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> was associated with higher coronary plaque burden </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>More noncalcified and calcified plaques and less mixed plaques were observed in diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Thus, MSCT may be used to identify differences in coronary plaque burden, which may be useful for risk stratification </plain></SENT>
</text></document>