<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine the prevalence of nonalcoholic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>fatty liver</z:hpo> disease (NAFLD) in type 2 diabetic population and to compare the prevalence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e>) and its risk factors between people with and without NAFLD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: The entire sample of type 2 diabetic outpatients (n = 2,839) who regularly attended our clinic was screened </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Main outcome measures were NAFLD (by patient history and liver ultrasound) and manifest <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> (by patient history, review of patient records, electrocardiogram, and echo-Doppler scanning of carotid and lower limb arteries) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The unadjusted prevalence of NAFLD was 69.5% among participants, and NAFLD was the most common cause (81.5%) of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>hepatic steatosis</z:hpo> on ultrasound examination </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of NAFLD increased with age (65.4% among participants aged 40-59 years and 74.6% among those aged &gt; or = 60 years; P &lt; 0.001) and the age-adjusted prevalence of NAFLD was 71.1% in men and 68% in women </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>NAFLD patients had remarkably (P &lt; 0.001) higher age and sex-adjusted prevalences of coronary (26.6 vs. 18.3%), cerebrovascular (20.0 vs. 13.3%), and peripheral (15.4 vs. 10.0%) <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> than their counterparts without NAFLD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In logistic regression analysis, NAFLD was associated with prevalent <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> independent of classical risk factors, glycemic control, medications, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> features </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: NAFLD is extremely common in people with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and is associated with a higher prevalence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Follow-up studies are needed to determine whether NAFLD predicts the development and progression of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>