<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Rapid-acting insulin analogs in basal-bolus regimens can reduce nocturnal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo>, so it is conceivable that twice-daily biphasic insulin analogs might reduce <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> in patients with insulin-treated type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We used a continuous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> monitoring system (CGMS) and self-reported episodes to investigate differences in the frequency of low <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> values in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, using either biphasic insulin aspart 30 (BIAsp 30) or biphasic human insulin 30 (BHI 30) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This was a double-blind, two-period, crossover trial involving 160 subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>After 8 weeks' run-in, subjects were randomized to the first of two 16-week treatment periods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: No differences in overall incidence of low interstitial <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (IG) were found </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Twenty-four-hour plots of CGMS showed low IG was more frequent at night than during the day and was unrecognized by patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At night, subjects spent significantly less time (percentage of total CGMS recorded) with IG &lt;3.5 and &lt;2.5 mmol/l during BIAsp 30 than during BHI 30 treatment, respectively (&lt;3.5 mmol/l: 6.36 vs. 7.93% [mean], 0.67 vs. 2.43% [median], P = 0.018; &lt;2.5 mmol/l: 2.35 vs. 2.86% [mean], 0 vs. 0% [median], P = 0.0467) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No treatment difference in A1C was observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Overall rates of low <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> over 24 h were not different but were twice as frequent at night than during the day in individuals with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Compared with BHI 30, BIAsp 30 was associated with similar low IG readings over 24 h but with fewer nocturnal episodes and less self-reported nocturnal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>