<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The effectiveness of intentional <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> in reducing <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e>) events in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This report describes 1-year changes in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> risk factors in a trial designed to examine the long-term effects of an intensive lifestyle intervention on the incidence of major <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This study consisted of a multicentered, randomized, controlled trial of 5,145 individuals with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, aged 45-74 years, with BMI &gt;25 kg/m2 (&gt;27 kg/m2 if taking insulin) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>An intensive lifestyle intervention (ILI) involving group and individual meetings to achieve and maintain <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> through decreased caloric intake and increased physical activity was compared with a <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> support and education (DSE) condition </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Participants assigned to ILI lost an average 8.6% of their initial weight vs. 0.7% in DSE group (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mean fitness increased in ILI by 20.9 vs. 5.8% in DSE (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A greater proportion of ILI participants had reductions in <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>, and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi>-lowering medicines </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Mean A1C dropped from 7.3 to 6.6% in ILI (P &lt; 0.001) vs. from 7.3 to 7.2% in DSE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Systolic and diastolic pressure, <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi>, and urine albumin-to-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> ratio improved significantly more in ILI than DSE participants (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: At 1 year, ILI resulted in clinically significant <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> in people with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This was associated with improved <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> control and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> risk factors and reduced medicine use in ILI versus DSE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Continued intervention and follow-up will determine whether these changes are maintained and will reduce <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> risk </plain></SENT>
</text></document>