<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Rho <z:chebi fb="1" ids="16235">guanine</z:chebi> nucleotide exchange factor 11 (ARHGEF11), located on chromosome 1q21, is involved in G protein signaling and is a pathway known to play a role in both insulin secretion and action </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We genotyped 52 single nucleotide polymorphims (SNPs) in ARHGEF11 and compared the genotype frequencies of subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (n = 145) or type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>/<z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo> (IGT) (n = 293) with those of control subjects with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance (NGT) (n = 358) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Thirty SNPs, spanning the entire gene, were significantly associated with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> or type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>/IGT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The most significantly associated SNP was rs6427340 (intron 2), in which the less common allele was the risk allele (odds ratio [OR] 1.82 [95% CI 1.20-2.70], P = 0.005 for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> vs. NGT and 1.79 [1.27-2.50], P = 0.0008 for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>/IGT vs. NGT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In an expanded set of nondiabetic subjects (n = 754), most of the type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-and IGT-associated SNPs were significantly associated with <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels during an oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test, with the same SNP (rs6427340) showing the most significant associations (P = 0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-and IGT-associated SNPs were in high linkage disequilibrium and constitute a single 133-kb haplotype block </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These results, coupled with similar findings in Pima Indians, suggest that sequence variation in ARHGEF11 may influence risk of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>