<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: It has been shown that adults with either long-standing type 1 or type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> had lower skeletal muscle strength than nondiabetic adults in cross-sectional studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of the study was to investigate longitudinal changes of muscle mass and strength in community-dwelling older adults with and without type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We examined leg and arm muscle mass and strength at baseline and 3 years later in 1,840 older adults aged 70-79 years in the Health, Aging, and Body Composition Study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Regional muscle mass was measured by dual energy X-ray absorptiometry, and muscle strength was measured using isokinetic and isometric dynamometers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Older adults with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (n = 305) showed greater declines in the leg muscle mass (-0.29 +/- 0.03 vs. -0.23 +/- 0.01 kg, P &lt; 0.05) and strength (-16.5 +/- 1.2 vs. -12.4 +/- 0.5 Nm, P = 0.001) compared with older adults without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Leg muscle quality, expressed as maximal strength per unit of muscle mass (Newton meters per kilogram), also declined more rapidly in older adults with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (-1.6 +/- 0.2 vs. -1.2 +/- 0.1 Nm/kg, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Changes in arm muscle strength and quality were not different between those with and without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Rapid declines in leg muscle strength and quality were attenuated but remained significant after controlling for demographics, body composition, physical activity, combined <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> diseases, interleukin-6, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> factor-alpha </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In older adults, type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is associated with accelerated loss of leg muscle strength and quality </plain></SENT>
</text></document>