<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To compare effects of early insulin vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> treatment on beta-cell function, metabolic control and quality of life (QL) in recently diagnosed patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Forty-nine patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> diagnosed 0-2 years before inclusion were randomized to two daily injections of premixed 30% soluble and 70% <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> at six diabetic clinics in Sweden </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi>-glucagon tests were performed yearly after 3 days of withdrawal of treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Thirty-four patients completed 4 years of study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Daily dose of insulin was increased from 20.4 +/- 1.8 U at year 1 to 26.1 +/- 2.9 U at year 4 (p = 0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">Glibenclamide</z:chebi> dosage increased from 2.7 +/- 0.4 mg at year 1 to 4.5 +/- 0.8 mg at year 4 (p = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Weight increased more in insulin than in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> treated (+4.4 +/- 0.8 vs. +0.3 +/- 1.0 kg, p &lt; 0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Following short-term withdrawal of treatment, the C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> responses to glucagon were significantly higher in the insulin vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> group at years 1 (p &lt; 0.01) and 2 (p &lt; 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>HbA1c improved identical during the first year but thereafter deteriorated in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> group (p &lt; 0.005 for difference at year 4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Ratios of proinsulin to insulin were higher during treatment in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi>- vs. insulin-treated patients after year 2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>QL after 4 years as measured by the MOS 36-item Short-Form Health Survey (SF-36) form was not significantly altered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In a 4-year perspective, beta-cell function deteriorated in both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>However, deterioration occurred faster in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi> group, indicating that alleviating demands on secretion by insulin treatment is beneficial </plain></SENT>
</text></document>