<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: The aim of this randomized placebo-controlled study was to evaluate the safety and efficacy of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> administered alone or in combination with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> in reducing insulin dosage requirements for improved glycaemic control in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> previously poorly controlled with combination therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In this multicentre, double-blind study, 222 patients with <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> A1c (HbA(1c))&gt;8.0% at screening treated with combination therapy initially were given titrated insulin therapy (to fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> &lt;140 mg/dl) and then were randomly assigned to 20-week treatment with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> or placebo in combination with insulin, with or without concurrent <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>More than 98% of patients were taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> prior to and during the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">Pioglitazone</z:chebi> significantly reduced (p &lt; 0.05) insulin dose requirements 2 weeks after treatment initiation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At study end relative to baseline, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> reduced daily insulin dosages by 12.0 units (p &lt; 0.001), a 21.5% (12.0/55.8 units at baseline) group mean average reduction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Relative to placebo, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> reduced daily insulin dosages by 12.7 units [95% confidence interval [CI]: -17.5, -8.0], while improving mean HbA(1c) levels [adjusted mean HbA(1c) change: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi>, -1.6% vs. placebo, -1.4% (not statistically different)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">Pioglitazone</z:chebi> also significantly increased <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47775">high-density lipoprotein cholesterol</z:chebi> levels [adjusted mean difference: +4.5 (95% CI: 2.6-6.5) mg/dl], <z:mp ids='MP_0005318'>decreased triglyceride levels</z:mp> [-43.9 (-69.2, -18.6) mg/dl], shifted <z:chebi fb="2" ids="39026">low-density lipoprotein</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi>) particle concentrations from small [pattern B, -13.6% (-17.7%, -9.5%)] to large [pattern A, +15.1% (10.8%, 19.5%)] and increased mean <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> particle size [+3.8 (2.6, 4.9) A] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>More <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi>-treated patients experienced <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>oedema</z:hpo> (9.0 vs. 4.5%) and <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> (9.1 vs. 2.7%) than placebo patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">Pioglitazone</z:chebi> in combination with insulin therapy improved glycaemic control, reduced insulin dose requirements and improved <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profiles in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> previously poorly controlled with combination therapy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>