<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> are <z:hpo ids='HP_0002155'>increased serum triglycerides</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003233'>decreased HDL cholesterol</z:hpo>, and a predominance of large <z:chebi fb="1" ids="39027">VLDL</z:chebi>, small <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi>, and small <z:chebi fb="17" ids="39025">HDL</z:chebi> particles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The comparative effects of thiazolidinedione <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50864">insulin sensitizers</z:chebi> on serum <z:chebi fb="1" ids="6495">lipoprotein</z:chebi> particle concentrations and sizes in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> are not known </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We studied the effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> (PIO) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> (ROSI) treatments on serum <z:chebi fb="1" ids="6495">lipoprotein</z:chebi> particle concentrations and sizes in type 2 diabetic patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This is a prospective, randomized, double-blind, multicenter, parallel-group study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After a 4-week placebo washout period, patients randomized to PIO (n = 369) were treated with 30 mg q.d. for 12 weeks followed by 45 mg q.d. for another 12 weeks, while patients randomized to ROSI (n = 366) were treated with 4 mg q.d. followed by 4 mg b.i.d. for the same intervals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="1" ids="6495">Lipoprotein</z:chebi> subclass particle concentrations and sizes were determined by proton nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy at baseline and end point (PIO [n = 333] and ROSI [n = 325] patients) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: PIO treatment increased total <z:chebi fb="1" ids="39027">VLDL</z:chebi> particle concentration less than ROSI treatment and decreased <z:chebi fb="1" ids="39027">VLDL</z:chebi> particle size more than ROSI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>PIO treatment reduced total <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> particle concentration, whereas ROSI treatment increased it </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Both treatments increased <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> particle size, with PIO treatment having a greater effect </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Whereas PIO treatment increased total <z:chebi fb="17" ids="39025">HDL</z:chebi> particle concentration and size, ROSI treatment decreased them; both <z:mp ids='MP_0001556'>increased HDL cholesterol levels</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: PIO and ROSI treatments have different effects on serum <z:chebi fb="1" ids="6495">lipoprotein</z:chebi> subclass particle concentrations and sizes in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>