<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To examine differences in telomere (terminal restriction fragment [TRF]) length and pulse wave velocity (PWV)--an index of arterial stiffness--in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with and without <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> (MA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A total of 84 men with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, 40 with MA and 44 without MA (aged 63.5 +/- 9.0 vs. 61.2 +/- 9.8 years), were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>TRF length was determined in white blood cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>MA was defined as albumin excretion rate (AER) in the range of 30-300 mg/24 h in at least two of three 24-h urine collections </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>PWV was assessed using applanation tonometry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Markers of <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> were also measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: TRF length was shorter in patients with MA than in those without MA (6.64 +/- 0.74 vs. 7.23 +/- 1.01 kb, respectively, P = 0.004) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>PWV was significantly higher in the patients with MA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Multivariate linear regression analysis in the total sample demonstrated an independent association between TRF length and age (P = 0.02), MA status (P = 0.04) or AER (P = 0.002), and plasma nitrotyrosine levels (P = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>AER was associated significantly with PWV (P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and MA have shorter TRF length and increased arterial stiffness than those without MA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Additionally, TRF length is associated with age, AER, and nitrosative stress </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>As shorter TRF length indicates older biological age, the increased arterial stiffness in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who have MA may be due to the more pronounced "aging " of these subjects </plain></SENT>
</text></document>