<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The purpose of this study was to compare two analog insulin therapies (prandial premixed therapy [<z:chebi fb="4" ids="53257">PPT</z:chebi>] versus basal/bolus therapy [BBT]) in type 2 diabetic patients previously treated with insulin glargine (&gt;or=30 units/day) plus oral agents, with the aim of demonstrating noninferiority of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="53257">PPT</z:chebi> to BBT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Patients were randomly assigned to <z:chebi fb="4" ids="53257">PPT</z:chebi> (lispro mix 50/50: 50% insulin lispro protamine suspension and 50% lispro; n = 187) t.i.d. with meals or BBT (glargine at bedtime plus mealtime lispro; n = 187) in a 24-week, multicenter, open-label, noninferiority trial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Investigators could replace lispro mix 50/50 with lispro mix 75/25 at the evening meal if the fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> target was unachievable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Baseline A1C was similar (<z:chebi fb="4" ids="53257">PPT</z:chebi> 8.8%; BBT 8.9%; P = 0.598) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At week 24, A1C was lower with BBT (6.78 vs. 6.95%, P = 0.021) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A1C was reduced significantly from baseline for both therapies (P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The difference in A1C change from baseline to the end point (BBT minus <z:chebi fb="4" ids="53257">PPT</z:chebi>) was -0.22% (90% CI -0.38 to -0.07) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Noninferiority of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="53257">PPT</z:chebi> to BBT was not demonstrated based on the prespecified noninferiority margin of 0.3% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The percentages of patients achieving target A1C &lt;7.0% (<z:chebi fb="4" ids="53257">PPT</z:chebi> versus BBT, respectively) were 54 vs. 69% (P = 0.009) and for target &lt;or=6.5% were 35 vs. 50% (P = 0.01) but did not differ for target &lt;or=6.0% or &lt;7.5% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Rates of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> were similar for both groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Although noninferiority of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="53257">PPT</z:chebi> to BBT was not demonstrated, findings for A1C reduction, percentage of patients achieving A1C targets, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo>, and number of required injections should be considered in the individual decision-making process of advancing insulin replacement to <z:chebi fb="4" ids="53257">PPT</z:chebi> versus BBT in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>