<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The aim of this study was to test the hypothesis that <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is independently associated with reduced lung function, both cross-sectionally and longitudinally </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We conducted cross-sectional and prospective analyses of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> status and lung function decline using baseline and 3-year follow-up data on 1,100 diabetic and 10,162 nondiabetic middle-aged adults from the <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>Atherosclerosis</z:hpo> Risk in Communities (ARIC) Study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Forced vital capacity (FVC) and forced expiratory volume in 1 s (FEV(1)) were measured at baseline and at the 3-year follow-up using standard spirometry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: At baseline, adults with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> had significantly lower predicted FVC (96 vs. 103%, P &lt; 0.001) and predicted FEV(1) (92 vs. 96%, P &lt; 0.001) than those without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>These differences remained significant after adjustment for demographic characteristics, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e>, smoking, physical activity index, education, and ARIC field center </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Graded, inverse associations were observed between <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo>, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> severity (i.e., duration of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and types of antidiabetes medications), and FVC and FEV(1) (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P(trend) &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In prospective analyses, FVC declined faster in diabetic adults than in their nondiabetic counterparts (64 vs. 58 ml/year, P = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> severity as indicated by intensity of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> treatment also showed graded relationships with the rate of FVC decline (P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These data support the notion that the lung is a target organ for diabetic injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Additional research is required to identify pathophysiologic mechanisms and to determine clinical significance </plain></SENT>
</text></document>