<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate the hypothesis that breast-feeding is associated with reduced type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> among African-American, Hispanic, and non-Hispanic white youth, mediated in part by current weight status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: The SEARCH Case-Control Study, an ancillary study to SEARCH for <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> in Youth, was conducted in two of six SEARCH clinical sites </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Eighty youth with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> aged 10-21 years were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Nondiabetic control participants were recruited from primary care provider offices (n = 167) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Breast-feeding information was recalled by biological mothers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Prevalence (%) of breast-feeding (any duration) was lower among youth with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> than among control subjects (19.5 vs. 27.1 for African Americans, 50.0 vs. 83.8 for Hispanics, and 39.1 vs. 77.6 for non-Hispanic whites) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The overall crude odds ratio for the association of breast-feeding (ever versus never) and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was 0.26 (95% CI 0.15-0.46) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Results were similar by race/ethnic group (P value for interaction = 0.17) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The odds ratio for the association after adjusting for 12 potential confounders was 0.43 (0.19-0.99) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>When current BMI z-score was added to the model, the odds ratio was attenuated (0.82 [0.30-2.30]), suggesting possible mediation through current childhood weight status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Analyses that incorporated duration of breast-feeding, adjusted for potential confounders, provided evidence for dose response (test for trend, P value &lt;0.0001), even after inclusion of BMI z-score </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Breast-feeding appears to be protective against development of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in youth, mediated in part by current weight status in childhood </plain></SENT>
</text></document>