<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: Self-monitoring of blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (SMBG) is important for patients treated with insulin to detect asymptomatic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> and to guide patients towards reaching blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> goal </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study compared two management programs for adjusting bedtime insulin dose: program 1 (performed by study subjects) vs. program 2 (performed by study subjects and reminded by investigators) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This is a prospective, open-level, 28-week randomized trial in poorly controlled type 2 diabetic subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>One hundred subjects treated with oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> drugs plus bedtime insulin with glycated <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> A(1C) (A1C) &gt;8.0% were screened and received a structure education package in a 4-week run-in period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Seventy-eight subjects were randomized to two treatment programs (adjust insulin dose by themselves with or without investigators' reminder) and reviewed by the investigators at a 4-week interval clinical visit </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The mean SMBG decreased significantly in both groups, with a greater decrease observed in program 2 vs. program 1 (from 198.7 +/- 43.1 to 122.6 +/- 21.9 mg/dl vs. from 194.0 +/- 42.7 to 151.6 +/- 37.7 mg/dl, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Bedtime insulin dose increased in both groups with a greater increase in program 2 (from 14.4 +/- 8.7 to 27.4 +/- 12.8 IU vs. from 14.3 +/- 8.3 to 18.4 +/- 6.2 IU, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was a significant reduction in A1C from 9.54 +/- 1.67% to 7.76 +/- 1.27%, with a greater decrease (p &lt; 0.001) in program 2 (2.17%) than in program 1 (1.40%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There were more subjects in the program 2 group achieving the treating targets: mean SMBG &lt; or =120 mg/dl (46.9 vs. 17.9%) and A1C &lt; or =7.0% (54.5 vs. 32.2%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There was no significant difference in the incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> and body weight changes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Systematically titrating bedtime insulin dose added to oral therapy, especially combined with health care reminders, can safely improve glycaemic control in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with poor glycaemic control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>This regimen may facilitate safe and effective insulin therapy in routine medical practice and improve achievement of recommended standards of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> care </plain></SENT>
</text></document>