<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Mammalian target of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9168">rapamycin</z:chebi> (mTOR) and its downstream target S6 kinase 1 (S6K1) mediate nutrient-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> by downregulating insulin receptor substrate proteins with subsequent reduced Akt phosphorylation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Therefore, mTOR/S6K1 inhibition could become a therapeutic strategy in insulin-resistant states, including type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We tested this hypothesis in the Psammomys obesus (P. obesus) model of nutrition-dependent type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, using the mTOR inhibitor <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9168">rapamycin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Normoglycemic and diabetic P. obesus were treated with 0.2 mg x kg(-1) x day(-1) i.p. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9168">rapamycin</z:chebi> or vehicle, and the effects on insulin signaling in muscle, liver and islets, and on different metabolic parameters were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Unexpectedly, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9168">rapamycin</z:chebi> worsened <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> in diabetic P. obesus without affecting glycemia in normoglycemic controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There was a 10-fold increase of serum insulin in diabetic P. obesus compared with controls; <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9168">rapamycin</z:chebi> completely abolished this increase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>This was accompanied by <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> and a robust increase of serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="3" ids="17087">ketone</z:chebi> bodies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9168">Rapamycin</z:chebi> decreased muscle insulin sensitivity paralleled by increased <z:chebi fb="15" ids="28087">glycogen</z:chebi> synthase kinase 3beta activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In diabetic animals, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9168">rapamycin</z:chebi> reduced beta-cell mass by 50% through <z:mp ids='MP_0006042'>increased apoptosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9168">Rapamycin</z:chebi> increased the stress-responsive c-Jun NH(2)-terminal kinase pathway in muscle and islets, which could account for its effect on <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> and beta-cell <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Moreover, <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-stimulated insulin secretion and biosynthesis were impaired in islets treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9168">rapamycin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9168">Rapamycin</z:chebi> induces fulminant <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> by increasing <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> and reducing beta-cell function and mass </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>These findings emphasize the essential role of mTOR/S6K1 in orchestrating beta-cell adaptation to <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>It is likely that treatments based on mTOR inhibition will cause exacerbation of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>