<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Several short-term trials on the effect of soy consumption on cardiovascular risks are available, but little evidence exists regarding the impact of long-term soy protein consumption among type 2 diabetic patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To determine the effects of long-term soy consumption on cardiovascular risks, we measured C-reactive protein (CRP) and kidney function indexes among type 2 diabetic patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This longitudinal randomized clinical trial was conducted among 41 type 2 diabetic patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> (18 men and 23 women) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Twenty patients in the soy protein group consumed a diet containing 0.8 g protein/kg body weight (35% animal proteins, 35% textured soy protein, and 30% vegetable proteins) and 21 patients in the control group consumed a similar diet containing 70% animal proteins and 30% vegetable proteins for 4 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Soy protein consumption significantly affected cardiovascular risks such as fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (mean change in the soy protein versus control groups: -18 +/- 3 vs. 11 +/- 2 mg/dl; P = 0.03), total cholesterol (-23 +/- 5 vs. 10 +/- 3 mg/dl; P = 0.01), <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47774">LDL cholesterol</z:chebi> (-20 +/- 5 vs. 6 +/- 2 mg/dl; P = 0.01), and serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> (-24 +/- 6 vs. -5 +/- 2 mg/dl; P = 0.01) concentrations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Serum CRP levels were significantly decreased by soy protein intake compared with those in the control group (1.31 +/- 0.6 vs. 0.33 +/- 0.1 mg/l; P = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Significant improvements were also seen in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000093'>proteinuria</z:hpo> (-0.15 +/- 0.03 vs. 0.02 +/- 0.01 g/day; P = 0.001) and urinary <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> (-1.5 +/- 0.9 vs. 0.6 +/- 0.3 mg/dl, P = 0.01) by consumption of soy protein </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Longitudinal soy protein consumption significantly affected <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0850624" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiovascular risk factors</z:e> and kidney-related biomarkers among type 2 diabetic patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>