<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To better define the efficacy and safety of rimonabant, the first selective cannabinoid type 1 (CB(1)) receptor <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, in a large population of overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients using pooled efficacy data from three Phase III nondiabetes Rimonabant in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>Obesity</z:hpo> and Related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0025517" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Metabolic Disorders</z:e> (RIO) studies, selected efficacy data from the RIO-<z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> study, and pooled safety data for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> four RIO studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: The RIO studies enrolled patients who were either overweight (BMI &gt;27 kg/m(2)) with at least one comorbidity (i.e., <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e>, or, for RIO-<z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp>, type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>) or <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients received daily treatment with rimonabant (5 or 20 mg) or placebo for 1 year plus a hypocaloric diet (600 kcal/day deficit) and advice on increased physical activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RIO-Europe (n = 1,508), RIO-North America (n = 3,045), and RIO-<z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">Lipids</z:chebi> (n = 1,036) excluded patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>; untreated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e> was an entry requirement for RIO-<z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">Lipids</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RIO-<z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> (n = 1,047) required the presence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> inadequately controlled by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> monotherapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The pooled intention-to-treat population comprised 5,580 patients without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (3,165 completed treatment) and 1,047 patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (692 completed treatment) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Most efficacy measures improved during the 4-week placebo run-in period, except that <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> decreased as expected in the early phase of a hypocaloric diet </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>After 1 year of randomized treatment, changes from baseline with 20 mg rimonabant in the nondiabetic population were as follows: body weight -6.5 kg, waist circumference -6.4 cm, <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> +16.4%, <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi> -6.9%, fasting insulin -0.6 muU/ml, and homeostasis model assessment for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> (HOMA-IR) -0.2 (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P &lt; 0.001 vs. placebo) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the diabetic population, 20 mg rimonabant reduced A1C levels by 0.6% (P &lt; 0.001 vs. placebo) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Regression analysis of change in <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi>, adiponectin (in RIO-<z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">Lipids</z:chebi>), and A1C (in RIO-<z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp>) versus body weight at 1 year by ANCOVA suggested that 45-57% of the effect of rimonabant could not be explained by the observed <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>At 1 year, adverse events more frequently reported with rimonabant were gastrointestinal, neurological, and psychiatric in nature </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Serious adverse events were infrequent and almost equivalent to placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Overall discontinuation rates were similar across treatment groups, except discontinuation from adverse events, which occurred more frequently with 20 mg rimonabant versus placebo (most commonly, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0868892,C0868894,C0011581,C0012706,C0868893" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">depressive disorders</z:e> [1.9 vs. 0.8%], <z:hpo ids='HP_0002018'>nausea</z:hpo> [1.4 vs. 0.1%], <z:hpo ids='HP_0100852'>mood alterations</z:hpo> with depressive symptoms [1.0 vs. 0.6%], and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000739'>anxiety</z:hpo> [1.0 vs. 0.3%]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>A thorough review of psychiatric and neurological adverse events was performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In overweight/<z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients, 20 mg/day rimonabant produced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> and significant improvements in multiple cardiometabolic risk factors such as waist circumference, A1C, <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Rimonabant was generally well tolerated, with more frequently reported adverse events being gastrointestinal, neurological, and psychiatric in nature </plain></SENT>
</text></document>