<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The hypothesis of <z:chebi fb="2" ids="23044">carotenoid</z:chebi> having a preventive role in <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is suggested by their <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> properties </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In this report, we investigated the relationship between baseline total plasma <z:chebi fb="2" ids="23044">carotenoid</z:chebi> levels and 9-year <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of dysglycemia (impaired fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> or type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>) in a healthy elderly population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: The Epidemiology of Vascular Ageing Study is a 9-year longitudinal study including 1,389 volunteers aged 59-71 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> was measured at baseline and at 2, 4, and 9 years after inclusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The relationship between plasma <z:chebi fb="2" ids="23044">carotenoid</z:chebi> at baseline and incidence of dysglycemia was determined by Cox proportional hazards regression analysis adjusting for potential confounders </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: At 9 years, 127 incident cases of dysglycemia had occurred </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Risk of dysglycemia was significantly lower in participants with plasma <z:chebi fb="2" ids="23044">carotenoid</z:chebi> in the highest quartile (Q4) compared with participants in the lowest quartile (Q1) (Q4 vs. Q1: relative risk 0.26 [95% CI 0.14-0.49], P &lt; 10(-4); Q3 vs. Q1: 0.55 [0.34-0.89], P = 0.01; and Q2 vs. Q1: 0.82 [0.51-1.31], P = 0.40) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>After controlling for sociodemographic variables, lifestyle habits, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e>, blood pressure, BMI, and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile, risk of dysglycemia remained significantly lower in participants in the highest quartile of total plasma <z:chebi fb="2" ids="23044">carotenoid</z:chebi> compared with participants in the lowest quartile (Q4 vs. Q1: 0.42 [0.22-0.82], P = 0.01; Q3 vs. Q1: 0.69 [0.41-1.15], P = 0.16; and Q2 vs. Q1: 0.80 [0.48-1.32], P = 0.38) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This study prospectively confirms that plasma <z:chebi fb="2" ids="23044">carotenoid</z:chebi> levels have an independent relationship to <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of dysglycemia </plain></SENT>
</text></document>