<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">Rosiglitazone</z:chebi> (RSG) is known to be an <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi> for the peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-gamma (PPARgamma) and promotes differentiation of pre-adipocytes into adipocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Leptin is highly correlated with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e>, while the activation of PPARgamma is known to inhibit Lep gene expression and leptin release </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study was performed to evaluate the relationship between changes in circulating leptin levels, insulin sensitivity and regional <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> after RSG treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Two hundred fifty-one type 2 diabetic patients (176 men and 75 women) who had been treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> and/or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> received 4 mg of RSG daily, in addition to the previous medications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Before and after RSG treatment (average duration 5.6+/-0.9 months), indices of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, metabolic parameters, and serum leptin and adiponectin levels were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Abdominal subcutaneous fat thickness (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SFT</z:e>(max)) and visceral fat thickness were measured by sonography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>After RSG treatment, HOMA-IR index decreased significantly (2.82+/-1.94 vs. 2.01+/-1.58), while BMI and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SFT</z:e>(max) increased, and leptin (4.72+/-3.77 vs. 5.69+/-4.30 ng/ml) and adiponectin levels (7.54+/-10.20 vs. 12.89+/-10.13 microg/ml) increased </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The increase in serum leptin correlated with an increase in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SFT</z:e>(max) (r=0.511, p&lt;0.001) and with a reduction in HOMA-IR (r=-0.368, p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The correlation of Delta leptin with Delta HOMA-IR and with Delta <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SFT</z:e>(max) was higher in females and among insulin-resistant subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, RSG improves the insulin sensitivity with increased serum leptin levels in patients with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo>, which is related to an increase in subcutaneous <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>