<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to determine if immune mechanisms in GAD positive patients' contribute to the pathogenesis of a specific sub-type of Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>GAD positive (n=8) and GAD negative (n=8) subjects diagnosed with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were matched for age, gender, body mass index, duration of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and glycaemic control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> subjects underwent an insulin-modified frequently sampled intravenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test to measure insulin sensitivity and insulin secretory function with minimal model analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In addition, BRIN-BD11 clonal beta-cells were supplemented with patients' sera to determine basal and alanine-stimulated insulin secretion and terminal complement complex (<z:chebi fb="15" ids="48347">TCC</z:chebi>) formation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Both groups were severely insulin resistant (0.56+/-0.17 vs. 0.99+/-0.3310(-4)min(-1)/(microUml(-1)) for GADneg and GADpos, respectively) but the GAD negative subjects had a higher basal (87+/-11 vs. 58+/-14pmoll(-1), p&lt;0.05) and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-stimulated insulin secretion (DeltaAUCins 0.96+/-0.12 vs. 0.60+/-0.12pmol/(l(-1)min), p&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In vivo measures of insulin secretion were negatively correlated with <z:chebi fb="15" ids="48347">TCC</z:chebi> formation, independent of antibody status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, GAD positive subjects initially diagnosed with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> are unable to compensate for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> due to more pronounced beta-cell impairment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="15" ids="48347">TCC</z:chebi> formation may be partly responsible for the insulin secretory dysfunction associated with this specific sub-type of Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>