<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The purpose of this study was to assess the <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-lowering efficacy and safety of rimonabant monotherapy in drug-naive type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: The Study Evaluating Rimonabant Efficacy in Drug-Naive Diabetic Patients (SERENADE) was a 6-month, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of 20 mg/day rimonabant in drug-naive patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (A1C 7-10%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The primary end point was A1C change from baseline; secondary end points included body weight, waist circumference, and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile changes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 281 patients were randomly assigned; 278 were exposed to treatment, and 236 (84.9%) completed the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Baseline A1C (7.9%) was reduced by -0.8% with rimonabant versus -0.3% with placebo (Delta A1C -0.51%; P = 0.0002), with a larger rimonabant effect in patients with baseline A1C &gt;or=8.5% (Delta A1C -1.25%; P = 0.0009) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>Weight loss</z:hpo> from baseline was -6.7 kg with rimonabant versus -2.8 kg with placebo (Delta weight -3.8 kg; P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Rimonabant induced improvements from baseline in waist circumference (-6 vs. -2 cm; P &lt; 0.0001), fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (-0.9 vs. -0.1 mmol/l; P = 0.0012), <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi> (-16.3 vs. +4.4%; P = 0.0031), and <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> (+10.1 vs. +3.2%; P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Adverse events of interest that occurred more frequently with rimonabant versus placebo were dizziness (10.9 vs. 2.1%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0002018'>nausea</z:hpo> (8.7 vs. 3.6%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0000739'>anxiety</z:hpo> (5.8 vs. 3.6%), depressed mood (5.8 vs. 0.7%), and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003401'>paresthesia</z:hpo> (2.9 vs. 1.4%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Rimonabant monotherapy resulted in meaningful improvements in glycemic control, body weight, and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile in drug-naive type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Further ongoing studies will better establish the benefit-to-risk profile of rimonabant and define its place in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> management </plain></SENT>
</text></document>