<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in the P2 promoter region of HNF4A were originally shown to be associated with predisposition for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in Finnish, Ashkenazi, and, more recently, Scandinavian populations, but they generated conflicting results in additional populations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We aimed to investigate whether data from a large-scale mapping approach would replicate this association in novel Ashkenazi samples and in U.K. populations and whether these data would allow us to refine the association signal </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Using a dense linkage disequilibrium map of 20q, we selected SNPs from a 10-Mb interval centered on HNF4A </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In a staged approach, we first typed 4,608 SNPs in case-control populations from four U.K. populations and an Ashkenazi population (n = 2,516) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In phase 2, a subset of 763 SNPs was genotyped in 2,513 additional samples from the same populations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Combined analysis of both phases demonstrated association between HNF4A P2 SNPs (rs1884613 and rs2144908) and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in the Ashkenazim (n = 991; P &lt; 1.6 x 10(-6)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Importantly, these associations are significant in a subset of Ashkenazi samples (n = 531) not previously tested for association with P2 SNPs (odds ratio [OR] approximately 1.7; P &lt; 0.002), thus providing replication within the Ashkenazim </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In the U.K. populations, this association was not significant (n = 4,022; P &gt; 0.5), and the estimate for the OR was much smaller (OR 1.04; [95%CI 0.91-1.19]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These data indicate that the risk conferred by HNF4A P2 is significantly different between U.K. and Ashkenazi populations (P &lt; 0.00007), suggesting that the underlying causal variant remains unidentified </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Interactions with other genetic or environmental factors may also contribute to this difference in risk between populations </plain></SENT>
</text></document>