<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To characterize insulin action in Africans with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001946'>ketosis</z:hpo>-prone <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (KPD) during remission </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: At Saint-Louis Hospital, Paris, France, 15 African patients with KPD with an average 10.5-month insulin-free near-normoglycemic remission period (mean A1C 6.2%) were compared with 17 control subjects matched for age, sex, BMI, and geographical origin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Insulin stimulation of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal, and insulin suppression of endogenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> production (EGP) and nonesterified fatty acids (NEFAs), was studied using a 200-min two-step (10 mU x m(-2) body surface x min(-1) and 80 mU x m(-2) x min (-1) insulin infusion rates) euglycemic clamp with [6,6-(2)H(2)]<z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> as the tracer </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Early-phase insulin secretion was determined during an oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The total <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal was reduced in patients compared with control subjects (7.5 +/- 0.8 [mean +/- SE] vs. 10.5 +/- 0.9 mg x kg(-1) x min(-1); P = 0.018) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>EGP rate was higher in patients than control subjects at baseline (4.0 +/- 0.3 vs. 3.0 +/- 0.1 mg x kg(-1) x min(-1); P = 0.001) and after 200-min insulin infusion (10 mU x m(-2) x min(-1): 1.6 +/- 0.2 vs. 0.6 +/- 0.1, P = 0.004; 80 mU x m(-2) x min(-1): 0.3 +/- 0.1 vs. 0 mg x kg(-1) x min(-1), P = 0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Basal plasma NEFA concentrations were also higher in patients (1,936.7 +/- 161.4 vs. 1,230.0 +/- 174.1 micromol/l; P = 0.002) and remained higher after 100-min 10 mU x m(-2) x min(-1) insulin infusion (706.6 +/- 96.5 vs. 381.6 +/- 55.9 micromol/l; P = 0.015) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The triad hepatic, adipose tissue, and skeletal muscle <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> is observed in patients with KPD during near-normoglycemic remission, suggesting that KPD is a form of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>