<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To evaluate family history (FH) of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (T2DM) as a risk factor for impaired fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (IFG), <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo> (IGT), T2DM and related metabolic traits in South East Asia and to compare the effects of a paternal versus maternal history </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We studied 4717 men and women (68% Chinese, 18% Malays and 14% Asian Indians) living in Singapore </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>FH was considered positive if at least one first degree relative had T2DM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>Obesity</z:hpo>, fasting <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and insulin levels were measured for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>Insulin resistance</z:hpo> (IR) was estimated by homeostasis model assessment (HOMA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>An oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test was carried for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> subjects except those on <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> medication </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A positive FH was associated with increased risk of IFG/IGT (OR=1.67, 95% CI=1.42-1.97) and T2DM (OR=2.95, 95% CI=2.36-3.70) as well as higher levels of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, HOMA-IR, fasting <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> (TG), and lower levels of <z:chebi fb="6" ids="39025">high density lipoprotein</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="17" ids="39025">HDL</z:chebi>) cholesterol and HOMA-beta </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A maternal history of T2DM appeared to have a greater impact on <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>-related traits than a paternal history of T2DM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Compared to individuals with no FH of T2DM, a maternal history was associated with (i) greater body mass index (BMI) (24.15kg/m(2) vs. 23.42kg/m(2), p=0.016) and waist-to-hip ratio (WHR) (0.874 vs. 0.865, p=0.037) in men; and (ii) greater WHR (0.788 vs. 0.779, p=0.004), fasting <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> (1.23mmol/L vs. 1.09mmol/L, p&lt;0.001), HOMA-IR (2.02 vs. 1.75, p&lt;0.001), fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (5.25mmol/L vs. 5.18mmol/L, p=0.005) and 2-h plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (6.01mmol/L vs. 5.78mmol/L, p=0.001) and lower <z:chebi fb="0" ids="47775">HDL-C</z:chebi> (1.41mmol/L vs. 1.47mmol/L, p=0.031) in women </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: T2DM appears to be heritable in South East Asians with excess maternal transmission of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, IR and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>