<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: We have determined 11-beta-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="35350">Hydroxysteroid</z:chebi> Dehydrogenase Type 1 (HSD11B1) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="18133">Hexose</z:chebi>-6-Phosphate Dehydrogenase (H6PD) <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression levels in adipose tissues from patients with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Six non-diabetic and seven diabetic male patients who undergo elective abdominal surgery were included in the study and visceral and subcutaneous adipose tissue samples were obtained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Fresh preadipocyte cultures were administered to low and high <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> medium (11M and 25M) in vitro for 24h and <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> extractions were performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>HSD11B1 and H6PD gene <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression levels were determined by real-time PCR and compared </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="17138">Glyceraldehyde-3-phosphate</z:chebi> Dehydrogenase (G3PD) <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> level is used as housekeeping gene expression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: HSD11B1 <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> levels were significantly higher in patient with T2DM than controls in both visceral and subcutaneous adipose tissues (3.35+/-0.7 vs. 0.37+/-0.1; P=0.01 and 2.07+/-0.8 vs. 0.11+/-0.05; P=0.01, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>H6PD <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> levels were also significantly higher in patient with T2DM than controls in both visceral and subcutaneous adipose tissues (3.95+/-1.2 vs. 1.95+/-0.8; P=0.050 and 2.23+/-1.1 vs. 0.46+/-0.1; P=0.043, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Failure to down-regulate HSD11B1 activity in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> may contribute to the pathogenesis of T2DM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Subcutaneous and visceral adipose tissues similarly exhibit the same variation in patients with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>