<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate ethnic differences in medication concerns (e.g., side effects and costs) that may contribute to ethnic differences in the adoption of and adherence to type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> treatments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We conducted face-to-face interviews from May 2004 to May 2006 with type 2 diabetic patients &gt; or =18 years of age (N = 676; 25% Latino, 34% non-Hispanic Caucasian, and 41% non-Hispanic African American) attending Chicago-area clinics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Primary outcomes of interest were concerns regarding medications and willingness to take additional medications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Latinos and African Americans had higher A1C levels than Caucasians (7.69 and 7.54% vs. 7.18%, respectively; P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Latinos and African Americans were more likely than Caucasians to worry about drug side effects (66 and 49% vs. 39%, respectively) and medication dependency (65 and 52% vs. 39%, respectively; both P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Ethnic minorities were also more likely to report reluctance to adding medications to their regimen (Latino 12%, African American 18%, and Caucasian 7%; P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In analyses adjusted for demographics, income, education, and <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> duration, current report of pain/discomfort with pills (odds ratio 2.43 [95% CI 1.39-4.27]), concern regarding disruption of daily routine (1.97 [1.14-3.42]), and African American ethnicity (2.48 [1.32-4.69]) emerged as major predictors of expressed reluctance to adding medications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Latinos and African Americans had significantly more concerns regarding the quality-of-life effects of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-related medications than Caucasians </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Whether these medication concerns contribute significantly to differences in treatment adoption and disparities in care deserves further exploration </plain></SENT>
</text></document>