<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Glycemic control decreases the incidence and progression of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0271672" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">diabetic complications</z:e> but increases the incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>Hypoglycemia</z:hpo> can impair hormonal and autonomic responses to subsequent <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Intensive glycemic control may increase mortality in individuals with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> at high risk for cardiovascular complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We tested the hypothesis that prior exposure to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> leads to impaired cardiovascular autonomic function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Twenty healthy subjects (age 28 +/- 2 years; 10 men) participated in two 3-day inpatient visits, separated by 1-3 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Autonomic testing was performed on days 1 and 3 to measure sympathetic, parasympathetic, and baroreflex function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A 2-h hyperinsulinemic [hypoglycemic (2.8 mmol/l) or euglycemic (5.0 mmol/l)] clamp was performed in the morning and in the afternoon of day 2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Comparison of the day 3 autonomic measurements demonstrated that antecedent <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> leads to 1) reduced baroreflex sensitivity (16.7 +/- 1.8 vs. 13.8 +/- 1.4 ms/mmHg, P = 0.03); 2) decreased muscle sympathetic nerve activity response to transient <z:chebi fb="0" ids="7596">nitroprusside</z:chebi>-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002615'>hypotension</z:hpo> (53.3 +/- 3.7 vs. 40.1 +/- 2.7 bursts/min, P &lt; 0.01); and 3) reduced (P &lt; 0.001) plasma <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> response to lower body negative pressure (3.0 +/- 0.3 vs. 2.0 +/- 0.2 nmol/l at -40 mmHg) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Baroreflex sensitivity and the sympathetic response to hypotensive stress are attenuated after antecedent <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Because impaired autonomic function, including decreased cardiac vagal baroreflex sensitivity, may contribute directly to mortality in <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e>, our findings raise new concerns regarding the consequences of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>