<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: There is a high prevalence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000135'>hypogonadism</z:hpo> in men with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This will lead to an increase in assessments of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000135'>hypogonadism</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">Statins</z:chebi> could potentially decrease <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> levels by reducing the availability of cholesterol for <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50113">androgen</z:chebi> synthesis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We compared <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> levels and hypogonadal symptoms with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statin</z:chebi> use in a cross-sectional study of 355 men with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Total <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="25" ids="50112">sex hormone</z:chebi>-binding globulin (SHBG), and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="23965">estradiol</z:chebi> were measured by an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Bioavailable <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> was measured by the modified <z:chebi fb="28" ids="28938">ammonium</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16189">sulfate</z:chebi> precipitation method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Free <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> was calculated using Vermeulen's formula </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Symptoms of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000135'>hypogonadism</z:hpo> were assessed using the <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50113">Androgen</z:chebi> Deficiency in the Aging Male questionnaire </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">Statins</z:chebi> were associated with lower total <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> (11.9 vs. 13.4 nmol/l, P = 0.006) and a trend toward lower SHBG (29.4 vs. 35.3 nmol/l, P = 0.034) compared with no treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Bioavailable <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi>, free <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="1" ids="23965">estradiol</z:chebi>, and hypogonadal symptoms were not affected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Subanalysis showed that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> was associated with reduced total <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> (11.4 vs. 13.4 nmol/l, P = 0.006) and a trend toward reduced SHBG (27.6 vs. 35.3 nmol/l, P = 0.022) compared with no treatment, and there was an apparent dose-response effect with the lowest levels of total <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> seen in men treated with &gt;or=20 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> (9.6 nmol/l, P = 0.017) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9150">Simvastatin</z:chebi> use was not associated with significant reductions in <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> or SHBG levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Assessing <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50113">androgen</z:chebi> status using total <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> in men with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statins</z:chebi>, particularly <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi>, may potentially lead to diagnostic error </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Levels of bioavailable <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> or free <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> are recommended for the assessment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000135'>hypogonadism</z:hpo> in this group if total <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> levels are borderline </plain></SENT>
</text></document>