<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To examine the efficacy and safety of vildagliptin vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> as add-on therapy to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> in patients with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> in a 52-week interim analysis of a large, randomized, double-blind, multicentre study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The primary objective was to demonstrate non-inferiority of vildagliptin vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> in glycosylated <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> (HbA(1c)) reduction at week 52 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Patients inadequately controlled on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> monotherapy (HbA(1c) 6.5-8.5%) and receiving a stable dose of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (mean dose 1898 mg/day; mean duration of use 36 months) were randomized 1:1 to receive vildagliptin (50 mg twice daily, n = 1396) or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> (titrated up to 6 mg/day; mean dose 4.5 mg/day, n = 1393) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Non-inferiority of vildagliptin was demonstrated (97.5% confidence interval 0.02%, 0.16%) with a mean (SE) change from baseline HbA(1c) (7.3% in both groups) to week 52 endpoint of -0.44% (0.02%) with vildagliptin and -0.53% (0.02%) with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Although a similar proportion of patients reached a target HbA(1c) level of &lt;7% with vildagliptin and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> (54.1 and 55.5%, respectively), a greater proportion of patients reached this target without <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> in the vildagliptin group (50.9 vs. 44.3%; p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) reductions were comparable between groups (mean [SE] -1.01 [0.06] mmol/l and -1.14 [0.06] mmol/l respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Vildagliptin significantly <z:mp ids='MP_0001262'>reduced body weight</z:mp> relative to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> (mean [SE] change from baseline -0.23 [0.11] kg; between-group difference -1.79 kg; p &lt; 0.001) and resulted in a 10-fold lower incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> than <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> (1.7 vs. 16.2% of patients presenting at least one hypoglycaemic event; 39 vs. 554 hypoglycaemic events, p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No severe <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> occurred with vildagliptin compared with 10 episodes with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> (p &lt; 0.01), and no patient in the vildagliptin group discontinued because of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> compared with 11 patients in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The incidence of adverse events (AEs), serious AEs and adjudicated cardiovascular events was 74.5, 7.1 and 0.9%, respectively, in patients receiving vildagliptin, and 81.1, 9.5 and 1.6%, respectively, in patients receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: When <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> alone fails to maintain sufficient glycaemic control, the addition of vildagliptin provides comparable efficacy to that of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> after 52 weeks and displays a favourable AE profile, with no <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> and a significant reduction in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> compared with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>