<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The purpose of this study was to examine the prevalence and correlates of elevated A1C in a large, nationally representative sample of adults without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in the U.S </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We analyzed data from 15,934 participants aged &gt;or=20 years without diagnosed <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who had A1C measurements in the 1999-2006 National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, a cross-sectional and nationally representative sample of the U.S. population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The overall prevalence of A1C &gt;6% was 3.8%, corresponding to 7.1 million adults without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in the U.S. population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Approximately 90% of these individuals had fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> &gt;or=100 mg/dl </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Older age, male sex, non-Hispanic black race/ethnicity, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003124'>hypercholesterolemia</z:hpo>, higher BMI, and lower attained education were significantly associated with having a higher A1C level even among individuals with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (&lt;100 mg/dl) and after multivariable adjustment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A single elevated A1C level (A1C &gt;6%) is common in the general population of adults without a history of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and is highly reliable for the detection of elevated fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Nondiabetic adults with elevated A1C are likely to have impaired fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and an array of other risk factors for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>