<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Both <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> are associated with increased morbidity and mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Published data suggest that orlistat 120 mg, a lipase inhibitor used to treat <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, may improve glycaemic parameters through <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo>-independent effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>AIM: To investigate the effect of orlistat 120 mg on <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo>, and assess whether changes in glycaemic parameters [fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) and <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> A1c (HbA1c)] are independent of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This retrospective analysis of pooled data from seven multicentre, double-blind, placebo-controlled studies involved overweight or <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (aged 18-70 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients were required to have a body mass index of 27-43 kg/m2, HbA1c of 6.5 to &lt;13%, and stable weight for &gt; or =3 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Subjects received orlistat 120 mg tid or placebo for 6 or 12 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 2550 overweight or <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were enrolled and randomized to treatment with orlistat 120 mg tid (n = 1279) or placebo (n = 1271) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>For the whole population, patients treated with orlistat 120 mg had significantly greater mean decreases in FPG compared with placebo-treated patients (-1.39 mmol/l vs. -0.47 mmol/l; p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In addition, orlistat 120 mg provided significantly larger mean decreases in HbA1c compared with placebo (-0.74% vs. -0.31%; p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>For patients with minimal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> (&lt; or =1% of baseline body weight), orlistat 120 mg still provided a significantly greater decrease in the least squares mean value for both FPG (-0.83 mmol/l vs. +/-0.02 mmol/l; p = 0.0052) and HbA1c -0.29% vs. +/-0.14%; p = 0.0008) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This suggested that the improvement of glycaemic control with orlistat 120 mg was independent of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Using linear regression analysis, improvement in glycaemic control (FPG and HbA1c) with orlistat 120 mg was less strongly correlated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> than for placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Orlistat 120 mg appears to improve glycaemic control more than would be predicted by <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> alone in overweight or <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Postulated mechanisms underlying this effect include an improvement of insulin sensitivity, a slower and incomplete digestion of dietary fat, reduction of postprandial plasma non-esterified fatty acids, decreased visceral adipose tissue, and stimulation of glucagon-like <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi>-1 secretion in the lower small intestine </plain></SENT>
</text></document>