<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the incidence, prevalence, and clinical characteristics of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> among U.S. non-Hispanic white (NHW) youth </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Data from the SEARCH for <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> in Youth Study (SEARCH study), a multicenter study of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> among youth aged 0-19 years, were examined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Incidence rates were calculated per 100,000 person-years across 4 incident years (2002-2005), and prevalence in 2001 was calculated per 1,000 youths </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Information obtained by questionnaire, physical examination, and blood and urine collection was analyzed to describe the characteristics of youth who completed an in-person visit </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The prevalence of type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (at ages 0-19 years) was 2.00/1,000, which was similar for male (2.02/1,000) and female (1.97/1,000) subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The incidence of type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was 23.6/100,000, slightly higher for male compared with female subjects (24.5 vs. 22.7 per 100,000, respectively, P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Incidence rates of type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> among youth aged 0-14 years in the SEARCH study are higher than <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> previously reported U.S. studies and many European studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Few cases of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in youth aged &lt;10 years were found </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (at ages 10-19 years) was 0.18/1,000, which is significantly higher for female compared with male subjects (0.22 vs. 0.15 per 1,000, P = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Incidence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was 3.7/100,000, with similar rates for female and male subjects (3.9 vs. 3.4 per 1,000, respectively, P = 0.3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>High levels of abnormal cardiometabolic and behavioral risk factor profiles were common among youth with both type 1 and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>For example, within each of four age-groups for youth with type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and two age-groups for youth with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, &gt;40% had elevated <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47774">LDL cholesterol</z:chebi>, and &lt;3% of youth aged &gt;10 years met current recommendations for intake of saturated fat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Among youth aged &gt;or=15 years, 18% with type 1 and 26% with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were current smokers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The SEARCH study is one of the most comprehensive studies of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in NHW youth </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>The incidence of type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in NHW youth in the U.S. is one of the highest in the world </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>While type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is still relatively rare, rates are several-fold higher than those reported by European countries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>We believe efforts directed at improving the cardiometabolic and behavioral risk factor profiles in this population are warranted </plain></SENT>
</text></document>