<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: Several mechanisms have been targeted as culprits of <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> during antihyperglycaemic treatment in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (T2DM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>These include reductions in <z:hpo ids='HP_0003076'>glucosuria</z:hpo>, increased food intake from fear of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e>, the anabolic effect of insulin, decreased metabolic rate and increased efficiency in fuel usage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The purpose of the study was to test the hypothesis that <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> efficiency increases as a result of insulin treatment in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We included ten patients with T2DM (eight males) on oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> treatment, median age: 51.5 years (range: 39-67) and body mass index (BMI): 30.1 +/- 1.2 kg/m2 (mean +/- s.e.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Muscle biopsies from m. vastus lateralis and m. deltoideus were obtained before and after seven weeks of intensive insulin treatment, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> respiration was measured using high-resolution respirometry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>State 3 respiration was measured with the substrates malate, <z:chebi fb="1" ids="15361">pyruvate</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="6" ids="14321,29987">glutamate</z:chebi>, succinate and <z:chebi fb="13" ids="16761">ADP</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>State 4o was measured with addition of oligomycine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>An age, sex and BMI-matched control group was also included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: HbA1c improved significantly and the patients gained on average 3.4 +/- 0.9 kg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Before treatment, respiratory control ratios (RCRs) of the T2DM were lower than the <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> controls [2.6 vs. 3.2 (p &lt; 0.05)], but RCR returned to the levels of the control subjects during treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Average state 4o of arm and leg declined by 14% (p &lt; 0.05) during insulin treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Tight glycaemic control leads to reductions in inner <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> membrane leak and increased efficiency of mitochondria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>This change in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> <z:mp ids='MP_0001532'>physiology</z:mp> could contribute to the <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> seen with antihyperglycaemic treatment </plain></SENT>
</text></document>