<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: The objective of this study is to assess the contribution of ADIPOQ variants to type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in Japanese Brazilians </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We genotyped 200 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (100 male and 100 female, aged 55.0 years [47.5-64.0 years]) and 200 control subjects with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerant (NGT) (72 male and 128 female, aged 52.0 years [43.5-64.5 years]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Whereas each polymorphism studied (T45G, G276T, and A349G) was not significantly associated with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo>, the haplotype GGA was overrepresented in our diabetic population (9.3% against 3.1% in NGT individuals, P=.0003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Also, this haplotype was associated with decreased levels of adiponectin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We also identified three mutations in exon 3: I164T, R221S, and H241P, but, owing to the low frequencies of them, associations with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> could not be evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The subjects carrying the R221S mutation had plasma adiponectin levels lower than those without the mutation (2.10 microg/ml [1.35-2.55 microg/ml] vs. 6.68 microg/ml [3.90-11.23 microg/ml], P=.015) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Similarly, the I164T mutation carriers had mean plasma adiponectin levels lower than those noncarriers (3.73 microg/ml [3.10-4.35 microg/ml] vs. 6.68 microg/ml [3.90-11.23 microg/ml]), but this difference was not significant (P=.17) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: We identified in the ADIPOQ gene a risk haplotype for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in the Japanese Brazilian population </plain></SENT>
</text></document>