<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: High levels of dietary fiber, especially soluble fiber, are recommended to lower serum cholesterol levels and improve glycemic control in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It is not clear, however, how high levels of fiber affect mineral balance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In a randomized crossover study, 13 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were fed a high-fiber (50 g total and 25 g soluble fiber) and a moderate-fiber (24 g total and 8 g soluble fiber) diet of the same energy, macronutrient, calcium, <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="81" ids="28659,35895">phosphorus</z:chebi> content for 6 weeks each </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Intestinal calcium absorption was determined by fecal recovery of (47)Ca </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Stool weight and mineral content were assessed during 3 days, and 24-h urinary mineral content and serum chemistry were assessed over 5 days at the end of each phase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The results were compared by repeated-measures ANOVA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Compared with the moderate-fiber diet, the high-fiber diet increased stool weight (165 +/- 53 vs. 216 +/- 63 g/day, P = 0.02) and reduced 24-h urinary calcium (3.3 +/- 1.7 vs. 2.4 +/- 1.2 mmol/day, P = 0.003) and <z:chebi fb="81" ids="28659,35895">phosphorus</z:chebi> (29.2 +/- 5.5 vs. 26.0 +/- 3.2 mmol/day, P = 0.003) excretion and serum calcium concentration (2.33 +/- 0.06 vs. 2.29 +/- 0.07 mmol/l, P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Calcium absorption, stool calcium, <z:chebi fb="131" ids="25107">magnesium</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="81" ids="28659,35895">phosphorus</z:chebi> content and serum <z:chebi fb="81" ids="28659,35895">phosphorus</z:chebi> concentration were not significantly different with the two diets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A high-fiber diet rich in soluble fiber has a small impact on calcium and <z:chebi fb="81" ids="28659,35895">phosphorus</z:chebi> balance in subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>It may be prudent to ensure adequate intake of calcium and other minerals in individuals consuming a high-fiber diet </plain></SENT>
</text></document>