<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM/HYPOTHESIS: The aim of the study was to investigate <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> function, fibre type distribution and substrate oxidation in arm and leg muscle during exercise in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> and lean controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Indirect calorimetry was used to calculate fat and carbohydrate oxidation during both progressive arm-cranking and leg-cycling exercises </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Muscle biopsies from arm and leg were obtained </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Fibre type, as well as <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15379">O(2)</z:chebi> flux capacity of saponin-permeabilised muscle fibres were measured, the latter by high resolution respirometry, in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, age- and BMI-matched <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> controls, and age-matched lean controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Fat oxidation was similar in the groups during either arm or leg exercise </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>During leg exercise at higher intensities, but not during arm exercise, carbohydrate oxidation was lower in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> compared with the other groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, <z:chebi fb="13" ids="16761">ADP</z:chebi>-stimulated state 3 respiration per mg muscle with parallel electron input from complex I+II was lower in m. vastus lateralis compared with <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> and lean controls, whereas no differences between groups were present in m. deltoideus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A higher percentage of type IIX fibres was seen in m. vastus lateralis in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> compared with <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> and lean controls, whereas no difference was found in the deltoid muscle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS/INTERPRETATION: This study demonstrates similar <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15379">O(2)</z:chebi> flux capacity, fibre type distribution and carbohydrate oxidation in arm muscle in the groups despite the presence of attenuated values in leg muscle in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> compared with <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> and lean controls </plain></SENT>
</text></document>