<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Multifaceted care has been shown to reduce mortality and complications in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that structured care would reduce renal complications in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A total of 205 Chinese type 2 diabetic patients from nine public hospitals who had plasma <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> levels of 150-350 micromol/l were randomly assigned to receive structured care (n = 104) or usual care (n = 101) for 2 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The structured care group was managed according to a prespecified protocol with the following treatment goals: blood pressure &lt;130/80 mmHg, A1C &lt;7%, <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47774">LDL cholesterol</z:chebi> &lt;2.6 mmol/l, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> &lt;2 mmol/l, and persistent treatment with renin-angiotensin blockers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The primary end point was <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> and/or renal end point (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> &gt;500 micromol/l or dialysis) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of these 205 patients (mean +/- SD age 65 +/- 7.2 years; disease duration 14 +/- 7.9 years), the structured care group achieved better control than the usual care group (diastolic blood pressure 68 +/- 12 vs. 71 +/- 12 mmHg, respectively, P = 0.02; A1C 7.3 +/- 1.3 vs. 8.0 +/- 1.6%, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>After adjustment for age, sex, and study sites, the structured care (23.1%, n = 24) and usual care (23.8%, n = 24; NS) groups had similar end points, but more patients in the structured care group attained &gt;or=3 treatment goals (61%, n = 63, vs. 28%, n = 28; P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients who attained &gt;or=3 treatment targets (n = 91) had reduced risk of the primary end point (14 vs. 34; relative risk 0.43 [95% CI 0.21-0.86] compared with that of those who attained &lt;or=2 targets (n = 114) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Attainment of multiple treatment targets reduced the renal end point and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In addition to protocol, audits and feedback are needed to improve outcomes </plain></SENT>
</text></document>