<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: The study evaluated the efficacy and tolerability of the dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor, vildagliptin, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> in drug-naïve elderly patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The primary objective was to demonstrate non-inferiority of vildagliptin vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> in glycated <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> (HbA1c) reduction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This was a double-blind, randomized, multicentre, active-controlled, parallel-group study of 24-week treatment with vildagliptin (100 mg daily, n=169) or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (titrated to 1500 mg daily, n=166) in drug-naïve patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> aged&gt;or=65 years (baseline HbA1c 7-9%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Participants had a mean age of 71 years, known duration of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> of 3 years and mean baseline HbA1c of 7.7% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At end-point, vildagliptin was as effective as <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, improving HbA1c by -0.64+/-0.07% and -0.75+/-0.07%, respectively, meeting the predefined statistical criterion for non-inferiority (upper limit of 95% confidence interval for between-treatment difference&lt;or=0.3%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Body weight changes were -0.45+/-0.20 kg in vildagliptin-treated patients (p=0.02) and -1.25+/-0.19 kg in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>-treated patients (p&lt;0.001; p=0.004 vs. vildagliptin) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The proportion of patients experiencing an adverse event (AE) was 44.3 vs. 50.3% in patients receiving vildagliptin and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Gastrointestinal (GI) AEs were significantly more frequent with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (24.8%) than with vildagliptin (15.0%, p=0.028), mainly driven by a 4.4-fold higher incidence of diarrhoea </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A low incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> was observed in both treatment groups (0% with vildagliptin and 1.2% with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Vildagliptin is an effective and well-tolerated treatment option in elderly patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, demonstrating similar improvement in glycaemic control as <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, with superior GI tolerability </plain></SENT>
</text></document>