<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To evaluate clinical efficacy and safety of biphasic insulin aspart (BIAsp) 30 twice daily (b.i.d.) vs. BIAsp 50 or BIAsp 70 (high-mix regimens) thrice daily (t.i.d.) <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> in combination with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> in a 36-week clinical trial in subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Efficacy measurements included <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> A(1c) (HbA(1c)) and eight-point plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (PG); safety included adverse events (AEs) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0745153" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemic episodes</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The three treatment groups (approximately 200 subjects in each group) were well matched regarding sex ratio, ethnicity, age and body mass index </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: After 12 weeks, 43% and 54% in the BIAsp 50 and 70 groups, respectively, switched their dinner insulin to BIAsp 30 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Both high-mix regimens were non-inferior to BIAsp 30 b.i.d., as measured by change in HbA(1c), and the BIAsp %50 regimen was superior </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The odds for meeting the American <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Association and The American Association of Clinícal Endocrinologist HbA(1c) targets of &lt;7% and &lt; or =6.5%, respectively, were significantly higher with the BIAsp 50 regimen than with BIAsp 30 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A significantly lower PG level was achieved from lunch until 02:00 hours with both high-mix regimens compared with BIAsp 30 b.i.d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>AEs were mild or moderate with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> three regimens </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Frequency of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0745153" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemic episodes</z:e> was comparable for the BIAsp 50 and the BIAsp 30 b.i.d. regimens but was significantly higher with BIAsp 70 t.i.d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Glycaemic control improved with BIAsp 50 t.i.d. without higher incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> compared with BIAsp 30 b.i.d.; with BIAsp 70 t.i.d. lower PG levels from lunch to 02.00 hours, but more <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0745153" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemic episodes</z:e> were obtained compared with BIAsp 30 b.i.d </plain></SENT>
</text></document>