<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To examine the association of glycemic status to magnetic resonance imaging indicators of brain pathological changes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This was a cross-sectional, population-based study of 4,415 men and women without <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> (mean age 76 years) participating in the Age Gene/Environment Susceptibility-Reykjavik Study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Glycemic status groups included the following: type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (self-report of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, use of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> medications, or fasting blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> &gt; or =7.0 mmol/l [11.1%]); impaired fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (IFG) (fasting blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> 5.6-6.9 mmol/l [36.2%]); and normoglycemic (52.7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Outcomes were total brain volume, white and gray matter volume, white matter lesion (WML) volume, and presence of cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: After adjustment for demographic and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0850624" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cardiovascular risk factors</z:e>, participants with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> had significantly lower total brain volume (72.2 vs. 71.5%; P &lt; 0.001) and lower gray and white matter volumes (45.1 vs. 44.9%, P &lt; 0.01 and 25.7 vs. 25.3%, P &lt; 0.001, respectively) and were more likely to have single (odds ratio 1.45 [95% CI 1.14-1.85]) or multiple (2.27 [1.60-3.23]) cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> compared with normoglycemic participants </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Longer duration of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was associated with lower total brain volume and gray and white matter volume, higher WML volume (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P(trend) &lt; 0.05), and a greater likelihood of single and multiple cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P(trend) &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Type 2 diabetic participants have more pronounced brain <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> and are more likely to have cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Duration of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is associated with brain changes, suggesting that type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> has a cumulative effect on the brain </plain></SENT>
</text></document>