<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To compare the efficacy and safety of adding mealtime pramlintide or rapid-acting insulin analogs (RAIAs) to basal insulin for patients with inadequately controlled type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In a 24-week open-label, multicenter study, 113 patients were randomly assigned 1:1 to addition of mealtime pramlintide (120 microg) or a titrated RAIA to basal insulin and prior oral antihyperglycemic drugs (OADs) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>At screening, patients were insulin naive or had been receiving &lt;50 units/day basal insulin for &lt;6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The basal insulin dosage was titrated from day 1, seeking fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) &gt; or =70-&lt;100 mg/dl </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Pramlintide and an RAIA were initiated on day 1 and week 4, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The proportion of patients achieving A1C &lt; or =7.0% without <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> or severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> at week 24 was the primary end point </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: More pramlintide- than RAIA-treated patients achieved the primary end point (30 vs. 11%, P = 0.018) with a similar dose of basal insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Pramlintide and an RAIA yielded similar mean +/- <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SEM</z:e> values for FPG and A1C at 24 weeks (122 +/- 7 vs. 123 +/- 5 mg/dl and 7.2 +/- 0.2 vs. 7.0 +/- 0.1%, respectively) and similar least squares mean reductions from baseline to end point (-31 +/- 6 vs. -34 +/- 6 mg/dl and -1.1 +/- 0.2 vs. -1.3 +/- 0.2%, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RAIAs but not pramlintide caused <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> (+4.7 +/- 0.7 vs. +0.0 +/- 0.7 kg, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Fewer patients reported mild to moderate <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> with pramlintide than with the RAIA (55 vs. 82%), but more patients reported <z:hpo ids='HP_0002018'>nausea</z:hpo> (21 vs. 0%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>No severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> occurred in either group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In patients taking basal insulin and OADs, premeal fixed-dose pramlintide improved glycemic control as effectively as titrated RAIAs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The pramlintide regimen sometimes caused <z:hpo ids='HP_0002018'>nausea</z:hpo> but no <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> and less <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>