<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To compare blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control when using biphasic insulin aspart (BIAsp) three times a day (using 70/30 high-mix before breakfast and lunch), with biphasic human insulin (BHI, 30/70) twice daily in adults with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> already treated with insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In a 60-day, open-label, crossover study, people with insulin-treated type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> [n = 38, baseline <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> A1c 8.3 +/- 0.9 (s.d.) %] were randomized to BIAsp three times a day before meals, as BIAsp 70 (70% insulin aspart and 30% protamine-complexed insulin aspart) before breakfast and lunch and BIAsp 30 (30/70 free and protamine-complexed insulin aspart) before dinner, or to human premix insulin (BHI) 30/70 twice a day before meals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A 24-h in-patient plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> profile was performed at the end of each 30-day treatment period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The total daily insulin dose of BIAsp regimen was 110% of BHI and the doses were not changed during the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There was no difference between BIAsp and BHI in geometric weighted average serum <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> over 24 h [7.3 vs. 7.7 mmol/l, BIAsp/BHI ratio 0.95 (95% CI 0.88-1.02), not significant (NS)], but daytime geometric weighted average <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentration was significantly lower with the BIAsp regimen than with BHI [8.3 vs. 9.2 mmol/l, BIAsp/BHI ratio 0.90 (0.84-0.98), p = 0.014] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The mealtime serum <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> excursion was also lower with BIAsp than with BHI with statistically significant differences at lunchtime [difference -4.9 (-7.0 to -2.7) mmol/l, p = 0.000); the difference in <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> excursions above 7.0 mmol/l was also significant [-5.8 (-8.3 to -3.2) mmol/l, p = 0.000) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The proportion of participants experiencing confirmed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0745153" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemic episodes</z:e> was similar between regimens (42 vs. 43%, NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: An insulin regimen using high-mix BIAsp (BIAsp 70) before breakfast and lunch and BIAsp 30 before dinner can achieve lower blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels during the day through reduced mealtime <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> excursions in particular at lunchtime than a twice-daily premix regimen </plain></SENT>
</text></document>