<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: We carried out an educational strategy to increase physician adherence to 8 recommendations for inpatient evaluation and management of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> endorsed by the American <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Association </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We evaluated physician attitude, barriers and facilitators to incorporate the proposed recommendations into clinical practice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We analyzed the impact of the educational strategy on process-of-care and outcome variables in 138 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> discharged from the internal medicine department before the intervention, at 3-month and at 9-month after the intervention </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: After the educational intervention there was a high motivation of physicians to adhere to the proposed recommendations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The intervention caused a significant reduction of insulin administered by sliding scale (50% vs. 7% vs. 3%, P=0.000), and in the median pre-discharge glycaemic values (185 mg/dL vs. 153 mg/dL vs. 161 mg/dL, P=0.005), in the three periods, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The use basal-bolus-correction insulin dosage increased in postintervention periods (17% vs. 85% vs. 99%, P=0.004) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Hypoglycaemia</z:e> (glycaemia &lt;60 mg/dL) episodes were similar among the three periods (0.30% vs. 0.70% vs. 1.07%, P=0.10) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The intervention required improvements to promote <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi>(A1c) ordering on admission and <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> intensification therapy at discharge when needed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our educational strategy improved physician adoption of practice guidelines </plain></SENT>
</text></document>