<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To examine the association between medication side-effects (SEs) and patient-reported outcomes (PROs) among patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> treated with oral antihyperglycaemic agents (OAHAs) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 1984 participants responded to an internet-based survey in the United States </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Data were collected on <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> 6 months and <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> 12 months prior to the survey </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Health-related quality of life (HRQoL) was measured using the EuroQol-5D (EQ-5D) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Also administered were the Treatment Satisfaction Questionnaire for Medication v.1.4 (TSQM) and the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Hypoglycaemia</z:e> Fear Survey II (HFS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Symptoms of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> were reported by 62.9% of participants, and 36.9% reported <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For those reporting <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e>, mean scores were lower for TSQM and EQ-5D and higher for HFS when compared with those with no symptoms (TSQM: 69.7 vs. 75.1; EQ-5D: 0.78 vs. 0.86; HFS: 17.5 vs. 6.2; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The same remained true when accounting for symptom severity, where severity was monotonically related with PRO scores (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Similarly, reported <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> was associated with lower treatment satisfaction (69.0 vs. 73.3) and HRQoL (0.77 vs. 0.83), and increased fear of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> (15.7 vs. 11.8) (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In mixed linear regression analysis, the associations between medication SEs and PROs remained significant after adjusting for patient and disease characteristics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Among patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> treated with OAHAs, self-reported <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> and <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> were associated with decreased treatment satisfaction and HRQoL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In addition, the presence of these SEs was associated with increased fear of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>