<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To describe the rationale for the European Exenatide (EUREXA) clinical study and describe the characteristics of the patient cohort </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: EUREXA is a multinational study of long-term effects of add-on exenatide vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and failure of diet/lifestyle plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> monotherapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">Metformin</z:chebi> failure was defined as <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> A1c (HbA1c) &gt; or = 6.5% and patients were overweight/<z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> (BMI &gt; or = 25 to &lt; 40 kg/m(2)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The primary end point is time to failure of combination treatment, defined from HbA1c concentration according to current criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At baseline, an oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test (OGTT) was performed, fasting blood was taken for <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile and patients were randomized to add-on exenatide (5 microg b.i.d. for 4 weeks then 10 microg b.i.d.) or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> (1 mg/day titrated to maximum dose) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 1039 patients were entered in the study, with mean (+/- s.d.) age 57.2 +/- 9.6 years, body mass index (BMI) 32.4 +/- 4.1 kg/m(2), duration of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> 5.6 +/- 4.5 years and HbA1c 7.4 +/- 0.7% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A history of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e>) was present for 64.8% of patients overall and duration of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was statistically significantly longer for patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> than without (p = 0.010) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">Lipid</z:chebi> abnormalities were reported for 48.9% of patients and 40.9% were taking at least one <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi>-lowering medication </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Patients included in the EUREXA study had early failure of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> and presented typical features of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>: overweight/<z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> and high prevalence of <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> abnormalities and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CVD</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In this population, the effects of exenatide vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> will be evaluated over at least 2.5 years </plain></SENT>
</text></document>