<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: There is growing evidence that osteocalcin, an osteoblast-derived protein locally acting on bone formation, can increase insulin secretion as well as insulin sensitivity and thus prevent the development of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> and <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in experimental animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In humans, osteocalcin has been reported to be decreased in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Because <z:hpo ids='HP_0009800'>gestational diabetes</z:hpo> mellitus (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GDM</z:e>) can serve as a model of pre-type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the aim of this study was to investigate osteocalcin in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GDM</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Osteocalcin measurement and an oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test were performed in 78 pregnant women (26 women had <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GDM</z:e> and 52 women had <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance [NGT] during pregnancy; women were matched for age and BMI) and in 34 women postpartum </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: During pregnancy osteocalcin was significantly higher in the women with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GDM</z:e> than in the women with NGT (15.6 +/- 6.4 vs. 12.6 +/- 4.0 ng/ml; P &lt; 0.015), whereas no difference was observed between the two groups at 12 weeks postpartum (36.2 +/- 10.2 vs. 36.2 +/- 13.0 ng/ml), when osteocalcin was found to be increased compared with the level in the pregnant state in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> women (+145 +/- 102% in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GDM</z:e> vs. +187 +/- 119% in NGT; P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Moreover, osteocalcin showed a significant correlation with basal and total insulin secretion in the whole study group (R = 0.3, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">GDM</z:e> osteocalcin was higher and thus less restrained than in women with NGT during pregnancy and furthermore correlated with insulin secretion parameters </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Therefore, it could be hypothesized that osteocalcin can enhance insulin secretion in insulin-resistant states; alternatively an effect of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000842'>hyperinsulinemia</z:hpo> on osteocalcin secretion cannot be excluded </plain></SENT>
</text></document>