<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Extracellular <z:chebi fb="9" ids="36976">nucleotides</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33838">nucleosides</z:chebi> are involved in regulation of skeletal muscle blood flow </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> induces cardiovascular dysregulation, but the extent to which the vasodilatatory capacity of <z:chebi fb="9" ids="36976">nucleotides</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33838">nucleosides</z:chebi> is affected in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The present study investigated 1) the vasodilatatory effect of ATP, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16704">uridine</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="15266,18036">triphosphate</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="6" ids="15713">UTP</z:chebi>), and <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> (ADO) and 2) the expression and distribution of P2Y(2) and P2X(1) receptors in skeletal muscles of diabetic subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: In 10 diabetic patients and 10 age-matched control subjects, leg blood flow (LBF) was measured during intrafemoral artery infusion of ATP, <z:chebi fb="6" ids="15713">UTP</z:chebi>, and ADO, eliciting a blood flow equal to knee-extensor exercise at 12 W (approximately 2.6 l/min) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The vasodilatatory effect of the purinergic system was 50% lower in the diabetic group as exemplified by an LBF increase of 274 +/- 37 vs. 143 +/- 26 ml/micromol ATP x kg, 494 +/- 80 vs. 234 +/- 39 ml/micromol <z:chebi fb="6" ids="15713">UTP</z:chebi> x kg, and 14.9 +/- 2.7 vs. 7.5 +/- 0.6 ml/micromol ADO x kg in control and diabetic subjects, respectively, thus making the <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35620">vasodilator</z:chebi> potency as follows: <z:chebi fb="6" ids="15713">UTP</z:chebi> control subjects (100) &gt; ATP control subjects (55) &gt; <z:chebi fb="6" ids="15713">UTP</z:chebi> diabetic subjects (47) &gt; ATP diabetic subjects (29) &gt; ADO control subjects (3) &gt; ADO diabetic subjects (1.5) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The distribution and <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression of receptors were similar in the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The vasodilatatory effect of the purinergic system is severely reduced in type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The potency of <z:chebi fb="9" ids="36976">nucleotides</z:chebi> varies with the following rank order: <z:chebi fb="6" ids="15713">UTP</z:chebi> &gt; ATP &gt; ADO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This is not due to alterations in receptor distribution and <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression, but may be due to differences in receptor sensitivity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>