<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> may occur as a result of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019693" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">HIV infection</z:e> and/or its treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="31654">Gliclazide</z:chebi> is a widely used drug for the treatment of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Efavirenz and nevirapine are widely used non-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="33838">nucleoside</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53756">reverse transcriptase inhibitors</z:chebi> for the treatment of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019693" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">HIV infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The role of Efavirenz and nevirapine on the pharmacodynamic activity of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31654">gliclazide</z:chebi> is not currently known </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study was to examine the effect of oral administration of efavirenz and nevirapine on blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and investigate their effect on the activity of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31654">gliclazide</z:chebi> in rats (<z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> and diabetic) and rabbits to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of the combination </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Studies in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> and alloxan induced diabetic rats were conducted with oral doses of 2 mg/kg bd. wt. of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31654">gliclazide</z:chebi>, 54 mg/kg bd. wt. of efavirenz or 18 mg/kg bd. wt. of nevirapine and their combination with adequate washout periods in between treatments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Studies in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> rabbits were conducted with 5.6 mg/1.5 kg bd. wt. of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31654">gliclazide</z:chebi>, 42 mg/1.5 kg bd. wt. of efavirenz or 14 mg/1.5 kg bd. wt. of nevirapine and their combination given orally </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Blood samples were collected at regular time intervals in rats from retro orbital puncture and by marginal ear vein puncture in rabbits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> the blood samples were analysed for blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> by GOD/POD method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Efavirenz and nevirapine alone have no significant effect on the blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> level in rats and rabbits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="31654">Gliclazide</z:chebi> produced hypoglycaemic/<z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> activity in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> and diabetic rats with peak activity at 2 h and 8 h and hypoglycaemic activity in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> rabbits at 3 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In combination, efavirenz reduced the effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31654">gliclazide</z:chebi> in rats and rabbits, and the reduction was more significant with the single dose administration of efavirenz than multiple dose administration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In combination, nevirapine has no effect on the activity of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31654">gliclazide</z:chebi> in rats and rabbits </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Thus, it can be concluded that the combination of efavirenz and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31654">gliclazide</z:chebi> may need dose adjustment and care should be taken when the combination is prescribed for their clinical benefit in diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>The combination of nevirapine and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31654">gliclazide</z:chebi> was safe </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>However, further studies are warranted </plain></SENT>
</text></document>