<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE The objective of this study was to determine the degree to which <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8774">ramipril</z:chebi> and/or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> changed beta-cell function over time among individuals with impaired fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (IFG) and/or <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo> (IGT) who participated in the <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Reduction Assessment With <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8774">Ramipril</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">Rosiglitazone</z:chebi> Medication (DREAM) Trial, which evaluated whether <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8774">ramipril</z:chebi> and/or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> could prevent or delay type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in high-risk individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS The present analysis included subjects (n = 982) from DREAM trial centers in Canada who had oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance tests at baseline, after 2 years, and at the end of the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>beta-Cell function was assessed using the fasting proinsulin-to-C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> ratio (PI/C) and the insulinogenic index (defined as 30-0 min insulin/30-0 min <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>) divided by homeostasis model assessment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> (insulinogenic index [IGI]/<z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> [IR]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS Subjects receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> had a significant increase in IGI/IR between baseline and end of study compared with the placebo group (25.59 vs. 1.94, P &lt; 0.0001) and a significant decrease in PI/C (-0.010 vs. -0.006, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In contrast, there were no significant changes in IGI/IR or PI/C in subjects receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8774">ramipril</z:chebi> compared with placebo (11.71 vs. 18.15, P = 0.89, and -0.007 vs. -0.008, P = 0.64, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The impact of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> on IGI/IR and PI/C was similar within subgroups of isolated IGT and IFG + IGT (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Effects were more modest in those with isolated IFG (IGI/IR: 8.95 vs. 2.13, P = 0.03; PI/C: -0.003 vs. -0.001, P = 0.07) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS Treatment with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi>, but not <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8774">ramipril</z:chebi>, resulted in significant improvements in measures of beta-cell function over time in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0362046" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">pre-diabetic</z:e> subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Although the long-term sustainability of these improvements cannot be determined from the present study, these findings demonstrate that the <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> preventive effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> was in part a consequence of improved beta-cell function </plain></SENT>
</text></document>