<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To characterize the relationships among long-term improvements in peripheral insulin sensitivity (<z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> disposal rate [GDR]), fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, and free fatty acids (FFAs) and concomitant changes in weight and adipose tissue mass and distribution induced by lifestyle intervention in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> individuals with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We measured GDR, fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, and FFAs during a euglycemic clamp and adipose tissue mass and distribution, organ fat, and adipocyte size by dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry, CT scan, and adipose tissue biopsy in 26 men and 32 women in the Look-AHEAD trial before and after 1 year of diet and exercise aimed at <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Weight and fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> decreased significantly (P &lt; 0.0001) and significantly more in men than in women (-12 vs. -8% and -16 vs. -7%, respectively; P &lt; 0.05), while FFAs during <z:hpo ids='HP_0000842'>hyperinsulinemia</z:hpo> decreased and GDR increased significantly (P &lt; 0.00001) and similarly in both sexes (-53 vs. -41% and 63 vs. 43%; P = NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Men achieved a more favorable fat distribution by losing more from upper compared with lower and from deeper compared with superficial adipose tissue depots (P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Decreases in weight and adipose tissue mass predicted improvements in GDR but not in fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> or fasting FFAs; however, decreases in FFAs during <z:hpo ids='HP_0000842'>hyperinsulinemia</z:hpo> significantly determined GDR improvements </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Hepatic fat was the only regional fat measure whose change contributed independently to changes in metabolic variables </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> undergoing a 1-year lifestyle intervention had significant improvements in GDR, fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, FFAs and adipose tissue distribution </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, changes in overall weight (adipose tissue mass) and hepatic fat were the most important determinants of metabolic improvements </plain></SENT>
</text></document>