<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Arterial stiffness occurs early in the atherosclerotic process; however, few data are available concerning risk factors for arterial stiffness in youth with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We identified factors associated with arterial stiffness in youth with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and assessed the effects of these factors on the relationship between arterial stiffness and <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> type (type 1 vs. type 2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A subset of patients from the SEARCH for <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> in Youth study with type 1 (n = 535) and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (n = 60), aged 10-23 years (52% male; 82% non-Hispanic white; <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> duration 65 +/- 49 months) had arterial stiffness, anthropometrics, blood pressure, fasting <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi>, and A1C measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Arterial stiffness was measured by brachial distensibility (brachD), pulse wave velocity (PWV), and augmentation index adjusted to heart rate of 75 beats/min (AI75) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Youth with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> had worse brachD (5.2 +/- 0.9 vs. 6.1 +/- 1.2%/mmHg), PWV (6.4 +/- 1.3 vs. 5.3 +/- 0.8 m/s), and AI75 (6.4 +/- 9.9 vs. 2.2 +/- 10.2%) than those with type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (P &lt; 0.01 for each) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>These differences were largely mediated through increased central <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> and higher blood pressure in youth with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We also found a pattern of association of arterial stiffness measures with waist circumference and blood pressure, independent of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> type </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Youth with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> have worse arterial stiffness than similar youth with type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Increased central <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> and blood pressure are associated with measures of arterial stiffness, independent of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> type </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Whether these findings indicate that youth with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> will be at higher risk for future complications requires longitudinal studies </plain></SENT>
</text></document>