<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The aim of this study was to investigate whether <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> B100 of <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> suffers increased damage by glycation, oxidation, and nitration in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, including patients receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: For this study, 32 type 2 diabetic patients and 21 healthy control subjects were recruited; 13 diabetic patients were receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> therapy (median dose: 1.50 g/day) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> was isolated from venous plasma by ultracentrifugation, delipidated, digested, and analyzed for protein glycation, oxidation, and nitration adducts by stable isotopic dilution analysis tandem mass spectrometry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Advanced glycation end product (AGE) content of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> B100 of <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> from type 2 diabetic patients was higher than from healthy subjects: arginine-derived AGE, 15.8 vs. 5.3 mol% (P &lt; 0.001); and lysine-derived AGE, 2.5 vs. 1.5 mol% (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Oxidative damage, mainly <z:chebi fb="0" ids="49033">methionine sulfoxide</z:chebi> residues, was also increased: 2.5 vs. 1.1 molar equivalents (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>3-Nitrotyrosine content was decreased: 0.04 vs. 0.12 mol% (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In diabetic patients receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> therapy, arginine-derived AGE and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="49033">methionine sulfoxide</z:chebi> were lower than in patients not receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>: 19.3 vs. 8.9 mol% (P &lt; 0.01) and 2.9 vs. 1.9 mol% (P &lt; 0.05), respectively; 3-nitrotyrosine content was higher: 0.10 vs. 0.03 mol% (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="24109">Fructosyl-lysine</z:chebi> residue content correlated positively with fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Arginine-derived AGE residue contents were intercorrelated and also correlated positively with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="49033">methionine sulfoxide</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> had increased arginine-derived AGEs and oxidative damage in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">apolipoprotein</z:chebi> B100 of <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This was lower in patients receiving <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> therapy, which may contribute to decreased oxidative damage, atherogenicity, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>