<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> when added to insulin therapy alone or in combination with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: After a 2 week placebo run-in period, eligible patients inadequately controlled on long-acting, intermediate-acting or premixed insulin (HbA1c &gt; or = 7.5% and &lt; or = 11%), were randomised 1:1 to the addition of once-daily <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> 100 mg or matching placebo over a 24-week study period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The study capped the proportion of randomised patients on insulin plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> at 75% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Further, the study capped the proportion of randomised patients on premixed insulin at 25% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> dose and the insulin dose were to remain stable throughout the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The primary endpoint was HbA1c change from baseline at week 24 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Mean baseline characteristics were similar between the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> (n = 322) and placebo (n = 319) groups, including HbA1c (8.7 vs. 8.6%), <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> duration (13 vs. 12 years), body mass index (31.4 vs. 31.4 kg/m(2)), and total daily insulin dose (51 vs. 52 IU), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At 24 weeks, the addition of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> significantly (p &lt; 0.001) reduced HbA1c by 0.6% compared with placebo (0.0%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A greater proportion of patients achieved an HbA1c level &lt; 7% while randomised to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> as compared with placebo (13 vs. 5% respectively; p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Similar HbA1c reductions were observed in the patient strata defined by insulin type (long-acting and intermediate-acting insulins or premixed insulins) and by baseline <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The addition of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> significantly (p &lt; 0.001) reduced fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> by 15.0 mg/dl (0.8 mmol/l) and 2-h postmeal <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> by 36.1 mg/dl (2.0 mmol/l) relative to placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>A higher incidence of adverse experiences was reported with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> (52%) compared with placebo (43%), due mainly to the increased incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi>, 16% vs. placebo, 8%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The number of hypoglycaemic events meeting the protocol-specified criteria for severity was low with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> (n = 2) and placebo (n = 1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>No significant change from baseline in body weight was observed in either group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: In this 24-week study, the addition of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> to ongoing, stable-dose insulin therapy with or without concomitant <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> improved glycaemic control and was generally well tolerated in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>