<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To compare the efficacy and safety of an intensified insulin regimen, using insulin glargine (glargine) once daily and pre-meal insulin glulisine (glulisine) (basal-bolus), with a conventional therapy, using premixed insulin (premix) twice daily </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This 52-week, open-label, randomized, multinational, multicentre trial included 310 subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (T2D) on premix, with or without <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, who were randomized to a basal-bolus regimen with glargine and glulisine (n = 153; mean +/- s.d. age 60.2 +/- 7.5 years; HbA1c 8.6 +/- 0.8%; weight 87.0 +/- 15.1 kg; T2D duration 12.8 +/- 5.8 years) or twice-daily premix (n = 157; age 60.9 +/- 7.8 years; HbA1c 8.5 +/- 0.9%; weight 84.3 +/- 15.0 kg; T2D duration 12.5 +/- 6.8 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The primary endpoint was change in HbA1c from baseline to endpoint </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Mean decrease in baseline-to-endpoint HbA1c for basal-bolus vs. premix was -1.31 vs. -0.80% (difference: -0.476%; 95% Cl: -0.714, -0.238; p = 0.0001, ancova) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>More subjects reached HbA1c &lt; or = 7.0% in the basal-bolus group than in the premix group [68 (46.6%) vs. 43 (27.9%); p = 0.0004], while they also experienced significantly lower mean +/- s.d. daytime (-2.7 +/- 2.3 vs. -2.3 +/- 2.5 mmol/l; p = 0.0033) and postprandial (-3.1 +/- 2.6 vs. -2.5 +/- 2.8 mmol/l; p &lt; 0.0001) blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Endpoint daily insulin doses were 98.0 +/- 48.7 vs. 91.3 +/- 44.3 IU (p = 0.2104); mean <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> was +3.6 +/- 4.0 vs. +2.2 +/- 4.5 kg (p = 0.0073) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Mean number of overall hypoglycaemic events with basal-bolus and premix was 13.99 and 18.54 events/patient year, respectively (difference: -3.90; 95% CI: -10.40, 2.60; p = 0.2385) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: An intensified basal-bolus regimen using glargine/glulisine results in a significantly superior glycaemic control vs. premix therapy in a population with long-standing insulin-treated T2D, with no increase in the rates of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>