<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The incretins glucagon-like <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi>-1 (GLP-1) and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-dependent insulinotropic <z:chebi fb="1" ids="15841">polypeptide</z:chebi> (GIP) account for up to 60% of postprandial insulin release in healthy people </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Previous studies showed a reduced incretin effect in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> but a robust response to exogenous GLP-1 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The primary goal of this study was to determine whether endogenous GLP-1 regulates insulin secretion in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Twelve patients with well-controlled type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and eight matched nondiabetic subjects consumed a breakfast meal containing <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15936,53455">D-xylose</z:chebi> during fixed <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> at 5 mmol/l above fasting levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Studies were repeated, once with infusion of the GLP-1 receptor <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, exendin-(9-39) (Ex-9), and once with saline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The relative increase in insulin secretion after meal ingestion was comparable in diabetic and nondiabetic groups (44 +/- 4% vs. 47 +/- 7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Blocking the action of GLP-1 suppressed postprandial insulin secretion similarly in the diabetic and nondiabetic subjects (25 +/- 4% vs. 27 +/- 8%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, Ex-9 also reduced the insulin response to intravenous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (25 +/- 5% vs. 26 +/- 7%; diabetic vs. nondiabetic subjects), when plasma GLP-1 levels were undetectable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The appearance of postprandial ingested d-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="18222">xylose</z:chebi> in the blood was not affected by Ex-9 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These findings indicate that in patients with well-controlled <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the relative effects of enteral stimuli and endogenous GLP-1 to enhance insulin release are retained and comparable with those in nondiabetic subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Surprisingly, GLP-1 receptor signaling promotes <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-stimulated insulin secretion independent of the mode of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> entry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Based on rates of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15936,53455">D-xylose</z:chebi> absorption, GLP-1 receptor blockade did not affect gastric emptying of a solid meal </plain></SENT>
</text></document>