<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: Sulphonylureas (SUs) are often used as first-line treatments for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in Japan, hence it is important to study new <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> drugs in combination with SUs in Japanese patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The efficacy and safety of the once-daily human glucagon-like <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi>-1 (GLP-1) analogue liraglutide were compared in 264 Japanese subjects [mean body mass index (BMI) 24.9 kg/m(2); mean glycated <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> (HBA1c) 8.4%] randomized and exposed to receive liraglutide 0.6 mg/day (n = 88), 0.9 mg/day (n = 88) or placebo (n = 88) each added to SU monotherapy (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi>, glicazide or glimeprimide) in a 24-week, double-blind, parallel-group trial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The mean change in HBA1c from baseline to week 24 (LOCF) was -1.56 (s.d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>0.84) and -1.46 (s.d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>0.95) with liraglutide 0.9 and 0.6 mg respectively, and -0.40 (s.d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>0.93) with placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>HBA1c decreased in the placebo group from 8.45 to 8.06%, while liraglutide reduced HBA1c from 8.60 to 7.14%, and from 8.23 to 6.67% at the 0.6 and 0.9 mg doses respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Mean HBA1c at week 24 of the two liraglutide groups were significantly lower than the placebo group (p &lt; 0.0001 for both) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>More subjects reached HBA1c &lt; 7.0% with liraglutide (0.6 mg: 46.5%; 0.9 mg: 71.3%) vs. placebo (14.8%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) levels were significantly improved with liraglutide (difference -1.47 mmol/l and -1.80 mmol/l with 0.6 and 0.9 mg vs. placebo; p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Overall safety was similar between treatments: no major <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0745153" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemic episodes</z:e> were reported, while 84/77/38 minor <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0745153" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemic episodes</z:e> occurred in the 0.6 mg/0.9 mg and placebo treatment groups (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> in combination with SU), reflecting lower ambient <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>No relevant change in mean body weight occurred in subjects receiving liraglutide (0.6 mg: 0.06 kg; 0.9 mg: -0.37 kg), while mean body weight decreased in subjects receiving placebo (-1.12 kg) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The addition of liraglutide to SU treatment for 24 weeks dose-dependently improved glycaemic control vs. SU monotherapy, without causing major <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> or <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> or loss </plain></SENT>
</text></document>