<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> (NO) is a key metabolic and vascular regulator </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Its production is stimulated by insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A reduced urinary excretion of NO products (NOx) is frequently found in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, particularly in association with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>However, whether the decreased NOx excretion in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is caused by a defective NOx production from arginine in response to <z:hpo ids='HP_0000842'>hyperinsulinemia</z:hpo> has never been studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We measured NOx fractional (FSR) and absolute (ASR) synthesis rates in type 2 diabetic patients with diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> and in control subjects, after l-[(15)<z:chebi fb="0" ids="17997">N(2)</z:chebi>-guanidino]-arginine infusion, and use of precursor-product relationships </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The study was conducted both before and after an euglycemic hyperinsulinemic ( approximately 1,000-1,200 pmol/l) clamp </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, NOx FSR was reduced both under basal (19.3 +/- 3.9% per day, vs. 22.9 +/- 4.5% per day in control subjects) and hyperinsulinemic states (24.0 +/- 5.6% per day, vs. 37.9 +/- 6.4% per day in control subjects; P &lt; 0.03 by ANOVA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Similarly, in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, NOx ASR was lower than in control subjects under both conditions (basal, 0.32 +/- 0.06 vs. 0.89 +/- 0.34 mol per day; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000842'>hyperinsulinemia</z:hpo>, 0.35 +/- 0.07 vs. 1.15 +/- 0.38 mol per day; P = 0.01 by ANOVA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the ability of insulin to stimulate both the FSR (4.7 +/- 3.2% per day) and the ASR (0.03 +/- 0.04 mol per day) of NOx was several-fold lower than that in control subjects (15.0 +/- 2.9% per day and 0.25 +/- 0.07 mol per day, P &lt; 0.03 and P &lt; 0.02, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Also the fraction of arginine flux converted to NOx (basal, 0.22 +/- 0.05% vs. 0.65 +/- 0.25%; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000842'>hyperinsulinemia</z:hpo>, 0.32 +/- 0.06% vs. 1.03 +/- 0.33%) was sharply reduced in the patients (P &lt; 0.01 by ANOVA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In type 2 diabetic patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo>, intravascular NOx synthesis from arginine is decreased under both basal and hyperinsulinemic states </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>This defect extends the concept of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> to NO metabolism </plain></SENT>
</text></document>