<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To evaluate the efficacy and safety of taranabant in overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (T2DM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This was a multicenter, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled study in overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with T2DM (ages &gt; or = 18 and &lt; or = 75 years) with a BMI &gt; or = 27 kg/m(2) and &lt; or = 43 kg/m(2) and HbA1c &gt; or =7.0 and &lt; or = 10.0%, who were either not on an antihyperglycaemic agent or on a stable dose of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (&gt; or = 1500 mg/day) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>After a 2-week placebo run-in, patients were randomized to placebo (N = 156) or taranabant 0.5-mg (N = 155), 1-mg (N = 157), or 2-mg (N = 155) once daily for 52 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Primary efficacy endpoints were changes from baseline in body weight (BW) and HbA1c at Week 36, with results at Week 52 being key secondary endpoints </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In the <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>-patients-treated population, using a last-observation-carried-forward analysis, reductions in BW were -2.5, -3.7, -4.5 and -5.1 kg at Week 36 and -2.4, -4.0, -4.6 and -5.3 kg at Week 52 in the placebo, 0.5-, 1- and 2-mg groups, respectively (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> doses significant vs. placebo at both time points) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The proportion of patients who lost &gt; or = 5 and &gt; or = 10% of their baseline BW was significantly greater in the 1- and 2-mg groups vs. placebo at Week 36 and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> taranabant groups vs. placebo at Week 52 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Reductions in HbA1c were -0.40, -0.47, -0.68 and -0.71% at Week 36 and -0.30, -0.43, -0.65 and -0.64% at Week 52, in the placebo, 0.5-, 1- and 2-mg groups, respectively (1- and 2-mg doses significant vs. placebo at both time points) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>After 52 weeks, the incidences of adverse experiences classified in the gastrointestinal (diarrhoea, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002018'>nausea</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002013'>vomiting</z:hpo>), <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system-related (dizziness, sensory-related), and psychiatric (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000737'>irritability</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000716'>depression</z:hpo>-related) organ systems were numerically higher or statistically significantly higher in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> taranabant groups compared with the placebo group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: After 36 and 52 weeks, treatment with taranabant at the 1- and 2-mg doses led to clinically significant <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> and improvement in glycaemic parameters in overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with T2DM that was associated with dose-related increases in adverse experiences </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Based on these data and data from other Phase III clinical studies, it was determined that the overall safety and efficacy profile of taranabant did not support further development for the treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>