<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>Weight loss</z:hpo> through lifestyle changes is recommended for nonalcoholic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>fatty liver</z:hpo> disease (NAFLD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, its efficacy in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is unproven </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Look AHEAD (Action for Health in <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp>) is a 16-center clinical trial with 5,145 overweight or <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> adults with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, who were randomly assigned to an intensive lifestyle intervention (ILI) to induce a minimum <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> of 7% or a control group who received <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> support and education (DSE) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>Fatty Liver</z:hpo> Ancillary Study, 96 participants completed proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy to quantify <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>hepatic steatosis</z:hpo> and tests to exclude other causes of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0023895" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">liver disease</z:e> at baseline and 12 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We defined <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>steatosis</z:hpo> &gt;5.5% as NAFLD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Participants were 49% women and 68% white </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean age was 61 years, mean BMI was 35 kg/m(2), mean <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>steatosis</z:hpo> was 8.0%, and mean <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29995">aspartate</z:chebi> aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) were 20.5 and 24.2 units/l, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>After 12 months, participants assigned to ILI (n = 46) lost more weight (-8.5 vs. -0.05%; P &lt; 0.01) than those assigned to DSE and had a greater decline in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>steatosis</z:hpo> (-50.8 vs. -22.8%; P = 0.04) and in A1C (-0.7 vs. -0.2%; P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There were no significant 12-month changes in AST or ALT levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>At 12 months, 26% of DSE participants and 3% (1 of 31) of ILI participants without NAFLD at baseline developed NAFLD (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A 12-month intensive lifestyle intervention in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> reduces <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>steatosis</z:hpo> and incident NAFLD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>