<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To examine the effect of intravenous iron and erythropoietin-stimulating agents (ESAs) on glycemic control and A1C of patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022658" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">kidney disease</z:e> (CKD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This was a prospective study of patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and CKD stage IIIB or IV undergoing intravenous iron (group A) and/or ESA (group B) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Full blood profiles were determined over the study period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Glycemic control was monitored using A1C, seven-point daily <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> three times weekly, and continuous <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> monitoring (CGM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were 15 patients in both group A and group B </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mean A1C (95% CI) values fell in both groups (7.40% [6.60-8.19] to 6.96% [6.27-7.25], P&lt;0.01, with intravenous iron and 7.31% [6.42-8.54] to 6.63% [6.03-7.36], P=0.013, ESA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There was no change in mean blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> in group A (9.55 mmol/l [8.20-10.90] vs. 9.71 mmol/l [8.29-11.13], P=0.07) and in group B (8.72 mmol/l [7.31-10.12] vs. 8.78 mmol/l [7.47-9.99], P=0.61) over the study period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">Hemoglobin</z:chebi> and hematocrit values significantly increased following both treatments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was no linear relationship found between the change in A1C values and the rise of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> following either treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Both iron and ESA cause a significant fall in A1C values without a change to glycemic control in patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and CKD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>At the present time, regular capillary <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> measurements and the concurrent use of CGM remain the best alternative measurements of glycemic control in this patient group </plain></SENT>
</text></document>