<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To compare the efficacy and safety of the rapid-acting insulin analog glulisine and regular insulin in hyperglycemic hospitalized patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A total of 180 hospitalized patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> received either glulisine (n = 88) or regular insulin (n = 92) before each meal in combination with insulin glargine at bedtime in a randomized double-blind fashion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> previous <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> medications were discontinued if applicable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Doses of insulin were adjusted to obtain target blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentrations of &lt;130 mg/dl before meals and at bedtime while avoiding <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Overall mean blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentrations were ∼ 8 mg/dl lower in the glulisine group than in the regular insulin group (152.6 ± 66.6 vs. 160.4 ± 70.8 mg/dl; P &lt; 0.0002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This improvement was wholly due to ∼ 22 mg/dl lower levels after 4 days of therapy (140 ± 55 vs. 162 ± 71 mg/dl; P &lt; 0.0007); after day 4, this difference progressively increased such that mean blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentrations from day 7 onward were ∼ 31 mg/dl lower in the glulisine group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean daily incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> was slightly but not significantly lower in the glulisine than the regular insulin group (0.10 ± 0.02 vs. 0.14 ± 0.03 episode/day; P &gt; 0.35) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In hospitalized type 2 diabetic patients, glulisine may provide better glycemic control than regular insulin, especially in those who have a prolonged length of stay </plain></SENT>
</text></document>