<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Reduction in <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> and high sensitivity (hs) C-reactive protein (CRP) are independent indicators of successful cardiovascular risk reduction with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statins</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study compared the effect of equivalent <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi>-lowering doses of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9150">simvastatin</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> on hsCRP in type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A crossover study of 26 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> taking either 40 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9150">simvastatin</z:chebi> or 10 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> was undertaken </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>After 3 months on one <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statin</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> and hsCRP were measured on 10 occasions over a 5-week period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The same procedure was then followed taking the other <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> was comparable on either treatment: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> 2.2 +/- 0.2 vs. 2.1 +/- 0.3 mmol/l (mean +/- SD; P = 0.19) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CRP of individuals taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> was significantly lower than when they were taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9150">simvastatin</z:chebi> (median 1.08 vs. 1.47 mg/l, P = 0.0002) and was less variable (median SD of logCRP 0.0036 vs. 0.178, P = 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Compared with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9150">simvastatin</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> reduced hsCRP and its variability in type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This enhanced anti-inflammatory effect may prove beneficial if lower CRP is associated with improved cardiovascular risk </plain></SENT>
</text></document>