<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Sustained <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> is associated with low cellular levels of the <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> (GSH), which leads to tissue damage attributed to <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We tested the hypothesis that diminished GSH in adult patients with uncontrolled type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is attributed to decreased synthesis and measured the effect of dietary supplementation with its precursors cysteine and glycine on GSH synthesis rate and <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We infused 12 diabetic patients and 12 nondiabetic control subjects with [²H₂]-glycine to measure GSH synthesis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We also measured intracellular GSH concentrations, reactive oxygen metabolites, and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="39" ids="44785">peroxides</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Diabetic patients were restudied after 2 weeks of dietary supplementation with the GSH precursors cysteine and glycine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Compared with control subjects, diabetic subjects had significantly higher fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (5.0 ± 0.1 vs. 10.7 ± 0.5 mmol/l; P &lt; 0.001), lower erythrocyte concentrations of glycine (514.7 ± 33.1 vs. 403.2 ± 18.2 μmol/l; P &lt; 0.01), and cysteine (25.2 ± 1.5 vs. 17.8 ± 1.5 μmol/l; P &lt; 0.01); lower concentrations of GSH (6.75 ± 0.47 vs. 1.65 ± 0.16 μmol/g Hb; P &lt; 0.001); diminished fractional (79.21 ± 5.75 vs. 44.86 ± 2.87%/day; P &lt; 0.001) and absolute (5.26 ± 0.61 vs. 0.74 ± 0.10 μmol/g Hb/day; P &lt; 0.001) GSH synthesis rates; and higher reactive oxygen metabolites (286 ± 10 vs. 403 ± 11 Carratelli units [UCarr]; P &lt; 0.001) and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="39" ids="44785">peroxides</z:chebi> (2.6 ± 0.4 vs. 10.8 ± 1.2 pg/ml; P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Following dietary supplementation in diabetic subjects, GSH synthesis and concentrations increased significantly and plasma <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="39" ids="44785">peroxides</z:chebi> decreased significantly </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Patients with uncontrolled type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> have severely deficient synthesis of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> attributed to limited precursor availability </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Dietary supplementation with GSH precursor amino acids can restore GSH synthesis and lower <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> and oxidant damage in the face of persistent <z:hpo ids='HP_0003074'>hyperglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>