<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To report the experience with vildagliptin in a patient population with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (T2DM) ≥75 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Efficacy data from seven monotherapy and three add-on therapy to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> studies, respectively, of ≥24 weeks duration were pooled; effects of 24 weeks of treatment with vildagliptin (50 mg bid) in patients ≥75 years were assessed in these two pooled datasets </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Safety data were pooled from 38 studies of ≥12 to ≥104 weeks duration; adverse events (AEs) profiles of vildagliptin (50 mg bid) were evaluated relative to a pool of comparators; 301 patients ≥75 years were analysed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Data in patients &lt;75 years are provided as a reference </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Mean age of the elderly population was 77 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Changes in <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> A1c (HbA1c) with vildagliptin in the patient group ≥75 years were -0.9% from a baseline of 8.3% in monotherapy (p &lt; 0.0001) and -1.1% from a baseline of 8.5% in add-on therapy to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (p = 0.0004), and these reductions were similar to those seen in the younger patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The corresponding weight changes in the elderly patients were -0.9 kg (p = 0.0277) and -0.2 kg [not significant (NS)], respectively, and no confirmed hypoglycaemic events, including no severe events, were reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>AEs, drug-related AEs, serious adverse events (SAEs) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo> were reported with a lower frequency in older patients receiving vildagliptin than comparators [133.9 vs. 200.6, 14.5 vs. 21.8, 8.8 vs. 16.5 and 0.0 vs. 1.7 events per 100 subject year exposure (SYE), respectively], and the incidence of discontinuations due to AEs was similar in the two groups (7.2 vs. 7.5 events per 100 SYE, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The safety profile of vildagliptin was overall similar in younger and older patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Vildagliptin was effective and well-tolerated in type 2 diabetic patients ≥75 years (mean age 77 years) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>