<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To evaluate the efficacy and safety of the potent and selective dipeptidyl peptidase-4 (DPP-4) inhibitor linagliptin administered as add-on therapy to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with inadequate glycaemic control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This 24-week, randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, parallel-group study was carried out in 82 centres in 10 countries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients with HbA1c levels of 7.0-10.0% on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> and a maximum of one additional antidiabetes medication, which was discontinued at screening, continued on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> ≥1500 mg/day for 6 weeks, including a placebo run-in period of 2 weeks, before being randomized to linagliptin 5 mg once daily (n = 524) or placebo (n = 177) add-on </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The primary outcome was the change from baseline in HbA1c after 24 weeks of treatment, evaluated with an analysis of covariance (ANCOVA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Mean baseline HbA1c and fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) were 8.1% and 9.4 mmol/l, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Linagliptin showed significant reductions vs. placebo in adjusted mean changes from baseline of HbA1c (-0.49 vs. 0.15%), FPG (-0.59 vs. 0.58 mmol/l) and 2hPPG (-2.7 vs. 1.0 mmol/l); <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> p &lt; 0.0001 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Hypoglycaemia</z:e> was rare, occurring in three patients (0.6%) treated with linagliptin and five patients (2.8%) in the placebo group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Body weight did not change significantly from baseline in both groups (-0.5 kg placebo, -0.4 kg linagliptin) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The addition of linagliptin 5 mg once daily in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> inadequately controlled on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> resulted in a significant and clinically meaningful improvement in glycaemic control without <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> or increased risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>