<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: This study compared the durability of glycemic control of twice-daily insulin lispro mix 75/25 (LM75/25: 75% insulin lispro protamine suspension/25% lispro) and once-daily insulin glargine, added to oral antihyperglycemic drugs in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: During the initiation phase, patients were randomized to LM75/25 or glargine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>After 6 months, patients with A1C ≤ 7.0% advanced to the maintenance phase for ≤ 24 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The primary objective was the between-group comparison of duration of maintaining the A1C goal </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of 900 patients receiving LM75/25 and 918 patients receiving glargine who completed initiation, 473 and 419, respectively, had A1C ≤ 7.0% and continued into maintenance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Baseline characteristics except age were similar in this group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Median time of maintaining the A1C goal was 16.8 months for LM75/25 (95% CI 14.0-19.7) and 14.4 months for glargine (95% CI 13.4-16.8; P = 0.040) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A1C goal was maintained in 202 LM75/25-treated patients (43%) and in 147 glargine-treated patients (35%; P = 0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>No differences were observed in overall, nocturnal, or severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>LM75/25 patients had higher total daily insulin dose (0.45 ± 0.21 vs. 0.37 ± 0.21 units/kg/day) and more <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> (5.4 ± 5.8 vs. 3.7 ± 5.6 kg) from baseline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Patients taking LM75/25 and glargine with lower baseline A1C levels were more likely to maintain the A1C goal (P = 0.043 and P &lt; 0.001, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A modestly longer durability of glycemic control was achieved with LM75/25 compared with glargine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Patients with lower baseline A1C levels were more likely to maintain the goal, supporting the concept of earlier insulin initiation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>