<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: We aimed to explore an optimal anthropometric indicator and optimal cut-off points for incident <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in Chinese adults </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: 61,703 subjects were followed for a median duration of 2 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Body mass index, waist circumference, waist-to-hip ratio and waist-to-height ratio were collected base on a standard protocol </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Receiver Operating Characteristic curve analyses were used to compare the predictive power of baseline BMI, WC, WHpR and WHtR for development of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were 2991 new cases of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> during follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>ROC curve analyses indicated that WHtR was the best predictor of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> for male (AUC = 0.633) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>For female, WHtR and WC had similar predictive ability (AUC = 0.701 and 0.695 respectively) and were superior to BMI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>WHpR was the weakest predictor in both genders </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The optimal WHtR cut-off values for incidence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were similar in both genders (0.53 vs. 0.52) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>BMI was higher in men (26 kg/m(2)) than women (24 kg/m(2)); and so did WC (91 cm in men vs. 85 cm in women) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: WHtR, and to some degree WC, are the best predictors of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, followed by BMI then WHpR which is the weakest predictor in the tested adults </plain></SENT>
</text></document>