<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To evaluate the efficacy and safety of saxagliptin vs. placebo in patients with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (T2DM) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0341697" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">renal impairment</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In this multicentre, randomized, parallel-group, double-blind, placebo-controlled study, patients with glycated <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> (HbA1c) 7-11% and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> clearance &lt;50 ml/min were stratified by baseline <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0341697" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">renal impairment</z:e> (moderate, severe or end-stage on haemodialysis), and randomized (1 : 1) to saxagliptin 2.5 mg once daily or placebo for 12 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Oral antihyperglycaemic drugs and insulin therapy present at enrolment were continued throughout the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The absolute change in HbA1c from baseline to week 12 (primary efficacy end-point) was analysed using an analysis of covariance model with last observation carried forward methodology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 170 patients were randomized and treated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The adjusted mean decrease from baseline to week 12 in HbA1c was statistically significantly greater in the saxagliptin group than in the placebo group; the difference between treatments was -0.42% (95% confidence interval: -0.71 to -0.12%, p = 0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Adjusted mean HbA1c decreases from baseline to week 12 were numerically greater with saxagliptin than with placebo in the subgroups of patients with moderate (-0.64 vs. -0.05%) and severe (-0.95 vs. -0.50%) <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0341697" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">renal impairment</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>HbA1c reductions were similar between saxagliptin and placebo in the subgroup with <z:hpo ids='HP_0003774'>end-stage renal disease</z:hpo> on haemodialysis (-0.84 vs. -0.87%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Saxagliptin was generally well tolerated; incidences of adverse events and hypoglycaemic events were similar to placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Saxagliptin 2.5 mg once daily is a well-tolerated treatment option for patients with inadequately controlled T2DM and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0341697" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">renal impairment</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>