<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: To compare 2-year glycaemic control, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> and healthcare expenditures following insulin glargine (glargine, n = 2105) or neutral protamine Hagedorn (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e>) insulin (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e>, n = 734) initiation in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (T2D) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Retrospective cohort study using an integrated US health insurance administrative database was conducted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Individuals with a <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> diagnostic claim and initiated basal insulin therapy with glargine or <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> from 2001 to 2005 dispensed at least one oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> drug prescription during 6 months prior to basal insulin initiation and enrolled in the same health insurance plan from 6 months before to 12 months or more after insulin initiation were identified </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Repeated measures mixed-effects models evaluated glycaemic and financial outcomes to account for factors potentially contributing to selection of insulin therapy, that is, age, gender, baseline HbA1c level, health expenditures, co-morbidities, healthcare utilization, pharmacy co-payment and follow-up <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> medications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Adjusted mean HbA1c value in the first year following insulin initiation was significantly lower for glargine versus <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> initiators (Δ = -0.43, p = 0.006); this difference diminished in the second year (Δ = -0.16, p = 0.375) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>First-year adjusted quarterly <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> incidence rates were lower for glargine (2.1%) versus <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> (2.4%) (p = 0.02) as was the second-year quarterly rate (1.8 vs. 2.2%; p = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Both the first- and second-year adjusted total healthcare expenditures were lower in the glargine versus <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> group (year 1: $18,720 vs. $19,996, p = 0.005; year 2: $15,008 vs. $17,336; p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Glargine therapy may be an effective long-term option for improving glycaemic control, with lower rates of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> and healthcare costs in patients with T2D </plain></SENT>
</text></document>