<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:mp ids='MP_0002498'>Leukocyte infiltration</z:mp> of adipose is a critical determinant of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0025517" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic diseases</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Fractalkine (CX3CL1) and its receptor (CX3CR1) comprise a chemokine system involved in leukocyte recruitment and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0001511" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">adhesion</z:e> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo>, but its role in adipose <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: CX3CL1 <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> and protein were quantified in subcutaneous adipose and blood during experimental human endotoxemia and in lean and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> human adipose </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>CX3CL1 cellular source was probed in human adipocytes, monocytes, and macrophages, and CX3CL1-blocking antibodies were used to assess its role in monocyte-adipocyte <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0001511" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">adhesion</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The association of genetic variation in CX3CR1 with metabolic traits was determined in a community-based sample </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Finally, plasma CX3CL1 levels were measured in a case-control study of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Endotoxemia induced adipose CX3CL1 <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> (32.7-fold, P &lt; 1 × 10(-5)) and protein (43-fold, P = 0.006) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>Obese</z:mp> subjects had higher CX3CL1 levels in subcutaneous adipose compared with lean (0.420 ± 0.387 vs. 0.228 ± 0.187 ng/mL, P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CX3CL1 was expressed and secreted by human adipocytes and stromal vascular cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Inflammatory cytokine induction of CX3CL1 in human adipocytes (27.5-fold <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> and threefold protein) was completely attenuated by pretreatment with a peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-γ <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>A putative functional nonsynonymous single nucleotide polymorphism (rs3732378) in CX3CR1 was associated with adipose and metabolic traits, and plasma CX3CL1 levels were increased in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> vs. nondiabetics (0.506 ± 0.262 vs. 0.422 ± 0.210 ng/mL, P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: CX3CL1-CX3CR1 is a novel inflammatory adipose chemokine system that modulates monocyte <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0001511" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">adhesion</z:e> to adipocytes and is associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>These data provide support for CX3CL1 as a diagnostic and therapeutic target in cardiometabolic disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>