<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The pathophysiological mechanisms to explain the association between risk of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and elevated concentrations of γ-glutamyltransferase (GGT) and alanineaminotransferase (ALT) remain poorly characterized </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We explored the association of liver enzymes with peripheral and hepatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, insulin secretion, insulin clearance, and glucagon concentration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We studied 1,309 nondiabetic individuals from the Relationship between Insulin Sensitivity and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">Cardiovascular disease</z:e> (RISC) study; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> had a euglycemic-hyperinsulinemic clamp and an oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test (OGTT) with assessment of insulin secretion and hepatic insulin extraction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The hepatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> index was calculated in 393 individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In both men and women, plasma concentrations of GGT and ALT were inversely related with insulin sensitivity (M/I) (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Likewise, the hepatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> index was positively correlated with both GGT (r = 0.37, P &lt; 0.0001, men; r = 0.36, P &lt; 0.0001, women) and ALT (r = 0.25, P = 0.0005, men; r = 0.18, P = 0.01, women) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These associations persisted in multivariable models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Increased GGT and ALT were significantly associated with higher insulin secretion rates and with both reduced endogenous clearance of insulin and hepatic insulin extraction during the OGTT (P = 0.0005 in men; P = 0.003 in women) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Plasma fasting glucagon levels increased over ALT quartiles (men, quartile 4 vs. quartile 1 11.2 ± 5.1 vs. 9.3 ± 3.8 pmol/L, respectively, P = 0.0002; women, 9.0 ± 4.3 vs. 7.6 ± 3.1, P = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In healthy individuals, increased GGT and ALT were biomarkers of both systemic and hepatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> with concomitant <z:mp ids='MP_0003058'>increased insulin secretion</z:mp> and decreased hepatic insulin clearance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The novel finding of a positive correlation between ALT and fasting glucagon level concentrations warrants confirmation in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>