<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Although the <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Prevention Program (DPP) and the Finnish <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Prevention Study (FDPS) demonstrated that <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> from lifestyle change reduces type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> incidence in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0362046" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">prediabetes</z:e>, the translation into community settings has been difficult </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The objective of this study is to report the first-year results of a community-based translation of the DPP lifestyle <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> (LWL) intervention on fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: We randomly assigned 301 overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> volunteers (BMI 25-40 kg/m(2)) with fasting blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> values between 95 and 125 mg/dL to a group-based translation of the DPP LWL intervention administered through a <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> education program (DEP) and delivered by community health workers (CHWs) or to an enhanced usual-care condition </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>CHWs were volunteers with well-controlled type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A total of 42.5% of participants were male, mean age was 57.9 years, 26% were of a race/ethnicity other than white, and 80% reported having an education beyond high school </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The primary outcome is mean fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> over 12 months of follow-up, adjusting for baseline <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Compared with usual-care participants, LWL intervention participants experienced significantly greater decreases in blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (-4.3 vs. -0.4 mg/dL; P&lt;0.001), insulin (-6.5 vs. -2.7 μU/mL; P&lt;0.001), homeostasis model assessment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> (-1.9 vs. -0.8; P&lt;0.001), weight (-7.1 vs. -1.4 kg; P&lt;0.001), BMI (-2.1 vs. -0.3 kg/m2; P&lt;0.001), and waist circumference (-5.9 vs. -0.8 cm; P&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This translation of the DPP intervention conducted in community settings, administered through a DEP, and delivered by CHWs holds great promise for the prevention of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> by significantly decreasing <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, insulin, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>