<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The concordance of <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> and diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> (DR) has been well reported in persons with type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>; however, for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, there is paucity of data especially from population-based studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to estimate the prevalence of <z:mp ids='MP_0002871'>albuminuria</z:mp> (micro - and macroalbuminuria) among persons with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and determine its role as a risk factor for presence and severity of DR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A population-based cross sectional study was conducted in cohort of 1414 subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> from Chennai metropolis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> the subjects underwent comprehensive eye examination including 45 degrees four-field stereoscopic digital photography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>DR was clinically graded using Early Treatment Diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>Retinopathy</z:hpo> Study scales </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A morning urine sample was tested for <z:mp ids='MP_0002871'>albuminuria</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Subjects were considered to have <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp>, if the urinary albumin excretion was between 30 and 300 mg/24 hours, and macroalbuminuria at more than 300 mg/24 hours </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The statistical software used was SPSS for Windows, Chicago, IL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Student t-test for comparing continuous variables, and χ2 test, to compare proportions amongst groups were used </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The prevalence of <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> in the study subjects was 15.9% (226/1414), and that of macroalbuminuria, 2.7% (38/1414) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Individuals with macroalbuminuria in comparison to micro- or normoalbuminuria showed a greater prevalence of DR (60.5% vs. 31.0% vs. 14.1%, p &lt; 0.001), and also a greater severity of the disease (60.9% vs. 21.4 vs. 9.9, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Every 6th individual in the population of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is likely to have <z:mp ids='MP_0002871'>albuminuria</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Subjects with <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp> were around 2 times as likely to have DR as those without <z:mp ids='MP_0002959'>microalbuminuria</z:mp>, and this risk became almost 6 times in the presence of macroalbuminuria </plain></SENT>
</text></document>