<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Abnormally elevated alanine aminotransferase (ALT) of nonspecific causes is a common outpatient problem </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Without considering ethnicity, several studies had suggested that it was associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> (IR) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate whether nonspecific elevated ALT in Taiwanese population could reflect a likely underlying IR and was associated with impaired fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> or type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (IFG/T2DM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The health examination profiles of 1313 Taiwanese were investigated cross-sectionally </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The prevalence and odds ratios (ORs) for IFG/T2DM and <z:mp ids='MP_0005266'>metabolic abnormalities</z:mp> in relation to elevated ALT were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Subjects with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> (MS) <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> had IFG/T2DM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The elevated ALT significantly correlated with MS and IFG/T2DM (i.e., 19.9-29.2% vs. 7.8% for MS, and 27.0-31.5% vs. 16.1% for IFG/T2DM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, after excluding MS and adjustment for age and sex, the elevated ALT alone was not consistently associated with IFG/T2DM (36 &lt; ALT ≤ 80 IU/L with OR 0.97, 95% CI 0.58-1.61; 80 &lt; ALT ≤ 120 IU/L with OR 0.55, 95% CI 0.13-2.37; none with ALT &gt; 120 had IFG) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In a cross-sectional analysis of Taiwanese industrial employees, elevated ALT associated with MS, but in subjects who did not meet MS criteria, elevated ALT by itself did not associate with IFG/T2DM </plain></SENT>
</text></document>