<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: Assess safety/tolerability and efficacy of the DPP-4 inhibitor vildagliptin in 515 patients with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (T2DM) and moderate or severe <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0341697" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">renal impairment</z:e> (RI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Double-blind, randomized, parallel-group, placebo-controlled, 24-week clinical trial assessing safety and efficacy of vildagliptin (50 mg qd) added to current <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> therapy, in patients with T2DM and moderate or severe RI (GFR ≥ 30 to &lt;50 or &lt;30 ml/min/1.73 m(2) ) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The study population comprised of 165 and 129 patients with moderate RI and 124 and 97 patients with severe RI randomized to vildagliptin and placebo, respectively, with most patients receiving background insulin therapy (68 and 81% for moderate and severe RI, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>After 24 weeks, the between-treatment difference in the adjusted mean change in A1C was -0.5 ± 0.1% (p &lt; 0.0001) in moderate RI (baseline A1C = 7.9%) and -0.6 ± 0.1% (p &lt; 0.0001) in severe RI (baseline A1C = 7.7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In patients with moderate RI, similar proportions of those receiving vildagliptin or placebo experienced any AE (68 vs. 73%), any SAE (9 vs. 9%), any AE leading to discontinuation (3 vs. 5%) or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> (1 vs. 1%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This was also true for patients with severe RI: AEs (73 vs. 74%), SAEs (19 vs. 21%), AEs leading to discontinuation (9 vs. 6%) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> (2 vs. 4%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In this 24-week study of 515 patients with T2DM and moderate or severe RI, vildagliptin added to ongoing <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> therapy had a safety profile similar to placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Further, relative to placebo, vildagliptin elicited a statistically and clinically significant decrease in A1C in patients with moderate or severe RI </plain></SENT>
</text></document>