<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: We evaluated intensive intervention in poorly controlled patients with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> involving weekly clinic visits and adjustment of therapy with analysis of three seven-point <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> profiles and intervention from an interdisciplinary staff </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Sixty-three patients were randomized to an intensive treatment group that obtained self-monitoring of blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (SMBG) profiles (six or seven values per day, 3 days/week) and were seen in the clinic at Weeks 1-6 and 12 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>SMBG results were downloaded, analyzed using Accu-Chek(®) 360° software (Roche Diagnostics, Indianapolis, IN), and used to adjust therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Control group subjects obtained <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> profiles and had clinic visits only at Weeks 0, 6, and 12 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were highly statistically significant improvements in the intensive treatment group compared with the control group between Weeks 0 and 6 with greater reductions in weekly mean glycemia (WMG) (-76.7±8.9 mg/dL vs. -20.5±8.1 mg/dL), glycemic variability (SD) (-16.3±3.1 mg/dL vs. -5.0±3.1 mg/dL), and glycated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> (-1.82±0.16% vs. -0.66±0.22%) without significant changes in frequency of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> or weight </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Improvements were sustained in the intensive treatment group through Week 12 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A minimal but statistically significant degree of improvement was seen in the control group at Week 12 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This short-term pilot study of an intensive monitoring, educational, and pharmacological interventions program resulted in dramatic improvement of glycemic control within 6 weeks, and these effects are sustained through Week 12 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>SMBG <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> profiles, calculation of WMG and SD, and graphical displays of <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> data can improve the effectiveness of adjustment of therapy at weekly clinic visits when combined with intensive support from a multidisciplinary team </plain></SENT>
</text></document>