<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate whether the dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor vildagliptin improves endothelium-dependent vasodilatation in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Sixteen subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (age 59.8 ± 6.8 years, BMI 29.1 ± 4.8 kg/m(2), HbA(1c) 6.97 ± 0.61) on oral blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>-lowering treatment were included </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Participants received vildagliptin 50 mg b.i.d. or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> 100 mg t.i.d. for four consecutive weeks in a randomized, double-blind, cross-over design </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>At the end of each treatment period, we measured forearm <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35620">vasodilator</z:chebi> responses to intra-arterially administered <z:chebi fb="9" ids="15355">acetylcholine</z:chebi> (endothelium-dependent <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35620">vasodilator</z:chebi>) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29321">sodium nitroprusside</z:chebi> (endothelium-independent <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35620">vasodilator</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Infusion of <z:chebi fb="9" ids="15355">acetylcholine</z:chebi> induced a dose-dependent increase in forearm blood flow in the experimental arm, which was higher during vildagliptin (3.1 ± 0.7, 7.9 ± 1.1, and 12.6 ± 1.4 mL ⋅ dL(-1) ⋅ min(-1) in response to three increasing dosages of <z:chebi fb="9" ids="15355">acetylcholine</z:chebi>) than during <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> (2.0 ± 0.7, 5.0 ± 1.2, and 11.7 ± 1.6 mL ⋅ dL(-1) ⋅ min(-1), respectively; P = 0.01 by two-way ANOVA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Treatment with vildagliptin did not significantly change the vascular responses to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29321">sodium nitroprusside</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Four weeks' treatment with vildagliptin improves endothelium-dependent vasodilatation in subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>This observation might have favorable cardiovascular implications </plain></SENT>
</text></document>