<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: In this randomized controlled trial we evaluated the effectiveness of medical nutritional therapy on Arab patients with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in Oman delivered by a dietitian </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Patients with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (n = 170) were randomly assigned to a group receiving usual nutritional care (n = 85) or a group receiving practice guidelines nutritional care (n = 85) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Anthropometric (weight, height, BMI and waist circumference) and biochemical (fasting blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, HbA1c ) variables were measured at baseline and after each appointment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients were given 1-3 appointments with a dietitian over 6 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Those in the group receiving practice guidelines nutritional care (n = 85) had significant changes in HbA(1c) (-0.8%, P = 0.001), fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (-1.3 mmol\l, P = 0.003) and weight (-5.1 kg, P = 0.05), whereas the patients in the usual nutritional care group (n = 85) had no significant improvements in either HbA(1c) (-0.4%, P = 0.248) or fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (-0.2 mmol/l, P = 0.638) during the same period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We also found a significant difference between the group receiving practice guidelines nutritional care and the usual nutritional care group, respectively, in waist circumference (96.9 ± 7.9 vs. 100.0 ± 8.7 cm, P = 0.019), <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi> levels (1.42 ± 0.58 vs. 1.98 ± 0.96 mmol\l, P = 0.001), cholesterol levels (5.1 ± 1.0 vs. 5.5 ± 0.9 mmol/l, P = 0.009) and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47774">LDL cholesterol</z:chebi> levels (3.58 ± 0.98 vs. 3.89 ± 0.98 mmol/l, P = 0.046) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Medical nutrition therapy provided by dietitians to Arab patients with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in Oman resulted in significant improvements in anthropometric and biochemical outcomes in both the usual nutritional care group and the group receiving practice guidelines nutritional care </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Subjects with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> tended to do better with practice guidelines nutritional care than with usual nutritional care </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Ongoing medical counselling in nutrition by a trained dietitian is important for better long-term metabolic control </plain></SENT>
</text></document>