<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To investigate the cost-effectiveness of liraglutide as add-on to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> in patients with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> uncontrolled with first-line <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Data were sourced from a clinical trial comparing liraglutide vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi>, both in combination with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, and a clinical trial comparing liraglutide vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi>, both as add-on to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Only the subgroup of patients in whom liraglutide was added to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> monotherapy was included in the cost-utility analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The CORE <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Model was used to simulate outcomes and costs with liraglutide 1.2 and 1.8 mg vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> and vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> over patients' lifetimes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Treatment effects were taken directly from the trials </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Costs and outcomes were discounted at 3.5% per annum and costs were accounted from a third-party payer (UK National Health System) perspective </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Treatment with liraglutide 1.2 and 1.8 mg resulted, respectively, in mean increases in quality-adjusted life expectancy of 0.32 ± 0.15 and 0.28 ± 0.14 quality-adjusted life years vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi>, and 0.19 ± 0.15 and 0.31 ± 0.15 quality-adjusted life years vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi>, and was associated with higher costs of £ 3003 ± £ 678 and £ 4688 ± £ 639 vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi>, and £ 1842 ± £ 751 and £ 3224 ± £ 683 vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi>, over a patient's lifetime </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Both liraglutide doses were cost-effective, with incremental cost-effectiveness ratios of £ 9449 and £ 16,501 per quality-adjusted life year gained vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi>, and £ 9851 and £ 10,465 per quality-adjusted life year gained vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi>, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Liraglutide, added to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> monotherapy, is a cost-effective option for the treatment of Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in a UK setting </plain></SENT>
</text></document>