<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: Fibroblast growth factor (FGF) 21 is an <z:chebi fb="32" ids="24621">endocrine</z:chebi> factor with multiple beneficial effects on <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> metabolism in animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to investigate the association of serum FGF21 levels with type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, latent autoimmune <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in adults (LADA) and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Serum FGF21 levels were determined by ELISA in patients with type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (n = 76), LADA (n = 68), type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (n = 77), and their age- and sex-matched controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The association of serum FGF21 with markers of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmunity</z:hpo> was studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In type 1 diabetic patients, serum FGF21 levels were significantly lower than controls [108.3 (61.5-180.1) vs. 196.0 (103.7-330.9) pg/ml, P &lt; 0.001] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In LADA patients, serum FGF21 levels were significantly lower than controls after adjustment for body mass index [210.9 (121.4-441.6) vs. 268.3 (159.5-443.6) pg/ml, P = 0.003] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>By contrast, serum FGF21 levels in type 2 diabetic patients were significantly higher than controls [381.2 (244.7-531.3) vs. 301.4 (173.9-444.2) pg/ml, P = 0.006] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>FGF21 levels increased progressively from type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, LADA, to type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (P &lt; 0.001 for global trend) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, FGF21 levels correlated inversely with titers of glutamic acid decarboxylase and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021670" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">insulinoma</z:e>-associated protein 2 autoantibodies in type 1 diabetic and LADA patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Serum FGF21 level is increased in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> but decreased in type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and LADA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In autoimmune <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the reduction in circulating FGF21 is closely associated with markers of pancreatic β-cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmunity</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>