<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Cardiovascular benefits of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16389">ubiquinone</z:chebi> have been previously demonstrated, and we administered it as a novel therapy in an experimental model of type 2 diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo>. db/db and dbH mice were followed for 10 weeks, after randomization to receive either vehicle or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16389">ubiquinone</z:chebi> (CoQ10; 10mg/kg/day) orally. db/db mice had elevated urinary albumin excretion rates and albumin:<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> ratio, not seen in db/db CoQ10-treated mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Renal cortices from db/db mice had lower total and oxidized CoQ10 content, compared with dbH mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Mitochondria from db/db mice also contained less oxidized CoQ10(<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16389">ubiquinone</z:chebi>) compared with dbH mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp>-induced increases in total renal collagen but not <z:hpo ids='HP_0000096'>glomerulosclerosis</z:hpo> were significantly decreased with CoQ10 therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>Mitochondrial</z:hpo> <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> and ATP production via complex II in the renal cortex were increased in db/db mice, with ATP normalized by CoQ10 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, excess renal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> <z:chebi fb="17" ids="16240">hydrogen peroxide</z:chebi> production and increased <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> membrane potential seen in db/db mice were attenuated with CoQ10 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Renal <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase activity was also lower in db/db mice compared with dbH mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Our results suggest that a deficiency in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> oxidized CoQ10 (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16389">ubiquinone</z:chebi>) may be a likely precipitating factor for diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000112'>nephropathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Therefore CoQ10 supplementation may be renoprotective in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, via preservation of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> function </plain></SENT>
</text></document>