<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To investigate the occurrence of neuronal damage, as the earliest change occurring, before the clinical evidence of diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: 70 eyes of subjects with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> and with no evidence of diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> (cases) and 40 eyes of subjects with no <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (controls) were studied using spectral-domain OCT and microperimetry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The influence of age and gender on the outcome measures was also analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Age- and gender-matched subjects showed a decreased mean <z:chebi fb="46" ids="15035">retinal</z:chebi> nerve fiber layer thickness in cases when compared to the controls (27 vs. 33 μm; p=0.018) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Among the cases, subjects between 40 and 45 years of age showed a reduced mean central foveal thickness (175.1 vs. 198.1 μm; p=0.05), mean <z:chebi fb="46" ids="15035">retinal</z:chebi> thickness in the central 6-mm fundus (260.5 vs. 275.3 μm; p=0.006) and mean <z:chebi fb="46" ids="15035">retinal</z:chebi> nerve fiber layer thickness (29 vs. 39 μm; p=0.036) when compared to the controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, no differences were noted in the microperimetry outcomes in cases when compared to the controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The duration of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and the glycemic control did not show any significant changes on the outcome measures in cases, except for a significantly lower mean <z:chebi fb="46" ids="15035">retinal</z:chebi> sensitivity in diabetics with glycosylated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> values&lt;7% as compared to those with glycosylated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi>≥7% (14.1±2.9 vs. 15.4±1.7 dB; p=0.027) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The results suggest that there is some evidence of early neuronal damage particularly on spectral-domain OCT, before the clinical evidence of diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo>, in subjects with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>