<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVE: <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> is a recognized risk factor for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000704'>periodontitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>There are conflicting data regarding whether healthy diabetic patients or diabetic patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0000704'>periodontitis</z:hpo> have an altered subgingival microbiota compared with nondiabetic individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of the present study was to detect quantitative differences in selected periodontopathogens in the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0399451" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">subgingival plaque</z:e> of diabetic patients using TaqMan quantitative PCR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL AND METHODS: Type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> patients with (n=9) or without <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0031090" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">periodontal disease</z:e> (n=15) were recruited and matched to nondiabetic control subjects (n=12 periodontally healthy, n=12 <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0000704'>periodontitis</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0399451" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Subgingival plaque</z:e> samples were collected from deep (&gt;4 mm probing depth) and shallow sites (≤3 mm probing depth) using paper points, and Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans, Fusobacterium nucleatum and Porphyromonas gingivalis were quantified </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Forty-eight subjects (69 samples) were recruited </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Marked differences were seen in the levels of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> three <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> species, relative to the total <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> population, according to periodontal health status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Using real-time quantitative PCR, <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> counts for P. gingivalis were significantly higher in deep pockets of diabetic and nondiabetic subjects compared with periodontally healthy subjects (p&lt;0.05) but did not differ significantly between diabetics and nondiabetics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A. actinomycetemcomitans was detected in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> groups in low quantities, and counts did not differ significantly between groups (p&gt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>F. nucleatum was abundant in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> groups, with no clear significant differences between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>P. gingivalis was found in higher quantities in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000704'>periodontitis</z:hpo> than in periodontally healthy subjects (p&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Statistically significant positive correlations were identified between pocket depth and counts for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> three species tested (p&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: A. actinomycetemcomitans, F. nucleatum and P. gingivalis were present in significantly different quantities and proportions in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0399451" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">subgingival plaque</z:e>, according to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0031090" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">periodontal disease</z:e> status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>No significant differences were identified between the subgingival microbiota of type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> patients compared with nondiabetic subjects </plain></SENT>
</text></document>