<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">Sulfonylureas</z:chebi> have been shown to increase mortality when used in combination with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This may not be a class effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylureas</z:chebi>, but rather secondary to differences in properties inherent to the individual <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylureas</z:chebi> (hypoglycaemic risk, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> receptor selectivity and effects on myocardial ischemic preconditioning) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to assess the risk of overall mortality in patients with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> treated with different combinations of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylureas</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A retrospective cohort study was conducted using an academic health center enterprise-wide electronic health record system to identify 7320 patients with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (3768 initiators of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi>) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, 2277 initiators of glipizide and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> and 1275 initiators of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>), ≥ 18 years of age and not on insulin or a non-insulin injectable at baseline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The patients were followed for mortality by documentation in the electronic health record and Social Security <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>Death</z:hpo> Index </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Multivariable Cox models with propensity analysis were used to compare cohorts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: No statistically significant difference in overall mortality risk was observed among the different combinations of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylureas</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> vs. glipizide and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (HR 1.03; 95% CI 0.89-1.20), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi>) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (HR 1.08; 95% CI 0.90-1.30), or with glipizide and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> vs. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glibenclamide</z:chebi>) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (HR 1.05; 95% CI 0.95-1.15) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our results did not identify an increased mortality risk among the different combinations of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylureas</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, suggesting that overall mortality is not substantially influenced by the choice of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>