<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: To assess the safety and tolerability of the dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor linagliptin in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Data were pooled from eight randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled Phase III clinical trials lasting ≤24 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Incidences were calculated with descriptive statistics for the overall population and for subgroups of elderly and renally impaired patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A total of 2523 patients received linagliptin 5 mg once daily and 1049 patients received placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The overall incidence of adverse events (AEs) or serious AEs with linagliptin was similar to placebo (AEs 55.8% vs. 55.0%; serious AEs 2.8% vs. 2.7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Overall aggregated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> incidence was 19.5% for linagliptin and 21.4% for placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Similar or reduced incidence of AEs versus placebo were seen with linagliptin for upper <z:hpo ids='HP_0011947'>respiratory tract infection</z:hpo> (3.3% vs. 4.9%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0002315'>headache</z:hpo> (2.9% vs. 3.1%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0000010'>urinary tract infection</z:hpo> (2.2% vs. 2.7%), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0851353" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">blood and lymphatic disorders</z:e> (1.0% vs. 1.2%), hypersensitivity (0.1% vs. 0.1%), hepatic enzyme increase (0.1% and 0.1%) and serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> increase (0.0% and 0.1%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was a slight increased frequency of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027441" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">nasopharyngitis</z:e> (5.9% vs. 5.1%) and cough (1.7% vs. 1.0%) with linagliptin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Hypoglycaemia</z:e> incidence was 8.2% for linagliptin and 5.1% for placebo; incidence was higher in patients with a background of sulphonylurea therapy (20.7% and 13.3%, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In patients not receiving concomitant sulphonylurea, the hypoglycaemic incidence with linagliptin was very low in both the total population (&lt;1%), and elderly and renally impaired patients (both &lt;1%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This pooled analysis shows that linagliptin is well tolerated, with a low risk of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>