<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitors (DPP-4i) improve glycaemic control in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, but their benefits on reverse cholesterol transport (RCT) remain unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We evaluated the effects of DPP-4i <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> 500 mg/kg/day on RCT in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> insulin-resistant CETP-apoB100 transgenic mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">Metformin</z:chebi> 300 mg/kg/day orally was used as a reference compound </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Both <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> showed the expected effects on <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> parameters </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Although no significant effect was observed on total cholesterol and <z:chebi fb="6" ids="39025">high-density lipoprotein</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="17" ids="39025">HDL</z:chebi>) cholesterol levels, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi>, but not <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, increased faecal cholesterol mass excretion by 132% (p &lt; 0.001 vs. vehicle), suggesting a potent effect on cholesterol metabolism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mice were then injected i.p. with (3) H-cholesterol labelled macrophages to measure RCT over 48 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Compared with vehicle, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> significantly increased macrophage-derived (3) H-cholesterol faecal excretion by 39% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Administration of (14) C-cholesterol labelled olive oil orally showed a significant reduction of (14) C-tracer plasma appearance over time with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi>, indicating that this drug promotes RCT through <z:mp ids='MP_0002647'>reduced intestinal cholesterol absorption</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>