<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: To assess the evolution of type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (T2DM) quality indicators in primary care centers (PCC) as part of the Group for the Study of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> in Primary Care (GEDAPS) Continuous Quality Improvement (GCQI) programme in Catalonia </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Sequential cross-sectional studies were performed during 1993-2007 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Process and outcome indicators in random samples of patients from each centre were collected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The results of each evaluation were returned to each centre to encourage the implementation of correcting interventions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Sixty-four different educational activities were performed during the study period with the participation of 2041 professionals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Clinical records of 23,501 patients were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A significant improvement was observed in the determination of some annual process indicators: HbA(1c) (51.7% vs. 88.9%); total cholesterol (75.9% vs. 90.9%); <z:mp ids='MP_0002871'>albuminuria</z:mp> screening (33.9% vs. 59.4%) and foot examination (48.9% vs. 64.2%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The intermediate outcome indicators also showed significant improvements: glycemic control [HbA(1c) ≤ 7% (&lt; 57 mmol/mol); (41.5% vs. 64.2%)]; total cholesterol [≤ 200 mg/dl (5.17 mmol/l); (25.5% vs. 65.6%)]; blood pressure [≤ 140/90 mmHg; (45.4% vs. 66.1%)] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In addition, a significant improvement in some final outcome indicators such as prevalence of foot <z:mpath ids='MPATH_579'>ulcers</z:mpath> (7.6% vs. 2.6%); <z:mpath ids='MPATH_686'>amputations</z:mpath> (1.9% vs. 0.6%) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> (18.8% vs. 8.6%) was observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Although those changes should not be strictly attributed to the GCQI programme, significant improvements in some process indicators, parameters of control and complications were observed in a network of primary care centres in Catalonia </plain></SENT>
</text></document>