<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Experimental evidence suggests that heat shock proteins (<z:chebi fb="24" ids="50430">HSP</z:chebi>) and asymmetric dimethylarginine (ADMA) are induced in the state of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> and stress conditions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>They are both inhibitors of nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> synthase (NOS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to evaluate the correlation between ADMA and HSP70, in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with respect to serum levels of C reactive protein (CRP) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We quantified serum HSP70, ADMA and CRP in 80 newly-diagnosed patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> plus 80 age-, sex and BMI-matched healthy controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The patients and controls were also stratified into groups of high and low CRP levels (cut-point: 2.5mg/ml) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> had significantly higher serum HSP70 (0.52 [0.51-0.66] vs. 0.27 [0.26-0.36], p&lt;0.001), ADMA (0.86 [0.81-0.92] vs. 0.72 [0.71-0.85], p&lt;0.05) and CRP (2.9 [1.7-3.4] vs. 1.6[1.2-2.3], p&lt;0.05) compared with healthy controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Serum HSP70 and ADMA levels were significantly correlated in patients with high CRP levels (r=0.89, p&lt;0.01), whereas there were no correlation in patients with low CRP (r=-0.37, p=0.07) and controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>This correlation was significant (r=0.77, p&lt;0.001) in patients with high CRP and also in patients with low CRP levels (r=-0.51, p&lt;0.05), after multiple adjustments for <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="17" ids="39025">HDL</z:chebi> levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>DISCUSSION: We showed that, in a state of high <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>; serum levels of ADMA parallel the HSP70 levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However in low <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, they are negatively correlated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The duality in HSP70 and ADMA correlation may be related to the duality of NOS function in low and high CRP levels </plain></SENT>
</text></document>