<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: We recently reported that after 26 weeks, exenatide once weekly (EQW) resulted in superior A1C reduction, reduced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo>, and progressive <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> compared with daily insulin glargine (IG) in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who were taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> alone or with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This 84-week extension study assessed the long-term safety and efficacy of EQW versus IG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This multicenter, open-label, randomized, two-arm, parallel trial assessed change in A1C, proportions of patients achieving A1C &lt;7.0 and ≤6.5%, body weight, incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo>, and overall safety </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of 415 patients who completed 26 weeks, 390 (194 EQW and 196 IG patients) entered the extension study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At 84 weeks, A1C decreased from baseline (8.3%) by -1.2% for EQW vs. -1.0% for IG (P = 0.029) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The proportions of patients who achieved end point A1C targets &lt;7.0 and ≤6.5% were 44.6% for EQW patients vs. 36.8% for IG patients (P = 0.084) and 31.3% for EQW patients vs. 20.2% for IG patients (P = 0.009), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients taking EQW lost 2.1 kg of body weight, whereas those taking IG gained 2.4 kg (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Among patients taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi>, the incidence of minor <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> was 24% for EQW patients vs. 54% for IG patients (P &lt; 0.001); among patients taking <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> alone, it was 8% for EQW patients vs. 32% for IG patients (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Among adverse events occurring in ≥5% of patients, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002014'>diarrhea</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002018'>nausea</z:hpo> occurred more frequently (P &lt; 0.05) in the EQW group than in the IG group (12 vs. 6% and 15 vs. 1%, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: After 84 weeks, patients treated with EQW continued to experience better glycemic control with sustained overall <z:hpo ids='HP_0001824'>weight loss</z:hpo> and a lower risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> than patients treated with IG </plain></SENT>
</text></document>