<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To test the hypothesis that <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>hepatic steatosis</z:hpo> is associated with risk factors for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> youth, mediated by cardiorespiratory fitness </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This was a cross-sectional study comparing insulin sensitivity between 30 overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> adolescents with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>hepatic steatosis</z:hpo>, 68 overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> adolescents without <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>hepatic steatosis</z:hpo>, and 11 healthy weight adolescents without <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>hepatic steatosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Cardiorespiratory fitness was determined by a graded maximal exercise test on a cycle ergometer </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Secondary outcomes included presence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> response to a 75-g oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> challenge </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>hepatic steatosis</z:hpo> was associated with 55% lower insulin sensitivity (P = 0.02) and a twofold greater prevalence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> (P = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Differences in insulin sensitivity (3.5 vs. 4.5 mU ⋅ kg(-1) ⋅ min(-1), P = 0.03), prevalence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> (48 vs. 20%, P = 0.03), and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> area under the curve (816 vs. 710, P = 0.04) remained between groups after matching for age, sex, and visceral fat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The association between <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>hepatic steatosis</z:hpo> and insulin sensitivity (β = -0.24, t = -2.29, P &lt; 0.025), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> (β = -0.54, t = -5.8, P &lt; 0.001), and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> area under the curve (β = 0.33, t = 3.3, P &lt; 0.001) was independent of visceral and whole-body <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Cardiorespiratory fitness was not associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>hepatic steatosis</z:hpo>, insulin sensitivity, or presence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>Hepatic steatosis</z:hpo> is associated with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> risk factors independent of cardiorespiratory fitness, whole-body <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028754" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">adiposity</z:e>, and visceral fat mass </plain></SENT>
</text></document>