<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: The aim of this study was to explore the association between pedometer-determined physical activity versus measures of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, inflammatory markers and arterial stiffness in people with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We analysed data from 224 men and 103 women with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, aged 54-66 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Physical activity was measured with waist-mounted pedometers during three consecutive days and the number of steps/day were calculated and classified in four groups: &lt; 5000 steps/day, 5000-7499 steps/day, 7500-9999 steps/day and ≥ 10000 steps/day </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Blood samples were analysed for <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi>, HbA(1c), inflammatory markers including C-reactive protein and interleukin-6 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Nurses measured blood pressure and anthropometrics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Aortic pulse wave velocity was measured with applanation tonometry over the carotid and femoral arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Mean steps/day was 7683 ± 3883 (median 7222, interquartile range 4869-10,343) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There were no differences in age, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> duration, blood pressure, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> or glycaemic control between the four groups of pedometer-determined physical activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Subjects with higher steps/day had lower BMI (28.8 vs. 31.5 kg/m(2), P &lt; 0.001), waist circumference (101.7 vs. 108.0 cm, P &lt; 0.001), lower levels of C-reactive protein (1.6 vs. 2.6 mg/l, P = 0.007), lower levels of interleukin-6 (1.9 vs. 3.8 pg ml, P &lt; 0.001) and lower pulse wave velocity (10.2 vs. 11.0 m/s, P = 0.009) compared with less physically active people </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: We conclude that physical activity measured with pedometer was associated not only with less abdominal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001513'>obesity</z:hpo>, but also with decreased systemic low-grade <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> as well as with low arterial stiffness, in people with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>