<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: This study was conducted to determine the association of insertion/deletion (I/D) polymorphism of the ACE gene in hypertensive and T2DM subjects in Egyptian population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The deletion (D) allele of the angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) gene has been studied in relation to <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> and type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (T2DM) with contradictory results which might be due to ethnic and geographical variations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Methods: A total of 85 subjects participated in this study; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> (Group 1); type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (Group 2) and controls (Group 3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Written informed consent was obtained. for each subject: age, sex, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> duration and the drugs used, blood pressure (systolic and diastolic), and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Genotyping was performed by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The frequency of DD genotype was significantly higher in hypertensive (60 %) and diabetic patients (68 %) compared to controls (33.3 %) (p=0.04, p=0.01 respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The DD genotype (vs DI and II genotype) in the hypertensive and diabetic groups is associated with increased risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> and/or <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>OR=3.00; 95%, Cl = 0.993-9.067; OR=4.250; 95%, Cl = 1.234-14.63 respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The D allele was more frequent in hypertensive (77.5 %) and diabetic patients (82 %) compared to controls (52.4 %) (p=0.004 and 0.002 respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The D allele (vs the I allele) is associated with increased risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> and <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> OR=3.13, 95%Cl=1.405-6.978; OR= 4.14, 95% CI= 1.615-10.622 respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The DD genotype and the D allele are associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in Egyptian patients (Tab </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>5, Fig. 1, Ref </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>32) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>