<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Prevention Program (DPP) and its Outcomes Study (DPPOS) demonstrated that either intensive lifestyle intervention or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> could prevent type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in high-risk adults for at least 10 years after randomization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We report the 10-year within-trial cost-effectiveness of the interventions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Data on resource utilization, cost, and quality of life were collected prospectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Economic analyses were performed from health system and societal perspectives </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Over 10 years, the cumulative, undiscounted per capita direct medical costs of the interventions, as implemented during the DPP, were greater for lifestyle ($4,601) than <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> ($2,300) or placebo ($769) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The cumulative direct medical costs of care outside the DPP/DPPOS were least for lifestyle ($24,563 lifestyle vs. $25,616 metformin vs. $27,468 placebo) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The cumulative, combined total direct medical costs were greatest for lifestyle and least for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> ($29,164 lifestyle vs. $27,915 metformin vs. $28,236 placebo) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The cumulative quality-adjusted life-years (QALYs) accrued over 10 years were greater for lifestyle (6.81) than <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (6.69) or placebo (6.67) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>When costs and outcomes were discounted at 3%, lifestyle cost $10,037 per QALY, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> had slightly lower costs and nearly the same QALYs as placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Over 10 years, from a payer perspective, lifestyle was cost-effective and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> was marginally cost-saving compared with placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Investment in lifestyle and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> interventions for <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> prevention in high-risk adults provides good value for the money spent </plain></SENT>
</text></document>