<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To assess the effects of meal timing on the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of the dipeptidyl peptidase IV (DPP-4) inhibitor vildagliptin in Japanese patients with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In this open-label, single-center crossover study, 12 Japanese patients with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were randomized to twice-daily vildagliptin 50 mg, administered 30 min before or immediately before breakfast and dinner for 7 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>After a 7-day washout period, patients received the other regimen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Blood samples were collected for the determination of vildagliptin, DPP-4, glucagon-like <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi>-1 (GLP-1) and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Vildagliptin absorption appeared slower when administered 30 min before rather than immediately before meals (tmax absolute range: 1.00 - 2.00 h vs. 0.33 - 1.58 h) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Vildagliptin Cmax and AUC0-8 h were essentially the same irrespective of meal timing (geometric mean ratio: Cmax 1.08 (90% CI; 0.92 - 1.26); AUC0-8 h 0.97 (90% CI; 0.91 - 1.05)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Meal timing did not affect pharmacodynamics; complete DPP-4 inhibition (&gt; 90%) was sustained for 8 h post-dose, and plasma active glucagon-like <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi>-1 levels increased 2 - 3-fold from baseline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) and postprandial plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (PPPG) reductions from baseline did not differ significantly with meal timing (30 min before vs. immediately before: FPG, -8.9 vs. -5.8 mg/dl; adjusted AUE0-4 h, -67.0 vs. -51.0 mg×h/dl) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Vildagliptin was well tolerated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Dosing 30 min or immediately before meals did not affect vildagliptin pharmacokinetics or pharmacodynamics in Japanese patients with Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>