<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND/PURPOSE: <z:mp ids='MP_0001573'>Abnormal alanine aminotransferase level</z:mp> (ALT) levels might be associated with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, but whether higher ALT levels within the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> range predict the risk is unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We followed a community-based cohort of 3446 individuals who were ≥35 years old without <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0012115'>hepatitis</z:hpo> B or C in southern Taiwan for 8 years (1997-2004) to study the risk for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with different <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> ALT levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Among the 337 incident <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> cases, 16.0% were from those with ALT levels &lt;10 IU/L, 44.5% with ALT levels 10-19 IU/L, 30.0% with ALT levels 20-39 IU/L, and only 9.5% with ALT levels ≥40 IU/L </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A cumulative hazard function test showed that the higher the ALT levels, the greater the cumulative incidence rate of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (p &lt; 0.001, log-rank test) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A multiple Cox proportional hazards analysis showed that increasing age, lower educational levels, higher body mass index levels (≥25 vs. &lt;25), and higher ALT levels (vs. the reference group, ALT &lt;10 IU/L), from hazard ratio (HR) = 1.8, for ALT = 10-19, HR = 3.7 for ALT = 20-39, to HR = 4.5 for ALT ≥40, were significant factors for developing <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The hazard ratios of higher ALT levels in the participants without alcohol consumption were similar to or higher than those in the total cohort </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Higher ALT levels, even within the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> range, are strong predictors of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> independently of body mass index levels with a dose-response relationship </plain></SENT>
</text></document>