<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: To evaluate the cost-effectiveness of insulin detemir vs. <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin once daily, in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in the Swedish setting based on clinical data from a published randomized controlled trial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Projections of long-term outcomes were made using the IMS CORE <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Model (CDM), based on clinical data from a 26-week randomized controlled trial that compared once daily insulin detemir and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin, when used to intensify insulin treatment in 271 patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and body mass index (BMI) 25-40 kg/m(2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Trial results showed that insulin detemir was associated with a significantly lower incidence of hypoglycemic events and significantly less <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> in comparison with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The analysis was conducted from a third party payer perspective and the base case analysis was performed over a time horizon of 40 years and future costs and clinical outcomes were discounted at a rate of 3% per year </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Insulin detemir was associated with higher mean (SD) quality-adjusted life expectancy (5.42 [0.10] vs. 5.31 [0.10] quality-adjusted life years [QALYs]) and lower overall costs (SEK 378,539 [10,372] vs. SEK 384,216 [11,230]; EUR 33,794 and EUR 34,300, respectively, where 1 EUR=11.2015 SEK) compared with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Sensitivity analysis showed that the principal driver of the benefits associated with insulin detemir was the lower rate of hypoglycemic events (major and minor events) vs. <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin, suggesting that detemir might also be cost-saving over a shorter time horizon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Limitations of the analysis include the use of data from a trial outside Sweden in the Swedish setting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Based on clinical input data derived from a previously published randomized controlled trial, it is likely that in the Swedish setting insulin detemir would be cost-saving in comparison with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">NPH</z:e> insulin for the treatment of patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>