<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Poor adherence to oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetics</z:chebi> has a negative influence on glycaemic control in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Real Time Medication Monitoring (RTMM) combines real time monitoring of patients' medication use with SMS reminders sent only if patients forget their medication, aiming to improve adherence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study aimed to investigate the effect of these SMS reminders on adherence to oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetics</z:chebi> in patients using RTMM and investigate patients' experiences with RTMM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Data were collected in a RCT involving 104 type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> patients with suboptimal adherence to oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetics</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Fifty-six patients were randomised to receive SMS reminders if they forgot their medication, 48 patients received no reminders </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Primary outcome measure was adherence to oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetics</z:chebi> registered with RTMM, measured as: (1) days without dosing; (2) missed doses; (3) doses taken within predefined standardized time windows </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients' experiences were assessed with written questionnaires </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Over the six-month study period, patients receiving SMS reminders took significantly more doses within predefined time windows than patients receiving no reminders: 50% vs. 39% within a 1-h window (p=0.003) up to 81% vs. 70% within a 4-h window (p=0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Reminded patients tended to miss doses less frequently than patients not reminded (15% vs. 19%, p=0.065) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Days without dosing were not significantly different between the groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The majority of patients reported positive experiences with RTMM and SMS reminders </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: RTMM with SMS reminders improves adherence of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> patients, especially the precision with which patients follow their prescribed regimen, and is well accepted by patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>TRIAL REGISTRATION: Netherlands Trial Register NTR1882 </plain></SENT>
</text></document>