<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: There are two types of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> affects younger people and needs treatment with insulin injections </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> affects older people and can usually be treated by diet and oral drugs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0011882" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Diabetic neuropathy</z:e> affects 10% of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> at diagnosis and 40% to 50% after 10 years. Enhanced <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control is the best studied intervention for the prevention of this disabling condition but there have been no systematic reviews of the evidence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To examine the evidence for enhanced <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control in the prevention of distal symmetric <z:hpo ids='HP_0001271'>polyneuropathy</z:hpo> in people with type 1 and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>SEARCH METHODS: We searched the Cochrane <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027868" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Neuromuscular Disease</z:e> Group Specialized Register (30 January 2012), CENTRAL (2012, Issue 1), MEDLINE (1966 to January 2012) and EMBASE (1980 to January 2012) for randomized controlled trials of enhanced <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>SELECTION CRITERIA: We included <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> randomized, controlled studies investigating enhanced glycemic control that reported <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e> outcomes after at least one year of intervention </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Our primary outcome measure was annual development of clinical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e> defined by a clinical scale </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Secondary outcomes included motor nerve conduction velocity and quantitative vibration testing.  DATA COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS: Two authors independently reviewed <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> titles and abstracts identified by the database searches for inclusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Two authors abstracted data from <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> included studies with a standardized form. A third author mediated conflicts. We analyzed the presence of clinical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e> with annualized risk differences (RDs), and conduction velocity and quantitative velocity measurements with mean differences per year.  MAIN RESULTS: This review identified 17 randomized studies that addressed whether enhanced <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control prevents the development of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e>. Seven of these studies were conducted in people with type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, eight in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, and two in both types </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>A meta-analysis of the two studies that reported the primary outcome (incidence of clinical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e>) with a total of 1228 participants with type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> revealed a significantly reduced risk of developing clinical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e> in those with enhanced <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control, an annualized RD of -1.84% (95% confidence interval (CI) -1.11 to -2.56). In a similar analysis of four studies that reported the primary outcome, involving 6669 participants with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, the annualized RD of developing clinical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e> was -0.58% (95% CI 0.01 to -1.17). Most secondary outcomes were significantly in favor of intensive treatment in both populations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>However, both types of diabetic participants also had a significant increase in severe adverse events including hypoglycemic events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS: According to high-quality evidence, enhanced <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control significantly prevents the development of clinical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e> and reduces nerve conduction and vibration threshold abnormalities in type 1 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo>, enhanced <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control reduces the incidence of clinical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442874" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neuropathy</z:e>, although this was not formally statistically significant (P = 0.06) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>However, enhanced <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control does significantly reduce nerve conduction and vibration threshold abnormalities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Importantly, enhanced <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control significantly increases the risk of severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001988'>hypoglycemic episodes</z:hpo>, which needs to be taken into account when evaluating its risk/benefit ratio </plain></SENT>
</text></document>