<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To assess β-cell function preservation after 3.5 years of intensive therapy with insulin plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (INS group) versus triple oral therapy (TOT group) with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5441">glyburide</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="8228">pioglitazone</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This was a randomized trial of 58 patients with treatment-naïve newly diagnosed type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients were treated with insulin and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> for a 3-month lead-in period followed by random assignment to the INS or TOT group. β-Cell function was assessed using a mixed-meal challenge test at randomization and 6, 12, 18, 30, and 42 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Analyses were intention to treat and performed with repeated-measures models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Completion rates at 3.5 years were 83% in the insulin group and 72% in the TOT group, with good compliance in both groups (87 ± 20% in the INS group vs. 90 ± 15% in the TOT group). β-Cell function was preserved at 3.5 years after diagnosis, with no significant change from baseline or difference between the two groups as measured by area under the curve (AUC) of C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> (P = 0.14) or the ratio of C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> to <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> AUC (P = 0.7) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Excellent glycemic control was maintained in both groups (end-of-study HbA(1c) 6.35 ± 0.84% in the INS group vs. 6.59 ± 1.94% in the TOT group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Weight increased in both groups over time (from 102.2 ± 24.9 kg to 106.2 ± 31.7 kg in the INS group and from 100.9 ± 23.0 kg to 110.5 ± 31.8 kg in the TOT group), with no significant difference between groups (P = 0.35) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Hypoglycemic events decreased significantly over time (P = 0.01) but did not differ between groups (P = 0.83) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: β-Cell function can be preserved for at least 3.5 years with early and intensive therapy for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> with either insulin plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> or triple oral therapy after an initial 3-month insulin-based treatment period </plain></SENT>
</text></document>