<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Abstract Background: Short-term intensive insulin therapy has been shown to induce long-term glycemic remission in patients with newly diagnosed type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, predictors of remission are still uncertain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This study was conducted to evaluate whether changes of 1,5-anhydroglucitol (1,5AG) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="24103">fructosamine</z:chebi> (FA) could be a predictor of remission </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Subjects and Methods: Newly diagnosed drug-naive patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (n=64) were enrolled </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After baseline assessments, continuous subcutaneous insulin infusion (CSII) was administered in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients until euglycemia was achieved and maintained for another 2 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Patients were subsequently followed monthly for 3 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>1,5AG and FA were measured before and after therapy and at 1-month follow-up </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Results: After CSII, A1C and FA decreased from baseline, whereas 1,5AG increased </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>1,5AG was higher at 1-month follow-up (11.5±4.1 vs. 6.7±2.8 mg/L, P&lt;0.001), whereas FA was lower (273.1±56.1 vs. 316.2±39.3 μmol/L, P=0.021) in the remission group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Stepwise logistic regression analysis showed that 1,5AG at 1-month follow-up rather than FA was an independent predictor of remission after adjusting for other confounders (odds ratio 1.56, 95% confidence interval [CI] 1.15-2.12, P=0.004) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The area under the curve of the receiver operating characteristic curve analysis was 0.85 (95% CI 0.75-0.96, P&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The optimal cutoff point for 1,5AG at 1-month follow-up was 8.9 mg/L (specificity, 83.3%; sensitivity, 78.6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: Improvement of 1,5AG predicts maintenance of glycemic remission after intensive insulin therapy in patients with newly diagnosed type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>