<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To compare the incidence of symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> between <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> in Muslim patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who fasted during Ramadan </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In a multicenter, pragmatic, randomized study, patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were recruited from clinical centers in India (n = 765) and Malaysia (n = 105) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Eligible patients (age ≥ 18 yrs) expressed their intention to daytime fast during Ramadan, were treated with a stable dose of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> with or without <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> for ≥3 months prior to screening visit, and had an HbA(1c) ≤ 10% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients were randomized in a 1:1 ratio to either switch to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> 100 mg q.d. or remain on their pre-study <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Daily diary cards were completed to document information on hypoglycemic symptoms and complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The primary endpoint was the overall incidence of symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> during Ramadan </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of the 870 patients randomized, 848 (n = 421 for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> and 427 for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi>) returned ≥1 completed diary card and were included in the analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The proportion of patients who recorded ≥1 symptomatic hypoglycemic event during Ramadan was lower with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> (3.8%) compared to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> (7.3%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The risk of symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> was significantly lower with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> (risk ratio [95% CI] = 0.52 [0.29, 0.94]; p = 0.028) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>By country, the proportions of patients who recorded ≥1 symptomatic hypoglycemic event during Ramadan were 4.1% vs. 7.7% in India and 1.9% vs. 3.8% in Malaysia for <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi>, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>No patient discontinued treatment due to a hypoglycemic event </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>One patient on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> and seven on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> had an event that required non-medical assistance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>No events required medical assistance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Both treatments were generally well tolerated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>LIMITATIONS: Symptomatic hypoglycemic events did not require a confirmatory blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> measurement, which may have overestimated hypoglycemic events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Measures of glycemic control and body weight were not assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Switching antihyperglycemic treatment to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="40237">sitagliptin</z:chebi> from a <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> reduced the risk of symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> by approximately 50% for Muslim patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who fasted during Ramadan </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>CLINICAL TRIAL REGISTRATION: Clinicaltrials.gov: NCT01340768 </plain></SENT>
</text></document>