<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: In adults, the shape of the <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> response during an oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test (OGTT) prospectively and independently predicts type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, no reports have described the utility of this indicator in younger populations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to compare type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> risk factors in Latino adolescents characterized by either a monophasic or biphasic <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> response during an OGTT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A total of 156 nondiabetic Latino adolescents completed a 2-h OGTT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Monophasic and biphasic groups were compared for the following type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> risk factors: fasting and 2-h <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, HbA(1c), <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> area under the curve (AUC), insulin sensitivity (Matsuda index), insulin secretion (insulinogenic index), and β-cell function as measured by the disposition index (insulin sensitivity × insulin secretion) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Of the participants, 107 youth were categorized as monophasic and 49 were biphasic </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Compared with the monophasic group, participants with a biphasic response exhibited lower HbA(1c) (5.4 ± 0.3 vs. 5.6 ± 0.3%, P &lt; 0.01) and lower <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> AUC (14,205 ± 2,382 vs. 16,230 ± 2,537 mg ⋅ dL(-1) ⋅ h(-1), P &lt; 0.001) with higher insulin sensitivity (5.4 ± 3.2 vs. 4.6 ± 3.4, P ≤ 0.05), higher insulin secretion (2.1 ± 1.3 vs. 1.8 ± 1.3, P = 0.05), and better β-cell function (10.3 ± 7.8 vs. 6.0 ± 3.6, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Differences persisted after adjusting for age, sex, and BMI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: These data suggest that the glycemic response to an OGTT may differentiate risk for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in youth </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This response may be an early marker of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> risk among high-risk youth </plain></SENT>
</text></document>