<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND &amp; OBJECTIVES: A large number of plants have been recognized to be effective in the treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Persistent <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020456" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hyperglycaemia</z:e> is associated with decreased function of immune system and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0917798" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral ischaemia</z:e> mainly due to increased <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> and <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammatory response</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Andrographis paniculata is a medicinal plant widely used in folk medicine for various purposes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In this study the effect of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> administration (7 days) of methanolic extract of A. paniculata leaves was studied in rats with experimentally induced <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, nootropic and immunostimulant activities were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The effect of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> administration of methanolic extract of A. paniculata leaves was also studied for cerebroprotective activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was induced in rats by <z:chebi fb="1" ids="9288">streptozotocin</z:chebi> (STZ) (65 mg/kg) + <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17154">nicotinamide</z:chebi> (150 mg/kg) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Various biochemical parameters were estimated using standard methods </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: A significant (P&lt;0.05) increase in cognitive function was observed in both <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> and type 2 diabetic rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Nootropic activity in terms of per cent reduction in latency period was more in type 2 diabetic rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A significant increase in blood lymphocyte count, splenic lymphocyte count and peritoneal macrophage count was observed in both <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> and type 2 diabetic rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Immunostimulant activity was observed more in type 2 diabetic rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The per cent decrease in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> was more in type 2 diabetic rats when compared to <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The per cent increase in <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase (SOD) levels was more in type 2 diabetic rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>INTERPRETATION &amp; CONCLUSIONS: The <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> activity of the methanolic extract of A. paniculata leaves was evident by decreased tissue malondialdehyde (<z:chebi fb="14" ids="32506">MDA</z:chebi>) levels and increased SOD levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>These properties may be responsible for the observed cerebroprotective activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>The methanolic leaf extract of A. paniculata showed significant immunostimulant, cerebroprotective and nootropic activities in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> and type 2 diabetic rats </plain></SENT>
</text></document>