<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Identifying modifiable covariables that reduce demographic disparities in controlling type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> could inform efforts to improve health equity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This retrospective study utilized electronic health record data on 22,285 adults with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> seen at 110 outpatient clinics in the Southeast U.S. from 2004-2008 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Demographic differences in <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> control and modifiable covariables which reduce those disparities were quantified using descriptive and logistic regression analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients were 55.8 +/- 14.6 (SD) years old, 57.5% women, 61.0% white: 39.0% black and had baseline body mass index 34. +/- .3 kg/ m2 and HbA1c 7.61 +/- 1.9% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The percentage with HbAlc &lt;7% was higher in Whites than blacks (55.6% vs. 44.7%, P &lt; .0001) and rose with age in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients from 45.3% at &lt;50, to 50.0% at 50-64, and 59.6% at &gt; or =65 years, P &lt; .001. white vs. black race (odds ratio [OR] 1.59, 95% confidence interval [CI] 1.51-1.68) and age/ 10 years (OR 1.20/10 years, 95% CI 1.17-1.22) were predictors of HbAlc &lt;7% in univariable logistic regression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In multivariable analysis, three modifiable covariables (initial HbAlc, therapeutic inertia, visit frequency) accounted for 47.9% of variance in <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>When accounting for these modifiable covariables, the independent impact of race/ethnicity (OR 1.21, 95% CI 1.13-1.30) and age (OR 1.13, 95% Cl 1.11-1.16) on HbA1c control declined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Race and age-related difference in <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> control declined significantly when modifiable covariates were considered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Greater attention to early diagnosis and treatment, ensuring regular healthcare visits and overcoming therapeutic inertia could improve <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> control and health equity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>