<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Introduction.  <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>Diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> (DM) is a major risk factor for developing <z:hpo ids='HP_0000802'>erectile dysfunction</z:hpo> (ED) and men with DM are often less responsive to phosphodiesterase type 5 (PDE5) inhibitors than ED due to other causes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Aims.  The aim of this study was to explore potential mechanisms whereby PDE5 inhibitors may have reduced efficacy in type 2 DM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Methods.  At 4 weeks of age, mice were either fed a high-fat diet (HFD) for 22-36 weeks or fed regular chow (control) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>An additional group of mice in the same genetic background had a genetic form of type 1 DM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Main Outcome Measures.  <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi> tolerance testing, intracorporal pressures (ICPs), <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> (OS), apoptotic cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> (active caspase-3 and apostain), PDE5, p53, and cyclic <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16750">guanosine</z:chebi> monophosphate (cGMP) levels, and histological examination of inflow arteries were performed in mice fed a HFD and control mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A group of mice with type 1 DM were studied for PDE5 expression levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Results.  <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> mice fed a HFD had <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo> compared with the age-matched mice fed on standard chow diet (control) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>HFD fed mice had reduced maximum ICPs following in vivo cavernous nerve electrical stimulation and increased apoptotic cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, OS, and p53 levels in the corporal tissue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, PDE5 levels were increased and cGMP levels were decreased </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In contrast, mice with type 1 DM did not have increases in PDE5 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Conclusions.  Taken together, our results suggest that type 2 DM-induced ED is associated with findings that could lead to reduced cGMP and may account for reduced efficacy of PDE5 inhibitors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Ellati RT, Dokun AO, Kavoussi PK, Steers <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">WD</z:e>, Annex BH, and Lysiak JJ </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Increased phosphodiesterase type 5 levels in a mouse model of type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>J Sex Med **;**:**-** </plain></SENT>
</text></document>