<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Aging is closely associated with muscle <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003077'>hyperlipidemia</z:hpo>, nonalcoholic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001397'>fatty liver</z:hpo> disease (NAFLD), and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We examined the hypothesis that muscle <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in healthy aging promotes increased hepatic de novo lipogenesis (DNL) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003077'>hyperlipidemia</z:hpo> by altering the distribution pattern of postprandial energy storage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Healthy, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> weight, sedentary elderly subjects pair-matched to young subjects were given two high-carbohydrate meals followed by ¹³C/¹H magnetic resonance spectroscopy measurements of postprandial changes in muscle and liver <z:chebi fb="15" ids="28087">glycogen</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> content, and assessment of DNL using ²H₂O </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Net muscle <z:chebi fb="15" ids="28087">glycogen</z:chebi> synthesis was reduced by 45% (P &lt; 0.007) in the elderly subjects compared with the young, reflecting severe muscle <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Net liver <z:chebi fb="15" ids="28087">glycogen</z:chebi> synthesis was similar between groups (elderly, 143 ± 23 mmol/L vs. young, 138 ± 13 mmol/L; P = NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Hepatic DNL was more than twofold higher in the elderly than in the young subjects (elderly, 14.5 ± 1.4% vs. young, 6.9 ± 0.7%; P = 0.00015) and was associated with approximately threefold higher postprandial hepatic <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> (TG) content (P &lt; 0.005) and increased fasting plasma TGs (elderly, 1.19 ± 0.18 mmol/L vs. young, 0.74 ± 0.11 mmol/L; P = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These results strongly support the hypothesis that muscle <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> in aging promotes <z:hpo ids='HP_0003077'>hyperlipidemia</z:hpo> and NAFLD by altering the pattern of postprandial carbohydrate storage away from muscle <z:chebi fb="15" ids="28087">glycogen</z:chebi> and into hepatic DNL </plain></SENT>
</text></document>