<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Latent autoimmune <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in adults (LADA) is a slowly developing form of autoimmune <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> characterized by the presence of type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>-associated autoantibody </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to determine the incidence and characteristics of LADA in a population-based cohort of Polish patients with newly-diagnosed <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL AND METHODS: The study cohort was taken from the resident population of the city Białystok, Poland, during the period 1 January to 31 December 2003, aged 20-64 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>During this period we identified 231 cases of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We measured glutamic acid decarboxylase (GADA) and insulin antibody (<z:mp ids='MP_0004157'>IAA</z:mp>), insulin, C <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> and glycated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> (HbA(1c)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Diagnosis of LADA was made according to Immunology <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Society and Action LADA criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The incidence of LADA was 10 per year per 100 000 people </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The proportion of patients with LADA was 8.9% among newly diagnosed cases with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Patients with LADA were younger at diagnosis (48.5 ±9.4 years vs. 54.8 ±10.6 years, p &lt; 0.01), had lower body mass index (26.9 ±9.3 kg/m(2) vs. 29.5 ±5.2 kg/m(2), p &lt; 0.05), C <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> (126 ±127 pmol/l vs. 446 ±592 pmol/l, p &lt; 0.001), and were less insulin resistant (HOMA IR 0.94 ±0.85 vs. 3.6±4.4, p &lt; 0.001) compared to patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Glycated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> and fasting <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> were similar in patients with LADA and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In addition to GAD, anti-insulin antibodies are useful for diagnosing autoimmune <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in adults </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Patients with LADA have similar <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control parameters (HbA(1c)) compared to patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, although they are usually younger and have a lower body mass index </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Patients with LADA make up a significant proportion of newly diagnosed people with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> in a Polish population </plain></SENT>
</text></document>