<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948379" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Impaired insulin secretion</z:e> from pancreatic β-cells is a major factor in the pathogenesis of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The main regulator of insulin secretion is the plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> concentration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Insulin secretion is modified by other nutrients, circulating hormones and the autonomic <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system, as well as local paracrine and autocrine signals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Autocrine signalling involves diffusible molecules that bind to receptors on the same cell from which they have been released </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The first transmitter to be implicated in the autocrine regulation of β-cell function was insulin itself </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The importance of autocrine insulin signalling is underscored by the finding that mice lacking insulin receptors in β-cells are <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> intolerant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In addition to insulin, β-cells secrete a variety of additional substances, including <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptides</z:chebi> (e.g. amylin, chromogranin A and B and their cleavage products), <z:chebi fb="65" ids="25512">neurotransmitters</z:chebi> (ATP and γ-aminobutyric acid) and ions (e.g. zinc) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Here we review the autocrine effects of substances secreted from β-cells, with a focus on <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> effects in stimulus-secretion coupling, present some novel data and discuss the general significance of autocrine signals for the regulation of insulin secretion </plain></SENT>
</text></document>