<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Incretin-based therapies provide additional options for treating type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We aimed to evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of exenatide monotherapy in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A 26-week, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> controlled, parallel-group study was conducted among <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> drug-naive <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients aged &gt; 18 years, and with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Participating patients were randomly assigned to receive exenatide or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> treatments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Fifty-nine patients (age (50.5 ± 8.6) years, body mass index (BMI) (30.2 ± 1.6) kg/m(2), and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> A1C (HbA(1C) (8.2 ± 1.2)%) were enrolled in the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">Glucose</z:chebi> control and weight reduction improved in both groups receiving treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>HbA(1C) and oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> tolerance test (OGTT) 2 hour glycemia reduction with exenatide was superior to that obtained with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> ((-2.10 ± 1.79)% vs. (-1.66 ± 1.38)%, (-5.11 ± 2.68) mmol/L vs. (-2.80 ± 2.70) mmol/L, P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Fast plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) reduction was not significantly different between the two groups ((-1.8 ± 2.0) mmol/L vs. (-1.6 ± 1.7) mmol/L, P &gt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Patients treated with exenatide achieved HbA(1C) of &lt; 7% (97% of patients) and &lt; 6.5% (79%) at end-point, vs. 93% and 73% with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> (P &gt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Greater weight reduction was also achieved with exenatide ((-5.80 ± 3.66) kg) than with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> ((-3.81 ± 1.38) kg, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Homeostasis model assessment of beta-cell function (HOMA-B) was not significantly increased, but the insulinogenic index and HOMA for insulin sensitivity (HOMA-S) were greatly improved in the exenatide group (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002018'>Nausea</z:hpo> was the most common adverse effect in exenatide treatment (30% vs. 8%; P &lt; 0.05), but most cases were of mild to moderate intensity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>One case in the exenatide group was withdrawn early because of severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0002018'>nausea</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>Hypoglycemia</z:hpo> events were often observed during the first 4 weeks, with 12% of patients in the exenatide and 3.2% in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> groups, respectively (P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>No incidents of severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> were reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Exenatide demonstrated more beneficial effects on HbA(1C), weight reduction and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> during 26 weeks of treatment, but there were more hypoglycemic events and mild-to-moderate <z:hpo ids='HP_0002018'>nausea</z:hpo> compared with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6801">metformin</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>These results suggested that exenatide monotherapy may provide a viable treatment option in newly developed type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>