<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: Although overweight is an important determinant of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> risk, it remains unclear whether food choices can still influence the risk for type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in overweight persons </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In this paper, we aim to clarify the role of dietary patterns in the development of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> individuals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We studied 20,835 overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> participants in the Dutch part of the European Investigation into <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">Cancer</z:e> and Nutrition (EPIC-NL) study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Dietary intake was measured using a validated food frequency questionnaire, and dietary patterns were generated using factor analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Incident type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> was verified against medical records </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Cox proportional hazards models were used to assess the association between the dietary patterns (factor scores categorized in quartiles) and incident type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Scoring on Pattern 1, characterized by fish, wine, chicken, raw vegetables and fruit juices, was not associated with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> risk after confounder adjustment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A high score on Pattern 2, characterized by soft drinks, fries and snacks, was associated with higher risk of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (HR Q4 vs. Q1 (95 % CI): 1.70 (1.31; 2.20), p (trend) ≤ 0.0001), particularly among less active individuals [less active: HR Q4 vs. Q1 (95 % CI): 2.14 (1.48; 3.09), p (trend) = 0.00004, more active: HR Q4 vs. Q1 (95 % CI): 1.35 (0.93; 1.97), p (trend) = 0.01; p (interaction) = 0.02] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A high score on a pattern high in soft drinks, fries and snacks and low in fruit and vegetables was associated with higher risk of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in overweight and <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> subjects especially among physically less active individuals </plain></SENT>
</text></document>