<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>ABSTRACT: BACKGROUND: Non-enzymatic glycation increases <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi>-oxygen affinity and reduces oxygen delivery to tissues by altering the structure and function of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi>.ObjectivesWe investigated whether an elevated blood concentration of glycosylated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> (HbA1c) could induce falsely high pulse oximeter oxygen saturation (SpO2) in type 2 diabetic patients during mechanical ventilation or oxygen therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Arterial oxygen saturation (SaO2) and partial pressure of oxygen (<z:chebi fb="3" ids="37370">PO2</z:chebi>) were determined with simultaneous monitoring of SpO2 in 261 type 2 diabetic patients during ventilation or oxygen inhalation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Blood concentration of HbA1c was &gt;7% in 114 patients and &lt;= 7% in 147 patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Both SaO2 (96.2 +/- 2.9%, 95% confidence interval [CI] 95.7-96.7% vs. 95.1 +/- 2.8%, 95% CI 94.7-95.6%) and SpO2 (98.0 +/- 2.6%, 95% CI 97.6-98.5% vs. 95.3 +/- 2.8%, 95% CI 94.9-95.8%) were significantly higher in patients with HbA1c &gt;7% than in those with HbA1c &lt;= 7% (Data are mean +/- SD, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> p &lt; 0.01), but <z:chebi fb="3" ids="37370">PO2</z:chebi> did not significantly differ between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Bland-Altman analysis demonstrated a significant bias between SpO2 and SaO2 (1.83 +/-0.55%, 95% CI 1.73% -1.94%) and limits of agreement (0.76% and 2.92%) in patients with HbA1c &gt;7% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The differences between SpO2 and SaO2 correlated closely with blood HbA1c levels (Pearson's r = 0.307, p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Elevated blood HbA1c levels lead to an overestimation of SaO2 by SpO2, suggesting that arterial blood gas analysis may be needed for type 2 diabetic patients with poor glycemic control during the treatment of hypoxemia </plain></SENT>
</text></document>