<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>Inflammation</z:mp> is postulated to play a role in diabetogenesis and its further vascular complications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim was to assess the inflammatory and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> parameters in patients of type 2 diabetic mellitus with or without complication </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>MATERIAL AND METHODS: Serum high sensitivity C-reactive protein (hs-CRP), nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> metabolite (NO(X)), fibrinogen, and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> parameters were measured in eighty type 2 diabetic males (40-65 years) without (n=40, group B) and with complication (16 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo>, group C; 24 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>, group D); and compared with 40 healthy, age and sex matched nondiabetic males (group A) from the general population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULT: The mean age of subjects and fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> among groups A, B, and C+D were 51.0±7.1 vs. 48.7±5.7 vs. 50.2±6.1 years (p&gt;0.05); and 96.7±10.4 vs. 134.3±27.8 vs. 136.4±29.8mg/dl (p&lt;0.001) respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> were older, with longer duration of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, and high fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The mean hs-CRP, NO(X), fibrinogen, TC, TG, and <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi>(C) varied significantly (p&lt;0.001) between control and diabetics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>hs-CRP, NO(X), and fibrinogen were found to be highest in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> group whereas no significant (p&gt;0.05) difference was noted between groups B and D in relation to hs-CRP and NO(X) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>TC and <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi>(C) were significantly (p&lt;0.001) high among group B patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Significant positive correlation was observed between <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> three inflammatory markers in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> categories of patients; between FPG, hs-CRP, and fibrinogen among patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>; between FPG, hs-CRP, and NO(X) in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, none of the <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> parameters showed any significant correlation with any of the inflammatory markers in any group of patients studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Low grade systemic <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp>, in association with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e>, plays a role in diabetogenesis and its complications </plain></SENT>
</text></document>