<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>Diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> is a global health problem affecting 366 million people worldwide and its prevalence is growing rapidly </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0011869" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Diabetic eye disease</z:e> is present in up to 25% of diabetic subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> is a <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> complication of <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> that can result in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000618'>blindness</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Generally, there are two stages of diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo>, non-proliferative and proliferative </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The longer a person has <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and the poorer metabolic control, the higher the chance of developing diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The majority of people with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> will ultimately develop diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo>.  Multifactorial therapy targeted to lifestyle modification and optional glycemic control reduces the risk </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> develops or progresses with time.  Primary (preventive) strategies include glycemic, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi>, and blood pressure control.  Glycemic control effectively reduces the incidence of diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In additional, its effect on progression of diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> has been demonstrated in randomized clinical trials.  Furthermore, tight control of blood pressure significantly reduces the progression of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000572'>visual loss</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, the Action to Control Cardiovascular Risk in <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> (ACCORD) Eye Study Group has shown that intensive blood pressure control has no beneficial effect on reducing the rate of diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> in subjects with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>.  Elevated serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemias</z:e> are associated with a higher risk of diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The beneficial effects of <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi>-lowering agents on the progression of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> have been reported </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Intensive combination therapy for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e> has been shown to effectively reduce the rate of progression of diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>.  Secondary strategies are focused on various pathophysiologic approaches such as blockade of the renin angiotensin system (<z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp>), anti-vascular endothelial growth factor agents, somatostatin analogues, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37699">protein kinase inhibitors</z:chebi>, and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35472">anti-inflammatory agents</z:chebi>.  The purpose of the current overview is to look into the medical management of diabetic <z:hpo ids='HP_0000488'>retinopathy</z:hpo>, and to explore the primary (preventive) measures as well as secondary strategies proposed to be effective in its medical management </plain></SENT>
</text></document>