<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE Patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> have a high incidence of cardiovascular events including <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Increased arterial stiffness (AS) predicts cardiovascular events in the general population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Cerebral white matter lesions (WMLs) are associated with an increased risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>It is unknown whether AS in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> is associated with WMLs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS We examined 89 patients recently diagnosed with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (&lt;5 years) and 89 sex- and age-matched controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>AS was assessed with carotid-femoral pulse wave velocity (PWV) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>WMLs were identified using magnetic resonance imaging and graded qualitatively with the Breteler scale (no/slight changes = 0, moderate changes = 1, severe changes = 2) and semiquantitatively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS The diabetic population had excellent glycemic control (HbA(1c), 6.5% [6.2-6.8]; median [interquartile range {IQR}]) and had, compared with the controls, lower office blood pressure (BP) (127 ± 12/79 ± 8 vs. 132 ± 14/84 ± 10 mmHg) and total cholesterol (4.3[3.9-4.7] vs. 5.6 [5.1-6.4]; mmol/L; median [IQR]), (P &lt; 0.01 for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Despite this, PWV was higher in the patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> compared with controls (9.3 ± 2.0 vs. 8.0 ± 1.6 m/s; P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>PWV was associated with Breteler score (OR 1.36 [95% CI 1.17-1.58]; P &lt; 0.001) and WML volume (OR 1.32 [95% CI 1.16-1.51]; P &lt; 0.001) per 1 m/s increase in PWV </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>These associations remained significant when adjusted for age, sex, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, 24-h mean arterial BP, BMI, heart rate, and use of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35674">antihypertensives</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statins</z:chebi> (Breteler score: OR 1.28 [95% CI 1.03-1.60]; P &lt; 0.05 and WML volume: OR 1.30 [95% CI 1.06-1.58]; P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS PWV was higher among patients with well-controlled type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> compared with controls and was independently associated with WMLs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>PWV may represent a clinically relevant parameter in the evaluation of cerebrovascular disease risk in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>