<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>UNLABELLED: BACKGROUND: The American <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>Diabetes</z:mp> Association (<z:chebi fb="36" ids="39048">ADA</z:chebi>) has published several <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> treatment algorithms, but none have been tested in real-life settings </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study is to analyze the feasibility of achieving and/or maintaining HbA1c levels &lt;7.0% using current <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> treatment guidelines and the resources available in the public health care system of Brazil </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A one-year, single-arm interventional study was conducted with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> patients in a primary care unit </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Intervention consisted of intensification of lifestyle changes and sequential prescription of drugs based on <z:chebi fb="36" ids="39048">ADA</z:chebi> guidelines using the medications available through the publicly funded Unified Health System (Sistema Único de Saúde, SUS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Ninety patients (age: 62.7±10.4 years; <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> duration: 8.2±9.1 years) completed the trial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>During the intervention period, increases were observed in number of oral <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> agent (OAD) classes per patient (1.50±0.74 vs. 1.67±0.7; p=0.015), OAD pills per patient (2.64±1.89 vs. 3.33±2.23 pills/patient; p &lt;0.001), insulin dosage (0.20±0.29 vs.0.50±0.36 UI/kg/day; p=0.008) and number of patients on insulin (19 [21%] vs. 31 [34%]; p&lt;0.01), but no improvement in HbA1c (7.2±1.6% vs. 7.3±1.5%; p=0.453) or frequency of patients on target, defined as HbA1c &lt;7% (53.3% vs. 48.9%; p=0.655) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients with baseline HbA1c &lt;7% had a small increase in HbA1c during the trial (6.3±0.4 vs. 6.7±0.9%; p=0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No such change was observed in those with baseline HbA1c ≥7% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In this group of patients with a mean baseline HbA1c of 7.2%, implementation of 2006/2009 ADA/EASD guidelines led to achievement of the therapeutic goal of HbA1c &lt;7% in a small proportion of patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>