<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVESince January 2008, <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> women with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> were advised to gain 0-5 kg during pregnancy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim with this study was to evaluate fetal growth and perinatal morbidity in relation to gestational <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> in these women.RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODSA retrospective cohort comprised the records of 58 singleton pregnancies in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> women (BMI ≥30 kg/m(2)) with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> giving birth between 2008 and 2011 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Birth weight was evaluated by SD z score to adjust for gestational age and sex.RESULTSSeventeen women (29%) gained ≤5 kg, and the remaining 41 gained &gt;5 kg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The median (range) gestational <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gains</z:mp> were 3.7 kg (-4.7 to 5 kg) and 12.1 kg (5.5-25.5 kg), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Prepregnancy BMI was 33.5 kg/m(2) (30-53 kg/m(2)) vs. 36.8 kg/m(2) (30-48 kg/m(2)), P = 0.037, and median HbA(1c) was 6.7% at first visit in both groups and decreased to 5.7 and 6.0%, P = 0.620, in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0878751" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">late pregnancy</z:e>, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Gestational <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> ≤5 kg was associated with lower birth weight z score (P = 0.008), lower rates of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001520'>large-for-gestational-age</z:hpo> (LGA) infants (12 vs. 39%, P = 0.041), delivery closer to term (268 vs. 262 days, P = 0.039), and less perinatal morbidity (35 vs. 71%, P = 0.024) compared with pregnancies with maternal <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> &gt;5 kg.CONCLUSIONIn this pilot study in <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> women with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, maternal gestational <z:mp ids='MP_0005456'>weight gain</z:mp> ≤5 kg was associated with a more proportionate birth weight and less perinatal morbidity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>