<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A B-cell-deficient model for Type 2 (non-insulin-dependent) <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> has been investigated with regard to insulin action at the cellular level </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Two-day-old male Sprague Dawley rats were injected with <z:chebi fb="1" ids="9288">streptozotocin</z:chebi> (90 mg/kg) or <z:chebi fb="2" ids="50744">citrate</z:chebi> buffer </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>At 6 weeks <z:chebi fb="1" ids="9288">streptozotocin</z:chebi>-treated animals were hyperglycaemic and exhibited <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>glucose intolerance</z:hpo>, e.g. at 45 min post-<z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (1.5 g/kg) the change in serum <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> level from baseline was 6 +/- 7 mg% in control rats vs. 212 +/- 18 mg% for the <z:chebi fb="1" ids="9288">streptozotocin</z:chebi>-treated rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Basal activity and insulin action in isolated adipocytes, as estimated by 2-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="15866">deoxyglucose</z:chebi> uptake and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> metabolism, were not influenced by <z:chebi fb="1" ids="9288">streptozotocin</z:chebi> treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>For example, uptake of 0.1 mmol/1 2-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="15866">deoxyglucose</z:chebi> at 1000 microU insulin/ml was 58 +/- 8 pmol/10(5) cells min-1 vs 54 +/- 6 pmol for adipocytes isolated from experimental vs. control animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Although serum insulin levels in <z:chebi fb="1" ids="9288">streptozotocin</z:chebi>-treated rats were significantly decreased (p less than 0.05), there was no difference in insulin receptor number or affinity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>Glucose intolerance</z:hpo> present in this model is similar to that in Type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, concomitant insulin intolerance was not observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Taken together with our findings of unaltered insulin action at the cellular level, this suggests that the pathogenesis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000855'>insulin resistance</z:hpo> is not dependent on <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>glucose intolerance</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Moreover, this hyperglycaemic model is responsive to oral hypoglycaemic agents and can be used to establish their direct effects on physiologic and cellular insulin action </plain></SENT>
</text></document>