<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>To investigate the possible contribution of glucokinase (GCK) and <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16335">adenosine</z:chebi> deaminase (<z:chebi fb="36" ids="39048">ADA</z:chebi>) loci to the genetic susceptibility to type 2 (non-insulin-dependent) <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo>, we studied the association of these loci with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in the Japanese population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Fifty patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> and 50 control subjects were analyzed for microsatellite polymorphism 3' to the GCK gene and PstI polymorphism in the <z:chebi fb="36" ids="39048">ADA</z:chebi> gene by polymerase chain reaction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The frequency of the most common GCK allele (Z) was significantly lower in type 2 diabetic patients than that in control subjects and a longer Z + 2 allele was more common in type 2 diabetic patients (26% vs. 15%, P = 0.053), particularly in those with younger <z:hpo ids='HP_0011007'>age of onset</z:hpo> (33% vs. 15%, younger <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> vs. control, P = 0.014) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The frequency of genotypes containing at least one Z + 2 allele was significantly more common in type 2 diabetic patients (46% vs. 28%, P &lt; 0.05), particularly in those with younger <z:hpo ids='HP_0011007'>age of onset</z:hpo> (61% vs. 28%, relative risk 4.00, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In contrast, there was no difference in allelic or genotypic frequencies of PstI polymorphism in the <z:chebi fb="36" ids="39048">ADA</z:chebi> gene between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Despite the association between the GCK locus and type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, none of the patients had known mutations (Glu265--&gt;AM265, Glu279--&gt;AM279, Gly299--&gt;Arg299, Glu300--&gt;Gln300, Leu309--&gt;Pro309) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These results suggest that the GCK locus, but not the <z:chebi fb="36" ids="39048">ADA</z:chebi> locus, contributes to the genetic susceptibility to type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in Japanese.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>