<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate the relative value of plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (PG) at different time points in assessing <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control of type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Glycemic profiles, i.e., PG at prebreakfast (8:00 A.M.), prelunch (11:00 A.M.), postlunch (2:00 P.M.), and extended postlunch (5:00 P.M.) times over the same day, were obtained in 66 type 2 diabetic patients on an ambulatory basis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The different time points of PG were compared with a measurement of HbA1c made in a reference laboratory </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Extended postlunch PG was lower than prebreakfast PG (104 +/- 21 vs. 133 +/- 35 mg/dl, P &lt; 0.02) in patients demonstrating good diabetic control (HbA1c &lt; or = 7.0%), was not different from prebreakfast PG (149 +/- 47 vs. 166 +/- 26 mg/dl, NS) in patients demonstrating fair diabetic control (7.0% &lt; HbA1c &lt; or = 8.5%), and was higher than prebreakfast PG (221 +/- 62 vs. 199 +/- 49 mg/dl, P &lt; or = 0.01) in those demonstrating poor diabetic control (HbA1c &lt; or = 8.5%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Prebreakfast, prelunch, postlunch, and extended postlunch PG values were <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> significantly correlated with HbA1c </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Multiple linear regression analysis demonstrated that postlunch PG and extended postlunch PG correlated significantly and independently with HbA1c, but that prebreakfast PG and prelunch PG did not </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Moreover, postlunch PG and extended postlunch PG demonstrated better sensitivity, specificity, and positive predictive value in predicting poor glycemic control than did prebreakfast PG or prelunch PG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: In type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, postlunch PG and extended postlunch PG are better predictors of glycemic control than fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We therefore suggest that they be more widely used to supplement, or substitute for, FPG in evaluating the metabolic control of type 2 diabetic patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>