<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine the effects of glycemic control on the counterregulatory responses to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Seven poorly controlled type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> patients (mean HbA1c, 11.3 +/- 1.1%) were studied by stepped hyperinsulinemic hypoglycemic clamp (nadir, 2.4 mmol/l) before and after improving glycemic control with insulin treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Counterregulatory hormones, symptoms, and four-choice reaction time were measured at each <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> plateau </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In patients with poorly controlled type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, counterregulatory hormone responses began at higher plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels than did those in healthy subjects (<z:chebi fb="2" ids="28918">epinephrine</z:chebi>, 4.4 +/- 0.2 vs. 3.7 +/- 0.2 mmol/l, P = 0.011) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After significant improvement in glycemic control (mean HbA1c, 8.1 +/- 0.9%, P &lt; 0.001) was achieved without severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo>, hormonal responses started at much lower plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels (e.g., <z:chebi fb="2" ids="28918">epinephrine</z:chebi>, 3.5 +/- 0.3 mmol/l, P = 0.005) and were significantly reduced in magnitude (e.g., area under <z:chebi fb="2" ids="28918">epinephrine</z:chebi> response curve, 306 +/- 93 vs. 690 +/- 107 nmol.min-1.l-1, P = 0.012) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This was accompanied by a change in the plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> threshold at which hypoglycemic symptoms first developed from 3.6 +/- 0.2 to 3.0 +/- 0.2 mmol/l (P = 0.019) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> threshold at which four-choice reaction time deteriorated did not change significantly (3.1 +/- 0.1 vs. 2.9 +/- 0.1 mmol/l, P = 0.125) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Counterregulatory responses begin at normoglycemia in poorly controlled type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Improving glycemic control with insulin therapy normalizes hormonal responses but lowers the plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels at which hypoglycemic symptoms develop to levels associated with impairment of four-choice reaction time, a marker of cognitive function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This process potentially increases the risk of severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo>, but to a lesser extent than occurs in type 1 disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>