<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine whether serum <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> intervention, in addition to conventional <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> treatment, could alter cardiovascular outcomes in type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: There were 164 type 2 diabetic subjects (117 men, 47 women) without a history of clinical <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007222" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="CVD">cardiovascular disease</z:e> randomized to receive either <z:chebi fb="0" ids="47612">bezafibrate</z:chebi> or placebo daily on a double-blind basis in addition to routine <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> treatment and followed prospectively for a minimum of 3 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Serial biochemical and noninvasive vascular assessments, carotid and femoral artery B-mode ultrasound measurements, and those pertaining to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010068" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary heart disease</z:e> (CHD)--clinical history, the World Health Organization (WHO) cardiovascular questionnaire, and resting and exercise electrocardiogram (ECG)--were recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="47612">Bezafibrate</z:chebi> treatment was associated with significantly greater reductions over 3 years in median serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> (-32 vs. 4%, P = 0.001), total cholesterol (-7 vs. -0.3%, P = 0.004), and total-to-<z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> ratio (-12 vs. -0.0%, P = 0.001), and an increase in <z:chebi fb="4" ids="47775">HDL cholesterol</z:chebi> (6 vs. -2%, P = 0.02) as compared with placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There was a trend toward a greater reduction of fibrinogen (-18 vs. -6%, P = 0.08) at 3 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>No significant differences between the two groups were found in the progress of ultrasonically measured <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0852949" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">arterial disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In those treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="47612">bezafibrate</z:chebi>, there was a significant reduction (P = 0.01, log-rank test) in the combined incidence of Minnesota-coded probable ischemic change on the resting ECG and of documented <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Improving <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0242339" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dyslipidemia</z:e> in type 2 diabetic subjects had no effect on the progress of ultrasonically measured <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0852949" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">arterial disease</z:e>, although the lower rate of "definite CHD events" in the treated group suggests that this might result in a reduction in the incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010068" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coronary heart disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>