<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To examine the effects of 4 weeks of subcutaneous administration of pramlintide, a synthetic analog of human amylin, on metabolic control in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> using insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: Serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="24103">fructosamine</z:chebi>, HbA1c, and fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi> were measured in 203 patients in a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled parallel-group multicenter trial using doses of 30 micrograms q.i.d., 60 micrograms t.i.d., and 60 micrograms q.i.d </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Statistically significant reductions in serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="24103">fructosamine</z:chebi> concentrations were observed in the pramlintide 30 micrograms q.i.d. group (17.5 +/- 4.9 mumol/l, P = 0.029), the pramlintide 60 micrograms t.i.d. group (24.1 +/- 4.9 mumol/l, P = 0.003), and the 60 micrograms q.i.d. group (22.6 +/- 4.1 mumol/l, P = 0.001) compared with the placebo group (3.5 +/- 3.8 mumol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>There were also statistically significant shifts in the proportion of patients with an abnormal serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="24103">fructosamine</z:chebi> concentration at baseline that normalized at week 4 within the pramlintide 60 micrograms t.i.d. group and the 60 micrograms q.i.d. group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Consistent with the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="24103">fructosamine</z:chebi> results, there were statistically significant reductions in HbA1c in the pramlintide 30 micrograms q.i.d. group (0.53 +/- 0.07%, P = 0.0447), the pramlintide 60 micrograms t.i.d. group (0.58 +/- 0.07%, P &lt; 0.0217), and the pramlintide 60 micrograms q.i.d. group (0.51 +/- 0.08%, P = 0.0242) compared with the placebo group (0.27 +/- 0.08%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Total cholesterol concentrations were also statistically significantly reduced in both the pramlintide 60 micrograms t.i.d. group (8.4 mg/dl, P &lt; 0.01) and 60 micrograms q.i.d. group (10.5 mg/dl, P &lt; 0.01) compared with placebo (1.2 mg/dl) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Body weight decreased in both of the pramlintide 60 micrograms groups, but the trend did not achieve statistical significance </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> was similar in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> treatment groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Reductions in serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="24103">fructosamine</z:chebi>, plasma total and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47774">LDL cholesterol</z:chebi> concentrations, and HbA1c support the hypothesis that pramlintide may improve metabolic control in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> using insulin </plain></SENT>
</text></document>