<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: To determine the effect(s) on <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control, insulin dose, and circulating insulin levels of the addition of a <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> (glipizide) to the treatment regimen of patients with insulin-requiring type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: Thirty seven patients with type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> taking insulin for at least 1 year prior to study and treated with &gt; or = 40 U of insulin per day were recruited for a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover trial </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients were treated with 3 months of insulin + placebo (I + P) and 3 months of insulin + glipizide (I + G), with an intermediate 1 month washout period using insulin therapy alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Adjustments were made initially to the maximum dose of glipizide (40 mg/day), followed by insulin dose adjustments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Twenty-nine of the 37 patients demonstrated a significant C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> response to Ensure and were selected for analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> in the I + G arm was 6.8 (121.8 mg/dl) vs. 8.7 mmol/L (156.0 mg/dl) in the I + P arm, P &lt; 0.001 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Mean plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> over 24 hours was 9.8 (176.9 mg/dl) for I + G vs. 11.3 mmol/L (203.8 mg/dl) for I + P, P &lt; 0.001 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Glycated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> was significantly different (9.8 I + G vs. 11.4% I + P, P &lt; 0.008) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The total daily insulin dose required was significantly lower with I + G (69.1 vs. 87.3 U, P &lt; 0.0005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, there were no significant differences in free insulin levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The addition of a <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> (glipizide) to insulin therapy in patients with insulin-requiring type 2 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo> taking large doses of insulin results in a rapid and substantial improvement in <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control despite a significant reduction in insulin dose </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Therefore, this form of combination therapy should be considered for patients with the above characteristics whose diet and exercise programs are correct but whose response to insulin therapy is inadequate </plain></SENT>
</text></document>