<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: This study tested a simple algorithm for beginning insulin for <z:mp ids='MP_0001261'>obese</z:mp> patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> after <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylurea</z:chebi> failure, comparing suppertime 70/30 insulin plus continued <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> with insulin alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: This was a multicenter ambulatory randomized double-masked parallel comparison </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>There were 208 subjects with secondary failure to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="26831">sulfonylureas</z:chebi> who took <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> titrated to 8 mg b.i.d. for 8 weeks; 145 subjects with fasting plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FPG) 180-300 mg/dl (10-16.7 mmol/l) on this treatment were randomized to placebo plus insulin (PI) or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> plus insulin (GI) for 24 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A dosage of 70/30 insulin before supper was titrated, seeking fasting capillary blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> (FBG) 120 mg/dl (6.7 mmol/l), equivalent to FPG 140 mg/dl (7.8 mmol/l) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Outcome measures included FPG, HbA1c, insulin dosage, weight, serum insulin and <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipids</z:chebi>, and adverse events </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: FPG and HbA1c were equivalent at baseline: 261 vs. 250 mg/dl (14.5 vs. 13.9 mmol/l), and 9.9 vs. 9.7% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At 24 weeks, the FPG target was achieved in both groups (136 vs. 138 mg/dl, 7.6 vs. 7.6 mmol/l), and HbA1c values were equal (7.7 vs. 7.6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, with GI, control improved faster and fewer subjects dropped out (3 vs. 15%, P &lt; 0.01), and less insulin was needed (49 vs. 78 U/d, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The outcomes were alike in other respects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>No subject had severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001943'>hypoglycemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Injection of 70/30 insulin before supper safely restored glycemic control of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> not controlled by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Control was restored more rapidly and with less injected insulin when <z:chebi fb="0" ids="5383">glimepiride</z:chebi> was continued </plain></SENT>
</text></document>