<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To demonstrate the efficacy, tolerability, and safety of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> compared with placebo in patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> inadequately controlled with diet and insulin </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS: A multicenter randomized double-blind placebo-controlled parallel-group comparison study was conducted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The trial was 26 weeks with a 2-week screening period and a 24-week period of treatment with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> or placebo, with forced titration from 25 mg t.i.d. to 50 mg t.i.d. after 4 weeks, and titration of 50 mg t.i.d. to 100 mg t.i.d. after 12 weeks based on <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> control </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The dosage of insulin was to remain stable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The primary efficacy variable was mean change from baseline in HbA1c, and secondary efficacy variables included mean changes in fasting and postprandial plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The addition of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> to the treatment of patients receiving background insulin and diet therapy resulted in a statistically significant reduction in mean HbA1c of 0.69% compared with placebo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were statistically significant reductions in postprandial plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> area under the curve, and in postprandial serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> levels in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi>-treated patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Gastrointestinal side effects were more frequently reported in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi>-treated patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There were no significant differences in hypoglycemic events or liver transaminase elevations between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: This study demonstrated that the addition of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2376">acarbose</z:chebi> to patients with type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> who are inadequately controlled with insulin and diet is safe and generally well tolerated and that it significantly lowers HbA1c and postprandial <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> levels </plain></SENT>
</text></document>