<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The aim of the study was 1) to establish the prevalence of GAD antibodies (GADab) in a population-based study of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in western Finland, 2) to genetically and phenotypically characterize this subgroup, and 3) to provide a definition for latent autoimmune <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> in adults (LADA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The prevalence of GADab was 9.3% among 1,122 type 2 diabetic patients, 3.6% among 558 <z:hpo ids='HP_0000833'>impaired glucose tolerance</z:hpo> (IGT) subjects, and 4.4% among 383 nondiabetic control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Islet antigen 2 antibodies (IA2ab) or islet cell antibodies were detected in only 0.5% of the GADab- patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The GADab+ patients had lower fasting C-<z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> concentrations (median [interquartile range]: 0.46 [0.45] vs. 0.62 [0.44] nmol/l, P = 0.0002) and lower insulin response to oral <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> compared with GADab- patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>With respect to features of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e>, the GADab+ patients had lower systolic (140 [29.1] vs. 148 [26.0] mmHg, P = 0.009) and diastolic (79.2 [17.6] vs. 81.0 [13.1] mmHg, P = 0.030) blood pressure values, as well as lower <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17855">triglyceride</z:chebi> concentrations (1.40 [1.18] vs. 1.75 [1.25] mmol/l, P = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>GADab+ men had a lower waist-to-hip ratio compared with GADab- patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Compared with GADab- patients and control subjects, the GADab+ patients had an increased frequency HLA-DQB1*0201/0302 (13 vs. 4%; P = 0.002) and other genotypes containing the *0302 allele (22 vs. 12%; P = 0.010) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, the frequency of these high-risk genotypes was significantly lower in GADab+ type 2 patients than in type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> of young or <z:hpo ids='HP_0003581'>adult onset</z:hpo> (0201/0302 or 0302/X: 36 vs. 66 vs. 64%, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The GADab+ type 2 group did not differ from control subjects with respect to genotypes containing the protective DQB1-alleles *0602 or *0603, nor with respect to the type 1 high-risk genotype in the IDDM1 (Hph1 +/+) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>We conclude that GADab+ patients differ from both GADab- type 2 diabetic patients and type 1 diabetic patients with respect to beta-cell function, features of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0948265" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">metabolic syndrome</z:e>, and type 1 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> susceptibility genes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Further, we propose that LADA be defined as GADab positivity (&gt;5 relative units) in patients older than 35 years at <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of type 2 <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>