<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Increased intramedullary apoptotic <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> of hematopoietic cells is thought to contribute to the ineffective hematopoiesis in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, high amounts of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e> <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> factor alpha (TNF alpha) have previously been correlated with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> marrows </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The present studies were undertaken to examine the status of two key downstream effectors of TNF alpha signaling, i.e. Caspase 1 and Caspase 3 enzymes, using a fluorometric assay in the bone marrow aspirate mononuclear cells (BMMNC) in relation to apoptotic DNA fragmentation detected by in situ end-labeling (ISEL) of DNA and with localization of TNF alpha in the corresponding biopsies from 14 MDS patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Both Caspase 1 and 3 were detectable in freshly harvested BMMNC, albeit median Caspase 3 levels (47.5 units/mg protein) being almost 10 times higher than Caspase 1 (4.0 units/mg protein) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Upon short-term culture for 4 h in a serum-supplemented medium in vitro a significant increase was seen in Caspase 3 activity (58.8 +/- 13.9 at 0 h vs. 177.8 +/- 55.2 units/mg protein at 4 h, n = 14, P = 0.017) and in percent cells labeled by ISEL (apoptotic index or AI%: 0.76% +/- 0.25% vs. 3.99% +/- 1.1%, n = 14, P = 0.004, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Caspase 1 activity increased after 15 min in culture </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, TNF alpha levels measured by immunohistochemistry correlated with the net increase in Caspase 3 activity after 4 h (p = 0.517, n = 13, P = 0.07) and the starting levels of Caspase 1 at 0 h correlated with the Caspase 3 levels attained at 4 h (p = 0.593, n = 13, P = 0.033) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Additionally when TNF alpha-positive bone marrows (8/14) were compared with the negative marrows (6/14) the Caspase 3 levels were significantly higher in the TNF alpha-positive marrows (189.6 +/- 66.2 vs. 25.0 +/- 14.6 units/mg protein, respectively, P = 0.043) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The increase in AI%, though not statistically significant, was also higher in the TNF alpha-positive marrows </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Finally in HL60 cells the effects of different Caspase inhibitors and pentoxifylline (PTX) (interferes with <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> signaling of cytokines) on TNF alpha-induced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> were evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>TNF alpha treatment significantly increased AI% (P &lt; 0.003) as compared to the untreated controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>A co-treatment with three Caspase inhibitors, zVAD.FMK (inhibitor of Caspases 1 and 3, 10 microM/l), Ac.YVAD.FMK (Caspase 1 inhibitor, 1 microM/l), Ac.DEVD.FMK (Caspase 3 inhibitor, 10 microM/l) as well as PTX (250 microM/l) significantly curtailed the AI% induced by TNF alpha </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The present studies thus identify the downstream effectors of TNF alpha-inducible <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> and so also the suppressors of TNF alpha apoptotic signaling </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>These results may have significant clinical implications in the therapy of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> in the future </plain></SENT>
</text></document>