<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Idiopathic acquired sideroblastic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anaemias</z:hpo> (IASAs) form a subgroup of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> and are characterized by <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> iron accumulation, bone marrow <z:hpo ids='HP_0012132'>erythroid hyperplasia</z:hpo> and decreased peripheral red blood cell counts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Increased intramedullary <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> of erythroid precursors is presumed to constitute the pathophysiological mechanism explaining this <z:hpo ids='HP_0010972'>ineffective erythropoiesis</z:hpo>, but if and how <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> dysfunction is implicated in this process is currently unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We therefore studied bone marrow precursor cells obtained from nine patients with IASA for (i) caspase 3 activity, (ii) numbers of Annexin V- and 7-amino-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="15369">actinomycin</z:chebi>-positive cells, (iii) numbers of cells with diminished <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> membrane potential, Delta Psi(m), and (iv) numbers of cells producing reactive oxygen species (ROS), and we compared the results with those of five <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> bone marrow samples </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Compared with controls, we found increased caspase 3 activity in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> IASA samples, which correlated with increased numbers of Annexin-V-positive cells (r = 0.7) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Analysis of different subpopulations showed <z:mp ids='MP_0006042'>increased apoptosis</z:mp> in erythroid populations compared with myeloid and/or lymphoid populations in five out of nine cases, and <z:mp ids='MP_0006042'>increased apoptosis</z:mp> in the last two populations in four out of nine cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>As evidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> dysfunction, Delta Psi(m) was found to be diminished in the erythroid subpopulations of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> cases of IASA (66.6 +/- 17% vs. 34.6 +/- 12% in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normals</z:mpath>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Delta Psi(m) decrease was correlated to Annexin V positivity (r = 0.7) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Astonishingly, no difference was found between IASA and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> bone marrows with regard to the number of ROS-producing cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In fact, both groups exhibited a similar low proportion of ROS production (10.3 +/- 7% in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normals</z:mpath> vs. 6.8 +/- 5% in IASA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Taken together, our results show that mitochondria are clearly implicated in the apoptotic process in IASA patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Whether this is a result of an intramitochondrial defect (e.g. Fe accumulation, secondary to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001427'>mitochondrial</z:hpo> or nuclear DNA mutations) or is secondary to an extracellular stimulus [e.g. <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e> <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> factor (TNF), Fas ligand (FasL)] remains to be determined </plain></SENT>
</text></document>