<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES: Recombinant erythropoietin (r-EPO) induces erythroid responses in patients affected by <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, the response rate declines to 10-15% in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> with substantial transfusion needs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Both in vitro and in vivo studies have suggested that the addition of growth factors (G-CSF, GM-CSF) or interleukin-3 (IL-3) may potentiate the effect of r-EPO on dysplastic erythropoiesis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to evaluate the effects of the combination of r-EPO with G-CSF, GM-CSF or IL-3 on the <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anemia</z:hpo> of heavily transfusion-dependent <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients, previously unresponsive to r-EPO alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: Sixty patients with transfusion-dependent <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, already treated without significant erythroid response with r-EPO alone, were scheduled to receive, for at least 8 weeks, r-EPO subcutaneously at the dose of 300 U/kg t.i.w. in combination with G-CSF (300 microcg s.c. t.i.w., 27 patients), or GM-CSF (300 microcg s.c. t.i.w., 23 patients), or IL-3 (5 microcg/kg s.c. t.i.w., 10 patients), after a two-week pre-phase during which G-CSF, GM-CSF and IL-3 were administered daily at the same dose, as single drugs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Ten patients were not evaluable for erythroid response because of relevant side effects related to GM-CSF or IL-3 administration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Overall, among 50 patients who completed the study, there were 3 erythroid responses (as determined by complete abolition of red-cell transfusions): 1 (4%) in the G-CSF + r-EPO and 2 (10.5%) in the GM-CSF + r-EPO treated groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>No patient responded to the combination of r-EPO + IL-3 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> responders had inappropriate serum levels of endogenous EPO and a relatively short disease duration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Both responders to GM-CSF + r-EPO developed <z:hpo ids='HP_0004808'>acute myeloid leukemia</z:hpo> 2-9 months after the start of the combined therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>A third elderly patient, treated with the same association, developed marrow <z:mpath ids='MPATH_133'>hypoplasia</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>A significant increase in leukocyte count occurred in 96% of patients who received r-EPO + G-CSF, 78.9% of those treated with r-EPO + GM-CSF and 66% of subjects receiving r-EPO + IL-3 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>A significant increase in platelet count was observed in a single patient receiving r-EPO and GM-CSF, while a slight decrease in platelet count with respect to baseline levels occurred in about 20% of patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>INTERPRETATION AND CONCLUSIONS: Our results suggest that the combination of r-EPO with G-CSF, GM-CSF or IL-3, at least at the doses and schedules employed in the present study, has limited efficacy on the <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anemia</z:hpo> of heavily transfusion-dependent <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients previously unresponsive to r-EPO alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>However, in this setting of patients, the combination of G-CSF or GM-CSF + r-EPO may occasionally be effective in subjects with low circulating levels of serum EPO and short disease duration </plain></SENT>
</text></document>