<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) constitute a challenge for the biologist as well as for the treating physician </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In Section I, Dr. Willman reviews the current classifications and disease mechanisms involved in this <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneous</z:hpo> clonal hematopoietic stem cell disorder </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A stepwise genetic progression model is proposed in which inherited or acquired genetic lesions promote the acquisition of "secondary" genetic events mainly characterized by gains and losses of specific chromosome regions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The genetic risk to develop <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> is likely multifactorial and dependent on various constellations of risk-producing and -protecting alleles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In Section II Dr. Barrett with Dr. Saunthararajah addresses the immunologic factors that may act as important secondary events in the development of severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001876'>pancytopenia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>T cells from patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> may suppress autologous erythroid and granulocytic growth in vitro, and T cell suppression by antithymocyte globulin or <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4031">cyclosporine</z:chebi> may significantly improve cytopenia, especially in <z:hpo ids='HP_0005505'>refractory anemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Recent studies have also demonstrated an increased vessel density in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> bone marrow, and a phase II trial of thalidomide showed responses in a subgroup of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients especially in those with low blast counts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In Section III Dr. Hellström-Lindberg presents results of allogeneic and autologous stem cell transplantation (SCT), intensive and low-dose chemotherapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The results of allogeneic SCT in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> are slowly improving but are still poor for patients with unfavorable cytogenetics and/or a high score according to the International Prognostic Scoring System </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A recently published study of patients between 55-65 years old showed a disease-free survival (DFS) at 3 years of 39% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Consolidation treatment with autologous SCT after intensive chemotherapy may result in long-term DFS in a proportion of patients with high-risk <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Low-dose treatment with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2038">5-azacytidine</z:chebi> has been shown to significantly prolong the time to leukemic transformation or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> in patients with high-risk MSA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Erythropoietin and granulocyte colony-stimulating factor may synergistically improve <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> levels, particularly in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001924'>sideroblastic anemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Recent therapeutic advances have made it clear that new biological information may lead to new treatment modalities and, in combination with statistically developed predictive models, help select patients for different therapeutic options </plain></SENT>
</text></document>