<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The impact of classification, prognostic factors and treatment on survival and rate of leukemic transformation was analysed in 197 patients with primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) treated in the Institute of Hematology and Blood Transfusion in the years 1980-2000 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS AND RESULTS: The patients were classified according to the FAB criteria and divided into risk groups according to the International Prognostic Scoring System (IPSS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A separate evaluation of 34 patients who underwent stem cell transplantation and of 163 of those not transplanted was performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Median survival of not transplanted patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB</z:e> (10.0 months) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB-T</z:e> (12.0 months) was significantly shorter than survival of RA (62.4 months) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RARS</z:e> (48.1 months, P &lt; 0.001) patients as well as survival of patients included in intermediate II </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>(13.8 months) and high (10.8 months) risk subgroups when compared to those with low (74.9 months) and intermediate I. risk (56.0 months, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A similar difference was observed in percentage of patients evolving towards <z:hpo ids='HP_0002488'>acute leukemia</z:hpo> and in estimated 3 years survival (EFS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>EFS of RA patients was 57% in contrast to 4% in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB-T</z:e> group (P &lt; 0.001) in the same way, EFS in low risk subgroup was 79% vs. 3% in high risk patients (P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Chemotherapy alone did not significantly affect median survival of patients with advanced <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> when compared with supportive care </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>On the contrary, median survival of transplanted patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB</z:e> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB-T</z:e> was 38.4 months in comparison to 11.5 months in those not transplanted (P &lt; 0.001) and 36.8 months vs. 12.0 months in transplanted and not transplanted patients with intermediate II. and high risk (P = 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The difference in survival between transplanted and not transplanted patients with RA and in patients in low and intermediate I. risk subgroups was not statistically significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: We confirmed an adverse effect of excess of blasts on prognosis of patients with primary <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Stem cell transplantation had a significant beneficial effect on survival of patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB</z:e> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB-T</z:e> as well as of patients included in intermediate II. or high risk subgroups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The impact of stem cell transplantation on survival of patients with RA or with low or intermediate I. risk was not significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Therefore, further criteria should be taken in account for indication of stem cell transplantation in these subgroups of patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>