<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The combination of fludarabine (FDR), high dose <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28680">cytarabine</z:chebi> and granulocyte colony stimulating factor (FLAG) with or without <z:chebi fb="0" ids="42068">idarubicin</z:chebi> (Ida) was used in the treatment of poor risk <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:mpath ids='MPATH_336'>leukaemia</z:mpath> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) in a single centre experience </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A total of 105 patients were treated over a 4-year period with 59% achieving a complete remission (CR); no statistical difference observed between FLAG and FLAG-Ida </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>For patients responding to FLAG +/- Ida, the median event-free survival (EFS) was 11 months and 23% at 5 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Such patients proceeded either to further chemotherapy or a haematopoietic stem cell transplant (HSCT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The median EFS (13 months vs. 8 months) and projected 5-year survival (37% vs. 13%) of patients undergoing HSCT was significantly better than those who did not (P = 0.021) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>, 14 of 72 patients remain alive in continuing CR (median duration 43 months) with 10 of 31 having had a HSCT vs. four of 41 that did not (P = 0.033) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Both regimens were well tolerated, with the majority of patients experiencing grade 1 or less non-haematological toxicity (mainly <z:hpo ids='HP_0002017'>nausea and vomiting</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The median time to neutrophil and platelet recovery was 28 and 31 d, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>No significant differences were seen with the addition of ida </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There was a 17% incidence of treatment-related <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>deaths</z:hpo>, of which 39% was caused by invasive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0851807" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">aspergillus infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The results show that FLAG +/- Ida is an effective and well-tolerated remission induction regimen for poor risk <z:mpath ids='MPATH_336'>leukaemia</z:mpath> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>