<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: To determine if granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF) with empirical antibiotics accelerates febrile <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> resolution compared with antibiotics without it </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: Eligible children were treated without prophylactic G-CSF and presented with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo> (temperature &gt;38.3 degrees C) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> afterward </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004808'>acute myelogenous leukemia</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> were excluded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Assignments were randomized between G-CSF (5 microg/kg/day) or none beginning within 24 hr of antibiotics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Subcutaneous administration was recommended, but intravenous G-CSF was allowed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Patients remained on study until absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;500/microl and &gt; or =48 hr without <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: One of 67 patients enrolled was ineligible, 59 had <z:hpo ids='HP_0006721'>acute lymphoblastic leukemia</z:hpo> (ALL) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Thirty-four were assigned to antibiotics, 32 to G-CSF plus antibiotics </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Adding G-CSF significantly reduced <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> and febrile <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> recovery times </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Median days to febrile <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> resolution was nine earlier with G-CSF (4 vs. 13 days) (P &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>However, there was no difference in the resolution of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo> between arms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Hospitalization median was shorter by 1 day with G-CSF (4 vs. 5 days) (P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>There was no difference in the duration of IV and oral antibiotic treatment, addition of antifungal therapy, and shock incidence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>A trend for decreased incidence of late <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo> with G-CSF was noted (6.3 vs. 23.5%) (P = 0.08) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Adding G-CSF to empiric antibiotic coverage accelerates chemotherapy-induced febrile <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> resolution by 9 days in pediatric patients, mainly with ALL, which results in a small but significant difference in the median length of hospitalization </plain></SENT>
</text></document>