<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Intravenous low-dose <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">5-aza-2'-deoxycytidine</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi>) in patients with advanced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) yields an approximately 50% overall response rate, including 20-25% complete remission </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">Decitabine</z:chebi>-treated <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients can be managed as outpatients after completion of a 3-day infusion schedule </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In-hospital nights (IHNs), overall survival (OS), and remaining life spent in hospital were evaluated and compared to a matched control group receiving different standard treatments </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Between July 1992 and September 2001, 99 high-risk <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients, median age 70 years (range 49-86), were treated with low-dose <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Durations of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> hospitalizations were recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>For matched-pair analysis, 44 decitabine-treated patients were matched to 44 MDS patients according to International Prognostic Scoring System classification, period of diagnosis, age, French-American-British classification, and gender </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Median number of IHN across <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients was 56 and survival was 481 days, resulting in 84% of remaining life spent at home </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In the matched-pair analysis, the median number of IHN was 57 in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> group vs. 50 in the control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Median survival was 400 vs. 371 days for the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> and control groups, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Median number of remaining life spent at home was identical (83% for both groups) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Matched patients who received only best supportive care (n=12) had a shorter median survival than the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> patients (234 vs. 400 days), and the proportion of remaining life spent at home was slightly greater (82 vs. 77%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, matched patients with induction therapy showed comparable IHN, OS, and remaining life spent at home </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, high-risk <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients treated with low-dose <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> have better survival, and spend comparable time in hospital than patients treated with supportive treatment </plain></SENT>
</text></document>