<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Despite significant advances in prevention and therapy, cytomegalovirus (CMV) <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> continues to be an important cause of morbidity and mortality in the hematopoietic stem cell transplant (HSCT) recipient </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The standard drug for pre-emptive therapy is intravenous <z:chebi fb="0" ids="465284">ganciclovir</z:chebi> (GCV) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Valganciclovir (VGC), the oral pro-drug of GCV, has excellent bioavailability and is ideal for oral therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Since March 2002, VGC was adopted in our center for outpatient pre-emptive therapy in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients undergoing allogeneic HSCT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Fifty-two allogeneic HSCT recipients were followed weekly via Digene hybrid capture assay </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Patients with a positive assay were treated with VGC 900 mg p.o. b.i.d. x 14 days followed by 900 mg p.o </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>QD until at least 7 days after a negative test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Eighteen patients (14 sib, four MUD) had 30 episodes of CMV DNA detection treated with oral VGC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Median duration of therapy was 21 days (range 10-21 days) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The rate of response was 93% (28/30) as confirmed by a negative assay within 14 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>No significant toxicity was encountered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Two patients failed oral VGC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>One case of CMV <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0014335" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">enteritis</z:e> was diagnosed in a patient with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> GVHD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Pre-emptive therapy of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0010823" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">CMV infection</z:e> with oral VGC is safe and effective in allogeneic HSCT recipients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>