<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Aberrant DNA methylation, which results in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0598766" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">leukemogenesis</z:e>, is frequent in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) and is a potential target for pharmacologic therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">Decitabine</z:chebi> indirectly depletes methylcytosine and causes hypomethylation of target gene promoters </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A total of 170 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> were randomized to receive either <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> at a dose of 15 mg/m2 given intravenously over 3 hours every 8 hours for 3 days (at a dose of 135 mg/m2 per course) and repeated every 6 weeks, or best supportive care </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Response was assessed using the International Working Group criteria and required that response criteria be met for at least 8 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients who were treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> achieved a significantly higher overall response rate (17%), including 9% complete responses, compared with supportive care (0%) (P &lt; .001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>An additional 12 patients who were treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> (13%) achieved hematologic improvement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Responses were durable (median, 10.3 mos) and were associated with transfusion independence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> had a trend toward a longer median time to <z:hpo ids='HP_0004808'>acute myelogenous leukemia</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AML</z:e>) progression or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> compared with patients who received supportive care alone (<z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients, 12.1 mos vs. 7.8 mos [P = 0.16]; those with International Prognostic Scoring System intermediate-2/high-risk disease, 12.0 mos vs. 6.8 mos [P = 0.03]; those with de novo disease, 12.6 mos vs. 9.4 mos [P = 0.04]; and treatment-naive patients, 12.3 mos vs. 7.3 mos [P = 0.08]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">Decitabine</z:chebi> was found to be clinically effective in the treatment of patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, provided durable responses, and improved time to <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AML</z:e> transformation or <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The duration of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> therapy may improve these results further </plain></SENT>
</text></document>