<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The suppressor of cytokine signalling-1 (SOCS1) protein is a <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e> suppressor </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Hypermethylation of SOCS1 gene, resulting in transcriptional silencing, is suggested to play an important role in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancer</z:e> development </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We sought to characterise SOCS1 methylation in primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) and clarify its clinical implications </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The methylation status of SOCS1 was analysed by methylation-specific polymerase chain reaction in 114 patients with primary <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> and serial studies were performed in 29 of them </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>SOCS1 methylation occurred in 54 patients (47.4%), and was more frequent in patients with high-risk <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> than in those with low-risk (52.6% vs. 25.8%, P = 0.011) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>SOCS1 methylation was closely associated with NRAS mutation (P = 0.010) and inversely associated with good-risk karyotype (P = 0.021) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>With a median follow-up of 17 months (range: 1-231 months), two patients acquired SOCS1 methylation during disease progression </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In two patients, SOCS1 methylation present at diagnosis, disappeared after haematopoietic stem cell transplantation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Patients with SOCS1 methylation had a higher cumulative risk of leukaemic transformation than those without (55.8% vs. 27.7% at 3 years, P = 0.004) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This difference remained significant within the subgroup of patients with high-risk <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> (67.3% vs. 45.1% at 3 years, P = 0.045) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This is the first report to demonstrate the clinical relevance of SOCS1 methylation in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>It may play an important role in the pathogenesis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, especially among patients with high-risk subtypes </plain></SENT>
</text></document>