<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018133" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GVH">graft-versus-host-disease</z:e> (aGvHD) is a major cause of mortality after allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation (alloHCT) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The goal of this study was to evaluate the incidence and risk factors for this complication </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: 330 consecutive patients (183 male and 147 female), aged 29 (10-56) years, treated with alloHCT in a single center between 1992-2003 were included in the analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>AlloHCT was performed after myeloablative conditioning from either related donor (rel-HCT) (n=223) or unrelated voulnteer (URD-HCT) (n=107) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>GVHD prophylaxis consisted of cyclosporin, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="44185">methotrexate</z:chebi> +/- <z:chebi fb="2" ids="8378">prednisolone</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Cumulative incidence of grade II-IV and grade III-IV aGvHD equaled 31% and 17%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In multivariate analysis the following factors were associated with increased risk of grade II-IV aGvHD: the diagnosis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> myeloid <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> (<z:mp ids='MP_0005481'>CML</z:mp>) or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) (vs. other diagnoses), URD-HCT (vs. Rel-HCT), years of alloHCT 1992-2001 (vs. 2002-2003), donor age &gt; or =35 years, and CD34+ cell dose &gt; or = 4.0 x 10(6)/kg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Increased risk of grade III-IV aGVHD was associated with: the use of <z:chebi fb="2" ids="8378">prednisolone</z:chebi> for aGvHD prophylaxis, the diagnosis of <z:mp ids='MP_0005481'>CML</z:mp> or <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, and CD3+ cell dose &gt; or =100 x l0(6)/kg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Incidence of aGvHD depends on various recipient-, donor-, and procedure-related factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This should be taken into account when planning treatment for every individual patient </plain></SENT>
</text></document>