<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>In this uni-centre retrospective study, we studied 120 adults with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:mpath ids='MPATH_342'>myeloid leukaemia</z:mpath> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AML</z:e>) (n = 88) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) (n = 32) who received first allogeneic HSCT to determine prognostic factors which are correlated with the outcome after myeloablative (MA) or non-myeloablative (non-MA) allogeneic HSCT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The median age of our cohort was 44 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Fifty-nine per cent of the patients were transplanted in complete remission (CR) and 41% were in relapse or refractory to induction or salvage therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A total of 97 patients received a MA regimen and 23 were treated with a non-MA regimen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The prognostic impact for several parameters was assessed by univariate and by multivariate analyses using the Cox regression model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Three-year probabilities of non-relapse mortality (34 vs. 54%; p = 0.9) did not differ in the MA and non-MA groups, but differences were observed in the disease-free survival (DFS) (43 vs. 17%; p = 0.1) and the relapse rate (RR) (29 vs. 62%; p = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Independently from the regimen, in uni- and multivariate analysis, survival was best in those patients who were transplanted in CR and experienced cGvHD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, outcome of patients with complex cytogenetic aberrations was identical to that of better prognostic subgroups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In this study, the clinical benefit of a lower toxicity regimen was offset by higher RR resulting in inferior results in the non-MA group, especially when no CR was achieved by prior induction or salvage therapy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>