<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We observed <z:hpo ids='HP_0003281'>increased ferritin</z:hpo> levels in newly diagnosed <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RARS</z:e> patients without transfusional <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0282193" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">iron-overload</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Hence, we hypothesized <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RARS</z:e> patients may harbor <z:mp ids='MP_0005638'>hemochromatosis</z:mp>-related mutations, which could contribute to the pathophysiology of this <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) subset </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We studied a cohort of 140 MDS patients: 42 with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RARS</z:e>, 10 with increased ringed sideroblasts, and 96 with other forms of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> (43 RA, 27 RAEB, 17 RAEB-T, 8 MDS/MPD, 1 CMML) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients were genotyped using restriction fragment length polymorphism, designed to detect C282Y and H63D mutations of the HFE gene </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We found significantly higher frequency of heterozygosity for C282Y mutation in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RARS</z:e> patients compared with a large control population of matched race individuals (21 vs. 9.8% in controls, P = 0.03); H63D genotype was not significantly increased </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Frequency of HFE variation in other <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> subtypes failed to differ significantly from controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Within this group, we included patients with a rare form of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, provisionally subclassified by WHO as <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RARS</z:e> with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001894'>thrombocytosis</z:hpo> (RARSt) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>10/14 RARSt patients were carriers of either C282Y or H63D allele significantly increased compared with the combined prevalence in a healthy population (71 vs. 33%, P &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We found expected distribution of mutant HFE alleles in patients with other forms of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> (9.1 vs. 9.8%, P = 0.82) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Increased prevalence of HFE gene mutations is not a generalized feature of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, but some subgroups of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, especially those characterized by excessive accumulation of ringed sideroblasts, exhibit C282Y mutations at a higher frequency than in other forms of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> and healthy controls </plain></SENT>
</text></document>