<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Aberrant regulation of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e> <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> factor alpha gene (TNF) and stroma-derived signals are involved in the pathophysiology of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplasia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Therefore, KG1a, a <z:mpath ids='MPATH_342'>myeloid leukaemia</z:mpath> cell line, was exposed to Tnf in the absence or presence of either HS-5 or HS-27a cells, two human stroma cell lines </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>While KG1a cells were resistant to Tnf-induced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> in the absence of stroma cells, Tnf-promoted <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> of KG1a cells in co-culture experiments with stroma cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>To investigate the Tnf-induced signals from the stroma cells, we examined expression changes in HS-5 and HS-27a cells after Tnf exposure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>DNA microarray studies found both discordant and concordant Tnf-induced expression responses in the two stroma cell lines </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Tnf promoted an increased <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression of pro-inflammatory cytokines [e.g. interleukin (IL)6, IL8 and IL32] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At the same time, Tnf decreased the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression of anti-apoptotic genes (e.g. BCL2L1) and increased the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression of pro-apoptotic genes (e.g. BID) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Overall, the results suggested that Tnf induced a complex set of pro-inflammatory and pro-apoptotic signals in stroma cells that promote <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> in malignant myeloid clones </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Additional studies will be required to determine which of these signals are critical for the induction of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> in the malignant clones </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Those insights, in turn, may point the way to novel therapeutic approaches </plain></SENT>
</text></document>