<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We have conducted several phase I/II clinical studies in a total of 65 MDS patients utilizing recombinant human hematopoietic growth factors including GM-CSF, IL-3, and EPO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Twenty-seven patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> were treated with either continuous i.v. infusion or single daily s.c. injection of rhGM-CSF at dosages from 15 micrograms/m2 to 1000 micrograms/m2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> of them exhibited white cell responses during the treatment cycles, but no sustained rise in reticulocytes or platelets was recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In four of the patients, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> with &gt; or = 15% blast cells in the bone marrow, the percentage of circulating blast cells increased during treatment with rhGM-CSF (at dosages of 500 micrograms/m2 and 1000 micrograms/m2, respectively), although no leukemic conversion occurred </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Of 9 patients treated so far with rhIL-3 at single daily s.c. dosages of 60 micrograms/m2, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> exhibited white cell responses; 8 exhibited significant improved platelet and reticulocyte counts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Nineteen further patients received rhEPO for a period of 14 weeks by s.c </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>(10,000 U five times weekly) or i.v. bolus administration (150-450 U/kg) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>None of these patients experienced an increase in white cell and platelet counts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A significant increase of the reticulocyte count was recorded in 3 patients only </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Another strategy involves the recruitment of leukemic cells into the cell cycle by hematopoietic growth factors followed by treatment with cycle-specific <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35610">cytostatic</z:chebi> agents </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Therefore in 10 patients administration of rhGM-CSF (250 g/m2/day x 14, s.c.) was combined with Ara-C treatment (20 mg/m2/day x 14; s.c.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Initial results of this pilot study available in 5 patients indicated that this approach may control leukemic cell proliferation and may increase number of mature myeloid cells in both bone marrow and peripheral blood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>A similar approach utilizing rhIL-3 in conjunction with Ara-C is on-going </plain></SENT>
</text></document>