<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE: <z:chebi fb="56" ids="16716">Benzene</z:chebi>-caused <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hematologic diseases</z:e> can be recognized as <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0028797" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">occupational diseases</z:e> (ODs) if they fulfill the legal requirements specified under No. 1303 of the appendix of the German ordinance on ODs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study is to analyze the most important criteria that determined whether these diseases were recognized or rejected as ODs according to No. 1303 in 2006 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In 2006, 70 suspected cases of OD No. 1303 reported in North Rhine-Westphalia were examined in terms of diagnosis, notifiers, cumulative <z:chebi fb="56" ids="16716">benzene</z:chebi> exposures, professions, coexposures, delays in notification, latency periods, interim periods, and recognition criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: 70 benign and malignant diseases of myeloid and lymphoid origin were reported as suspected ODs, among them 41 B-cell non-Hodgkin's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> (B-cell NHL) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Latency periods ranged between 14 and 57 years (median 37; mean 36.3+/-11.4; n=45), estimated cumulative <z:chebi fb="56" ids="16716">benzene</z:chebi> exposures varied from 0 to 144 ppm-years (median 12; mean 11.4+/-22.8; n=59) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Four of 70 suspected cases were recognized as OD No. 1303 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In 37 cases (52.9%), the nature of the disease was assessed as being nontypical of OD No. 1303, in 50 cases (71.4%), no sufficient <z:chebi fb="56" ids="16716">benzene</z:chebi> exposure could be found </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Mature-cell NHL and Hodgkin's <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo> were not recognized as OD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Cumulative <z:chebi fb="56" ids="16716">benzene</z:chebi> exposures&lt;or=12.3 ppm-years were not regarded as being sufficient to cause OD No. 1303 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: When diagnosing <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hematologic diseases</z:e>, physicians should ask the patients about their occupational history and, in particular, consider <z:chebi fb="56" ids="16716">benzene</z:chebi> exposures dating back several decades </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>To improve the state of knowledge of OD No. 1303, it is important that diseases are consistently classified according to WHO criteria and any kind of myeloid and lymphoid disease, including NHL, is reported </plain></SENT>
</text></document>