<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The efficacy of human recombinant erythropoietin (rEPO) in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) has generally been best in untransfused patients with 'refractory <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anaemia</z:hpo>' according to the World Health Organization (WHO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We treated 63 MDS patients [excluding refractory <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anaemia</z:hpo> with excess blasts, type 2 (<z:e sem="disease" ids="C1318551" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">RAEB2</z:e>)] with a previously tested combination of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6067">13-cis-retinoic acid</z:chebi> and dihydroxylated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28940">vitamin D3</z:chebi> +/- 6-thioguanine in addition to rEPO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Most patients were categorized as refractory cytopenia with multilineage <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath> and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1318550" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">RAEB1</z:e>, with intermediate 1 International Prognostic Scoring System (IPSS) score; <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> had Hb &lt;95 g/l, and 70% required regular erythrocyte transfusions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Treatment was well tolerated, and erythroid response rate according to new International Working Group criteria was 60%: 50% in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1318550" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">RAEB1</z:e> and 64% in non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB</z:e> patients (P = 0.383) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Response rate was not affected by transfusion requirement (63%; 58% in untransfused), IPSS and WHO Prognostic Scoring System scores, and weekly rEPO dosage (30-50 000 U vs. 80 000 U) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Median response duration was 16 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Median survival reached 14 months for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1318550" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">RAEB1</z:e> and 55 months for non-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB</z:e> patients, with a significant difference in the latter between responders and non-responders (median 82 months vs. 44 months; P = 0.036) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Our combined therapy, independent of rEPO dosage, achieved in patients with unfavourable response predictors, a rate of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anaemia</z:hpo> improvement comparable to the best obtained in lower risk patients by high-dose rEPO </plain></SENT>
</text></document>