<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Invasive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004030" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">aspergillosis</z:e> (IA) is most commonly caused by the morphospecies Aspergillus fumigatus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, genetic-based methods indicate that organisms phenotypically identified as A. fumigatus actually constitute a mold complex, designated Aspergillus section fumigati subgenus fumigati </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Multilocus sequencing and analysis was performed on fungi identified as A. fumigatus from the clinical culture collection maintained at the National Institutes of Health from 2000 through 2008, with a focus on the internal transcribed spacer 1 and 2 regions of ribosomal DNA (rDNA), beta-tubulin, and rodlet A genes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We reviewed the medical records, radiology, and histopathology of corresponding patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>To confirm identification of Neosartorya udagawae isolates, mating studies were performed with reference strains </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Antifungal susceptibility testing was performed by broth microdilution and read at 48 hours </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Thirty-six cases of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> attributed to A. fumigatus were identified; 4 were caused by N. udagawae (3 in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0740451" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">granulomatous disease</z:e> and 1 in a patient with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Disease due to N. udagawae was <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo>, with a median duration of 35 weeks, compared with a median duration of 5.5 weeks for patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0740451" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">granulomatous disease</z:e> who had <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> due to A. fumigatus sensu stricto (P &lt; .05 , Mann-Whitney U test) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Infection</z:e> spread across anatomical planes in a contiguous manner and was refractory to standard therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Two of the 4 patients died </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>N. udagawae demonstrated relatively higher minimum inhibitory concentrations to various agents, compared with those demonstrated by contemporary A. fumigatus sensu stricto isolates </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: To our knowledge, this is the first report documenting <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> due to N. udagawae </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Clinical manifestations were distinct from those of typical IA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Fumigati-mimetics with inherent potential for antifungal resistance are agents of IA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Genetic identification of molds should be considered for unusual or refractory IA </plain></SENT>
</text></document>