<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: This study measured how <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) patients value transfusion independence (TI), reduced transfusions (RT) and transfusion-dependence (TD) using health utility assessment methodology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: 47 MDS patients were interviewed, US (n = 8), France (n = 9), Germany (n = 9) and the UK (n = 21), to elicit the utility value of TI, RT and TD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Health states were developed based on literature; patient forum discussions; and were validated by a hematologist </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Face-to-face interviews used the feeling thermometer Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) and the Time Trade-Off (TTO) method to value the health states on a 0 (dead) to 1 (perfect health) scale </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Socio-demographic, clinical, and quality-of-life (EQ-5D) characteristics were surveyed to describe the patient sample </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS AND DISCUSSION: The mean age was 67 years (range: 29-83); 45% male, 70% retired; 40% had secondary/high school education, or higher (32%), and 79% lived with family, a partner or spouse, or friends </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The mean time from <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> diagnosis was 5 years (range:1-23) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Most patients (87%) received previous transfusions and 49% had received a transfusion in the last 3 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Mean EQ-5D index score was 0.78; patients reported at least some problem with mobility (45%), usual activities (40%), pain/discomfort (47%), and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000739'>anxiety</z:hpo>/<z:hpo ids='HP_0000716'>depression</z:hpo> (34%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Few patients had difficulty understanding the VAS (n = 3) and TTO (n = 4) exercises </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Utility scores for TI were higher than for RT (0.84 vs. 0.77; p &lt; 0.001) or TD (0.84 vs. 0.60; p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Three patients rated TD worse than dead </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Corresponding VAS scale scores were 78 vs. 56; (p &lt; 0.001), and 78 vs. 31 (p &lt; 0.001), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Patients value TI, suggesting an important role for new treatments aiming to achieve greater TI in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>These results can be used in preference-based health economic evaluation of new <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> treatments, such as in future cost-utility studies </plain></SENT>
</text></document>