<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Epigenetic gene silencing due to promoter methylation is observed in human <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1306459,C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">cancers</z:e> like <z:hpo ids='HP_0004808'>acute myeloid leukemia</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AML</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Little is known about aberrant methylation in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>), a <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneous</z:hpo> clonal stem cell disorder with a approximately 30% risk of transformation into <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0280449" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">secondary AML</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Recent evidence demonstrated that ID4, a negative regulator of transcription, may act as a <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e>-suppressor gene </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>To clarify the role of ID4 in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, we employed methylation-specific PCR (MSP) to examine the methylation status of ID4 in 144 adult de novo <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We found that ID4 methylation was present in 35.4% (n=51) of these <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients and methylaiton was correlated significantly with World Health Organization (WHO) subtypes and International Prognostic Scoring System (IPSS) risk groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Patients with advanced stages of WHO subtypes (45.8% vs. 21.3%, P=0.002) and higher risk IPSS subgroups (45.7% vs. 26.0%, P=0.014) exhibited a significantly higher frequency of ID4 methylation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The median survival of patients with ID4 methylation was shorter than patients without ID4 methylation (12.2 months vs. 26.9 months, P=0.005) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Multivariate analysis indicated that ID4 methylation status was the independent factor that impacted <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo>-free survival (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">LFS</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Disease in patients with ID4 methylation progressed more rapidly than those without ID4 methylation (P=0.047, HR=2.11) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Our results suggest that ID4 may be a therapeutic target in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>