<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Clonal chromosomal abnormalities are observed in 30-50% of primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Although the prognostic relevance of cytogenetics is generally appreciated, the prognostic value of cytogenetic evolution has rarely been evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In this study, we retrospectively analyzed cytogenetic features at diagnosis and during follow-up in 85 patients with primary <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Cytogenetic evolution occurred in 18 of the 85 patients (21%), with chromosomes 8, 5, and 1 most often involved </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients with higher levels of marrow blasts (P = 0.034), more advanced stages of World Health Organization (WHO) subtypes (44% vs. 16%, P = 0.035), and higher risk International Prognostic Scoring System (IPSS) subgroups (47% vs. 16%, P = 0.021) had higher incidences of developing cytogenetic evolution </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, the median survival of patients in the group with cytogenetic evolution was 25.8 months, compared with 45.4 months for patients in the group without cytogenetic evolution (P = 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The same result was also found for time to progression: patients with cytogenetic evolution progressed more rapidly than those without cytogenetic evolution (P = 0.007) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Knowledge of cytogenetic evolution offers useful information for clinicians to make more accurate prognostic assessments for patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>