<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We report 23 consecutive pediatric patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> who received allogeneic HSCT on IRB approved protocols between 1992 and 2009 at Children's Memorial Hospital (Chicago, IL) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Nine patients had de novo <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, whereas 14 patients had treatment-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> patients had a documented cytogenetic abnormality, and <z:mp ids='MP_0004026'>monosomy</z:mp> 7/7q- was seen in 12 patients (52%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Fourteen of 23 patients received a myeloablative conditioning regimen; RIC regimens were used for the remaining nine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Five patients relapsed post-transplant, including four patients who received RIC transplant and four patients with treatment-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>For the entire group, estimated five-yr <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e> and OS were 47% and 50%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Treatment-related <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> was associated with decreased <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e> in comparison with de novo <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> (33% vs. 70%, p = 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Five-year OS rates reached 80% for those with de novo <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RIC regimens were associated with decreased three-yr <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RFS</z:e> in comparison with myeloablative regimens (22% vs. 68%, p = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>There was no correlation of survival with blast count at diagnosis, IPSS score, cytogenetic abnormality, donor type, or HLA match </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Larger series are needed to confirm prognostic factors so that higher-risk patients can be targeted with novel approaches </plain></SENT>
</text></document>