<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Recombinant human granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF) was administered to 10 patients with refractory <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancies</z:e>, 2 patients who had <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> with severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> and to a patient who had delayed marrow recovery after 3 cycles of therapy for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002488'>acute leukemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A marked <z:hpo ids='HP_0001875'>neutropenia</z:hpo> and <z:mp ids='MP_0000223'>monocytopenia</z:mp> was observed within 5 min after an i.v. injection of GM-CSF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>This persisted for 1-2 h and seemed related to activation of an adhesive <z:chebi fb="2" ids="17089">glycoprotein</z:chebi> (MO1) on the surface of these cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>With continued daily i.v. administration of GM-CSF, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients with refractory <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancies</z:e> developed a striking <z:hpo ids='HP_0001974'>leukocytosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Total leukocyte counts reached 75,000/microliters within 2 weeks of treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>This was due to an increase in band and segmented neutrophils, eosinophils and monocytes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Accelerated myelopoiesis required the continuous presence of GM-CSF; with pump failure for 24 h or discontinuation after 14 days, leukocyte counts returned to <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> levels in 24-48 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>GM-CSF also increased myelopoiesis in the patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> or following anti-leukemic treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>These observations suggest that this growth factor should prove a useful adjunct in the treatment of patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0006826" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">malignancies</z:e> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0005528'>bone marrow failure</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>