<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>This report describes the final results of a Phase II clinical trial investigating the efficacy of rabbit antithymocyte globulin (rATG), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4031">ciclosporin</z:chebi>, steroids, and granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (GCSF) in patients with untreated aplastic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anaemia</z:hpo> (AA), or low to intermediate-risk and hypocellular <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We treated 24 patients each with AA and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> with rATG (3·5 mg/kg/d × 5; reduced to 2·5 mg/kg/d × 5 in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> ≥ 55 years), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4031">ciclosporin</z:chebi> (5 mg/kg orally daily × 6 months), steroids (1 mg/kg daily, tapered off over 1 month), and GCSF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The overall response rate in AA patients was 64% compared to 25% in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The median time to response was 3 months in AA patients and 4 months in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Pretreatment clinical characteristics, such as age, sex, blood counts, cellularity, cytogenetics, or HLA-DR15 status, did not predict for response </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Response to therapy, however, predicted for improved overall survival (OS), with a 3-year OS of 89% vs. 43% in responders versus non-responders, respectively (P &lt; 0·001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Infusion reactions occurred in about half the patients and were manageable </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0854467" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Myelosuppression</z:e>, elevation in liver enzymes, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> were common </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The early mortality in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients was 13% vs. 0% in AA patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>