<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Recently, a less toxic regimen comprising reduced <z:chebi fb="0" ids="4027">cyclophosphamide</z:chebi> (Cy), fludarabine, and anti-thymocyte globulin (ATG) (Cy-Flu-ATG) was used to condition high-risk patients scheduled for allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation (alloHSCT) instead of standard Cy-ATG in patients with severe <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo> (AA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We performed a randomized phase III study to compare the regimen-related toxicities (RRTs) of two different conditioning regimens: Cy-ATG vs. Cy-Flu-ATG </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Patients in the Cy-ATG arm received Cy at 200 mg/kg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Those in the Cy-Flu-ATG arm received fludarabine (Flu) at 150 mg/m(2) and Cy at 100 mg/kg </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A total of 83 patients (40 in the Cy-ATG and 43 in the Cy-Flu-ATG) were enrolled </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Seventy-nine patients had AA and four had <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> predefined RRTs were significantly lower in patients of the Cy-Flu-ATG arm (23.3 vs. 55.0 %; p = 0.003) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Infection</z:e> with identified causative organism and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019156" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">sinusoidal obstruction syndrome</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000790'>hematuria</z:hpo>, febrile episodes, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> from any cause tended to be more frequent in Cy-ATG arm but did not differ significantly between arms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There was no difference in neutrophil engraftment failure (2.5 vs. 2.33 %; p = 0.959), <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018133" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="GVH">graft-versus-host disease</z:e> (GvHD) (15.0 vs. 23.3 %; p = 0.388), and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> GvHD (16.7 vs. 16.2 %; p = 0.961) between Cy-ATG and Cy-Flu-ATG arms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The 4-year survival rate did not differ between the Cy-ATG and Cy-Flu-ATG arms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Preconditioning with Cy-Flu-ATG was superior to that afforded by Cy-ATG in terms of reducing RRT levels without increasing engraftment failure </plain></SENT>
</text></document>