<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A cytogenetic study was performed in 27 patients suspected of t-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> or t-ANLL </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In 12 patients the diagnosis of t-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> or t-ANLL was confirmed by morphological, cytochemical and immunophenotypical analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The cases were classified as RA (one), <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB</z:e> (four), <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CMML</z:e> (two), ANLL (five) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>They had received chemotherapy and/or RT for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019829" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="hd">Hodgkin's disease</z:e> (eight cases), <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0280100" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">solid tumours</z:e> (three cases) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0006775'>multiple myeloma</z:hpo> (one case) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Clonal chromosome abnormalities were found in bone marrow or peripheral blood cells in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> the 12 cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Five patients had a clonal abnormality of chromosome no. 5 (<z:mp ids='MP_0004026'>monosomy</z:mp>, deletions, translocation and inversion of 5q) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The critical region on chromosome no. 5 comprised bands q12-q34 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:mp ids='MP_0004026'>Monosomy</z:mp> and deletion of chromosome 7q was observed in the other two patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the six remaining patients various karyotypic patterns were observed including a t(4;11) (q21;q23) in one case, <z:mp ids='MP_0004026'>monosomies</z:mp> (four cases) and <z:mp ids='MP_0004027'>trisomies</z:mp> (one case) of different chromosomes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In the other 15 cases, the presence of a <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> karyotype together with the morphological and immunophenotypical characterisation was consistent with a diagnosis of non-neoplastic specimens </plain></SENT>
</text></document>