<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Although <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> are <z:hpo ids='HP_0001425'>heterogeneous</z:hpo> disorders comprising a benign subset of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005528'>bone marrow failure</z:hpo> similar to <z:hpo ids='HP_0001915'>aplastic anemia</z:hpo>, no laboratory test has been established to distinguish it from <z:hpo ids='HP_0005528'>bone marrow failures</z:hpo> that can evolve into <z:hpo ids='HP_0004808'>acute myeloid leukemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Plasma thrombopoietin levels were measured in 120 patients who had <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>thrombocytopenia</z:hpo> (&lt; 100 × 10(9)/L) to determine any correlation to markers associated with immune pathophysiology and outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Thrombopoietin levels were consistently low for patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0005505'>refractory anemia</z:hpo> with excess of blasts, while patients with other myelodysplatic syndrome subsets had more variable results </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients with thrombopoietin levels of 320 pg/mL and over had increased <z:chebi fb="0" ids="24410">glycosylphosphatidylinositol</z:chebi>-anchored protein-deficient blood cells (49.1% vs. 0%), were more likely to have a low International Prognostic Scoring System (IPSS) score (≤1.0, 100% vs. 65.5%), a higher response rate to immunosuppressive therapy (84.2% vs. 14.3%), and a better 5-year progression-free survival rate (94.1% vs. 63.6% for refractory cytopenia with unilineage <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>; 100.0% vs. 44.4% for refractory cytopenia with multilineage <z:mpath ids='MPATH_589'>dysplasia</z:mpath>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, increased plasma thrombopoietin levels were associated with a favorable prognosis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005528'>bone marrow failure</z:hpo> and could, therefore, represent a reliable marker for a benign subset of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>