<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The present study aimed to directly compare the efficacy and safety of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2038">azacitidine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We compared the overall response rate (ORR) (complete responses, partial responses, marrow complete responses, and haematological improvements), overall survival (OS), event-free survival (EFS), time to leukaemic transformation, and adverse outcomes between <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2038">azacitidine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To minimize the effects of treatment selection bias in this observational study, adjustments were made using the propensity-score matching method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Among 300 patients, 203 were treated with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2038">azacitidine</z:chebi> and 97 with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Propensity-score matching yielded 97 patient pairs </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In the propensity-matched cohort, there were no significant differences between the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2038">azacitidine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> groups regarding ORR (44% vs. 52%), OS (26 vs. 22.9 months), EFS (7.7 vs. 7.0 months), and rate of leukaemic transformation (16% vs. 22% at 1 year) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In patients ≥ 65 years of age, survival was significantly better in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2038">azacitidine</z:chebi> group (P = 0.017) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients who received <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> experienced more frequent episodes of grade 3 or 4 cytopenia and infectious episodes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We found that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2038">azacitidine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50131">decitabine</z:chebi> showed comparable efficacy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Among patients ≥ 65 years of age, survival was significantly better in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2038">azacitidine</z:chebi> group (ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT01409070) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>