<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) is a <z:mp ids='MP_0001795'>Gram-negative</z:mp> spiral bacterium, classified as a carcinogen of class I, according to the World Health Organization (WHO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> is a major cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0005263'>gastritis</z:hpo>, gastric and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002588'>duodenal ulcer</z:hpo> disease and increases the risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0012126'>gastric cancer</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>It has been implicated in the pathogenesis of several gastrointestinal, systemic or <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hematological diseases</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The present review aims in deciphering the role of the bacterium in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0947743,C0018939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hematological disorders</z:e>, increasing the awareness of gastroenterologists, hematologists and internal medicine practitioners, regarding the bacterium-associated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hematological diseases</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The efficacy of H. pylori eradication in increasing the platelet count in adult patients with primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0001973'>immune thrombocytopenia</z:hpo> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16039">ITP</z:chebi>) has been confirmed, linking the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> with the disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Moreover, as the bacterium causes <z:hpo ids='HP_0001891'>iron deficiency anemia</z:hpo> (IDA) by several mechanisms, recent guidelines indicate H. pylori <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> (Hp-I) to be sought in IDA patients if histology is negative and to be eradicated if present </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, it has been widely recognized that anti-H. pylori treatment causes regression of the low-grade B-cell gastric MALT <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Despite the well established associations of Hp-I with the aforementioned <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0947743,C0018939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hematological disorders</z:e>, we highlight the possible role of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> to other <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0018939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hematological diseases</z:e> or conditions such as non-Hodgkin <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphomas</z:hpo> of the stomach, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0278494" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="MGUS">monoclonal gammopathy of undetermined significance</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001889'>megaloblastic anemia</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>We finally underline the elevated risk of childhood <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> and of <z:mp ids='MP_0001914'>hemorrhage</z:mp> in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0005779" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">coagulation disorders</z:e>, due to the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>