<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To analyze the clinical characteristics and risk factors on responses and survival of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004818'>paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PNH</z:e>) clones </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The clinical data of 31 MDS cases with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PNH</z:e> clones from October 2004 to June 2012 were retrospectively analyzed to reveal the influence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PNH</z:e> clone size on responses and survival </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: ①The chromosome karyotypes were analyzed in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> patients, 23 patients with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> karyotype, 7 patients with abnormal karyotype [including 3 patients with +8, 2 -Y, 1 del(7q) and 1 Xp+] and 1 patient with no mitosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>1 patient belonged to low-risk, 27 intermediate-1 risk, 2 intermediate-2 risk and 1 high-risk groups, respectively, according to IPSS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>There were significantly statistical differences between responders and nonresponders in terms of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>, ANC, Reticulocyte count and IPSS (P values were 0.049, 0.006, 0.031 and 0.043, respectively). ②The overall responsive rate was 67.7%, no patients progressed to <z:hpo ids='HP_0002488'>acute leukemia</z:hpo> (AL) during median follow-up of 19 months after immunosuppressive therapy (IST) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The 3-year and 5-year overall survival rates were 82.7% and 55.1%,respectively. ③According to univariate analysis,age, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and ANC had significant influence on survival (P values were 0.050, 0.031 and 0.026, respectively). ④The <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PNH</z:e> clone size had no significant influence on survival through univariate and COX analyses (P=0.393) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PNH</z:e> clone had less cytogenetic abnormalities, higher probability of response to IST and lower probability of progression to AL; Furthermore, the <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">PNH</z:e> clone size had no significant influence on response and survival </plain></SENT>
</text></document>