<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>gamma-Interferon (IFN-gamma) has previously been found to induce monocytic differentiation in established leukemic cell lines, such as <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019829" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="hd">HL</z:e>-60 and U937 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The aim of the present study was to evaluate the differentiative effect of highly purified recombinant (r)IFN-gamma on fresh bone marrow cells from patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> nonlymphocytic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> (n = 11) or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (n = 3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Blast cells were cultured in suspension in the presence or absence of rIFN-gamma (10-10(3) U/ml) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>While 6 out of 14 cases were unresponsive to rIFN-gamma in vitro, the remaining 8 patients showed a significant increase (0.05 greater than p greater than 0.001) in the percentage of cells expressing C3bi receptors, detected by OKM1 (median value in control cell, 9.5; median value in rIFN-gamma-treated cells, 31) and Mo1 (8.5 vs. 36), and in the percentage of cells expressing the monocytic antigens detected by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37238">Mo2</z:chebi> (8 vs. 28) and MY4 (6.5 vs. 32.5) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In the responsive patients morphologic changes consistent with monocytic maturation, as well as a strong increase of alpha-naphthyl <z:chebi fb="49" ids="30089,47622">acetate</z:chebi> esterase activity and of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9505">nitroblue tetrazolium</z:chebi> reducing capability were observed upon culture with rIFN-gamma </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We conclude that (a) rIFN-gamma may induce in vitro monocytic differentiation of blasts from <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> nonlymphocytic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo> patients, and that (b) this agent should be investigated for its capacity to be active in vivo </plain></SENT>
</text></document>