<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Clonality, in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, can only be assessed in patients with chromosomal rearrangements or in females heterozygote for X chromosome restricted polymorphisms. "Illegitimate" rearrangements of the immunoglobulin heavy chain (IgH) gene and incomplete rearrangements involving V delta 2 and D delta 3 segments of the T-cell receptor delta (TcR delta) gene are seen in some cases of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AML</z:e>, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">AML</z:e> post-<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SMD</z:e>, and can be detected by a sensitive PCR method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In order to analyse clonality in additional cases in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, we looked for Ig H and TcR delta gene rearrangement by PCR in 95 cases of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A rearrangement of the Ig H gene was seen in 2 of the 95 patients: in the circulating blood of 2 of the 36 cases of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:mpath ids='MPATH_501'>myelomonocytic leukaemia</z:mpath> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">CMML</z:e>) and in none of the marrow samples of the other 59 MDS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>A rearrangement of the TcR delta gene (involving V delta 2 and D delta 3 segments) was seen in three cases (in the circulating blood of two other CMLL patients, and in the bone marrow of another <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patient) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Twenty-five of the 90 cases of <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> with negative PCR findings, in addition to the five cases with positive PCR findings underwent Southern blot analysis of Ig H and TcR delta genes, and PCR analysis of V delta 1 and J delta 1 segments of the TcR delta gene </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Those examinations were <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> the cases tested </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In patients with positive PCR findings for Ig H or V delta 2 D delta 3 rearrangements, the proportion of rearranged cells was evaluated at 1-5% in four cases, and 5-10% in the remaining patient </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Because the analysis was performed on total circulating leukocytes or total nucleated marrow cells, the nature of the clonal population in positive cases (lymphoid cells? myeloid cells? blasts?) could not be determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>From a practical point of view, Ig H and TcR delta gene rearrangements seem to very rare in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, and cannot be used as clonality markers in most cases </plain></SENT>
</text></document>