<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The authors investigated the incidence of the plasminogen activator inhibitor-2 (PAI-2) in 88 patients with haematological <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In four patients (4.5%) an elevated PAI-2 level was found: in patient (no. 1) with non-differentiated <z:mpath ids='MPATH_336'>leukaemia</z:mpath> which developed as a result of transformation of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo>, in a female patient (no. 2) with non-differentiated blastic crisis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:mpath ids='MPATH_342'>myeloid leukaemia</z:mpath>, in a female patient (no. 3) with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:mpath ids='MPATH_502'>monocytic leukaemia</z:mpath> (M5) and in a pregnant female (patient no. 4) with a <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0019829" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="hd">malignant lymphogranuloma</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In none of the other patients with another type of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:mpath ids='MPATH_342'>myeloid leukaemia</z:mpath> or other haematological <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumours</z:e> PAI-2 was detected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>High PAI-2 levels after successful <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35610">cytostatic</z:chebi> treatment and attainment of complete remission reached <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> levels, during a relapse high PAI-2 levels were recorded again </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The authors assume that the presence of PAI-2 may suggest a monocytic origin of the cells which produce it </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>They conclude also that its value may reflect the activity of the disease with high levels during presentation or relapse of the disease and a drop or disappearance of PAI-2 after successful treatment and achieved remission </plain></SENT>
</text></document>