<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Underlying diseases, pathogenic bacteria, clinical background and outcome were studied during 91 febrile episodes complicated by <z:hpo ids='HP_0100806'>sepsis</z:hpo> in 55 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0376545" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">hematological malignancies</z:e>, who had been admitted to our hospital (Jikei University Kashiwa Hospital) between January 1990 and December 1994 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Particularly in patients with P. aeruginosa <z:hpo ids='HP_0100806'>sepsis</z:hpo>, we compared the prophylactic effect of ciprofloxacin (CPFX) alone with that of the combination of polymyxin B (PL-B) plus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6104">kanamycin</z:chebi> (KM) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The major underlying diseases were <z:hpo ids='HP_0004808'>acute myelocytic leukemia</z:hpo> and malignant <z:hpo ids='HP_0002665'>lymphoma</z:hpo>, followed by <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> lymphocytic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> myelocytic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001909'>leukemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Nearly two-thirds of the pathogenic microorganisms isolated were <z:mp ids='MP_0001796'>gram-positive</z:mp> bacteria (including coagulase-negative staphylococci and Staphylococcus aureus); approximately one-quarter were <z:mp ids='MP_0001795'>gram-negative</z:mp> bacteria (such as Pseudomonas aeruginosa), and the remainder were fungi </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>These microorganisms usually induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0100806'>sepsis</z:hpo> when granulocyte counts were decreased </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0100806'>Sepsis</z:hpo> was a direct cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> in about 60% of the patients and P. aeruginosa <z:hpo ids='HP_0100806'>sepsis</z:hpo> had the worst outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Oral administration of CPFX was more effective than PL-B plus KM in preventing P. aeruginosa <z:hpo ids='HP_0100806'>sepsis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The difference in effectiveness might depend on the absorption profile of the drugs </plain></SENT>
</text></document>