<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>In order to reduce <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anaemia</z:hpo> in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) a stepwise treatment protocol including erythropoietin (EP) and granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF) was designed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Thirty-seven <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> patients (stages I-III) with symptomatic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001903'>anaemia</z:hpo> were first given EPO 10,000 U s.c </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>3 times weekly for 6 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Those not responding, i.e. increased their <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> levels &gt; 15 g/l, proceeded into the second phase of the study where GM-CSF (200 micrograms/d. s.c. on weeks 1-6) was combined with EPO (10,000 U s.c </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>3 times weekly on weeks 5-14) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Following the initial EPO treatment phase, 14 of the 37 patients (38%) responded with increased <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Responders were significantly different from non-responders in that their pre-treatment values of s-EPO, s-LDH and bone marrow blast cell counts were lower, their baseline <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> levels higher and their transfusion dependency less pronounced </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Eighteen of the 23 non-responders proceeded into the second phase, 13 of those were evaluable having completed the entire schedule </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Three of the 13 initially EPO resistant patients (23%) responded to the GM-CSF/EPO combination with increased <z:chebi fb="34" ids="35143">haemoglobin</z:chebi> levels, suggesting a positive synergy between the two cytokines </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Thus, the overall response rate to the present protocol was 46% (17 of 37 cases), but only a limited subset of the patients did clearly benefit from the combined GM-CSF/EPO administration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Therefore, we believe this step-wise approach to multiple growth factor treatment in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>, starting with EPO alone and reserving the combination for refractory cases, has considerable advantages, taking into account both medical and socio-economical aspects </plain></SENT>
</text></document>