<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A study of bone marrow <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> was undertaken in 51 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndromes</z:hpo> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e>) treated with granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF) and erythropoietin (EPO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In 19 of these patients (37%), a significant improvement in the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> level was found after treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>Apoptosis</z:mpath> was measured using a nick-end labeling (TUNEL) technique </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> had a significantly higher percentage of labelled (apoptotic) cells in the bone marrow compared to healthy individuals (56.3 +/- 3.8% vs. 16.2 +/- 1.4%, p = 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> showed a lower percentage of apoptotic cells than patients with RA (68.5 +/- 9% vs. 46.5 +/- 4.8%, p &lt; 0.05), while patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">RAEB</z:e> did not differ significantly from either RA or <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In the patients who responded to treatment, the bone marrow samples displayed significant morphological changes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The percentages of erythroid precursors and myeloblasts were reduced after treatment, and patients who had ring sideroblasts before treatment also showed a reduction in the percentage of these cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Total erythroid index also decreased in responding patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The percentage of apoptotic cells decreased significantly in responding patients (58.8 +/- 4.8% before treatment vs. 44.5 +/- 5.5% after treatment, mean reduction 18.3%, p = 0.0003), whereas no significant change was found in non-responding patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Our results suggest that one important mechanism behind the positive effects of treatment with G-CSF and EPO is a reduction in the degree of ineffective hematopoiesis in <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MDS</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>