<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The first case of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004032" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">disseminated aspergillosis</z:e> caused by Aspergillus ustus in an allogeneic peripheral stem cell transplant patient is described </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The patient, a 46-year-old female with a history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002863'>myelodysplastic syndrome</z:hpo>, underwent high-dose chemotherapy and total body irradiation prior to transplantation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>She was released from the hospital 49 days posttransplant (p.t.) in a stable condition with an absolute neutrophil count (ANC) of 2,700 cells per microl </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Multiple antimicrobial agents, including <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6076">itraconazole</z:chebi> (ITR), were prescribed during hospitalization and at the time of discharge </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Three days after discharge, the patient was readmitted with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0085692" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hemorrhagic cystitis</z:e>, persistent <z:hpo ids='HP_0001873'>thrombocytopenia</z:hpo>, and bilateral pulmonary consolidation, although no <z:hpo ids='HP_0001945'>fever</z:hpo> was present </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The ANC at the time of readmission was 3,500 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Upon detection of a pulmonary nodule (day 67 p.t.), a bronchoalveolar lavage was performed; the lavage fluid was positive for both cytomegalovirus and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0030389" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">parainfluenza</z:e> virus and negative for fungus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The patient was placed on <z:chebi fb="0" ids="465284">ganciclovir</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>A biopsy specimen from a leg lesion also noted on day 67 p.t. revealed septate hyphae consistent with Aspergillus species, and a culture subsequently yielded Aspergillus ustus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Confirmation detection of A. ustus was made by demonstration of characteristic reproductive structures with the presence of Hülle cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>On day 67 p.t., ITR was discontinued and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="2682">liposomal amphotericin B</z:chebi> (AMB) was initiated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The patient's condition worsened, and she died 79 days p.t </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>At the time of autopsy, septate hyphae were present in heart, thyroid, and lung tissues, with lung tissue culture positive for A. ustus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In vitro susceptibility testing indicated probable resistance to AMB but not to ITR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>This case supports the need for the development of rapid methods to determine antifungal susceptibility </plain></SENT>
</text></document>