<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Deep-seated <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0343939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">trichosporonosis</z:e> is a lethal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0029118" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">opportunistic infection</z:e> that disseminates rapidly and widely in immunocompromised patients, and early diagnosis is crucial for the treatment of this <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We developed a novel nested-PCR assay that detects DNA specific for clinically important strains of Trichosporon in serum samples from patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0343941" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">disseminated trichosporonosis</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In this assay, two sets of oligonucleotide primers were derived from the sequence of 26S rRNA genes of Trichosporon asahii </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The specific fragment was amplified from T. asahii and T. mucoides, but not from other microorganisms, including some other basidiomycetous fungi (Cryptococcus, Malassezia, Rhodotorula, and Sporobolomyces) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Target DNA was detected by the nested PCR with as little as 5 fg of the extracted DNA of T. asahii </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In a study using 11 clinical samples, the specific fragment was detected by the nested PCR in 64% (7 of 11) of sera from patients with histologically diagnosed <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0343941" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">disseminated trichosporonosis</z:e>, while <z:chebi fb="0" ids="53457">glucuronoxylomannan</z:chebi> antigen was detected in only 54% (6 of 11) of the samples </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Our new nested-PCR assay using serum samples can be performed repeatedly throughout the course of the disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In addition, not only can it be used for early diagnosis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0343939" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">trichosporonosis</z:e>, but it may also be beneficial for monitoring its progress or response to therapy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>