<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: The clinical and pathophysiological effects of a <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> reduction of cerebral blood flow in humans are not completely known </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We investigated whether rats subjected to bilateral common carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (bCCA-o) developed focal neurological deficits, gait dysfunction, and working memory alterations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Eighteen male Wistar rats were subjected to bCCA-o, 13 were sham-operated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We assessed sensorimotor functions, gait on a 60 cm-long elevated bridge, and working memory (object recognition and Y maze tests) before and 30, 60, and 90 days after surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Histological analysis was performed in a subgroup of 10 rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: No rat showed sensorimotor alterations after surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Although gait performances of both bCCA-o and sham-operated rats declined over time, the differences reached statistical significance only for the bCCA-o group (mean+/-SE: 26.8+/-5.0; 22.4+/-4.9; 24.5+/-5.5 cm at 30, 60, and 90 days, respectively) in comparison with baseline (52.9+/-5.2 cm; P&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>At 60 and 90 days, bCCA-o rats in comparison with sham-operated rats showed decreased performances on object recognition (discrimination index: 0.15+/-0.03 vs. 0.29+/-0.05 at 60 days and 0.10+/-0.04 vs. 0.41+/-0.07 at 90 days; P&lt;0.05) and on Y maze test (alternating rats: 9.9 vs. 85.7% at 60 days and 16.6 vs. 100% at 90 days; P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In none of the animals were cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> detected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Selective neuronal <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> was observed in the cortex and hippocampus of both bCCA-o and sham-operated rats without any obvious difference </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: bCCA-o in the Wistar rat induces persistent and progressive gait and working <z:hpo ids='HP_0002354'>memory impairment</z:hpo> without producing sensorimotor deficit or cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>This model may help to elucidate some physiopathological aspects of neurological impairment associated with states of cerebral <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>