<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We investigated the effect of a newly synthesized <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29108">Ca2+</z:chebi> channel <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, NC-1100, on cerebral blood flow (CBF) and metabolism in spontaneously hypertensive rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The rats received a bolus injection of 0.2 or 1.0 mg/kg NC-1100 i.v. and 1-h <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> was then induced by bilateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (group 1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The rats in group 2 were continuously infused with NC-1100 0.03 or 0.1 mg/kg per min, starting immediately after bilateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp>, for the 1 h of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and following 3-h recirculation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Group 1: during <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>, CBF in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> rats decreased to 6-8% of the resting values </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>At 1 h <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>, brain tissue <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> increased 11.5-, 10.1- and 9.8-fold of the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> control given vehicle or NC-1100, 0.2 and 1.0 mg/kg, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The ATP levels were better preserved by NC-1100 administration; 0.61 +/- 0.04 (mean +/- S.E.M.), 0.80 +/- 0.09 and 0.97 +/- 0.14 mmol/kg (P &lt; 0.05 vs. vehicle), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Group 2: during recirculation, CBF in NC-1100-treated rats returned to 83-90% of the resting values, but to only 65% in the vehicle group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Postischemic brain <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> at 3 h was less well preserved and ATP was dose dependently better preserved in NC-1100- than vehicle-treated rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>It is considered that pre- as well as postischemic administration of a <z:chebi fb="0" ids="29108">Ca2+</z:chebi> channel <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, NC-1100, is beneficial to attenuate and also ameliorate the metabolic and circulatory derangement in the ischemic brain </plain></SENT>
</text></document>