<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A unique blood supply to the brain, the 'Circle of Willis' (COW), exists in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> mammals except for the Mongolian gerbil (Meriones unguiculatus) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This system is capable of compensating for a decrease in blood supply in one of the four arteries, which may occur during pathological conditions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The posterior connection between the basilar artery and the carotid artery system have been found to be missing in most gerbils </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, in some of the animals, the anterior communication was not complete, thus leading to partial <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> following unilateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Due to those peculiar characteristics, the Mongolian gerbil today has become a widespread animal model for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>M. unguiculatus has been used in most of the studies while the level of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> has been evaluated by the development of neurological symptoms created by the occlusion of the carotid arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In the present study we investigated the vasculature structure of the commonly used gerbil, M. unguiculatus (MU-TF) and compared it to the vasculature of the Israeli gerbil, Meriones tristrami as well as to that of the <z:mp ids='MP_0001189'>Albino</z:mp> rat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>We determined the correlation between the anatomical pattern and the biochemical responses during partial or complete <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and <z:mp ids='MP_0002316'>anoxia</z:mp> by monitoring the oxidation-reduction state of the intramitochondrial <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16908">NADH</z:chebi> using an in vivo surface fluorescence technique </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The corrected fluorescence signal was found to be inversely correlated with oxygen availability and could thus be used as an indicator for the level of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> developed after carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This is the first time that the brain vasculature of two lines of M. tristrami (MT-HU, MT-BD) has been investigated.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>