<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Possible effect of an ethanolic root extract of Pongamia pinnata (L) Pierre (P. pinnata) on oxidant-<z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> status and histopathological changes in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>-reperfusion injury in the rat forebrain have been investigated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Further, its effect was also assessed on long-term <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1695782" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral hypoperfusion</z:e>-induced changes in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000739'>anxiety</z:hpo>, cognitive and histopathological parameters </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Cerebral post-ischemic reperfusion is known to be associated with generation of free radicals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In the present study, bilateral common carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (BCCAO) for 30 min followed by 45 min reperfusion produced increases in <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation, <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase (SOD) activity and a fall in the total tissue sulfhydryl (T-SH) levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The ethanolic extract of roots of P. pinnata (50 mg kg(-1), po for 5 days) attenuated the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>-reperfusion-induced increase in <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation, SOD activity and a fall in T-SH levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The extract also ameliorated histopathological changes and inflammatory cell infiltration in the frontoparietal region of the rat brain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The extract (50 mg kg(-1), po for 15 days) was also found to alleviate the long-term hypoperfusion-induced <z:hpo ids='HP_0000739'>anxiety</z:hpo> and <z:mp ids='MP_0005202'>listlessness</z:mp> (open field paradigm) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was an improvement of learning and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0233794" disease_type="Mental or Behavioral Dysfunction" abbrv="">memory deficits</z:e> (Morris' water maze testing) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>It also attenuated reactive changes in forebrain histology like <z:hpo ids='HP_0002171'>gliosis</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1262091" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">lymphocytic infiltration</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002446'>astrocytosis</z:hpo> and cellular <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Results suggest protective role of P. pinnata in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>-reperfusion injury and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0241832" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebrovascular insufficiency</z:e> states </plain></SENT>
</text></document>