<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>To investigate the hemodynamics and clinical presentation of common carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (CCAO), we reviewed 6,415 patients with suspected <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007273" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">carotid artery disease</z:e> in whom a color Duplex imaging (CDI) examination was performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>According to distal vessel patency, the following CDI classification of CCAO was adopted: type I (patent both distal vessels); type II (isolated patency of external carotid artery); type III (isolated patency of internal carotid artery); and type IV (both distal vessels occluded) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Thirty-five (0.5%) cases met the CDI criteria for CCAO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Twenty-nine of those (83%) had at least one patent distal vessel </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Ten patients (29%) presented with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, 20 (57%) with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>transient ischemic attacks</z:hpo> (<z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>TIAs</z:hpo>) and five (14%) were asymptomatic </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The incidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> was higher in type IV (50%) vs. type II (30%) and in type II vs. type I (10%) lesions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Similarly, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002326'>TIAs</z:hpo> presented more often in type II (67%) and IV (50%) vs. in type I (40%) lesions (p = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Retrograde flow in the ophthalmic artery and concomitant severe contralateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006135'>artery stenosis</z:mp> were more often related with type II and IV lesions (p = 0.02 and 0.04, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CCAO is usually accompanied by patent distal vessel(s) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The proposed CCAO classification correlates well with the patients' clinical status and may help to better clarify the outcome of this rare entity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Among the main arteries of the developed collateral circulation, only the flow direction in the ophthalmic artery may be of clinical value </plain></SENT>
</text></document>