<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIMS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39015">Apolipoprotein</z:chebi> B-100 (apoB-100) has been implicated in <z:hpo ids='HP_0003077'>hyperlipidemia</z:hpo>, which contributes to the pathogenesis of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disorders</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Our aim was to investigate whether the expression of human apoB-100 in transgenic mice and/or a high-cholesterol diet cause cerebral microvascular lesions, and whether these conditions augment <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>-related capillary damage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>MAIN METHODS: Human apoB-100 overexpressing transgenic (Tg(apoB-100), n=23) and <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> mice (C5/B6, Wt, n=26) were supplied with standard or 2% cholesterol-enriched diet for 17-19 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>Cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> was induced by unilateral common carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Cortical samples were embedded for electron microscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Microvascular density (number of microvascular profiles/examined area), lumen diameter, the swelling of astrocytic endfeet, the occurrence of endothelial microvilli (affected capillaries expressed as ratio of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> capillaries encountered), and the ratio of intact capillaries (devoid of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> the above pathology) were calculated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>KEY FINDINGS: The expression of apoB-100 coincided with decreased cortical microvascular density (195+/-7 vs. 223+/-8 vessels/mm(2), vs. Wt; P&lt;0.008) and increased capillary lumen diameter (3.16+/-0.5 vs. 2.88+/-0.6 microm, vs. Wt; P&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>Cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> promoted the swelling of perivascular astrocytes (62.1+/-4.2 vs. 36.5+/-4.0%, vs. contralateral, Wt; P&lt;0.001), and reduced the ratio of intact capillaries (32.1+/-5.6 vs. 65.2+/-3.7%, vs. contralateral, Wt; P&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0003077'>Hyperlipidemia</z:hpo> did not exacerbate the injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>SIGNIFICANCE: The overexpression of human apoB-100 alters the density of the microvascular network and the diameter of capillaries, which may compromise cerebrovascular reactivity during <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>