<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>CONTEXT: The ischemic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0221505" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain lesions</z:e> induced in rats by temporary occlusion of the bilateral common carotid arteries and restoration of blood flow to an ischemic brain region is associated with generation of reactive oxygen species with consequent reperfusion injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The present study investigated the neuroprotective potential of Hibiscus rosa sinensis L </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>(Malvaceae) in a bilateral common carotid artery (BCCA) occlusion model of global cerebral ischemic reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: The animals underwent 30 min BCCA occlusion and 45 min reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="43" ids="17790">methanol</z:chebi> extract of H. sinensis (100, 200, 300 mg/kg/day for 6 days, p.o.) was administered 30 min before induction of BCCA occlusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The bilateral common carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> resulted in increase in <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation, and reduction in <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase (SOD), catalase (CAT) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> reductase (GSH) activity </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The extract attenuated the ischemic reperfusion-induced increase in <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation and fall in SOD, CAT, and GSH levels </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1695782" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral hypoperfusion</z:e> caused a propensity towards <z:hpo ids='HP_0000739'>anxiety</z:hpo> and was accompanied by deficits of learning and memory </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The extract ameliorated <z:hpo ids='HP_0000739'>anxiety</z:hpo> and there was improvement of learning and memory </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Discussion: The administration of H. sinensis prevented the <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> and the biochemical changes associated with cerebral ischemic reperfusion injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The mechanism of such protection of H. sinensis may be due to cerebral adaptation, through augmentation of cellular <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidants</z:chebi> such as GSH, SOD and CAT </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The results suggest the protective role of H. sinensis in ischemic reperfusion injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: This study indicates the beneficial role of H. sinensis in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0241832" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebrovascular insufficiency</z:e> states and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000726'>dementia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>