<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Carotid artery stenting (CAS) has grown as a possible alternative for the treatment of extracranial cerebrovascular disease in the past decade </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>A preexisting contralateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> has been described as a risk factor for inferior outcomes after carotid endarterectomy, but its impact on CAS outcomes is less understood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: A retrospective review of 417 CAS procedures performed between May 2001 and July 2010 at a single center using self-expanding nitinol stents and mechanical embolic protection devices was conducted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Patients were divided into two groups, those with a preexisting contralateral carotid occlusion (group A, n = 39) versus those without a contralateral occlusion (group B, n = 378) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Patient demographics and comorbidities as well as 30-day and late <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001658'>myocardial infarction</z:hpo> (MI) rates were analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mean follow-up was 4 years (range: 0-9.4 years) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Overall, mean age of the 314 men and 103 women was 70.5 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In group A, there were two (5.1%) octogenarians and nine patients (23.1%) with symptomatic disease as compared with group B with 53 (14%) octogenarians and 121 (32%) patients with symptomatic disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The overall 30-day <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, and MI rates were 0.5%, 1.9%, and 0.7%, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>When comparing group A with group B, these results were not significantly different: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> (0% vs. 0.5%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> (2.6% vs. 1.9%), and MI (0% vs. 0.8%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Long-term outcomes for groups A and B were also not significantly different: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> (25.6% vs. 22.2%), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> (5.3% vs. 3.4%), and MI (15.4% vs. 14%) (p = nonsignificant) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: A preexisting contralateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> does not seem to adversely impact CAS outcomes </plain></SENT>
</text></document>