<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The present study was to investigate the effect of W. calendulacea on <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and reperfusion-induced cerebral injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>Cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> was induced by occluding right and left common carotid arteries (global <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>) for 30 min followed by reperfusion for 1 h and 4 h individually </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Various biochemical alterations, produced subsequent to the application of bilateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (BCAO) followed by reperfusion viz. increase in <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation (LPO), <z:chebi fb="17" ids="16240">hydrogen peroxide</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="30492">H2O2</z:chebi>), and decrease in reduced <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> (GSH), catalase (CAT) and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase (SOD), level in the brain tissue, Western blot analysis (Cu-Zn-SOD and CAT) and assessment of cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>All</z:hpo> those enzymes are markedly reversed and restored to near <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> level in the groups pretreated with W. calendulacea (250 and 500 mg/kg given orally in single and double dose/day for 10 days) in dose-dependent way </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The effect of W. calendulacea had increased significantly the protein expression of copper/zinc <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase (Cu-Zn-SOD) and CAT in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>W. claendulacea was markedly decrease cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> damages but results are not statistically significant </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>It can be concluded that W. calendulacea possesses a neuroprotective activity against <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> in rat </plain></SENT>
</text></document>