<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Ischemia</z:e>/reperfusion leads to <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> and <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> which damages membrane highly <z:chebi fb="7" ids="26208">polyunsaturated fatty acids</z:chebi> (HPUFAs) and eventually induces neuronal <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>This study evaluates the effect of the administration of Pistacia lentiscus L. essential oil (E.O.), a mixture of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="35186">terpenes</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35189">sesquiterpenes</z:chebi>, on modifications of fatty acid profile and endocannabinoid (eCB) congener concentrations induced by transient bilateral common carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (BCCAO) in the rat frontal cortex and plasma </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Adult Wistar rats underwent BCCAO for 20 min followed by 30 min reperfusion (BCCAO/R) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>6 hours before surgery, rats, randomly assigned to four groups, were gavaged either with E.O </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>(200 mg/0.45 ml of sunflower oil as vehicle) or with the vehicle alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: BCCAO/R triggered in frontal cortex a decrease of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="36005">docosahexaenoic acid</z:chebi> (DHA), the membrane highly <z:chebi fb="1" ids="26208">polyunsaturated fatty acid</z:chebi> most susceptible to oxidation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Pre-treatment with E.O. prevented this change and led further to decreased levels of the enzyme cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2), as assessed by Western Blot </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In plasma, only after BCCAO/R, E.O. administration increased both the ratio of DHA-to-its precursor, eicosapentaenoic acid (<z:chebi fb="113" ids="28364">EPA</z:chebi>), and levels of palmytoylethanolamide (PEA) and oleoylethanolamide (OEA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>Acute</z:hpo> treatment with E.O. before BCCAO/R elicits changes both in the frontal cortex, where the BCCAO/R-induced decrease of DHA is apparently prevented and COX-2 expression decreases, and in plasma, where PEA and OEA levels and DHA biosynthesis increase </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>It is suggested that the increase of PEA and OEA plasma levels may induce DHA biosynthesis via peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor (PPAR) alpha activation, protecting brain tissue from <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>/reperfusion injury </plain></SENT>
</text></document>