<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>AIM: Effects of carotid artery stenting (CAS) on patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> internal carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> are unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: This study included 21 patients who underwent successful CAS treatment and 41 patients who received optimal medical therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Modified Rankin Scale (mRS) and cardiocerebral vascular events were compared between CAS and medical therapy group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The mRS in CAS group was lower than in control group during a 2-year follow up (P&lt;0.05 or 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The combined cerebrovascular events and mortality in study group was lower than in the control group (33.4% vs. 56.1%, P=0.045), but there was no statistically significant difference in the cerebrovascular event (28.6% vs. 46.3%, P=0.088) or mortality rate (4.8% vs. 9.8%, P=0.247) between the two groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Cox regression analysis revealed that smoking (RR=3.189, 95% CI 1.020-9.968, P=0.046), <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp> (RR=2.717, 95% CI 1.113-6.631, P=0.028), and baseline National Institute of Health <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> scale (RR=2.984, 95% CI 1.049-8.485, P=0.040) were independent risk factors for major cerebrovascular events following CAS </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: CAS was superior to drug therapy in achieving better functional outcomes in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> internal carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>However, CAS was not associated with a statistically significant reduction in cerebrovascular events or mortality </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Larger and randomized clinical trials are required to ascertain the long-term benefits of CAS in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> internal carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>