<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The ability of the kappa-opioid receptor <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonists</z:chebi> U50488H and U62066E (spiradoline mesylate) compared with the non-kappa close structural analogue U54494A to affect postischemic <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> of the selectively vulnerable hippocampal CA1 neurons was examined in male Mongolian gerbils </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The gerbils were treated with either saline vehicle or 10 mg/kg i.p. of one of the test drugs 30 minutes before and again 2 hours after a 10-minute period of bilateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> or sham occlusion under light methoxyflurane anesthesia </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Seven days after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and reperfusion the brains were perfusion-fixed, and hippocampal CA1 cells were counted in a blind fashion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In ischemic gerbils that received only vehicle, there was a 78.9% loss of CA1 neurons compared with sham-occluded gerbils </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In contrast, in U50488H-treated gerbils, mean cell loss was reduced to 33.9% (p less than 0.01 vs. vehicle-treated group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>U62066E was even more effective in reducing postischemic CA1 degeneration to only 20.7% (p less than 0.0001 vs. vehicle-treated group) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>However, treatment with the non-kappa analogue U54494A did not cause any apparent protection; the gerbils in this group showed an 80.7% loss of CA1 neurons </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Our results are consistent with the hypothesis that kappa-receptor stimulation is associated with improved postischemic neuronal preservation </plain></SENT>
</text></document>