<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>U74006F (21-[4-(2,6-di-1-pyrrolidinyl-4-pyrimidinyl)-1-piperazinyl]-16 alpha-methylpregna-1,4,9(11)-triene-3,20-dione, monomethane <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33543">sulfonate</z:chebi>) is a novel and potent inhibitor of central <z:mp ids='MP_0008912'>nervous</z:mp> system tissue <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation that is devoid of classical steroid hormonal activities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Its possible efficacy in attenuating postischemic mortality and neuronal <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> was examined in gerbils following 3-hour unilateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Male Mongolian gerbils received two intraperitoneal injections of either vehicle or U74006F (3 or 10 mg/kg), the first injection 10 minutes before and the second injection at the end of the 3-hour ischemic episode </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In an initial series of experiments, vehicle-treated gerbils displayed 60.9% (14 of 23) survival 24 hours after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>, which decreased to 34.8% (8 of 23) at 48 hours </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the 10 mg/kg U74006F-treated group showed 86.7% (13 of 15) survival at 24 hours (p less than 0.15 vs. vehicle) and 80.0% (12 of 15) survival at 48 hours (p less than 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In a second series, neurons in the hippocampal CA1 subfield and the medial and lateral cerebral cortex were counted in gerbils surviving 24 hours after unilateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Comparison of neuronal densities in the ischemic hemisphere with those in the contralateral nonischemic hemisphere revealed significant neuronal preservation in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> three brain regions of 10 mg/kg i.p. x 2 U74006F-treated gerbils </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Our results show that U74006F can improve survival and attenuate neuronal <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> in a severe <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007786" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain ischemia</z:e> model.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>