<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The effects of global <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> on neurochemical parameters in the brain were examined in rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Global <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> was produced by temporary occlusion of the bilateral common carotid arteries 24 hr after the permanent electrocauterization of the bilateral vertebral arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In 10-min cerebral ischemic rats, the brain levels of <z:chebi fb="3" ids="25375">monoamine</z:chebi> were unaltered </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The brain levels of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16865">gamma-aminobutyric acid</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="3" ids="16865">GABA</z:chebi>), which increased about 1.5-fold just before recirculation, almost recovered to the levels of the sham operated group (sham ope </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>levels) within 5 min after recirculation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The brain levels of cyclic <z:chebi fb="47" ids="16027,28971">AMP</z:chebi> (cAMP), although they altered a little just before recirculation, increased about 6-fold 1 min after recirculation, and they recovered to the sham ope. levels 3-5 min later </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In 30-min cerebral ischemic rats, the brain levels of <z:chebi fb="3" ids="25375">monoamine</z:chebi> decreased to about 40% of the sham ope. levels just before recirculation, and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> (NE) and 5-hydroxytryptamine (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="28790">5-HT</z:chebi>) levels did not recover within 30 min after recirculation in the telencephalon </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The brain <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16865">GABA</z:chebi> levels which increased about 2-fold just before recirculation, recovered to the sham ope. levels in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> brain regions by 30-min recirculation except for the levels in cerebral cortex and cerebellum </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The brain cAMP levels which increased about 3.5-fold 10 min after recirculation, almost recovered 20 min later </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>However, the cAMP levels in the telencephalon decreased to levels lower than the sham ope. levels 30 min after recirculation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>It is suggested that the changes of these neurochemical parameters in the telencephalon are related in part to the abnormalities of behavior and EEG activity which have been already reported </plain></SENT>
</text></document>