<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE: The <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50075">dihydropyridine</z:chebi> L-type <z:chebi fb="1" ids="38215">calcium channel blocker</z:chebi> isradipine has been reported to exhibit neuroprotective properties in some, but not <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo>, studies performed in the rat middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) model </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In the present study, we examined isradipine in several other models of focal and global <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>: rat <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52261">rose bengal</z:chebi>, mouse MCAO, and gerbil bilateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (BCAO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>For comparison, a novel <z:chebi fb="1" ids="38215">calcium channel blocker</z:chebi>, SB201823A, that we have previously shown to be neuroprotective in rat and gerbil models was also examined in the mouse </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: In the gerbil BCAO model, isradipine was administered at 2.5 mg/kg i.p. as a single dose 60 minutes after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> (n = 10) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Corresponding controls received vehicle (n = 10), and sham-operated animals received no treatment (n = 6) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Locomotor activity and histological assessments were made at 4 days after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In the rat photothrombotic occlusion model, isradipine was administered at 2.5 mg/kg i.p. as a single dose 60 minutes after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> (n = 10), and corresponding controls (n = 10) received vehicle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Histological assessment was made at 7 days after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the mouse MCAO model, isradipine was also administered at 2.5 mg/kg i.p. as a single dose 60 minutes after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Histological assessments were made at 1 (n = 13), 2 (n = 9), and 4 (n = 9) days after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Vehicle numbers were n = 10, n = 6, and n = 8, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Isradipine and SB201823A were also examined using a combined preischemia and postischemia regimen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Isradipine was administered at 2.5 mg/kg i.p. before occlusion, 1.25 mg/kg i.p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>1 hour after occlusion, 1.25 mg/kg i.p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>2 hours after occlusion, and 2.5 mg/kg twice a day for 3 days after occlusion (n = 16) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>Corresponding controls received vehicle at the same time points (n = 14) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>SB201823A was administered 30 minutes before occlusion, 30 minutes after occlusion, and twice daily for 3 days (n = 12) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>Corresponding controls received vehicle (n = 9) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>Histological assessment was performed at 4 days after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="19" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: When given after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>, isradipine failed to affect lesion volume in both the rat and mouse models </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="20" pm="."><plain>In the gerbil, locomotor <z:hpo ids='HP_0000752'>hyperactivity</z:hpo> and hippocampal cell loss were unaffected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="21" pm="."><plain>Given before and after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> in the mouse, isradipine was also ineffective, whereas SB201823A produced a significant reduction in lesion volume </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="22" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The L-type <z:chebi fb="1" ids="38215">calcium channel blocker</z:chebi> isradipine was devoid of neuroprotective activity in focal and global models of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> in three species of normotensive animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="23" pm="."><plain>These results were compared with data for the novel <z:chebi fb="1" ids="38215">calcium channel blocker</z:chebi> SB201823A, which exhibited a significant effect after pre- and postocclusion administration in the mouse model of permanent focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>