<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="9" ids="15355">Acetylcholine</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi>) release into the extracellular space was measured by HPLC with electrochemical detection after in vivo intracerebral microdialysis in the striatum of gerbils subjected to 15 min of bilateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> followed by 5 h of recirculation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Tissue <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="3" ids="15354">choline</z:chebi> (Ch) contents were also determined during <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and after 5, 30, 60, and 120 min of reflow </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Fifteen minutes of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> led to a significant transient increase in extracellular <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> concentration (threefold after 7.5 min of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>) concomitant with a reduced endogenous <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> level (-62%) and increased tissue Ch content (ninefold) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Recirculation significantly reduced the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> release during the early period of reflow (-50% vs. basal level), followed by a significant increase in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> release between 1 and 3 h of reflow (45-55% vs. basal level) and subsequent normalization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Simultaneously, a "rebound" of tissue <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> level occurred in the early period of reflow (fourfold vs. ischemic value), followed by gradual normalization after 2 h of reperfusion, whereas a rapid decrease in tissue Ch levels was found after 30 min of reflow </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>These findings represent the first demonstration of a biphasic release of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15355">ACh</z:chebi> during <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and reperfusion, as assessed by intracerebral microdialysis in gerbils </plain></SENT>
</text></document>