<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="22470">alpha-Tocopherol</z:chebi> (alpha-TC) is considered an important endogenous brain <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The utility of brain alpha-TC levels as an index of in vivo <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation has recently been suggested </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Therefore, we explored the significance of alpha-TC levels in brains to ischemic insults associated with global or focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Four ischemic models were used and alpha-TC was measured by HPLC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Brain alpha-TC levels in gerbils exposed to 20 min bilateral carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (CAO) and 60 min reperfusion was 10.8 +/- 2.1 micrograms/g (x +/- S.D., n = 6) vs. 10.8 +/- 1.8 micrograms/g (n = 6) in sham controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In gerbils subjected to 3 h unilateral CAO and 2 h RP, a procedure marked by <z:hpo ids='HP_0000707'>neurological abnormalities</z:hpo>, brain alpha-TC levels of ischemic and non-ischemic hemispheres were essentially the same (10.7 +/- 1.6 vs. 10.1 +/- 1.4 micrograms/g, n = 4) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In rats subjected to 80 min unilateral middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> followed by 60 min reperfusion, or 6 h occlusion without reperfusion, the brain alpha-TC levels in ipsilateral ischemic and contralateral non-ischemic cortex were not different (12.1 +/- 1.2 vs. 11.9 +/- 2.6 micrograms/g or 12.2 +/- 1.6 vs. 13.4 +/- 1.2 micrograms/g, n = 4-8) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Our results demonstrated that brain alpha-TC levels can not be used as index of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>/reperfusion related <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation or tissue injury </plain></SENT>
</text></document>