<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="51349">Polyamines</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">N-methyl-D-aspartate</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">NMDA</z:chebi>) receptors are both thought to play an important role in secondary neuronal injury after <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Ifenprodil, known as a noncompetitive inhibitor of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="51349">polyamine</z:chebi> sites at the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">NMDA</z:chebi> receptor, was studied after transient focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> occurred </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Spontaneously hypertensive male rats, each weighing between 250 and 350 g, underwent 3 hours of tandem middle cerebral artery (<z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>) and common carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> followed by reperfusion for a period of 3 hours or 21 hours </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Intravenous ifenprodil (10 microg/kg/minute) or saline infusion was started immediately after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion and continued throughout the ischemic period </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Physiological parameters including blood pressure, blood gas levels, blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi>, and rectal and temporal muscle temperatures were monitored </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Six rats from each group were evaluated at 6 hours postocclusion for brain water content, an indicator of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002181'>brain edema</z:hpo>, and Evans blue dye extravasation for blood-brain barrier breakdown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>Infarct</z:mpath> volume was also measured in six rats from each group at 6 and 24 hours postocclusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Ifenprodil treatment significantly reduced <z:hpo ids='HP_0002181'>brain edema</z:hpo> (82.5 +/- 0.4% vs. 83.5 +/- 0.4%, p &lt; 0.05) and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume (132 +/- 14 mm3 vs. 168 +/- 25 mm3, p &lt; 0.05) compared with saline treatment, with no alterations in temporal muscle (brain) or rectal (body) temperature (35.9 +/- 0.4 degrees C vs. 36.2 +/- 0.2 degrees C; 37.7 +/- 0.4 degrees C vs. 37.6 +/- 0.6 degrees C; not significant) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>These results demonstrate that ifenprodil has neuroprotective properties after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>/reperfusion injury in the absence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002045'>hypothermia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>This indicates that <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonists</z:chebi> selective for the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="51349">polyamine</z:chebi> site of the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">NMDA</z:chebi> receptors may be a viable treatment option and helps to explain some of the pathophysiological mechanisms involved in secondary injury after transient focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> has occurred </plain></SENT>
</text></document>