<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>A closed cranial window was implanted in male Mongolian Gerbils to investigate leukocyte-endothelium interactions (LEI) at the brain surface in global <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> (GCI) by intravital fluorescence microscopy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Four days after 15 min of bilateral common carotid <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> the ischemic tissue damage was histologically analysed in selectively vulnerable areas of the brain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The frequency of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="52672">Rhodamine 6G</z:chebi> labeled leukocytes rolling along ("roller") and firmly attached ("sticker") to postcapillary endothelium was assessed before and up to 180 min after GCI </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>As compared to the sham operated control animals induction of LEI was found in animals with GCI, following a steady increase up to a significant level attained at 60 min (rollers) or at 120 min of reperfusion (sticker), respectively (p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In animals with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> histological assessment revealed a significant decrease of viable neurons in the CA1-sector of hippocampus (neurons/mm2 +/- <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SEM</z:e>: 1308 +/- 71 vs. 829 +/- 106), in parietal neocortex (727 +/- 17 vs. 542 +/- 49), and in striatum (547 +/- 26 vs. 352 +/- 49; p &lt; 0.01), respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>A significant correlation between the extent of irreversible neuronal damage and the frequency of leukocyte adherence to the endothelium could not be established </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Nevertheless a direct correlation between the number of surviving neurons and of rolling leukocytes was observed, which may be suggestive of a protective potential of leukocyte rolling </plain></SENT>
</text></document>