<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The effects of the peptidergic nootropic drug Cerebrolysin on spatial memory and motor activity were examined in intact and ischemic rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Ischemic-hypoxic damage was induced by injection of Na-<z:chebi fb="53" ids="17514">cyanide</z:chebi> followed by bilateral occlusion of common carotid arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Immediately afterwards Cerebrolysin or saline was administered, either by continuous intraventricular (i.v.) infusion or by daily intraperitoneal (i.p.) injection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Rats were tested for spatial memory and motor activity in the <z:mp ids='MP_0001465'>Morris water maze</z:mp> on days 3 and 4 post-surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The best dose of the substance for i.p. administration was known from previous studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Therefore we had to investigate the dose-response-relationship and tolerability of the drug after i.v. administration in intact rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Infusion (i.v.) of a high dose of Cerebrolysin (0.57 mg/day) decreased motor activity and spatial memory of intact rats (p &lt; 0.01 and p &lt; 0.05, respectively) but low dose of Cerebrolysin was well tolerated in the intact animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Ischemia</z:e> led to deterioration of motor activity in control rats (p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Cerebrolysin significantly counteracted deleterious motor changes due to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> up to the level of intact controls after both i.v. infusion (0.0057 mg/day) and daily i.p. drug administration (100 mg/kg bw and day) indicating an accelerating recovery after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>