<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We tested the hypothesis that the excitatory neurotransmitter receptor <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi>, alpha amino-3-hydroxy-5-<z:chebi fb="36" ids="29309">methyl</z:chebi>-4-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="35595">isoxazole</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17272">propionate</z:chebi> (AMPA), would worsen cerebral cortical oxygen supply/consumption balance during focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In this study, we compared regional cerebral blood flow, arterial and venous O2 saturation, O2 extraction and oxygen consumption of ischemic and AMPA treated ischemic and control regions of rat brain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Ischemia</z:e> was induced by middle cerebral artery (<z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi>) occlusion in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="6015">isoflurane</z:chebi> (1.4%) anesthetized Wistar rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Twenty minutes after <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion, 10(-5) M AMPA was applied to the ischemic cortex (IC) for a period of 40 min; the fluid was changed every 10 min </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After 1 hr of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>, animals were sacrificed and regional cerebral blood flow (rCBF) was determined using the C14-iodoantipyrine autoradiographic technique </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Regional arterial and venous oxygen saturation were determined microspectrophotometrically </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In control, the cerebral blood flow and oxygen consumption of the IC were significantly lower than the contralateral cortex (rCBF: 46 +/- 20 vs. 81 +/- 39 ml/min/100g, O2 consumption: 2.8 +/- 1.4 vs. 3.6 +/- 1.4 ml O2/min/100g) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>10(-5) M AMPA did not significantly alter regional cerebral blood flow and oxygen consumption of the IC, but did decrease the average venous O2 saturation of the IC from 50.2 +/- 3.9% to 46.7 +/- 1.6% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>AMPA also significantly increased the frequency of small veins with less than 45% O2 saturation in the IC (8 out of 56 veins in IC vs. 18 out of 56 veins in AMPA treated IC) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Thus, topical application of 10(-5) M AMPA to the ischemic area worsens cerebral O2 balance and suggests that excitatory amino acids contribute to the degree of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>