<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>This experiment evaluated the potential for ketamine HCl, a non-competitive <z:chebi fb="6" ids="14321,29987">glutamate</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, to minimize injury resulting from temporary focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Male spontaneously hypertensive rats were randomly assigned to receive either ketamine (n = 13) or <z:chebi fb="2" ids="5615">halothane</z:chebi> anesthesia (n = 12) during 2 h of reversible middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Ketamine was administered as a 50 mg/kg i.v. loading dose followed by a continuous 1.25 mg/kg/min i.v. infusion beginning 25 min prior to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and continued until 30 min after reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>An additional group of rats (ketamine-shams, n = 8) underwent craniectomy and ketamine administration (as above) but the middle cerebral artery was not ligated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Physiologic values were similar between groups with the exception of plasma <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> which was elevated in the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="5615">halothane</z:chebi>-MCAO group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After 4 days recovery, rats in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> groups were neurologically evaluated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were no differences between the two groups undergoing MCAO for neurologic grading or open field behavior, although both groups performed worse than did ketamine-shams (P less than 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In contrast, motor performance revealed more severe deficits in the ketamine-MCAO rats vs either the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="5615">halothane</z:chebi>-MCAO or ketamine-sham groups (P less than 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume was then planimetrically measured after triphenyl tetrazolium <z:chebi fb="76" ids="17996">chloride</z:chebi> (TTC) staining of fresh brain sections </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Mean +/- S.D. <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume was not different between the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="5615">halothane</z:chebi>-MCAO (134 +/- 51 mm3) and ketamine-MCAO (131 +/- 64 mm3) groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Seven of 8 sham rats were free of TTC demarcated injury and in the remaining rat injury was minimal.(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>