<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To determine the prevalence and independent predictors of significant atherosclerotic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001920'>renal artery stenosis</z:hpo> (<z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp>) in unselected hypertensive patients undergoing coronary angiography and to assess the 6-month outcome of those patients with a significant <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: One thousand, four hundred and three consecutive hypertensive patients undergoing drive-by renal arteriography were analyzed retrospectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Univariate and multivariate logistic regression analyses were performed to identify independent predictors of <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In patients with significant <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> (&gt;or=50% <z:chebi fb="2" ids="8069">luminal</z:chebi> narrowing), 6-month follow-up was assessed and outcome was compared between patients with or without renal revascularization </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The prevalence of significant <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> was 8% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After multivariate analysis, coronary [odds ratio 5.3; 95% confidence interval (CI) 2.7-10.3; P &lt; 0.0001], peripheral (odds ratio 3.3; 95% CI 2.0-5.5; P &lt; 0.0001), and cerebral artery (odds ratio 2.8; 95% CI 1.5-5.3; P = 0.001) diseases, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000082'>impaired renal function</z:hpo> (odds ratio 2.9; 95% CI 1.8-4.5; P &lt; 0.0001) were found as independent predictors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At least one of these predictors was present in 96% of patients with <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In 74 patients (66%) with significant <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp>, an ad hoc revascularization was performed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>At follow-up, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16737">creatinine</z:chebi> clearance was significantly higher in revascularized than in nonrevascularized patients (69.2 vs. 55.5 ml/min per 1.73 m, P = 0.029) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>By contrast, blood pressure was comparable between both groups, but nonrevascularized patients were taking significantly more <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35674">antihypertensive drugs</z:chebi> as compared with baseline (2.7 vs. 2.1, follow-up vs. baseline; P = 0.0066) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The prevalence of atherosclerotic <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> in unselected hypertensive patients undergoing coronary angiography was low </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Coronary, peripheral, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007774" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral artery diseases</z:e>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000082'>impaired renal function</z:hpo> were independent predictors of <z:mp ids='MP_0011356'>RAS</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Ad hoc renal revascularization was associated with better renal function and fewer intake of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35674">antihypertensive drugs</z:chebi> at follow-up </plain></SENT>
</text></document>