<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The paper reports on rate and type of thrombotic events occurring during the observational, prospective, inception-cohort, multicenter ISCOAT study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>2,745 unselected, daily practice patients, consecutively referring to 34 Italian anticoagulation clinics to monitor the oral <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50249">anticoagulant</z:chebi> treatment, were included in the study from beginning of their first <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50249">anticoagulant</z:chebi> course </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>During a total follow-up of 2,011 patient-years of treatment 70 thrombotic events (3.5 per 100 patient years) were recorded in 67 patients: 20 fatal (1%), 39 major (1.9%) and 11 minor (0.6%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>34/70 events occurred within the first 90 days of treatment (relative risk - at multivariate analysis - of &lt; or =90 days vs. &gt;90 = 20.6, C.I </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>12.7-33.5; p &lt;0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The risk was higher in patients aged &gt; or =70 y (1.62, C.I </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>1.0-2.61; p &lt;0.05), and when indication for <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50249">anticoagulant</z:chebi> treatment was peripheral/<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007774" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral arterial disease</z:e> (1.84, C.I </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>1.01-3.36; p &lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The frequency of thrombotic events was 17.5% when international normalised ratio (INR) levels were &lt; 1.5, decreasing to 2.3% for INRs within the 2-2.99 category (relative risk of INRs &lt;2.0 vs. &gt; or =2 = 1.88, C.I </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>1.16-3.07; p &lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The recorded rate of thrombotic events was lower than that reported in the few available studies </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>A greater risk should be expected during the first 90 days of treatment, when anticoagulation levels are &lt;2.0 INR, in patients &gt; 70 years and in those with cerebrovascular/<z:hpo ids='HP_0004950'>peripheral arterial disease</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>