<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The neuroprotective effect of post-ischemic treatment with the novel, highly water-soluble, <z:chebi fb="6" ids="14321,29987">glutamate</z:chebi> AMPA receptor <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi> YM872 was evaluated by using <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e> imaging and histopathology of rats subjected to permanent <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Two treatment groups with continuous i.v. infusion of 20 mg kg-1 h-1 YM872 during either the first 4 h or first 24 h after <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion, called 4 h YM872 treatment group (n=9) and 24 h YM872 treatment group (n=8) respectively, were compared to a control group (n=8) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The main end-point was T2 weighted <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e> imaging and histopathology 24 h after <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Also the time evolution of the ischemic tissue damage was studied by diffusion weighted <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e> imaging 412 and 24 h after <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The volume of ischemic tissue damage as assessed by diffusion weighted <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e> imaging 412 h after <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion was significantly smaller in both YM872 treatment groups (99+/-52 mm3 and 102+/-44 mm3 compared to 186+/-72 mm3 in the control group, +/-S.D. and p=0.008) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume as assessed by T2 weighted <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">MR</z:e> imaging 24 h after <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion was significantly smaller only in the 24 h YM872 treatment group (262+/-57 mm3 compared to 366+/-49 mm3 in the control group, +/-S.D. and p=0.01) while the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume in the 4 h YM872 treatment group (357+/-88 mm3) was similar to the control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>YM872 treatment significantly reduced the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume 24 h after <z:chebi fb="70" ids="34342">MCA</z:chebi> occlusion when the drug was administered as continuous infusion during the 24-h observation period </plain></SENT>
</text></document>