<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>Uveitis</z:hpo> is a general term that refers to the <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammation</z:mp> of uveal tract, which is an important cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000618'>blindness</z:hpo> in young people </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>It is well known that <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo> can be the initial manifestation of a <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0442893" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">systemic disease</z:e> (S.D.), and may appear years before the diagnosis of the <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0277554" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">primary disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>Uveitis</z:hpo> should be integrated in a systemic study with proper testing </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Therefore, the diagnosis is a matter for the ophthalmologist and the Specialist in internal medicine </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We have made a retrospective study of 71 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0012121'>panuveitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We found 54.9% of primary <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo> and 45.1% of S.D. associated <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo>, most of them with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (16/71) and Ankylosing Spondilytis (7/71) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>HLA typing of the patients showed a decreased frequency of HLA A1 and HLA A3 antigens and an increased frequency of the HLA B27 antigen, when compared to a Portuguese control population </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>We confirmed the important role of HLA B27 as an independent susceptibility factor for <z:hpo ids='HP_0012122'>anterior uveitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The lowest HLA A3 frequency was observed in the group of S.D. associated <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo>, which could suggest that this antigen may play a role as a factor of resistance to <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>