<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: We sought to test the hypothesis that vascular endothelial function is impaired in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's syndrome and reflects increased levels of <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's syndrome is a multisystem <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1290884" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory disorder</z:e> commonly complicated by vascular <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> and arterial <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysm</z:hpo> formation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The precise mechanisms underlying <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's syndrome are not known </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We studied 19 patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's syndrome (18 to 50 years old, 9 men) and 21 healthy volunteers (18 to 50 years old, 10 men) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Brachial artery flow-mediated dilation (endothelium-dependent), and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28787">nitroglycerin</z:chebi> (NTG)-induced dilation (endothelium-independent) were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>To investigate <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> mechanisms, vascular studies were repeated 1 h after administration of <z:chebi fb="122" ids="21241">vitamin C</z:chebi> (1 g, intravenous) in 12 patients and 12 control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Flow-mediated dilation was reduced in patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet's syndrome</z:e> as compared with control subjects (0.7 +/- 0.9% vs. 5.7 +/- 0.9%, p = 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In contrast, there were no significant differences in the brachial artery diameter (4.2 +/- 0.2 vs. 4.0 +/- 0.2 mm, p = 0.47) or NTG-induced dilation (19.7 +/- 1.9% vs. 19.7 +/- 1.2%, p = 0.98) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In regression analysis, <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's syndrome was associated with impaired flow-mediated dilation independent of age, gender, brachial artery diameter, blood pressure, cholesterol and <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="122" ids="21241">Vitamin C</z:chebi> increased flow-mediated dilation in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's syndrome (0.2 +/- 0.7% to 3.5 +/- 1.0%, p = 0.002), but not in control subjects (4.3 +/- 0.6% to 4.7 +/- 0.4%, p = 0.51) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In both groups, NTG-induced dilation and brachial artery diameter were unchanged after <z:chebi fb="122" ids="21241">vitamin C</z:chebi> treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Vascular endothelial function is impaired in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet's syndrome</z:e> and can be rapidly improved by <z:chebi fb="122" ids="21241">vitamin C</z:chebi> treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Our results support a role for <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> in the pathophysiology of <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's syndrome and provide a rationale for therapeutic studies aimed at reducing vascular complications in this disorder </plain></SENT>
</text></document>