<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>PURPOSE: <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>Thrombosis</z:mp>, usually venous, occurs in 10% to 25% of patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease, but its pathogenesis is poorly understood </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We evaluated parameters of hemostasis and their relation with <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> in a series of patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>SUBJECTS AND METHODS: We studied 38 patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (13 with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo>), 38 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0004936'>venous thrombosis</z:hpo> without <z:hpo ids='HP_0100724'>thrombophilia</z:hpo>, and 100 control subjects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Levels or presence of protein C, protein S, antithrombin, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25297">methylenetetrahydrofolate</z:chebi> reductase C677T, factor V Leiden, prothrombin gene G20210A, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003613'>antiphospholipid antibodies</z:hpo>, plasminogen, tissue-type plasminogen activator (tPA), type-1 tPA inhibitor (PAI-1), PAI-1 4G/5G polymorphism, prothrombin fragment 1+2, plasmin/alpha(2)-antiplasmin complexes, thrombomodulin, and activated factors VII and XII were determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: There were no deficiencies in protein C, protein S, antithrombin, or factor V Leiden in the patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease, nor was there evidence of most other thrombotic abnormalities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Compared with control subjects, however, the <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease group had elevated mean (+/- SD) levels of prothrombin fragment 1+2 (2091 +/- 1323 pmol/L vs. 804 +/- 398 pmol/L, P &lt;0.001), plasmin/alpha2-antiplasmin complexes (410 +/- 220 microg/L vs. 214 +/- 92 microg/L, P &lt;0.001), and thrombomodulin (37 +/- 24 ng/mL vs. 27 +/- 10 ng/mL, P &lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>These levels did not differ between patients with or without <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Thrombophilic factors do not seem to explain most thromboses in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>There is increased thrombin generation, fibrinolysis, and thrombomodulin in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease, but these abnormalities are not related to <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>