<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Turkey is one of the countries where <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease is most prevalent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Although its pathogenesis is not defined clearly, infectious agents are thought to play a role in the etiology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In one study of a group of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo> patients, including those with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease, increased seropositivity to B. burgdorferi was reported by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The seroprevalence of B. burgdorferi has been found to be as high as 36% in some rural areas of Turkey, although <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0024198" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Lyme disease</z:e> caused by B. burgdorferi is quite rare </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In this study, we investigated the seroreactivity to B. burgdorferi antigens in patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease and compared it with that of healthy and disease controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: This study was conducted in Izmir in western Turkey </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>B. burgdorferi immunoglobulin (Ig)M and IgG antibodies were tested by ELISA in the sera of patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease ( n=30), <z:hpo ids='HP_0001370'>rheumatoid arthritis</z:hpo> patients as disease controls ( n=31), and healthy controls ( n=31) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Positive results were confirmed by Western blotting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The difference in B. burgdorferi seropositivity between the groups was not significant by any method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Seroreactivity to B. burgdorferi antigens by ELISA was detected in 26.7% of the patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease, 35.5% of those with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001370'>rheumatoid arthritis</z:hpo>, and 19.4% of the healthy controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Immunoblots were positive in 13.3% of the <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease patients, 22.6% of the <z:hpo ids='HP_0001370'>rheumatoid arthritis</z:hpo> patients, and 12.9% of healthy controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: These results suggest no association between <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease and B. burgdorferi <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>