<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: We investigated whether Adamantiades-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet's disease</z:e> (ABD) is related to impaired aortic (Ao) elastic properties and left ventricular (LV) function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Adamantiades-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet's disease</z:e> is an <z:e sem="disease" ids="C1290884" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory disorder</z:e> characterized by <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> leading to vascular complications and, rarely, <z:mp ids='MP_0001856'>myocarditis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We studied 82 patients with ABD (age: 40 +/- 12 years) and 24 <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> control subjects by echocardiography </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Abdominal Ao diameter (mm/m(2)) and Ao elastic indexes--namely, Ao strain (%), distensibility (cm(2) x dyn(-1)x 10(-6)), stiffness index, and pressure strain modulus (Ep) (cm(2) x dyn(-1) x 10(-6))--were calculated from the echocardiographically derived thoracic Ao diameters (mm/m(2)), and the measurement of pulse pressure obtained by cuff sphygmomanometry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Isovolumic relaxation time (IVRT) (ms), deceleration time (DT) (ms), and flow propagation velocity (FPV) (cm/s) were measured by Doppler echocardiography to assess diastolic LV function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The duration of disease and presence of vascular complications were noted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Patients versus control subjects had increased Ao diameters (p &lt; 0.01), lower mean Ao strain and distensibility (4 vs. 9 and 1.4 vs. 3.4, respectively, p &lt; 0.01), higher mean aortic stiffness index and Ep (15.6 vs. 6 and 1.17 vs. 0.44, respectively, p &lt; 0.01), and impaired IVRT and FPV (p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Aortic function indexes were related to the duration of disease (p &lt; 0.01) and increased DT (p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Deceleration time &gt;190 ms predicted vascular complications with 80% sensitivity and 71% specificity (odds ratio 6.52 [confidence interval: 2.23 to 19.03]) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Aortic elastic properties and diastolic LV function are impaired in patients with ABD and are interrelated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The link between diastolic LV dysfunction and vascular complications suggests the presence of a common pathophysiologic pathway and provides a possible marker of risk for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0042373" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">vascular disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>