<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease is a <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> of unknown aetiology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Particular <z:mp ids='MP_0001799'>viral</z:mp> and <z:mp ids='MP_0001794'>bacterial</z:mp> pathogens have long been suspected of playing a role in the pathogenesis of the disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Chlamydia pneumoniae is an intracellular bacterium capable of causing <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Some reports have suggested that the microorganism might be involved in the pathogenesis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The purpose of the present study was to investigate a possible correlation between C. pneumoniae <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> and <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>For this purpose, 90 consecutive patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease and 50 healthy controls were enrolled </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Immunoglobulin A (IgA) and IgG antibodies to C. pneumoniae were determined by 2 different techniques, namely indirect fluorescent antibody assay (IFA) and enzyme linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>IgA antibodies to C. pneumoniae were detected in 17 (18.9%) patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease and in 1 (2%) healthy control by IFA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>By ELISA 27 patients (30.0%) and 6 controls (12.0%) had C. pneumoniae IgA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A significant difference was observed for IgA seropositivity between the 2 groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Although IgG seropositivity between the 2 groups did not differ significantly, the number of individuals with IgG titres of &gt; or = 1:1000 was significantly higher in the patient group (43.1%) compared with the control group (13.9%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>These finding provide serological evidence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> C. pneumoniae <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> in association with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>