<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Microorganisms such as streptococcus and autoantigens such as 60 kD heat-shock protein (HSP60) are implicated in the etiopathogenesis of <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (BD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Peripheral blood mononuclear cells from patients with BD (n = 16) and healthy controls (HC) (n = 11) were cultured for 5 days with extracts of S. sanguis-KTH-1 (SS), E. coli (EC) and a mixed <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptide</z:chebi> combination from human HSP60 (aa 136-50, 179-97, 224-58 and 336-51) reported to be associated with BD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>T and NK cell subset changes were determined by flow cytometry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In unstimulated 5-day cultures gammadelta+ (both CD4+gammadelta+ and CD8+gammadelta+), CD8+alphabeta+, CD4+CD56+ and CD8+CD11b+ cells were increased in BD compared to HC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In antigen-stimulated cultures of BD patients CD3+ and alphabeta+ T cells responded to HSP60 <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptides</z:chebi> whereas EC stimulated only CD16/ CD56+ NK cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In the control group, similar to BD, alphabeta+ and CD4+ T cells responded to HSP60 <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptides</z:chebi>, however SS and EC mainly activated cytotoxic T cell subsets (CD8+CD11b and CD4+CD56+ T cells) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Significant increases in unstimulated T cell subsets suggest the presence of an in vivo T cell activation in BD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In both patients and controls similar patterns of responses were observed against different microorganisms, however the role of human HSP60 <z:chebi fb="7" ids="16670">peptides</z:chebi> as immunodominant, crossreactive antigens could not be demonstrated </plain></SENT>
</text></document>