<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Genetic factors predisposing individuals to <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (BD) are considered to play important roles in the development of the disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Patients with BD exhibit elevated levels of pro-inflammatory cytokines, and affected organs show a significant neutrophil and lymphocyte infiltration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Current evidence suggests that the activated lymphocytes contribute to neutrophil and endothelial cell activation in these patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The cytotoxic T lymphocyte-associated antigen (CTLA)-4 molecule plays an important role in immune regulation by downregulating T-cell activation, and the CTLA-4 49A/G polymorphism in the exon 1 has been shown to be associated with a number of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmune diseases</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In an attempt to demonstrate whether there is an association of the CTLA-4 49A/G polymorphism with BD in the Turkish population, we genotyped 59 Turkish patients and 99 healthy individuals for single-nucleotide polymorphisms </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>For this purpose, genomic DNA was obtained from the peripheral blood of individuals and the region of interest was amplified using PCR </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Genotyping was performed using the BbvI restriction endonuclease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>It was shown that the distribution of the CTLA-4 exon 1 49A/G allele and genotype frequencies did not differ between patients with BD and healthy controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, allele and genotype frequencies of CTLA-4 49 A and A/A were significantly higher in patients with ocular involvement compared with patients without these symptoms (90.6% vs. 65.1%, odds ratio (OR) = 9.67, P = 0.011; and 81.25% vs. 39.5%, OR = 9.56, P = 0.015, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A statistically significant difference in the A allele frequency was observed in patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0010783'>erythema</z:hpo> nodosum-like lesions (86.1% vs. 65.8%, OR = 6.24, P = 0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>There was also an increase in A/A genotype frequency, but the difference was not statistically significant (72.2% vs. 41.5%, OR = 6.5, P = 0.068) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Our data suggest that BD patients with ocular involvement and <z:hpo ids='HP_0010783'>erythema</z:hpo> nodosum-like lesions have a higher frequency of both the A allele and the A/A genotype at position 49 of exon 1 of CTLA-4 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>These results may also indicate that CTLA-4 is a disease-modifying rather than a susceptibility gene for BD </plain></SENT>
</text></document>