<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>In this study we aimed to investigate IVS3 +17T/C single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) of CD28 gene, +49A/G and -318C/T SNPs of CTLA-4 gene in patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (BD) and their potential association to the main clinical features of the disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>These polymorphisms were investigated in a Turkish population of 123 patients with BD and 179 healthy controls, by using PCR-RFLP technique </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>HLA-B*51 genotype was also studied in both groups by using PCR-SSP </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The frequency of IVS3 +17TC genotype of the CD28 gene was significantly increased in BD patients compared to controls (43.6% vs. 31.2%, OR = 1.663, 95% CI = 1.033-2.679, P = 0.039) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>CTLA-4 +49GG genotype frequency was found to be significantly lower in patients with BD than those of healthy controls (4% vs. 10.6%, OR = 0.357, 95% CI = 0.130-0.983, P = 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Genotype and allele frequencies of the CTLA-4-318C/T polymorphism between the BD and healthy control groups were not significantly different (12.2% vs. 10.6%, OR = 1.170, 95% CI = 0.570-2.402, P = 0.713) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>There were no associations between the studied polymorphisms and the main clinical features of BD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The frequencies of HLA-B*51 were 60.3% and 30.7% in BD and control groups, respectively (OR = 3.429, 95% CI = 2.115-5.559, P = 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Association between HLA-B*51 and each studied polymorphism did not reach to significant levels (OR = 0.479, 95% CI = 0.228-1.004, P = 0.064 for CD28 IVS3 +17TT genotype; OR = 2.180, 95% CI = 1.025-4.639, P = 0.061 for TC genotype; OR = 1.570, 95% CI = 0.870-2.836, P = 0.146 for C allele) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These results may suggest that CD28 IVS3 +17TC genotype may be a risk factor for the development of BD, on the contrary CTLA-4 +49GG genotype may be protective in the studied Turkish population </plain></SENT>
</text></document>