<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: Gender differences, especially in disease severity, are observed in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (BD), a systemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> of unknown etiology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>To determine the putative role of <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> on neutrophil activity exhibited by patients with BD, peripheral blood neutrophils were examined in vitro before and after treatment with <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Peripheral blood neutrophils of 49 patients with BD (26M:23F), 33 patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0038013" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ankylosing spondylitis</z:e> (AS) (23M:10F), 8 female patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001007'>hirsutism</z:hpo> and 31 healthy individuals (19M:12F) were analyzed by flow cytometry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Neutrophil-ROS-generating capacity, anti-CD66b, anti-CD16, Phi-philux and PI staining techniques were used for evaluating neutrophil activation and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Gender differences were striking not only in the mean oxidative burst response but also in the rate of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Male BD patients manifested increased burst response before <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> treatment compared with females (8.0 +/- 4.9 vs. 4.9 +/- 3.3, p &lt; 0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Consistent with oxidative burst results, baseline percentages of CD66b (99.1 +/- 0.9 vs. 94.7 +/- 5.3 p &lt; 0.04) and CD16 expressing cells were greater in male BD patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A <z:mp ids='MP_0006043'>decreased apoptosis</z:mp> ratio was observed using phi-philux and PI staining in BD patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>This was especially significant in male compared to female BD patients (2.4 +/- 1.4 vs. 6.8 +/- 5.8, p &lt; 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>BD itself rather than the gender was found to be the most important predictor of this altered <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> ratio in BD determined by linear regression analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Our results suggest that a contribution of <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> to the BD pathogenesis cannot be ruled out </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>However, causative factors for disturbed <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> especially seen in male BD patients need to be further evaluated </plain></SENT>
</text></document>