<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (BD) is a multisystemic immuno-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C1290884" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">inflammatory disorder</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Inflammatory processes may cause <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation, alteration of <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profile and increase the risk of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002621'>atherosclerosis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The aim of this study was to evaluate the association between thiolactonase (HTLase) activity and plasma <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17230">homocysteine</z:chebi> levels (tHcy) in a BD population and to investigate their association with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="25297">methylenetetrahydrofolate</z:chebi> reductase (MTHFR) 677C--&gt;T genotype </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHOD: A total of 35 BD patients were compared to 39 healthy volunteers </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Significantly higher tHcy levels associated with lower HTLase activities were found in BD patients as compared to healthy controls (p&lt;0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>These patients also exhibited lower values of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="17855">triglycerides</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="47775">high-density lipoprotein cholesterol</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="47775">HDL-C</z:chebi>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Homozygosity for the T allele of the MTHFR gene was more frequent in BD patients (14.3% vs. 7.7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>It was associated with significantly higher tHcy levels (16.9 micromol/L for n=17 vs. 13.1 micromol/L for n=18; p&lt;0.05) and markedly lower HTLase activity (362.6+/-156.7 U/L vs. 414.2+/-180.2 U/L) for the (TT+CT) and CC genotypes, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Moreover, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="47775">HDL-C</z:chebi> levels were inversely correlated with tHcy (r=-0.5; p=0.004) but positively associated with HTLase activity (r=0.374; p=0.038) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These correlations were also present in several clinical manifestations, such as ocular, neurological involvement or <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Homozygosity of the T allele of the MTHFR gene is prevalent in BD patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>High levels of tHcy associated with low HTLase activities may be one of the causes leading to <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> in BD patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>