<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: The present study aimed to investigate the interactions among salivary S. mutans colonisation, serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37684">mannose</z:chebi> binding lectin level (MBL), <z:hpo ids='HP_0000155'>oral ulcer</z:hpo> activity and disease course in patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (BD) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: One hundred and six BD patients, 25 patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0001370'>rheumatoid arthritis</z:hpo> (RA) and 42 healthy controls (HC) were included in the study </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>BD patients were grouped as active (n=52) or inactive (n=54) according to <z:hpo ids='HP_0000155'>oral ulcer</z:hpo> status of the previous 3 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Salivary colonisation of S. mutans levels were investigated by standard <z:hpo ids='HP_0000670'>Caries</z:hpo> Risk Test (CRT) Bacteria kits (Ivoclar, Vivadent) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>S. mutans colonies were categorized as high (&gt; or =10(5) colony forming unit (CFU)/ml of saliva) or low (10(5)CFU/ml) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Serum <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37684">mannose</z:chebi> binding lectin (MBL) levels were measured by ELISA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: High levels of salivary S. mutans colonisation was significantly more present in BD (50%) than HC (28.6%)(p=0.039), whereas no significant difference was observed between RA and other groups (p&gt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>S. mutans presence in saliva was associated with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000155'>oral ulcers</z:hpo> (61.5% in patients with active <z:hpo ids='HP_0000155'>oral ulcers</z:hpo> vs 38.9% in inactives) (p=0.020) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>S. mutans colonisation in saliva was significantly higher among male BD patients with a severe disease course than a milder disease (p=0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Increased salivary S. mutans colonisation was also related to very low serum MBL (&lt;100 ng/ml) in BD compared to controls (p=0.04) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: The relationship between increased presence of S. mutans and MBL deficiency with active disease pattern may indicate an impaired innate immune response in BD patients which may predispose to <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0555971" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">oral infections</z:e> and a severe disease course </plain></SENT>
</text></document>