<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease is a <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> inflammatory <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Vascular involvement is one of the major complications of <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease, during the course of the disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Previous studies showed that <z:chebi fb="2" ids="35457">ACE inhibitors</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statins</z:chebi> may improve endothelial functions in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">endothelial dysfunction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The aim of our study is to compare the effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="43755">lisinopril</z:chebi> to placebo on <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">endothelial dysfunction</z:e> in patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>PATIENTS AND METHODS: We prospectively studied 92 (48 female) <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's patients who were diagnosed according to the International Study Group criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Endothelial dysfunction</z:e> was evaluated by brachial artery flow-mediated <z:mpath ids='MPATH_66'>dilatation</z:mpath> (FMD) method using high-resolution vascular ultrasound device at baseline and after for 3-month therapy </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Patients were consecutively randomized into three groups as (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> (n = 31), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="43755">lisinopril</z:chebi> (n = 31), and placebo groups (n = 30) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Patients in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> group received 20 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="43755">lisinopril</z:chebi> group received 10 mg <z:chebi fb="0" ids="43755">lisinopril</z:chebi> per day, and placebo group received placebo per day for 3 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The baseline characteristics of patients were similar among three groups; however, high-sensitive C-reactive protein (hs-CRP) levels were lower in <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> group than placebo group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>A significant improvement in FMD was observed in both <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> (5.0 ± 1.4 vs. 12.8 ± 3.6%, P &lt; 0.001) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="43755">lisinopril</z:chebi> groups (5.0 ± 1.2 vs. 11.4 ± 5.0%, P &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Partial significant enhancement was observed in placebo group (4.9 ± 1.1% vs. 5.7 ± 1.0, P = 0.002) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>However, it was lower than the cutoff value for <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">endothelial dysfunction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: These findings suggest that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="43755">lisinopril</z:chebi> improve endothelial functions in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>However, large studies are needed to determine the long-term effects of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="39548">atorvastatin</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="43755">lisinopril</z:chebi> therapy </plain></SENT>
</text></document>