<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (BD) is a helper T cell-mediated <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmune disease</z:hpo> characterised by recurrent orogenital <z:mpath ids='MPATH_579'>ulcers</z:mpath>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo> and <z:mp ids='MP_0001212'>skin lesions</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The helper T cells are divided into Th1, Th2 and Th17 cells according to the pattern of cytokine secretion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Th1 and Th17 cells can contribute to the development of the disease with their respective proinflammatory cytokines, IFN-γ and IL-17 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In this study, we investigated the relative role of Th17, Th1 and Th2 cells in BD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Peripheral blood mononuclear cells were isolated from 30 patients with BD, for whom the detailed clinical manifestations and medication history were investigated and recorded </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Surface markers and intracellular levels of IL-17, IFN-γ and IL-4 in isolated CD4+ T cells were measured using flow-cytometry from these patients and from two control groups, 34 <z:hpo ids='HP_0001370'>rheumatoid arthritis</z:hpo> patients and 24 healthy blood donors to analyse the relationship of Th1, Th17 and Th2 cells in BD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The ratio of Th17/Th1 cells was significantly increased in BD compared to healthy controls (0.16±0.09 vs. 0.10±0.04, p=0.012), while there was no difference in the ratios of Th1/Th2 or Th17/Th2 cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Th17/Th1 ratio was elevated in BD patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo> or <z:mp ids='MP_0000376'>folliculitis</z:mp> compared to those without it (0.21±0.10 vs. 0.13±0.06, p=0.045 for <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo>; 0.18±0.10 vs. 0.12±0.05, p=0.036 for <z:mp ids='MP_0000376'>folliculitis</z:mp>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our results confirm that TH17 cells are instrumental in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo> and <z:mp ids='MP_0000376'>folliculitis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, our findings suggest that the role of Th17 cells should be interpreted in the context of their ratio to Th1 cells </plain></SENT>
</text></document>