<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (BD) is known to be associated with HLA-B*51, especially HLA-B*5101, in many different ethnic groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Recently, several HLA-A or -B alleles have been proposed as possible candidate genes for BD in addition to HLA-B*5101 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>To investigate those associations, we studied HLA-A and -B alleles in Japanese ocular BD patients and the association of possible susceptibility HLA genes with visual prognosis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Eighty-eight Japanese BD patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0000554'>uveitis</z:hpo> and 104 healthy controls were enrolled for analyses of HLA-A and B alleles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Statistical analysis was performed with Fisher's exact test and odds ratio (OR) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Association of the possible susceptible HLA gene and visual prognosis was also examined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The phenotype frequency (PF) of HLA-A*2601 was significantly higher in the patients (37.5%) than the controls (14.4%) (pc=0.00529, OR=3.56), especially in patients without HLA-B*5101 (57.4% vs. 14.1%, pc=4.58x10-6, OR=8.21) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In contrast, the PF of HLA-A*2601 was not increased in patients with HLA-B*5101 (14.6% vs. 15.8%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Also, the PF in patients possessing HLA-A*2601 or HLAB* 5101 was increased up to 77.3% </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Interestingly, the PF of HLA-A*2601 was significantly associated with poor visual prognosis corresponding to visual acuity of 0.1 or less in the worse eye (p=0.0262) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Our results indicate that HLA-A*2601 is possibly associated with ocular BD, independent of HLAB* 5101, indicating that HLA-A*2601 is an additional susceptibility allele candidate of ocular BD in Japan </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>HLAA* 2601 would also be a possible marker for poor visual prognosis </plain></SENT>
</text></document>