<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The <z:hpo ids='HP_0002633'>vasculitis</z:hpo> of <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet disease (BD) is distinctive because of involvement of both arteries and veins of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> sizes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The concept of vasculo-<z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet disease has been adopted for cases in which vascular manifestations are present and often dominate the clinical features </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>While venous manifestations are frequent and have been reported in many publications, data regarding arterial lesions in patients with BD are rare and often isolated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In this study, we report the main characteristics, treatment, and long-term outcome of 101 patients with arterial lesions among a cohort of 820 (12.3%) BD patients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Factors that affect prognosis were assessed by multivariate analysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There were 93 (91.2%) male patients; the median (Q1-Q3) age at diagnosis of BD was 33 (27-41) years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Arterial lesions included <z:hpo ids='HP_0002617'>aneurysms</z:hpo> (47.3%), occlusions (36.5%), stenosis (13.5%), and <z:mp ids='MP_0010139'>aortitis</z:mp> (2.7%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Lesions mainly involved the aorta (n = 25) and femoral (n = 23) and pulmonary (n = 21) arteries </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Patients with arterial lesions were more frequently male (91.2% vs. 62.4%, respectively; p = 0.017) and had higher rates of venous involvement (80.4% vs. 29.8%, respectively; p &lt; 0.001) compared to patients without arterial manifestations </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Thirty-nine (38.6%) patients achieved complete remission </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>In multivariate analysis, the presence of venous involvement (odds ratio [OR], 0.29; 95% confidence interval [CI], 0.08-1.11) and arterial occlusive lesions (OR, 0.13; 95% CI, 0.01-1.25) were negatively associated with complete remission </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The use of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35705">immunosuppressants</z:chebi> (OR, 3.38; 95% CI, 0.87-13.23) was associated with the occurrence of complete remission </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The 20-year survival rate was significantly lower in BD patients with arterial involvement than in those without arterial lesions (73% vs. 89%, respectively; p &lt; 0.0001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, the long-term outcome of arterial lesions in BD is poor, especially in the case of occlusive lesions and associated venous involvement </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>The use of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35705">immunosuppressants</z:chebi> improved the prognosis </plain></SENT>
</text></document>