<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the clinical features, diagnosis methods, therapeutic principles of intestinal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet's disease</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: king Union Medical College Hospital from August 1998 to April 2010 were retrospectively analyzed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: The clinical courses of patients with intestinal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet's disease</z:e> were from 26 days to 33 years, and the average duration was 6.32 +/- 1.01 years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The appearance of extra-gastrointestinal symptoms was significantly earlier than that of gastrointestinal symptoms (7.35 +/- 1.39 years vs. 3.24 +/- 0.82 years, P&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The predominant gastrointestinal manifestations were right lower quadrant pain (95.56%) and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002573'>hematochezia</z:hpo> or <z:hpo ids='HP_0002249'>melena</z:hpo> (40.00%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Misdiagnosis occurred in 17 cases </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In patients without systemic medicine therapy before surgery, the incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0392618" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">postoperative infection</z:e> of incision site and abdominal cavity was significantly higher than that in those undergoing systemic medicine therapy (80.00% vs. 0%, P&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Because of the diversity of gastrointestinal manifestations, intestinal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0004943" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Behcet's disease</z:e> is easily misdiagnosed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The systemic medical therapy before surgery could decrease the incidence of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> of incision and abdominal cavity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>