<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0856169" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Endothelial dysfunction</z:e> is previously demonstrated in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (BD) and <z:chebi fb="27" ids="27300">vitamin D</z:chebi> is implicated to affect endothelial functions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We aimed to evaluate the status of serum 25(OH)Vit D3 levels and its association with disease activity, endothelial function and carotis intima media thickness (CIMT) in patients with BD </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Thirty-six BD (F/M: 22/14, mean age: 39.6 years) patients and 51 healthy controls (F/M: 28/23, mean age: 34.5 years) were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0001370'>Rheumatoid arthritis</z:hpo> (RA) (n=33) patients (F/M: 26/7, mean age: 50.82 years) were also enrolled, as a disease control group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Endothelial function was evaluated by brachial artery flow mediated <z:mpath ids='MPATH_66'>dilatation</z:mpath> (FMD) and CIMT with B-Mode ultrasound </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="27" ids="27300">vitamin D</z:chebi>-deficient BD patients received 1000 IU <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28940">Vitamin D3</z:chebi> daily for 3 months </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Less than 50 nmol/L levels of 25<z:chebi fb="2" ids="29191">(OH)</z:chebi> Vit D3 were present in 61.1% (n=22) of BD and 35.3% (n=18) of HC (serum 25(OH)Vit D3 levels: BD: 44.5 (9-112) vs HC: 56 (14-125) nmol/lt, p=0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CIMT and FMD were also significantly different between BD and HC [0.56 (0.35-9.26) vs. 0.39 (0-0.52) and 5.20 (0.56-30.58) vs. 9.04 (-6.9-34.17), p=0.001 and p=0.02, respectively] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, no correlation was observed between 25(OH)VitD3 levels and CIMT or FMD (r=0.6, p=0.7 and r=0.03, p=0.8, respectively) at baseline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CIMT measurements improved after replacement therapy (0.56 vs. 0.49, p=0.02), FMD measurements also improved, but not reaching statistical significance (5.2 vs. 8.28, p=0.06) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: A high presence of <z:hpo ids='HP_0100512'>vitamin D deficiency</z:hpo> was observed in BD patients from Turkey and replacement of <z:chebi fb="27" ids="27300">vitamin D</z:chebi> had favourable effects on endothelial function </plain></SENT>
</text></document>