<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The relation between the biochemical and serological properties of 'Streptococcus sanguis' was studied to characterize the strains isolated from <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0011389" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">dental plaque</z:e> of patients with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease and controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Seven reference and 100 clinical strains preserved by the <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's Disease Research Committee of Japan were identified using established criteria and differentiated with antisera against Strep. oralis ATCC 10557, Strep. sanguis ATCC 10556 and 'Strep. sanguis' ST7, compatible with the criteria </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Uncommon serovars (serotypes) KTH-1 (= ATCC 49298), KTH-2 (= ATCC 49296), KTH-3 (= ATCC KTH-4 (= ATCC 49297) and B220 (serovar KTH-1) with both IgA1 protease and neuraminidase (sialidase) were identified as Strep. oralis, whereas common serovars ST3 with IgA1 protease alone and ST7 without both enzymes were identified as Strep. sanguis and Strep. gordonii, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Isolates previously ranked as uncommon serovars were identified as Strep. oralis, whereas the rest ranked as common serovars were identified as the same species as those of the grouping strains </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A soft-agar technique was available for species identification except for Strep. oralis serovar KTH-1 reacting with the antiserum against Strep. gordonii ST7 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>The frequency of isolation of Strep. oralis was higher in <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease (52%) than in controls (38%), but no difference was observed between the properties of the two groups of isolates </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Strep. oralis virulence factors may be involved in breach the mucosal barrier in patients with specific reactivity to these antigens and inducing <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet's disease </plain></SENT>
</text></document>