<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>In order to know the possibility that gamma delta TCR+ T cells induced by Mycobacterium avium complex (MAC) <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infections</z:e> participate in the expression of host resistance and in the occurrence of <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet disease, we examined the behaviour of them in MAC-infected host mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In both BALB/c (Bcgs; MAC-susceptible) and CBA/JN (Bcgr; MAC-resistant) strain mice, a transient but appreciable increase in the number of gamma delta TCR+ T cells in the host peritoneal lymphocytes was noted around week 1 to 2 after M. intracellulare <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> via ip. route </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>The degree of induction of gamma delta TCR+ T cells was somewhat higher in CBA/JN mice than in BALB/c mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Therefore, gamma delta TCR+ T cells are partly responsible for the expression of host resistance against the MAC in the early phase of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>However, the subsequent decrease in the level of gamma delta TCR+ T cells was observed by week 5 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Thus, in the case of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> state of MAC <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>, the size of gamma delta TCR+ T cell-pool seems to be in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> level </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>This suggests that per cell activity of gamma delta TCR+ T cells rather than mobilizing number of them is important factor in the mechanisms for occurrence of allergic diseases including <z:chebi fb="6" ids="22696">Beh</z:chebi>çet disease </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Although, the early increase in gamma delta TCR+ T cells of peritoneal cells was also observed during the course of M. fortuitum <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0021311,C0009450" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">infection</z:e>, the degree of induction of gamma delta TCR+ T cells in A/J mice (M. fortuitum-susceptible) was in similar level as that in BALB/c mice (M. fortuitum-resistant).(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 250 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>