<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>INTRODUCTION: Although multiple studies of demographic variables have been associated with allograft <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp>, these results are not routinely reproducible </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="?"><plain>Are <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">ESRD</z:e> patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0398623" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypercoagulable states</z:e> (HCS) (<z:hpo ids='HP_0001976'>antithrombin III deficiency</z:hpo>, protein S or C deficiency, activated protein C resistance, and anticardiolipin antibodies) at predictably greater risk for allograft <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Between 1996 and 1999, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> renal transplant candidates were screened for <z:hpo ids='HP_0100724'>hypercoagulability</z:hpo> risk factors [HRF] (multiple arteriovenous access thromboses, prior <z:hpo ids='HP_0002625'>deep vein thrombosis</z:hpo>, prior allograft <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0262428" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">collagen vascular disease</z:e>, multiple <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0000786" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">miscarriages</z:e>, <z:mp ids='MP_0002055'>diabetes</z:mp>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002960'>autoimmune disease</z:hpo>, and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0002986" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Fabry's disease</z:e>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>HRF(+) candidates were then tested for HCS status </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We administered preemptive posttransplant i.v </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">Heparin</z:chebi> in HCS(+) patients and observed the impact of this intervention upon the incidence of allograft <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We compared demographic data and incidence of allograft <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> in an historic control (346 patients transplanted between June 31, 1992, and March 5, 1996) not tested for HCS and a study cohort (502 patients transplanted between March 6, 1996, and June 31, 1999) prospectively screened for HRF </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>HRF(+) patients who were HCS(+) in the study cohort received i.v. <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> immediately after transplant and p.o. <z:chebi fb="8" ids="10033">warfarin</z:chebi> as outpatients </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Demographic characteristics previously implicated in allograft <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> were equivalently distributed in both cohorts with the exceptions that more living-donor transplants (33.1% vs. 15.3%) were performed in study cohort, CIT&gt;24 hr occurred in more control patients (37.3% vs. 22.1%) and more study patients (16.7% vs. 0%) received tacrolimus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0398623" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Hypercoagulable states</z:e> were found upon reevaluating five of seven controls (71.4%), who lost prior allografts to <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0398623" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Hypercoagulable states</z:e> were prospectively detected in 10 study patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0100724'>hypercoagulability</z:hpo> risk factors </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Most (9 of 10) study patients receiving anticoagulation have achieved long-term allograft function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Study group allograft <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> incidence was reduced (1.59% vs. 4.05%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0398623" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Hypercoagulable states</z:e> were demonstrated in most episodes of allograft <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Control patients who lost prior allografts to <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> were anticoagulated after retransplantation and 100% achieved long-term allograft function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Long-term allograft function has been achieved in 90% of study patients when prophylactically anticoagulating study patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0398623" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypercoagulable states</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>A 2.6-fold reduction in the expected incidence of allograft <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> was observed in anticoagulated patients with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0398623" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypercoagulable states</z:e> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>