<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>UNLABELLED: Antithrombin (AT), a <z:chebi fb="1" ids="17822">serin</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37670">protease inhibitor</z:chebi> (serpin) produced in the liver, inhibits mainly thrombin and factor Xa </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0272375" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Antithrombin deficiency</z:e> (AD) is associated with a higher incidence of <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>CASE REPORT: We report a newborn with uncomplicated birth in the 40+5 week of gestation and postnatal appearance of a reticular, livide haematoma on the right upper arm and a tonic clonic <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0014544" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">epileptic</z:e> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001250'>seizure</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Clinical examination revealed weak pulses in the A. radialis and ulnaris </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>MRI scan showed a large <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> in the A. carotis interna and externa with large <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> and a <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0302148,C0087086" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">thrombus</z:e> in the A. subclavia </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Laboratory work up showed elevated D-dimers and antithrombin levels &lt;20% (lowest 15%), age-related values for protein C, protein S, plasminogen, and no other inherited <z:hpo ids='HP_0100724'>thrombophilia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>THERAPY: We started anticoagulation with unfractionated <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> intravenously (aPTT: 50-60 s) and under suspicion of an AD the substitution of AT (70 U/kg body weight) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>In course of time we changed anticoagulation to low molecular weight <z:chebi fb="5" ids="28304">heparin</z:chebi> (Anti Xa 0.6-0.8 U/ml) and substitution of 250 E/kg AT every second day </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In the molecular work up we found a homozygous missense mutation in exon 2 of SERPINC1 gene (type "Budapest 3") </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Molecular analysis showed also heterozygous mutations in both parents and a homozygous mutation in the asymptomatic brother aged three years </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>At age of six months we changed the anticoagulation to <z:chebi fb="0" ids="10034">coumadin</z:chebi> (INR 2.5-3.5) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Anticoagulation with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="10034">coumadin</z:chebi> was also started in the brother </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>DISCUSSION: Hereditary AD is associated with an increased risk of <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The homozygous status mainly leads to intrauterine fetal loss or the occurrence of peri- and postnatal <z:mp ids='MP_0005048'>thrombosis</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>Therapy consists in the substitution of AT and a lifelong anticoagulation with <z:chebi fb="6" ids="28384">vitamin K</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonists</z:chebi> also in asymptomatic patients </plain></SENT>
</text></document>