<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>In a recent study of focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> in rats, pre-ischemic administration of the synthetic allosteric <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> modifier RSR13 (2-[4-[[3,5-dimethylanilino) <z:chebi fb="1" ids="23019">carbonyl</z:chebi>] <z:chebi fb="36" ids="29309">methyl</z:chebi>] phenoxy]-2-methylproprionic acid) reduced cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size when combined with the <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">NMDA</z:chebi> receptor <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi> dizocilpine (MK-801) but not when given alone </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that post-ischemic RSR13 administration would enhance neuroprotection afforded by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">NMDA</z:chebi> receptor antagonism in a rat model of transient middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Fasted normothermic Wistar rats underwent 75 min of temporary MCAO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>At <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of reperfusion, rats randomly received: (1) 0.9% <z:chebi fb="1" ids="26710">NaCl</z:chebi> (vehicle) i.v. alone (n=16); (2) 0.9% <z:chebi fb="1" ids="26710">NaCl</z:chebi>+dizocilpine (0.25 mg/kg) i.v </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>(n=16); or (3) RSR13 (150 mg/kg)+dizocilpine (0.25 mg/kg) i.v </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>(n=17) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Seven days later, neurologic deficit and cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size were determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Dizocilpine alone compared to vehicle reduced mean+/-S.D. subcortical (52+/-24 mm(3) vs. 122+/-64 mm(3), P=0.003) and cortical (35+/-35 mm(3) vs. 125+/-72 mm(3), P=0.00074) <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volumes </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>When compared to dizocilpine alone, the combination of RSR13+dizocilpine further reduced subcortical (37+/-14 mm(3) vs. 52+/-24 mm(3), P=0 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>034) and cortical (8+/-19 mm(3) vs. 35+/-35 mm(3), P=0.018) <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>RSR13+dizocilpine improved neurologic scores vs. either dizocilpine alone (P=0.0014) or vehicle (P=10(-7)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The combination of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">NMDA</z:chebi> receptor antagonism and a RSR13 mediated rightward shift of the oxy-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="35143">hemoglobin</z:chebi> dissociation curve improved outcome from MCAO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Because this occurred after reperfusion, our results suggest that the post-ischemic brain continues to suffer from hypoperfusion defects, which are amenable to therapy by enhanced <z:chebi fb="0" ids="15379">O(2)</z:chebi> delivery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>The results also support the concept that neuroprotective strategies, which combine drugs with different mechanisms of action, may yield cumulative benefits </plain></SENT>
</text></document>