<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>LY341122 (2-(3, 5-di-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="30355">t-butyl</z:chebi>-4-hydroxyphenyl)-4-(2-(4-methylethylaminomethyl-ph enylox y)ethyl)<z:chebi fb="0" ids="35597,35790">oxazole</z:chebi>) is a potent inhibitor of <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation which has been shown to protect against global <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and traumatic brain injury in rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The purpose of this study was to examine the effect of LY341122 on ischemic injury in a highly reproducible model of focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> in rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Male Sprague-Dawley rats were anesthetized with <z:chebi fb="2" ids="5615">halothane</z:chebi> and subjected to 120 min of temporary middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> by retrograde insertion of an intraluminal nylon suture coated with poly-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="18019,29967">L-lysine</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The drug (LY341122, n=19) or vehicle (phosphate-buffered saline (PBS), n=10) was administered i.v </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>(as a 5 or 10 mg/kg bolus followed by a 5 or 10 mg/kg/h infusion for 20 h, respectively, starting 1 or 2 h after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp>) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Neurological status was evaluated during middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (60 min) and daily for 3 days thereafter </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Three days after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007786" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia, brains</z:e> were perfusion-fixed and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volumes and <z:hpo ids='HP_0002181'>brain edema</z:hpo> were determined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>LY341122 significantly improved the neurological score compared to vehicle at 24, 48 and 72 h after middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Treatment with LY341122 significantly reduced total <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> treated groups compared to vehicle rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Cortical <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume was significantly reduced by LY341122 treatment in the 10 mg/kg (1 h) and LY341122 10 mg/kg (2 h) groups compared to vehicle rats (14.7+/-9.5 vs. 106.8+/-20.9 mm(3), and 36.9+/-20.1 vs. 106 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>8+/-20.9 mm(3), respectively (mean+/-S.E.M.)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Striatal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume was also significantly reduced by treatment with LY341122 in the 10 mg/kg (1 h) group compared to vehicle (23.7+/-3.4 vs. 68 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>2+/-6.7 mm(3)) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>These results demonstrate the neuroprotective efficacy of LY341122 in focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>