<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>In the present studies we have examined the effects of a new <z:chebi fb="1" ids="38215">calcium channel blocker</z:chebi>, LY393615 ((N-Butyl-[5,5-bis-(4-fluorophenyl)<z:chebi fb="0" ids="26911">tetrahydrofuran</z:chebi>-2-yl]<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16830">methylamine</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="16" ids="36807">hydrochloride</z:chebi>, NCC1048) in a model of <z:mp ids='MP_0005039'>hypoxia</z:mp>-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> in vitro and in a gerbil model of global and in two rat models of focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0917798" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral ischaemia</z:e> in vivo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Results indicated that LY393615 protected against <z:mp ids='MP_0005039'>hypoxia</z:mp>-hypoglycaemic insults in brain slices and also provided significant protection against <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischaemia</z:e>-induced hippocampal damage in gerbil global <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0917798" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral ischaemia</z:e> when dosed at 10, 12.5 (P&lt;0.05) or 15 mg/kg i.p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>(P&lt;0.01) 30 min before and 2 h 30 min after occlusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The compound penetrated the brain well after a 15 mg/kg i.p. dose and had a half-life of 2.5 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In further studies LY393615 was protective 1 h post-occlusion when administered at 15 mg/kg i.p. followed by 2 doses of 5 mg/kg i.p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>2 and 3 h later </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>LY393615 dosed at 15 mg/kg i.p. followed by 2 further doses of 5 mg/kg i.p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>(2 and 3 h later) also produced a significant reduction in the <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume following Endothelin-1 (Et-1) middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> in the rat when administration was initiated immediately (P&lt;0.01) or 1 h (P&lt;0.05) after occlusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The compound was also evaluated in the intraluminal monofilament model of focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischaemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The animals had the middle cerebral artery occluded for 2 h, and 15 min after reperfusion LY393615 was administered at 15 mg/kg i.p. followed by 2 mg/kg/h i.v. infusion for 6 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>There was no reduction in <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume using this dosing protocol </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, in the present studies we have reported that a novel <z:chebi fb="1" ids="38215">calcium channel blocker</z:chebi>, LY393615, with good bioavailability protects against neuronal damage caused by <z:mp ids='MP_0005039'>hypoxia</z:mp>-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020615" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hypoglycaemia</z:e> in vitro and both global and focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0917798" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral ischaemia</z:e> in vivo </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The compound is neuroprotective when administered post-occlusion and may therefore be a useful anti-ischaemic agent </plain></SENT>
</text></document>