<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Remodeling of the cerebral vasculature contributes to the pathogenesis of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Remodeling is caused by increased smooth muscle proliferation and may be due to an increase in the responsiveness of vascular cells to epidermal growth factor (EGF) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="27584,30834">Aldosterone</z:chebi> is a risk factor for <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, and the literature suggests it may play a role in increasing the expression of the receptor for EGF (EGFR) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> for the EGF-stimulated pathway would be elevated in the vasculature of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>-prone spontaneously hypertensive rats (SHRSP) and that this and experimental ischemic cerebral infract size would be reduced by <z:chebi fb="0" ids="27584,30834">aldosterone</z:chebi> inhibition with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9241">spironolactone</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>We found that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9241">spironolactone</z:chebi> treatment reduced the size of cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> after middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> in SHRSP (51.69 +/- 3.60 vs. 22.00 +/- 6.69% of hemisphere-infarcted SHRSP vs. SHRSP + <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9241">spironolactone</z:chebi> P &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Expression of EGF and EGFR <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> was higher in cerebral vessels and aorta from adult SHRSP compared with Wistar-Kyoto rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Only the expression of EGFR <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> was elevated in the young SHRSP </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9241">Spironolactone</z:chebi> reduced the EGFR <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression in the aorta (1.09 +/- 0.25 vs. 0.56 +/- 0.11 phosphorimage units SHRSP vs. SHRSP + <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9241">spironolactone</z:chebi> P &lt; 0.05) but had no effect on EGF <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In vitro incubation of aorta with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="27584,30834">aldosterone</z:chebi> +/- <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9241">spironolactone</z:chebi> produced similar results, suggesting a direct effect of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="27584,30834">aldosterone</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Thus <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9241">spironolactone</z:chebi> may reduce the size of cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> via a reduction in the expression of the EGFR <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi>, leading to reduced remodeling </plain></SENT>
</text></document>