<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Experimental and clinical data suggest an important role of iron in <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0917798" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral ischaemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We measured <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume and analysed the <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp>, and also the excitatory and <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammatory responses</z:mp> to brain injury in a rat <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> model after an increased oral iron intake </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Permanent middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) was performed in ten male Wistar rats fed with a diet containing 2.5% <z:chebi fb="1" ids="23019">carbonyl</z:chebi> iron for 9 weeks, and in ten control animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="6" ids="14321,29987">Glutamate</z:chebi>, interleukin-6 (IL-6) and <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumour</z:e> <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> factor-alpha (TNF-alpha) were determined in blood samples before and at 2, 4, 6, 8, 24 and 48 h after MCAO, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33202">thiobarbituric acid</z:chebi> reaction substances (TBARS) were analysed at 48 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>Infarct</z:mpath> volume was measured at 48 h by image analysis on brain slices stained with 1% TTC </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Tissue iron was measured by atomic absorption spectrophotometry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>Infarct</z:mpath> volume was 66% greater in the iron fed rats than in the control group (178+/-49 mm(3) versus 107+/-53 mm(3), P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Significant higher levels of <z:chebi fb="6" ids="14321,29987">glutamate</z:chebi>, IL-6 and TNF-alpha were observed in the group with iron intake (peak values were obtained at 6, 8 and 4 h, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Iron-fed animals also showed significantly higher levels of TBARS than those receiving a <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> diet (6.52+/-0.59 vs. 5.62+/-0.86 micro mol/l, P=0.033) Liver iron stores (3500+/-199 vs. 352+/-28 micro g Fe/g, P&lt;0.0001), but not brain iron stores (131 vs. 139 micro g Fe/g, P=0.617), were significantly higher in the iron fed rats group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>These results suggest that iron intake is associated with larger <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volumes after MCAO in the rat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>This effect seems to be associated with higher <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp>, excitotoxicity and <z:mp ids='MP_0001845'>inflammatory responses</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>