<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>The use of progenitors and stem cells for neural grafting is promising, as these not only have the potential to be maintained in vitro until use, but may also prove less likely to evoke an immunogenic response in the host, when compared to primary (fetal) grafts </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We investigated whether the short-term survival of a grafted conditionally immortalised murine neuroepithelial stem cell line (MHP36) (2 weeks post-implantation, 4 weeks post-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischaemia</z:e>) is influenced by: (i) immunosuppression (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="4031">cyclosporin A</z:chebi> (CSA) vs. no CSA), (ii) the local (intact vs. lesioned hemisphere), or (iii) global (lesioned vs. sham) brain environment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>MHP36 cells were transplanted ipsi- and contralateral to the lesion in rats with middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAo) or sham controls </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Animals were either administered CSA or received no immunosuppressive treatment </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>A proliferation assay of lymphocytes dissociated from cervical lymph nodes, grading of the survival of the grafted cells, and histological evaluation of the immune response revealed no significant difference between animals treated with or without CSA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>There was no difference in survival or immunological response to cells grafted ipsi- or contralateral to the lesion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Although a local upregulation of immunological markers (MHC class I, MHC class II, CD45, CD11b) was detected around the injection site and the ischaemic lesion, these were not specifically upregulated in response to transplanted cells </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These results provide evidence for the low immunogenic properties of MHP36 cells during the initial period following implantation, known to be associated with an <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> host immune response and ensuing graft rejection </plain></SENT>
</text></document>