<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Studies suggest iron exacerbates the damage caused by <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Our aim was to elucidate the effect of <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0282193" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">iron overload</z:e> on <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size after middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) and to evaluate the efficacy of tempol, a <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase mimetic, as a neuroprotective agent </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Rats were administered iron +/- tempol before MCAO; control rats received saline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The middle cerebral artery was occluded for 24 h, and the size of the resultant <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> was assessed and expressed as the percentage of the hemisphere infracted (%HI) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Iron treatment increased <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> size compared with control (51.83 +/- 3.55 vs. 27.56 +/- 3.28%HI iron treated vs. control, P = 0.01); pretreatment with tempol reversed this (51.83 +/- 3.55 vs. 26.09 +/- 9.57%HI iron treated vs. iron + tempol treated, P = 0.02) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that reactive oxygen species (ROS) were responsible for the iron-induced damage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>We measured ROS generated by exogenous iron in brain and peripheral vasculature from rats that had not undergone MCAO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There was no increase in ROS production in the brain of iron-treated rats or in brain slices incubated with iron <z:chebi fb="2" ids="50744">citrate</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>However, ROS generation in carotid arteries incubated with iron <z:chebi fb="2" ids="50744">citrate</z:chebi> was significantly increased </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>ROS generation from the brain was assessed after MCAO by dihydroethidine staining; there was a dramatic increase in the ROS generation by the brain in the iron-treated rats compared with control 30 min after MCAO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>We propose that iron-induced ROS generation in the cerebral vasculature adds to <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> during an ischemic episode after the disruption of the blood-brain barrier </plain></SENT>
</text></document>