<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Kappa-opioid receptors (KOR) have been implicated in neuroprotection from ischemic neuronal injury, but less work has been performed with transient focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> to determine the role of KOR during reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We tested the effects of a selective and specific KOR <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi>, BRL 52537 hydrochloride [(+/-)-1-(3,4-dichlorophenyl)<z:chebi fb="9" ids="46887">acetyl</z:chebi>-2-(1-pyrrolidinyl)methylpiperidine], and the standard KOR <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, nor-binaltorphimine dihydrochloride [nor-BNI; 17,17'-(dicyclopropylmethyl)-6,6',7,7'-6,6'-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="29342">imino</z:chebi>-7,7'-binorphinan-3,4',14,14'-tetrol], on functional and histological outcome after transient focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> in the rat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>By use of the intraluminal filament technique, <z:chebi fb="2" ids="5615">halothane</z:chebi>-anesthetized adult male Wistar rats were subjected to 2 h of middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> confirmed by laser Doppler flowmetry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In a blinded, randomized fashion, rats were treated with 1). saline (vehicle) 15 min before reperfusion followed by saline at reperfusion for 22 h, 2). saline 15 min before reperfusion followed by BRL 52537 (1 mg x kg(-1) x h(-1)) at reperfusion for 22 h, 3). saline 15 min before reperfusion followed by nor-BNI (1 mg x kg(-1) x h(-1)) at reperfusion for 22 h, or 4) nor-BNI (1 mg/kg) 15 min before reperfusion followed by BRL 52537 (1 mgx kg(-1)x h(-1)) and nor-BNI (1 mg x kg(-1) x h(-1)) at reperfusion for 22 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>Infarct</z:mpath> volume (percentage of ipsilateral structure) analyzed at 4 days of reperfusion was significantly attenuated in saline/BRL 52537 rats (n = 8; cortex, 10.2% +/- 4.3%; caudoputamen [CP], 23.8% +/- 6.7%) (mean +/- <z:e sem="disease" ids="AmbiguousAbbrv" disease_type="AmbiguousAbbrv" abbrv="ambiguous">SEM</z:e>) compared with saline/saline treatment (n = 8; cortex, 28.6% +/- 4.9%; CP, 53.3% +/- 5.8%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Addition of the specific KOR <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi> nor-BNI to BRL 52537 completely prevented the neuroprotection (n = 7; cortex, 28.6% +/- 5.3%; CP, 40.9% +/- 6.2%) conferred by BRL 52537 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>BRL 52537 did not produce postischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0002045'>hypothermia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These data demonstrate that KORs may provide a therapeutic target during early reperfusion after <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>IMPLICATIONS: The neuroprotective effect of selective kappa-opioid <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonists</z:chebi> in transient focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> is via a selective action at the kappa-opioid receptors </plain></SENT>
</text></document>