<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE: Cerebroprotection after the administration of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">N-methyl-D-aspartate</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonists</z:chebi> has been well documented </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The present study sought to determine whether a cerebroprotective effect could be achieved with the administration of a non-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">N-methyl-D-aspartate</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonist</z:chebi>, GYKI 52466 (1-(4-aminophenyl)-4-<z:chebi fb="36" ids="29309">methyl</z:chebi>-7,8-<z:chebi fb="13" ids="29357,29358">methylene</z:chebi>-dioxy-5H-2,3-benzodiazep ine <z:chebi fb="16" ids="36807">hydrochloride</z:chebi>; molecular weight, 330) after middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> in the rat </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Neurological deficit and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume 24 hours after permanent left middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> in Fischer rats (n = 7-13 per group per dose) were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarcts</z:mpath> was visualized by the lack of reduction of 2,3,5-triphenyltetrazolium <z:chebi fb="76" ids="17996">chloride</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: GYKI 52466 (10 mg.kg-1 i.p. at 0, 2, 4 hours) after middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> had no effect on <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>GYKI 52466 (10 mg.kg-1 i.v. for 5 minutes followed by 15 mg.kg-1.hr-1 i.v. for 2 hours immediately after middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> reduced cortical <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume by 68% (from 69 mm3 in vehicle-treated to 22 mm3 in GYKI 52466-treated animals; p less than 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>A 1-hour delay before initiation of drug infusion resulted in a 48% reduction in cortical <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume (from 60 mm3 vehicle-treated rats to 31 mm3 in GYKI 52466-treated rats; p less than 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>A 2-hour delay before initiation of drug infusion had no effect on cortical <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Neurological deficits (with blinded assessment after 24 hours) were improved after immediate treatment and after delayed treatment (1 or 2 hours) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: The cerebroprotective effect of GYKI 52466 in the rat suggests a possible therapeutic role for non-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="31882">N-methyl-D-aspartate</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonists</z:chebi> given shortly after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>