<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Prior prolonged oxygen exposure is associated with some protection against <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>-reperfusion (IR) injury to rat brain tissue, but also with toxic effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We sought to compare the magnitude of protection offered by prolonged and intermittent oxygen pretreatments against IR injury to the rat brain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Rats were divided into four experimental groups, each of 21 animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>The first two were exposed to 95% inspired (normobaric <z:mp ids='MP_0002319'>hyperoxia</z:mp>, NBHO) for 4 h/day for 6 consecutive days (intermittent NBHO) or for 24 continuous hours (prolonged NBHO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The second two groups acted as controls were exposed to 21% oxygen </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After 24 h, they were subjected to 60 min of right middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) followed by 24 h of reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The animals were sacrificed for assessment of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002181'>brain edema</z:hpo>, and blood-brain barrier (<z:chebi fb="2" ids="33602">BBB</z:chebi>) permeability, respectively </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Prolonged and intermittent NBHO pretreatment reduced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume by 63.3% and 73.7%, respectively, when compared to the respective NBNO groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Intermittent NBHO (when compared to intermittent NBNO) also reduced the post-ischemic increment of brain water content significantly (81.53+/-0.8%, vs. 80.12+/-0.79%) and Evans Blue extravasation (7.49+/-2.89+/-g/g tissue vs. 3.9+/-0.79 microg/g tissue, P&lt;0.001), while prolonged NBHO had no significant effect on brain water content (81.69+/-1.16% vs. 80.74+/-0.94%) and EB extravasations (6.48+/-2.42 microg/g tissue vs. 4.31+/-1.07 microg/g tissue) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Intermittent <z:mp ids='MP_0002319'>hyperoxia</z:mp> had relatively more significant effects on <z:hpo ids='HP_0002181'>brain edema</z:hpo> and <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33602">BBB</z:chebi> protection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Although preconditioning with both prolonged and intermittent oxygen exposure protects rat brain tissue against IR injury, the intermittent <z:mp ids='MP_0002319'>hyperoxia</z:mp> could have relatively more protective effects in this regard </plain></SENT>
</text></document>