<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Muscarinic receptor <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonists</z:chebi> are used clinically for their therapeutic peripheral effects on bladder function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>However, these agents may also act on central muscarinic receptors, especially in individuals with compromised blood-brain barrier function </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We compared the effects of <z:chebi fb="28" ids="16684">atropine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9622">tolterodine</z:chebi>, agents that do and do not readily cross the blood-brain barrier, respectively, administered peripherally (intravenous [i.v.]) and centrally (intracerebroventricular [i.c.v.]) on cystometrography in conscious rats after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> induced by middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> or sham surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9622">tolterodine</z:chebi> would produce greater improvement in bladder capacity and less impairment in bladder contractility and that the effects of both agents would be greater in rats with <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> and sham-operated rats after peripheral administration, but that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9622">tolterodine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="28" ids="16684">atropine</z:chebi> would exert similar effects after central administration </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Bladder capacity was markedly reduced following <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Low-dose i.v. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9622">tolterodine</z:chebi> (&lt;or=20 nmol/kg) significantly reversed this effect without altering residual volume or bladder contraction pressure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Low-dose i.v. <z:chebi fb="28" ids="16684">atropine</z:chebi> (2 nmol/kg) had no effect on bladder capacity but significantly decreased bladder contraction pressure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Higher doses of i.v. <z:chebi fb="28" ids="16684">atropine</z:chebi> (&gt;or=20 nmol/kg) significantly increased bladder capacity but also significantly increased residual volume and decreased bladder contraction pressure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9622">Tolterodine</z:chebi> was significantly more efficacious than <z:chebi fb="28" ids="16684">atropine</z:chebi> in increasing bladder capacity, whereas <z:chebi fb="28" ids="16684">atropine</z:chebi> produced significantly greater increases in residual volume and reductions in bladder contraction pressure; these treatment group differences were also observed in sham-operated animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="9622">Tolterodine</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="28" ids="16684">atropine</z:chebi> administered i.c.v. significantly increased bladder capacity following <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007785" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">cerebral infarction</z:e> or sham surgery; however, this was accompanied by significantly increased residual volume and decreased bladder contraction time </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>The decrease in bladder contraction time was significantly smaller after <z:chebi fb="0" ids="9622">tolterodine</z:chebi> vs <z:chebi fb="28" ids="16684">atropine</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Peripherally acting muscarinic receptor <z:chebi fb="68" ids="48706">antagonists</z:chebi> may be preferable to centrally acting agents for minimizing adverse events, such as incomplete bladder emptying, even in individuals with compromised blood-brain barrier function </plain></SENT>
</text></document>