<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">Statins</z:chebi> exert rapid cholesterol-independent vasoprotective effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Here, we tested whether postevent treatment with intravenously (i.v.) administered <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38545">rosuvastatin</z:chebi> improves <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> outcome in mice </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: 129/SV <z:mp ids='MP_0002169'>wild-type</z:mp> mice were subjected to 1-hour filamentous middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAo), followed by reperfusion, and were postevent treated with i.v. or intraperitoneal (i.p.) <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38545">rosuvastatin</z:chebi> given up to 6 hours after MCAo (dose range 0.02 to 20 mg kg(-1) body weight) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38545">Rosuvastatin</z:chebi>, when administered i.v., significantly reduced lesion size when given up to 4 hours after MCAo and in doses as low as 0.2 mg kg(-1) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>In contrast, i.p. administration provided protection only when given directly on reperfusion at a dose of 20 mg kg(-1) but not at lower doses or later time points </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Lesion protection was evident as late as 5 days after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007786" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain ischemia</z:e> and was associated with functional improvements in the pole-test and wire-hanging test (2.0 mg kg(-1) dose) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Neuroprotection with i.v. <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38545">rosuvastatin</z:chebi> was achieved with peak plasma concentrations &lt;0.5 ng ml(-1) (ie, with 0.2 mg kg(-1)) and was associated with increased levels of phosphorylated Akt kinase and endothelial nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> synthase in the vasculature </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: <z:chebi fb="0" ids="38545">Rosuvastatin</z:chebi>, given intravenously at pharmacologically relevant concentrations, protects from focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007786" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain ischemia</z:e> up to 4 hours after an event </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In our opinion, the development of an intravenous <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statin</z:chebi> formulation is warranted for <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> trials with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35664">statins</z:chebi> in humans </plain></SENT>
</text></document>