<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Experimental evidence suggests that reactive free radicals are generated during <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007786" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain ischemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We investigated the effect of a novel brain penetrant, low molecular weight, non-peptidyl carbon, oxygen- and nitrogen-centered radical scavenger, IAC, on <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume and sensory-motor performance in a rat transient middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> model (tMCAO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Rats received 90 min tMCAO and treated with i.p. or i.v. injections of vehicle or IAC following tMCAO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Sensory-motor performance was evaluated by neuroscore tests (NS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume was evaluated at 72 h after tMCAO </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Rats treated with IAC i.p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>(1 or 6 h after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of tMCAO) or i.v </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>(1 h after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of tMCAO) showed significant improvement in NS during the 3 or 21 day follow-up period when compared to vehicle treated rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volumes were significantly decreased compared to vehicle in rats receiving IAC i.p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>1 h or 6 h after occlusion, approximately 30.5% decrease compared to vehicle, or i.v </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>1 h after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of tMCAO, 48.6% decrease compared to vehicle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>These results demonstrate that IAC has neuroprotective properties with a wide therapeutic window following tMCAO in rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>IAC could therefore be a candidate for the treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>