<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">Antioxidants</z:chebi> have been the focus of studies for developing neuroprotective agents to be used in the therapy for <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, which is an <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> and progressive <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0524851" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">neurodegenerative disorder</z:e> and is the second leading cause of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> throughout the world </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>In fact, many herbal <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidants</z:chebi> have been developed in in vitro and in vivo experiments and some of these have been tested in clinical studies of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Embelia ribes have been reported to have <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In addition to these effects, this study was designed to investigate the neuroprotective effect of ethanolic extract of E. ribes Burm fruits on middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO)-induced focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> in rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Male Wistar <z:mp ids='MP_0001189'>albino</z:mp> rats were fed ethanolic E. ribes extract (100 and 200 mg/kg body weight; p.o.) for 30 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After 30 days of feeding, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> animals were anaesthetized with chloral <z:chebi fb="1" ids="35505">hydrate</z:chebi> (400 mg/kg, i.p.) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The right middle cerebral artery was occluded with a 4-0 suture for 2 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The suture was removed after 2 h to allow reperfusion injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain><z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">Ischemia</z:e> followed by reperfusion in ischemic group rats significantly (P &lt; 0.001) reduced the grip strength activity and non-enzymatic (reduced <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi>, GSH) and enzymatic [<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> peroxidase (GPx), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> reductase (GR) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi>-S-transferase (GST)] <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> levels in hippocampus and frontal cortex compared to sham-operated rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Further, serum <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> dehydrogenase (LDH) and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33202">thiobarbituric acid</z:chebi> reactive substance (TBARS) levels in hippocampus and frontal cortex were significantly increased in ischemic group compared to sham-operated rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, ethanolic E. ribes extracts pretreatment significantly (P &lt; 0.001) increased the grip strength activity, and GSH, GPx, GR and GST levels in hippocampus and frontal cortex with significant decrease in LDH levels in serum and TBARS levels in hippocampus and frontal cortex compared to MCAO + vehicle group rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>The data from this study suggest that <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> treatment with ethanolic E. ribes extract enhances the <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> defense against MCAO- induced focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> in rats and exhibits neuroprotective activity </plain></SENT>
</text></document>