<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Previous studies utilizing alpha-melanocyte-stimulating hormone (alpha-<z:chebi fb="6" ids="16768">MSH</z:chebi>) or the synthetic analog [Nle(4),<z:chebi fb="0" ids="29996"> D-Phe</z:chebi>(7)] alpha-<z:chebi fb="6" ids="16768">MSH</z:chebi> have reported beneficial effects in animal models of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo>, with the latter studies suggesting melanocortin receptor subtype-4 (MC4R) activation as a protective mechanism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The present study directly addresses the hypothesis that MC4R activation may ameliorate ischemic brain injury by assessing the efficacy of a novel small molecule MC4R <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi> RY767, administered in a pharmacokinetically guided and pharmacologically validated dosing regimen, in a rat <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> model of transient middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (tMCAO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Male Wistar rats were subjected to 90-min tMCAO followed by 72 h of reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Treatments were i.p. pretreatment with MK-801 (15 min prior to occlusion, positive control), or combined i.v. and p.o. daily administrations of vehicle, <z:chebi fb="10" ids="4167">dextrose</z:chebi> (negative control) or RY767 in blinded fashion initiated 2 h after occlusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>Infarct</z:mpath> volume in MK-801-treated rats (158.7 +/- 22.3 mm(3)) was reduced significantly compared to vehicle <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume (243.4 +/- 12.5 mm(3)), whereas <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volumes in <z:chebi fb="10" ids="4167">dextrose</z:chebi>- (224.3 +/- 16.5 mm(3)) and RY767- (262.1 +/- 19.2 mm(3)) treated rats did not differ from vehicle <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>These results indicate that selective MC4R activation provides no significant neuroprotection, as reflected by <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume, in a rat <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> model utilizing a 90-min ischemic insult </plain></SENT>
</text></document>