<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Phellinus linteus, a natural growing mushroom, has been known to exhibit anti-<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0027651" disease_type="Neoplastic Process" abbrv="">tumor</z:e>, anti-inflammatory, anti-allergic and anti-oxidant effects </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Aiming to exploit the neuroprotective effects of P. linteus, we evaluated its effects on <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume reduction in a rat model of focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Male Sprague-Dawley rats were subjected to right middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Filtrate of P. linteus broth culture (various doses), fractionated filtrate (based on molecular weight) or control medium was administered intraperitoneally to rats before or after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> induction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Rats were killed at 24 h after the <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> surgery </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Cortical and caudoputaminal <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volumes were determined separately using an image analysis program following staining with 2,3,5-triphenyltetrazolium <z:chebi fb="76" ids="17996">chloride</z:chebi> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Significant cortical <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume reductions were found in the pre-treatment groups (30 and 60 minutes before <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>) compared with the control group, showing dose dependence </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Posttreatment (30 minutes after ischemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo>) also significantly reduced cortical <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, the higher molecular weight (≥12 000) fraction of the culture filtrate was more effective compared with the lower molecular weight fraction </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The present findings suggest that P. linteus may be a new promising approach for the treatment of focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>, with the additional benefit of a wide therapeutic time window since significant <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume reduction is obtained by administration even after the ischemic event </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Our finding that the higher molecular weight fraction of the P. linteus culture filtrate demonstrated more prominent effect may provide a clue to identify the neuroprotective substances and mechanisms </plain></SENT>
</text></document>