<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain><z:hpo ids='HP_0100543'>Cognitive impairments</z:hpo>, including spatial memory and learning deficiencies, are common after <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="50114">Estrogen</z:chebi> substitution improves cognitive functions in post-menopausal women and ovariectomized rodents, partially through induction of neuroplasticity in the hippocampal formation </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Post-ischemic housing of male rats in an enriched environment (EE) improves functional outcome, without changing <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16469">17beta-estradiol</z:chebi> combined with an EE would accelerate cognitive recovery after focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007786" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain ischemia</z:e> in ovariectomized rats and that recovery would be related to altered expression of nerve growth factor-induced gene (NGFI)-A in the hippocampus </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="16469">17beta-estradiol</z:chebi> or placebo pellets were implanted 6 h after transient middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Two days later, rats were placed in an EE or a deprived environment (DE) for 6 weeks </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At 5 weeks after middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp>, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16469">17beta-estradiol</z:chebi>-treated rats housed in an EE showed improvements in cognitive function (i.e. shorter latency and path in the <z:mp ids='MP_0001465'>Morris water maze</z:mp> task) compared with placebo-treated animals housed in an EE </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, beneficial effects on latency and path were observed when comparing EE-housed vs. DE-housed <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16469">17beta-estradiol</z:chebi>-treated rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>When comparing <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16469">17beta-estradiol</z:chebi>-treated EE-housed rats vs. placebo-treated DE-housed rats, pronounced effects on latency and path were observed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain><z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>Infarct</z:mpath> volumes did not differ between groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="16469">17beta-estradiol</z:chebi>-treated EE-housed rats had significantly higher NGFI-A <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> expression bilaterally in the cornu ammonis 1 region and in the ipsilateral dentate gyrus of the hippocampus, compared with placebo-treated EE-housed rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16469">17beta-estradiol</z:chebi> treatment combined with an EE improved recovery of cognitive function after experimental <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0007786" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">brain ischemia</z:e>, putatively through the upregulation of NGFI-A in hippocampal subregions </plain></SENT>
</text></document>