<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Aralia has been reported to exhibit various pharmacological properties, including anti-inflammatory, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35526">antidiabetic</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> activities </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We performed in vitro and in vivo analyses on the neuroprotective effects of an ethanolic extract of the aerial parts of Aralia cordata Thunb </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>(Araliaceae) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In cultured cortical neurons from rats, A. cordata (5-20 microg/mL) inhibited 100 muM <z:chebi fb="17" ids="16240">hydrogen peroxide</z:chebi> (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16240">H(2)O(2)</z:chebi>)-induced apoptotic neuronal <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, elevation of intracellular calcium concentration ([Ca(2+)](i)) and generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Since <z:chebi fb="0" ids="37659">oleanolic acid</z:chebi> isolated from A. cordata also inhibited <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16240">H(2)O(2)</z:chebi>-induced neuronal <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, increase in [Ca(2+)](i) and ROS generation in cultured cortical neurons, some of the neuroprotective effects of A. cordata might be attributable to this compound </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In rats, A. cordata prevented cerebral ischemic injury induced by 3 h of middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp>, followed by 24 h of reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Ischemic <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo> volumes were significantly reduced in rats that received A. cordata (50 mg/kg, orally) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>These animals exhibited a corresponding improvement in neurological function and a reduction of neuronal <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo>, as determined histologically from the cortex and hippocampal regions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>It is possible that the anti-oxidative properties of A. cordata may be responsible for its neuroprotective effects against focal cerebral ischemic injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>In future, A. cordata might play a therapeutic role in the prevention and treatment of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002180'>neurodegeneration</z:hpo> in <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>