<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the effects of neonatal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> on progenitor cells lining the lateral ventricles </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Intraventricular injection of replication-incompetent green fluorescent protein (GFP)-expressing lentivirus was performed in postnatal day 1 (P1) rats to specifically label radial glia/type B neural stem cells and ependymal cells of the lateral ventricle </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>A subset of animals was exposed to transient middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) at P7, with mild or moderate injury confirmed by diffusion-weighted MRI and histology </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Newborn cells were identified by GFP expression, location and expression of cell type-specific markers in the striatum, cortex and olfactory bulb using confocal microscopy and systematic random sampling </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Three weeks lentiviral GFP transduction of cells in the lateral ventricle, abundant GFP-expressing neurons and glia were identified in the rostral migratory stream, olfactory bulb and striatum as expected from labeling the subventricular zone (SVZ) type B neural stem cell lineage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Two weeks following mild or severe focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> at P7, no GFP-expressing neurons were detected in striatum or cortex although some single-labeled doublecortin+ immature neurons were detected in the penumbra </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The densities of GFP+/ glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP)+ astrocytes and GFP+/O4+ oligodendrocytes were reduced in the striatum following MCAO (4.8 +/- 1.02 vs. 2.5 +/- 0.4 cells/high-power field, HPF; p = 0.005; 2.8+/- 1 vs. 0.5 +/- 0.2 cells/HPF, p = 0.008) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, there was a reduction of GFP+ cells in the olfactory bulb following MCAO (58.8 +/- 14.9 vs. 19.6 +/- 5.4 cells/HPF, p = 0.025) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Finally, there was an increased percentage of GFP+/GFAP+ cells (70 vs. 50%), with a decreased proportion of GFP+/O4+ cells (14 vs. 30%) in injured animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Neurogenesis originating from cells of the lateral ventricle, including SVZ type B cells, is significantly reduced following neonatal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, neonatal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> disrupts gliogenesis in the striatum, decreasing overall numbers of new glia and shifting the population towards astrocytes </plain></SENT>
</text></document>