<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Recent studies suggest that dietary virgin olive oil (VOO) reduces <z:mp ids='MP_0005039'>hypoxia</z:mp>-reoxygenation injury in rat brain slices </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We sought to extend these observations in an in vivo study of rat <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>-reperfusion injury </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Four groups, each consisting of 18 Wistar rats, were studied </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>One group (control) received saline, while three treatment groups received oral VOO (0.25, 0.5, and 0.75 mL/kg/day, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After 30 days, blood <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> profiles were determined, before a 60-min period of middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After 24-h reperfusion, neurological deficit scores, <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002181'>brain edema</z:hpo>, and blood brain barrier permeability were each assessed in subgroups of six animals drawn from each main group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>VOO reduced the <z:chebi fb="15" ids="39026">LDL</z:chebi>/<z:chebi fb="17" ids="39025">HDL</z:chebi> ratio in doses of 0.25, 0.5, and 0.75 mL/kg/day in comparison to the control group (p &lt; 0.05), and offered cerebroprotection from <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>-reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>For controls vs. doses of 0.25 vs. 0.5 vs. 0.75 mL/kg/day, attenuated corrected <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volumes were 207.82 +/- 34.29 vs. 206.41 +/- 26.23 vs. 124.21 +/- 14.73 vs. 108.46 +/- 31.63 mm3; brain water content of the infarcted hemisphere was 82 +/- 0.25 vs. 81.5 +/- 0.56 vs. 80.5 +/- 0.22 vs. 80.5 +/- 0.34%; and blood brain barrier permeability of the infarcted hemisphere was 11.31 +/- 2.67 vs. 9.21 +/- 2.28 vs. 5.83 +/- 1.6 vs. 4.43 +/- 0.93 micro-g/g tissue (p &lt; 0.05 for measures in doses 0.5 and 0.75 mL/kg/day vs. controls) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Oral administration of VOO reduces <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume, <z:hpo ids='HP_0002181'>brain edema</z:hpo>, blood brain barrier permeability, and improves neurologic deficit scores after transient MCAO in rats </plain></SENT>
</text></document>