<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To explore the influence of recombination granulocyte colony stimulating factor (rG-CSF) on mobilization and distribution of bone marrow stem cells (BMSCs) in blood and brain tissue, and its role in protecting brain in rats with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: One hundred and six Sprague-Dawley (SD) rats were divided into sham-operated group (n=10),model group (n=48), rG-CSF group (n=48) according to the method of random digital table, and rats in model and rG-CSF groups were divided into four subgroups: i.e. 2, 3, 7 and 14 days subgroups, with 12 rats in each subgroup </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) model was reproduced with nylon thread </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In rats of rG-CSF group rG-CSF (10 μg/kg) was administered by subcutaneous injection 3 days before and 2 days after operation respectively, once a day </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Rats in sham-operated and model groups were administered with <z:mpath ids='MPATH_458'>normal</z:mpath> saline in the same volume, once a day </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>At the corresponding time after operation, general neural function score (GNFS) of rats was measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Blood was collected through abdominal aorta, then white blood cell (WBC) and CD34+ cells in peripheral blood were counted </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Brain pathologic changes were observed, and expression of CD34+ cells in rats brain tissue was determined by using immunohistochemical method </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: (1) GNFS was lower obviously in 2-day model group compared with that in sham-operated group, and then increased gradually </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>At 7 days and 14 days after operation, GNFS in rG-CSF group was higher significantly than that in model group (7 days: 11.86±0.69 vs. 10.53±0.76, 14 days: 13.38±0.52 vs. 12.38±0.52, both P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>(2) WBC and CD34+ cells in peripheral blood in model group increased obviously, with the highest level appeared at 3 days and lowered at 7 days and 14 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Increase of WBC and CD34+ cells in rats of rG-CSF group was more obvious than that of model group at each time point except CD34+ in 14 days group [WBC (×10(9)/L) 2 days: 11.75±1.76 vs. 8.07±1.27, 3 days: 13.07±1.70 vs. 10.88±1.78, 7 days: 8.63±1.36 vs. 5.58±1.57, 14 days: 6.98±0.98 vs. 4.87±0.92; CD34+ (cells/μl) 2 days: 8.83±2.14 vs. 3.17±0.75, 3 days: 13.50±1.87 vs. 5.00±1.55, 7 days: 5.33±1.21 vs. 2.33±1.21, P&lt;0.05 or P&lt;0.01] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>(3) Expression of CD34+ cells in the brain of rats in 2-day model group increased significantly, and the highest level appeared at 7 days and decreased at 14 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>Absorbance (A) value of CD34+ cells expression in rat brains of each rG-CSF group was more significant than that in model group (2 days: 43.21±4.41 vs. 22.04±2.95, 3 days: 45.79±1.76 vs. 25.69±2.44, 7 days: 52.09±2.86 vs. 33.04±2.62, 14 days: 29.73±1.99 vs. 16.91±2.95, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P&lt;0.01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="14" pm="."><plain>(4) The signs of injury to brain in pathological examination were less obvious in 14 days rG-CSF group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="15" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: BMSCs could be induced to enter peripheral blood and "home" to brain tissue after <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="16" pm="."><plain>It was showed that BMSCs increased in number at first and then decreased in peripheral blood and brain, the peak number was found on 3rd day in peripheral blood and 7th day in brain </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="17" pm="."><plain>Mobilization with rG-CSF could increase the number of BMSCs in peripheral blood and brain tissue </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="18" pm="."><plain>The effect of mobilization of BMSCs on protecting brain was significant after <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>, and effect appeared to be more pronounced with prolongation of mobilization </plain></SENT>
</text></document>