<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To study the effect of Leptin on neuron <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> in mice with <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> injury and its mechanism </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Seventy-five mice were randomly divided into three groups </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo>/reperfusion injury model in mice was reproduced by middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> for 2 hours followed by reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>In Leptin intervention group mice were given Leptin 1 μg/g during <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> by intraperitoneal injection </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Mice in the model group were given equal amount of phosphate buffer saline </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>After reperfusion for 24 hours, the neuron <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> was detected by terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase-mediated <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17625">dUTP</z:chebi> nick end labeling (TUNEL) staining </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>The <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> and protein expression of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> relative gene caspase-3 and bcl-2 were determined by reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) and immuno histochemistry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Most of neuron <z:mp ids='MP_0001651'>necrosis</z:mp> was observed in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> center in model group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Compared with sham-operation group, neuron <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> rate, <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> and protein expression of caspase-3 and bcl-2 in model group increased significantly [<z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> rate: (68.65 ± 0.79)% vs. (4.40 ± 0.00)%, caspase-3 mRNA: 2.563 ± 0.250 vs. 0.153 ± 0.020, bcl-2 mRNA: 0.337 ± 0.100 vs. 0.125 ± 0.030, caspase-3 protein (absorbance value, A value): 0.57 ± 0.05 vs. 0.37 ± 0.03, bcl-2 protein (A value): 0.51 ± 0.04 vs. 0.35 ± 0.01, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000001'>all</z:hpo> P&lt;0.01] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> rate of penumbra neurons was reduced in Leptin intervention group significantly compared with model group [(42.30 ± 8.45)% vs. (68.65 ± 0.79)%, P&lt;0.01] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Compared with model group, the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> and protein expression of caspase-3 in Leptin intervention group were reduced significantly [caspase-3 mRNA: 2.267 ± 0.040 vs. 2.563 ± 0.250, caspase-3 protein (A value): 0.45 ± 0.04 vs. 0.57 ± 0.05, P&gt;0.05 and P&lt;0.01], and the <z:chebi fb="2" ids="33699">mRNA</z:chebi> and protein expression of bcl-2 in Leptin intervention group upregulated significantly [bcl-2 mRNA: 0.662 ± 0.040 vs. 0.337 ± 0.100, bcl-2 protein (A value): 0.76 ± 0.09 vs. 0.51 ± 0.04, both P&lt;0.01] </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Leptin could reduce <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath> of neurons through down-regulation of the expression of caspase-3 and up-regulation of the expression of bcl-2 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>The results suggest that Leptin plays a neuroprotective role in <z:hpo ids='HP_0002637'>cerebral ischemia</z:hpo> injury </plain></SENT>
</text></document>