<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: We tested the hypothesis that both <z:hpo ids='HP_0011010'>chronic</z:hpo> and <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> inflammatory processes contribute to worse reperfusion injury and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> outcome in an experimental model of T2DM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>MATERIALS AND METHODS: Twelve- to thirteen-week-old male <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16646">Zucker</z:chebi> Diabetic Fatty (ZDF) rats vs. <z:chebi fb="3" ids="16646">Zucker</z:chebi> Lean Controls (ZLC) rats were tested at baseline and after middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (<z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e>) and reperfusion (I-R) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Neutrophil <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0001511" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">adhesion</z:e> to the cerebral microcirculation, neutrophil expression of CD11b, infarction size, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo>, neurologic function, sICAM, and cerebral expression of neutrophil-endothelial inflammatory genes were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: At baseline, CD11b and sICAM were significantly increased in ZDF vs. ZLC animals (p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>After I-R, significantly more neutrophil <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0001511" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome;Acquired Abnormality" abbrv="">adhesion</z:e> and cell aggregates were observed in ZDF vs. ZLC (p &lt; 0.05); infarction size, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo>, and neurologic function were significantly worse in ZDF vs. ZLC (p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>CD11b and sICAM-1 remained significantly increased in ZDFs (p &lt; 0.05), and cerebral expression of IL-1β, GRO/KC, E-selectin, and sICAM were significantly induced in ZDF, but not ZLC groups (p &lt; 0.05) after 2.5 hours of reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Both sides of the neutrophil-endothelial interface appear to be primed prior to I-R, and remain significantly more activated during I-R in an experimental model of T2DM </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Consequently, reperfusion injury appears to play a significant role in poor <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> outcome in T2DM </plain></SENT>
</text></document>