<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>BACKGROUND: Patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> are often transferred to tertiary care centers for advanced interventional services </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We hypothesized that the presence of a proximal cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> on CT angiography (CTA) is an independent predictor of the use of these services </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>METHODS: We performed a historical cohort study of consecutive <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> patients presenting within 24 h of symptom <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo> to an academic emergency department who underwent emergent CTA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Use of tertiary care interventions including intra-arterial (IA) thrombolysis, mechanical clot retrieval, and neurosurgery were captured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: During the study period, 207/290 (71%) of patients with <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> underwent emergent CTA </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Of the patients, 74/207 (36%) showed evidence of a proximal cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp>, and 22/207 (11%) underwent an interventional procedure </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Those with proximal occlusions were more likely to receive a neurointervention (26% vs. 2%, p &lt; 0.001) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>They were more likely to undergo IA thrombolysis (9% vs. 0%, p = 0.001) or a mechanical intervention (19% vs. 0%, p &lt; 0.0001), but not more likely to undergo neurosurgery (5% vs. 2%, p = 0.2) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>After controlling for the initial NIH <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> scale (NIHSS) score, proximal occlusion remained an independent predictor of the use of neurointerventional services (OR 8.5, 95% CI 2.2-33) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Evidence of proximal occlusion on CTA predicted use of neurointervention with sensitivity of 82% (95% CI 59-94%), specificity of 71% (95% CI 64%-77%), positive predictive value (<z:chebi fb="0" ids="53261">PPV</z:chebi>) of 25% (95% CI 16%-37%), and negative predictive value (NPV) of 97% (95% CI 92%-99%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: Proximal cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> on CTA predicts the need for advanced neurointerventional services </plain></SENT>
</text></document>