<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Centella asiatica has been used as psychoactive and <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> herbal medicine since ancient time </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The present study was design to evaluate the preventive role of ethanolic extract of C. asiatica in middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) in rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Male Wistar rats were gavaged orally with C. asiatica extract (100, 200 and 300 mg/kg body weight once daily) for 21 days and thereafter subjected to right MCAO for 2 h followed by 22-h reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Brain injury was evaluated by 2,3,5-triphenyltetrazolium <z:chebi fb="76" ids="17996">chloride</z:chebi> and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="51686">hematoxylin</z:chebi> and eosin staining </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Behavioural outcomes as neurological deficit, rota rod test, and grip strength were assessed </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>In addition, <z:chebi fb="23" ids="18059">lipid</z:chebi> peroxidation, enzymatic and non enzymatic <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidants</z:chebi> were analyzed to assess the <z:mp ids='MP_0003674'>oxidative stress</z:mp> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Our results revealed that C. asiatica administration greatly improved neurobehavioral activity and diminished infarction volume along with the restored histological <z:mp ids='MP_0000002'>morphology</z:mp> of brain in MCAO rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Furthermore, supplementation with this extract to MCAO group has reduced the level of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="33202">thiobarbituric acid</z:chebi> reactive species, restored <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> content and augmented the activities of <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> enzymes-catalase, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> peroxidase, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi> reductase, <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16856">glutathione</z:chebi>-S-transferase and <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18421">superoxide</z:chebi> dismutase in a dose-dependent manner in ischemic rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The remarkable <z:chebi fb="11" ids="22586">antioxidant</z:chebi> activity of C. asiatica may be attributed to its bioactive <z:chebi fb="0" ids="35191">triterpenes</z:chebi>, asiatic acid, asiaticoside, madecassic acid and madecosside and may be translated to clinical level for prevention of <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>