<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVE: To investigate the effects of echinacoside on the extracellular striatal levels of <z:chebi fb="1" ids="18357,33569">norepinephrine</z:chebi> (NE), <z:chebi fb="40" ids="18243">dopamine</z:chebi> (<z:mp ids='MP_0000273'>DA</z:mp>), homovanillic acid (HVA), 3, 4-dihydroxyphenylethanoid acid (DOPAC), 5-hydroxyindoleacetic acid (HIAA), and 5-hydroxytryptamine(<z:chebi fb="0" ids="28790">5-HT</z:chebi>) in middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: The middle cerebral artery was occluded in male Sprague-Dawley rats </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Three days later microdialysis probes were placed into the right striatum of MCAO rat brains and the brains were perfused with Ringer's solution at a rate of 1.5 microL/min </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Cerebral microdialysates were collected every 30 minutes from awake and freely moving rats before assaying for NE, <z:mp ids='MP_0000273'>DA</z:mp>, HVA, DOPAC, HIAA, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28790">5-HT</z:chebi> levels by reverse phase HPLC with electrochemistry </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: Three days after MCAO, the extracellular striatal levels of NE, <z:mp ids='MP_0000273'>DA</z:mp>, DOPAC, HIAA, HVA, and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="28790">5-HT</z:chebi> of the MCAO rats increased significantly (at least P &lt; 0.05 vs. control) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>However, simultaneous treatment with echinacoside (30.0 or 15.0 mg/kg) attenuated these increases (at least P &lt; 0.05 vs. non-treated model rats) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSION: These results imply that echinacoside may protect striatal <z:chebi fb="0" ids="49168">dopa</z:chebi> minergic neurons from the injury induced by MCAO and may help prevent and treat cerebral ischemic diseases </plain></SENT>
</text></document>