<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>OBJECTIVES: To compare outcome of ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> patients undergoing rescue endovascular procedure for proximal middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> with matched patients without endovascular procedure after unsuccessful intravenous thrombolysis </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>METHODS: Endovascularly treated patients with middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (n = 41) were matched by propensity score with similar patients treated by intravenous thrombolysis and having a considerable post-thrombolysis neurological deficit (n = 82) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>We compared their three-month outcome (modified Rankin Scale) and frequency of symptomatic intracerebral haemorrhage </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>For the endovascular group, we report <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo>-to-puncture time, <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo>-to-recanalization time, and recanalization rates </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>RESULTS: In age, gender, time from <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo>, admission National Institutes of Health <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>Stroke</z:hpo> Scale, systolic and diastolic blood pressure, blood <z:chebi fb="105" ids="17234">glucose</z:chebi>, history of <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000819'>diabetes mellitus</z:hpo>, <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0020473" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">hyperlipidaemia</z:e>, <z:hpo ids='HP_0005110'>atrial fibrillation</z:hpo>, and <z:hpo ids='HP_0001635'>congestive heart failure</z:hpo>, and in aetiology, the groups were similar </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Endovascular group patients had a recanalization rate of 90%, and more often reached three-month modified Rankin Scale 0-2 (36·6% vs. 18·3%, P = 0·03) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Mortality was equally common (19·5%) in both groups, and frequency of symptomatic intracerebral haemorrhage was 9·8% vs. 14·6% (P = 0·45) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The endovascular group's median <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo>-to-puncture time was four-hours and six-minutes and <z:hpo ids='HP_0003674'>onset</z:hpo>-to-recanalization time was five-hours and 12 min </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>The latter time was more than one-hour longer in patients treated under general anaesthesia compared with patients treated under conscious sedation (median four-hours 50 min vs. five-hours 58 min; P &lt; 0·01) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>CONCLUSIONS: Rescue endovascular approach increases likelihood of recanalization and may improve functional outcome in <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> ischaemic <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> patients with proximal middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> who did not respond to intravenous thrombolysis </plain></SENT>
</text></document>