<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Background: Men have a higher <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> incidence compared to women until advanced age </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>The contribution of hormones to these sex differences has been extensively debated </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>In experimental <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo>, <z:chebi fb="1" ids="23965">estradiol</z:chebi> is neuroprotective, whereas <z:chebi fb="5" ids="50113">androgens</z:chebi> are detrimental </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>However, prior studies have only examined the effects of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> treatment paradigms; therefore, the timing and mechanism by which ischemic sexual dimorphism arises are unknown </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Methods: The effects of exogenous neonatal <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50113">androgen</z:chebi> exposure on subsequent injury induced by middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> in adulthood in male rats were examined </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Rats were administered vehicle (oil), <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="17272">propionate</z:chebi> (TP) or the non-aromatizable <z:chebi fb="3" ids="50113">androgen</z:chebi> <z:chebi fb="1" ids="16330">dihydrotestosterone</z:chebi> (DHT) for 5 days after birth </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>At 3 months of age, a focal <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> was induced </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>Results: <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">Testosterone</z:chebi>-treated rats (but not DHT-treated animals) had decreased <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volumes (20 vs. 33%, p &lt; 0.05) as well as increased <z:chebi fb="1" ids="23965">estradiol</z:chebi> levels (39.4 vs. 18.6 pg/ml, p &lt; 0.0001) compared to oil-treated animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>TP-injected males had increased testicular aromatase (P450arom) levels (3.6 vs. 0.2 ng/ml, p &lt; 0.0001) compared to oil-treated males </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>The level of <z:hpo ids='HP_0001417'>X-linked</z:hpo> inhibitor of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath>, the primary endogenous inhibitor of caspase-induced <z:mpath ids='MPATH_3'>apoptosis</z:mpath>, was increased in TP-treated rats compared with the oil-treated males </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: Neonatal exposure to exogenous <z:chebi fb="51" ids="17347">testosterone</z:chebi> upregulates testicular aromatase expression in male rats and leads to adult neuroprotection secondary to changes in serum <z:chebi fb="1" ids="23965">estradiol</z:chebi> levels and cell <z:hpo ids='HP_0011420'>death</z:hpo> proteins </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>This study suggests that early exposure to gonadal hormones can have dramatic effects on the response to adult cerebrovascular injury </plain></SENT>
</text></document>