<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Reperfusion therapy for <z:hpo ids='HP_0002140'>ischemic stroke</z:hpo> can cause secondary brain injury, especially under hyperglycemic (HG) conditions </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Here we investigated the effect of <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> treatment with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi>, a peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-gamma (PPAR-γ) <z:chebi fb="4" ids="48705">agonist</z:chebi>, prior to postischemic reperfusion, on <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> outcome during HG <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Male Wistar rats that were either normoglycemic (NG) or HG by STZ (50 mg/kg; for 5-6 days) underwent middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) for 2 hours with 2 hours of reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Animals were treated i.v. with <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> (1mg/kg; n=16), <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> (1mg/kg) + the free radical scavenger Tempol (50mg/kg; n=10) or vehicle (n=16) ten minutes prior to reperfusion and <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume, <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo> formation and cerebral blood flow (CBF) were measured </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Compared to NG, HG <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> significantly increased <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume from 5.2±3.0% vs. 14.7±3.6% (p&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain><z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">Rosiglitazone</z:chebi> prevented the increased <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume induced by HG that was only 6.9±2.0% (p&lt;0.05 vs. HG) but did not have any effect on <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>edema</z:hpo> formation that was increased by 3.0% in both HG vehicle and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi>-treated ipsilateral vs. contralateral hemispheres (p&lt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Combined treatment of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> + Tempol did not significantly change brain water content that remained 2.2% greater than contralateral (p&lt;0.05), but reversed the neuroprotective properties of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> in HG MCAO animals such that <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume was 14.3±4.4% (p&gt;0.05 vs. vehicle) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The lack of an effect of combined treatment of <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> + Temple may be due to a decrease in reperfusion CBF that was only 60% of baseline (p&lt;0.01) compared to 82% and 89% for HG vehicle and <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> treated animals (p&gt;0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>In conclusion, <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:chebi fb="0" ids="50122">rosiglitazone</z:chebi> treatment prior reperfusion was neuroprotective but not vascular protective during HG <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>