<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Background: <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">Lactate</z:chebi> protects mice against the ischaemic damage resulting from transient middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) when administered intracerebroventricularly at reperfusion, yielding smaller lesion sizes and a better neurological outcome 48 h after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischaemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>We have now tested whether the beneficial effect of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> is long-lasting and if <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> can be administered intravenously </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Methods: Male ICR-CD1 mice were subjected to 15-min suture MCAO under xylazine + ketamine anaesthesia </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Na <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16651">L-lactate</z:chebi> (2 µl of 100 mmol/l) or vehicle was administered intracerebroventricularly at reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>The neurological deficit was evaluated using a composite deficit score based on the neurological score, the rotarod test and the beam walking test </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Mice were sacrificed at 14 days </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>In a second set of experiments, Na <z:chebi fb="0" ids="16651">L-lactate</z:chebi> (1 µmol/g body weight) was administered intravenously into the tail vein at reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>The neurological deficit and the lesion volume were measured at 48 h </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Results: Intracerebroventricularly injected <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> induced sustained neuroprotection shown by smaller neurological deficits at 7 days (median = 0, min = 0, max = 3, n = 7 vs. median = 2, min = 1, max = 4.5, n = 5, p &lt; 0.05) and 14 days after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischaemia</z:e> (median = 0, min = 0, max = 3, n = 7 vs. median = 3, min = 0.5, max = 3, n = 7, p = 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Reduced tissue damage was demonstrated by attenuated hemispheric <z:mpath ids='MPATH_127'>atrophy</z:mpath> at 14 days (1.3 ± 4.0 mm(3), n = 7 vs. 12.1 ± 3.8 mm(3), n = 5, p &lt; 0.05) in <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi>-treated animals </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Systemic intravenous <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> administration was also neuroprotective and attenuated the deficit (median = 1, min = 0, max = 2.5, n = 12) compared to vehicle treatment (median = 1.5, min = 1, max = 8, n = 12, p &lt; 0.05) as well as the lesion volume at 48 h (13.7 ± 12.2 mm(3), n = 12 vs. 29.6 ± 25.4 mm(3), n = 12, p &lt; 0.05) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>Conclusions: The beneficial effect of <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> is long-lasting: <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> protects the mouse brain against ischaemic damage when supplied intracerebroventricularly during reperfusion with behavioural and histological benefits persisting 2 weeks after <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischaemia</z:e> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>Importantly, <z:chebi fb="4" ids="24996">lactate</z:chebi> also protects after systemic intravenous administration, a more suitable route of administration in a clinical emergency setting </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>These findings provide further steps to bring this physiological, commonly available and inexpensive neuroprotectant closer to clinical translation for <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
</text></document>