<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>We investigated the putative role of nitric <z:chebi fb="177" ids="25741,29356">oxide</z:chebi> in the expression of neuronal injury following both transient severe forebrain <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> (CA1 neuronal injury) and transient or permanent middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (neocortical pannecrosis) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Using the four-vessel occlusion model and increasing doses of N-omega-<z:chebi fb="13" ids="29785">nitro</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16467,29952">L-arginine</z:chebi>, 2-40 mg/kg, we were unable to demonstrate any reduction in the percentage of CA1 cells injured following 10 min of transient severe forebrain <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> followed by seven days of reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>Higher doses proved toxic insofar as they increased the mortality following the ischemic insult </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Saline-treated animals (n = 8) had 77 +/- 10% CA1 injury while those treated with 2 mg/kg of <z:chebi fb="13" ids="29785">nitro</z:chebi>-arginine i.v. had 80 +/- 7% (n = 7), and those with 10 mg/kg i.v. had 78 +/- 11% (n = 8) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Two of five rats given 20 mg/kg i.v., three of eight given 40 mg/kg i.v., and two of six given 10 mg/kg i.v. followed by 3 x 10 mg/kg i.p., died </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Of those treated with high-dose <z:chebi fb="13" ids="29785">nitro</z:chebi>-arginine and which survived <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> and seven days' reperfusion, no significant reduction in CA1 injury was detected </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Wistar rats and spontaneously hypertensive rats treated with either saline or <z:chebi fb="13" ids="29785">nitro</z:chebi>-arginine i.v. were exposed to 2 h of transient middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> followed by 22 h of reperfusion </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>There were seven animals in each group </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="8" pm="."><plain>Wistars treated with saline had 198 +/- 67 mm3 (mean +/- S.D.) of neocortical infarction, and those treated with 10 m/kg of <z:chebi fb="13" ids="29785">nitro</z:chebi>-arginine i.v. had 199 +/- 93 mm3 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="9" pm="."><plain>Spontaneously hypertensive rats, transiently ischemic, treated with saline had 164 +/- 25 mm3 of <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume, while those treated with 2 mg/kg i.v. had 151 +/- 53 mm3, and those treated with 10 mg/kg i.v. had 145 +/- 29 mm3 </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="10" pm="."><plain>Animals treated with 40 mg/kg i.v. had a nonsignificantly larger mean <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume (191 +/- 81 mm3) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="11" pm="."><plain>High dose <z:chebi fb="13" ids="29785">nitro</z:chebi>-arginine caused an increase in <z:hpo ids='HP_0000822'>hypertension</z:hpo> in the spontaneously hypertensive rats and increased the severity of focal <z:e sem="disease" ids="C0022116" disease_type="Disease or Syndrome" abbrv="">ischemia</z:e> as measured by intra-ischemic regional cerebral blood flows </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="12" pm="."><plain>A final group of seven spontaneously hypertensive rats underwent permanent middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> and repeated dosing with N-omega-<z:chebi fb="13" ids="29785">nitro</z:chebi>-<z:chebi fb="0" ids="16467,29952">L-arginine</z:chebi> i.p </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="13" pm="."><plain>In these animals an <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume of 234 +/- 60 mm3 was observed, which was again not statistically different from saline-treated controls (208 +/- 43 mm3, n = 7).(ABSTRACT TRUNCATED AT 400 WORDS) </plain></SENT>
</text></document>