<document xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:z="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/z" source="Whatizit"><text><SENT sid="0" pm="."><plain>Variability in the effects of the intraluminal suture method of middle cerebral <z:mp ids='MP_0006134'>artery occlusion</z:mp> (MCAO) in the rat has been a common and disadvantageous finding </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="1" pm="."><plain>Therefore, we systematically investigated the effects of suture type and rat strain on outcome </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="2" pm="."><plain>First, the clinical and neuropathological effects of permanent MCAO with either an uncoated or a <z:chebi fb="144" ids="48140">silicone</z:chebi>-coated nylon suture were studied over 7 days in Sprague-Dawley rats (n = 36 for each type of suture) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="3" pm="."><plain>Outcome was less severe with the uncoated compared with the <z:chebi fb="144" ids="48140">silicone</z:chebi>-coated suture (e.g. total cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume at 24 h before any fatalities was 119.9 +/- 79.8 mm3, cf. 183.0 +/- 36.5 mm3, n = 12 for each, P &lt; 0.05; and overall mortality rate was 12.5% cf. 33%, respectively), but much more variable (coefficient of variation was 66.6% cf. 19.9%, respectively) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="4" pm="."><plain>Second, being more consistent in its effects, the <z:chebi fb="144" ids="48140">silicone</z:chebi>-coated suture was further studied in Wistar and Fischer-344 rats (n = 12 for each) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="5" pm="."><plain>Seventy-five per cent of the Wistar's died prematurely from gross hemispheric <z:hpo ids='HP_0000969'>oedema</z:hpo> </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="6" pm="."><plain>Motor deficit and extent of infarction in the Fischer-344 rats were both significantly greater compared with Sprague-Dawley rats (e.g. total cerebral <z:mpath ids='MPATH_124'>infarct</z:mpath> volume at 24 h in the former was 253.6 +/- 25.4 mm3, n = 11, P &lt; 0.05), and more consistent (coefficient of variation was only 10.0%) </plain></SENT>
<SENT sid="7" pm="."><plain>It was concluded that the <z:chebi fb="144" ids="48140">silicone</z:chebi>-coated suture and the Fischer-344 rats strain produced the most consistent results and their novel combination provides a reliable <z:hpo ids='HP_0011009'>acute</z:hpo> <z:hpo ids='HP_0001297'>stroke</z:hpo> model </plain></SENT>
</text></document>